All right, you chipmunks.
Ready to sing your song?
- I'll say we are!
- Yeah. Let's sing it now.
- OK, Simon?
- OK.
- OK, Theodore?
OK, Alvin? Alvin?
- Alvin!
- OK!
You wanna be Atticus Finch.
- Oh, that makes me feel so good!
- I like him.
- Why?
- Well, he's honest.
- Yes.
- He stands up for the right thing.
- And he's a good father.
- He is.
- He did it all by himself.
- Did what all by himself?
- Raised his kids.
He didn't raise them by himself!
Excuse me, who was the woman
- that came to their house every day?
- Calpurnia.
- Calpurnia. He remembered!
- And what about Boo?
What about Boo?
I think that Boo Radley
is one of the most interesting
characters in To Kill a Mockingbird.
Excuse me? I'm a teacher.
"Xmas" is not a word
in the English language.
It's either "Merry Christmas"
or "Happy Holidays."
- Thank you.
- Sure.
- Mom. Tell me more about Livia.
- She killed everybody off,
so her son Tiberius could inherit
the throne, just like Nixon.
The same stories...
Shakespeare, you know,
like those plays we went
to see at the Old Globe.
- Anita?
- Hey, Mom.
- Want somethin' to eat?
- Oh, no thanks. I already ate.
- Are you sure? I made soy cutlets.
- I'm fine. I already ate.
Wait. You've been kissing.
- No, I haven't. No, I haven't.
- Yes, you have. Yes, you have.
- I can tell.
- You can't tell.
Not only can I tell,
I know who it is. It's Darryl.
What you got under your coat?
It's unfair that we can't
listen to our music.
It's because it is about drugs
and promiscuous sex.
- Simon & Garfunkel is poetry.
- Yes, it is the poetry of drugs
and promiscuous sex.
Honey, they're on pot.
First, it was butter.
Then it was sugar and white flour,
bacon, eggs, bologna,
rock and roll, motorcycles.
Then, it was celebrating Christmas
on a day in September
when you knew it
wouldn't be commercialized.
- What else are you gonna ban?
- Honey, you want
to rebel against knowledge.
I'm trying to give you the CliffsNotes
on how to live life in this world.
We're like nobody else I know!
I am a college professor.
Why can't I teach my own kids?
- Use me!
- Darryl says that you use knowledge
to keep me down.
He says I'm a "yes" person
and you are trying to raise us
in a "no" environment.
Well, clearly "no" is a word
Darryl doesn't hear much.
I can't live here! I hate you!
Even William hates you.
- I don't hate her.
- You do hate her.
You don't even know the truth.
- Sweetheart, don't be a drama queen.
- Feck you!
- Hey!
- This is a house of lies!
There it is.
- Your sister used the "f" word.
- I think she said, "feck."
- What's the difference?
- The letter "u."
- Are you really in our grade?
- Yeah.
Hey, guys, check it out.
William doesn't have any pubes.
How old are you, man?
He's not a man.
He's a little baby-kid.
- I bet he doesn't even get zits yet.
- Everyone has hair.
- What's wrong with you?
- Pipsqueak!
- How old are you? Like two?
- What's your age, man?
- How old are you?
- You're pathetic!
Where are your pubes?
I had 'em.
I shaved 'em off.
He's a funny guy!
See you, Pubes.
- Hey, noodle.
- Hi, guys.
Put on your seatbelt.
- We got our annuals today.
- Received your annual.
Right, received.
I look so much younger
than everyone else.
Enjoy it while you can.
Mom, it's time.
- Can this wait till we get home?
- Mom, pull over.
Tell him the truth.
Tell him how old he is.
- He knows how old he is.
- But other kids make fun of him
because of how young he looks.
Nobody includes him.
They call him "The Narc"
behind his back.
- They do?
- What's a narc?
- A narcotics officer.
- Well, what's wrong with that?
Come on, you guys.
It's no big deal.
I'm 12. She skipped me a grade.
Big deal. I'm a year younger.
They're 13, I'm 12.
- Aren't I?
- I also put you in first grade
when you were five,
and I never told you.
- So I'm how old?
- Don't you realize that this
- is gonna scar him forever?
- Honey, sweetheart,
don't be Cleopatra. We have
to be both his mother and his dad.
- You put too much pressure on him.
- How old...
And when he rebels in some strange
and odd way, don't blame me.
- ...am I?
- I skipped you an extra grade.
You're 11!
Eleven?
So you skipped fifth grade!
There's too much padding in the grades.
- I taught elementary school.
- Eleven?
You also skipped kindergarten,
because I taught it to you
when you were four.
This explains... so much.
You've robbed him of an adolescence.
Adolescence is a marketing tool.
Honey, I know you were
expecting puberty,
but you're just gonna have
to shine it on for a little while.
Who needs a "crowd"?
Who put such a high premium
on being typical?
You're unique.
You're two years ahead of everybody.
Take those extra years
and do what you want.
Go to Europe for a year.
Take a look around.
See what you like.
Follow your dream.
You'll still be the youngest lawyer
in the country.
Your dad was so proud of you.
He knew that you were
a predominantly accelerated child.
What about me?
You are rebellious
and ungrateful of my love.
Well, somebody's
gotta be normal around here.
Eleven.
This song explains why I'm leaving
home to become a stewardess.
We can't talk?
We have to listen to rock music?
I love you.
Hey, man, take good care
of her in San Francisco, man.
One day... you'll be cool.
Look under your bed.
It'll set you free.
Watch the plant.
You're 18 and I can't stop you.
Bye.
She'll be back.
Maybe not soon.
Hey, William. Hey!
Here's a theory
for you to disregard...
...completely.
Music, you know, true music...
...not just rock and roll,
it chooses you.
It lives in your car, or alone,
listening to your headphones...
...with the vast, scenic bridges
and angelic choirs in your brain.
It's a place apart...
...from the vast, benign lap of America.
Did you know that The Letter
by The Box Tops
was a minute and 58 seconds long?
It means nothing.
Nil. But it takes them less
than two minutes to accomplish
what Jethro Tull takes hours
to not accomplish!
You see that, this is fatuous,
pseudo-blubber. You know?
I mean, which is fine, but...
foist it off as art?
You know, or The Doors... Jim Morrison?
He's a drunken buffoon,
posing as a poet.
- I like The Doors.
- Give me The Guess Who.
They got the courage
to be drunken buffoons,
which makes them poetic.
It's quite an honor to have
the world's greatest rock critic
and editor of Creem magazine back
home in San Diego for a few days:
- Lester Bangs.
- Live, American Woman.
Have you ever... The most brilliant
piece of gobbledy-gook ever!
Give me some White Light/White Heat.
Iggy Pop! Amen.
Put this on.
This isn't on your playlist either.
Lester, don't you think
it's a little bit early for that?
Not for me.
OK, that was Lester Bangs, this
is Alice Wisdom, and here is Iggy Pop.
So you're the kid
who's been sending me those articles
- from the school newspaper.
- Yeah. Yeah.
I've been doin' some stuff
for a local underground paper also.
What are you, like
the star of your school?
- They hate me.
- You'll meet them all again
on their long journey to the middle.
Your writing is damn good. It's just a
shame you missed out on rock and roll.
- It's over. It's over!
- Over?
You got here just in time
for the death rattle.
Last gasp. Last grope.
- At least I'm here for that.
- Yeah, what do you type on?
Smith Corona Galaxis Deluxe.
- And you like Lou Reed?
- The early stuff.
In his new stuff,
he's trying to be Bowie.
He should just... be himself.
Yeah, but if Bowie's doing Lou,
and if Lou's doing Bowie,
- Lou's still doing Lou.
- If you like Lou.
- You take drugs?
- No.
Smart kid.
I used to do speed.
You know, and sometimes
a little cough syrup?
I'd stay up all night,
just writin' and writin'.
I mean, like 25 pages of dribble.
You know, about
The Faces, or Coltrane.
You know, just to fuckin' write.
All right. It's been nice to meet ya.
Keep sending me your stuff.
I can't stand here all day
talking to my many fans.
Yeah. I understand. OK.
- Goodbye.
- Yeah. Bye.
- Bye.
You need a ride?
No, man, I took the bus.
You know, because once you go to LA,
you're gonna have friends like crazy.
But they're gonna be fake friends.
They're gonna try to corrupt you.
You got an honest face,
and they're gonna tell you everything.
But you cannot make friends
with the rock stars.
- Is it OK if I...
- If you're gonna be a true journalist,
you know, a rock journalist...
First, you never get paid much.
But you will get free records
from the record company.
Jesus.
Fuckin' nothin' about you
that is controversial, man.
God, it's gonna get ugly, man.
They're gonna buy you drinks,
you're gonna meet girls, they're gonna
try to fly you places for free,
offer you drugs.
I know, it sounds great,
but these people
are not your friends.
These are people who want you
to write sanctimonious stories
about the genius of rock stars.
And they will ruin
rock and roll and strangle
everything we love about it.
They're trying to buy respectability
for a form that is gloriously
and righteously dumb!
I mean, you're smart enough
to know that.
And the day it ceases to be dumb
is the day that it ceases to be real.
Right? And then it just
becomes an industry of cool.
I'm tellin' you, you're coming along at
a very dangerous time for rock and roll.
I mean, the war is over. They won.
Ninety-nine percent of what passes
for rock and roll these days,
silence is more compelling.
That's why I think you should just
turn around and go back, you know,
and be a lawyer or something.
But I can tell from your face
that you won't.
I can give you 35 bucks.
Give me 1,000 words on Black Sabbath.
- An assignment?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Hey.
You have to make your reputation
on being honest,
and...
you know, unmerciful.
Honest.
Unmerciful.
If you get into a jam,
you can call me.
I stay up late.
Look at this. An entire
generation of Cinderellas,
and there's no slipper coming.
You just remember,
you wanted to be Abraham Lincoln.
You wanted to be Atticus Finch
in To Kill A Mockingbird.
You want to get high?
Lookin' to get high?
All I have to do is listen.
- That's what Lester Bangs said.
- As long as I know this is a hobby.
I'll pick you up right here
at 11:00 sharp.
If you get lost, use the family whistle.
- Good luck.
- Thanks.
- Don't take drugs!
- "Don't take drugs!"
Yes, Mother!
Hi. I'm William Miller.
I'm here from Creem Magazine,
to interview Black Sabbath.
Not on the list.
- I'm a journalist. Here's a copy...
- You're not on the list.
Go to the top of the ramp
with the other girls.
We won't bite.
What happens after I go
to the top of the ramp?
- Who are you with?
- Me? I'm with myself.
No, who are you with. What band?
I'm here to interview Black Sabbath.
I'm a journalist.
- I'm not... Not a... You know.
- You're not a what?
You're not a what?
- Not a... groupie.
- Groupie?
We are not groupies.
This is Penny Lane, man.
Show some respect.
Groupies sleep with rock stars 'cause
they wanna be near someone famous.
We're here because of the music.
We are Band Aids.
She used to run a school
for Band Aids.
We don't have intercourse with
these guys. We support the music.
We inspire the music. We're here...
because of the music.
Marc Bolan broke her heart, man.
- It's famous.
- It's a long story.
I'm retired now. Visiting friends.
She was the one who changed
everything. She was the one who said,
"No more sex. No more exploiting
our bodies and our hearts."
- Right. Right.
- Just blow jobs, and that's it.
It's all happening!
- It's all happening!
Penny!
- It's all happening.
- OK. This is our journalist friend.
Journalist friend meet
Polexia Aphrodisiac,
Estrella Star.
- And you are...
- William Miller.
Here comes Sabbath!
Ozzy! Ozzy Osbourne!
It's me, Polexia!
Come on, get out of here!
Back up! Back up!
I think I saw Sapphire in there.
Does anybody remember laughter?
- Sapphire!
- Come on!
Passes, girls. Come and get 'em.
- Oh, no. Not this one.
- Who brought Opie?
- Oh, he's with us.
- Top of the ramp!
- Don't go anywhere, Opie.
- I'll take care of this.
If I can.
Come on, boys.
Pick it up, will ya?
This is outrageous.
We're an hour and a half late!
I'm comin', I'm comin'.
Freddy!
Open up, it's Stillwater!
We're on the show!
Hi.
I'm a journalist.
I write for Creem Magazine.
Oh, the enemy. A rock writer.
Right. Well, I'd like to interview you,
or somebody from your band.
Look, I'm sorry,
but could you please fuck off?
We play for the fans, not the critics.
Freddy!
Russell, Jeff, Ed, Larry.
I really love your band.
I think the song Fever Dog
is a big step forward for you guys.
And you guys producing it
yourselves instead of Glyn Johns,
that was the right thing to do.
And Russell...
Russell, the guitar sound...
...is "incindiary."
Incendiary.
Way to go.
- Hey, man.
- Don't stop there.
- Where you goin'? Come back.
- I'm incendiary too, man.
- Freddy!
- Hey.
- How you doin', buddy?
- How you doin'? He's with us.
- Come on this way, bro.
- He's not on your list!
Here's a list of people
who do belong, all right?
- Red Dog! Hey, Red Dog.
- Hey-hey!
- We're playing here tomorrow night.
- Yeah?
How you doing, brother?
- Good to see you, man.
- Good to see you, too.
That's the Allman Brothers Band's
number one roadie.
- How are the guys?
- They're having a ball, man.
Having a ball.
Yeah, you know, when we have a party,
we have an Allman Brothers Band
party, man.
Everybody's boogying,
everybody's getting off.
We're like family, man.
Hey, we've got these now.
Check that out.
Yeah, you can taste the color
with your mind, brother.
- You're all gonna be in Maryland?
- Yeah.
All right. All right. Hey, Dickey
and Gregg send you love, brother.
- Cool.
- Take it easy.
Take it easy, brother.
Some people have a hard time
explaining rock and roll.
Really explain rock and roll.
Maybe Pete Townshend, but that's OK!
Rock and roll is a lifestyle,
and a way of thinking, and it's
not about money and popularity,
although some money would be nice.
But it's a voice that says, "Here I am,
and fuck you
if you can't understand me."
And one of these people
is gonna save the world.
And that means that rock and roll
can save the world,
all of us together.
And the chicks are great. But what it
all comes down to is that thing:
the indefinable thing when people
catch something from your music.
What I'm talking about is...
Wait, what am I talking about?
- The buzz.
And the chicks, the whatever,
is an offshoot of the buzz.
Like you saying you liked Fever Dog.
That is the fucking buzz!
Hey.
Found you a pass.
Thanks. I got in with Stillwater.
Stillwater.
Now, you're mysterious.
- How old are you?
- Eighteen.
Me, too.
How old are we, really?
Seventeen.
- Me, too!
- Actually, I'm 16.
Me, too. Isn't it funny?
The truth just sounds different.
I'm 15.
What's your real name?
I'll never tell.
- The Enemy! Yes.
- Russell! Hey. Hey.
This... is Penny Lane.
Penny Lane, Russell Hammond.
- Pleasure.
- "Penny Lane." Like the song.
Have we met?
Come here, man.
I wanna tell you something.
Two, two. Two!
It's... It's not what you put into it.
It's what you leave out.
You listen to...
listen to Marvin Gaye.
A song like
What's Happening Brother,
there is a single "whoo"
at the end of the second verse.
You know that "whoo"?
That single "whoo"?
I know that "whoo." Yeah.
Yeah. That's what you remember, man.
It's the little things.
The silly things. The mistakes.
There is only one of them
and it makes the song.
It's what you leave out.
Yeah. That's rock and roll.
You're supposed to be the enemy.
What are you, 18?
- Yes.
- There you go.
Still young enough to be honest.
All right.
Could we bring the lights down?
Won't you get on my back
for a piggyback ride?
Hey, get The Enemy in here.
Get on my back for a piggyback ride
San Diego! You ready, baby?
Hell, yeah!
- Good evening, San Diego!
- Stand right over there.
Would you please welcome,
from Troy, Michigan...
...Stillwater!
Russell! I love you!
Thank you!
Hey! You...
You wanna come to LA?
We'll be at the Riot House all week.
- Riot House?
- Yeah.
The Continental Hyatt House.
It's on Sunset Strip.
Oh, yeah. Right. Sunset Strip.
Well, tell your friend...
...Miss "Penny Lane," to call me.
Tell her it ain't
California without her.
And we want her around,
like last summer.
Say it just like that.
- Got it. Got it.
- I'm under Harry Houdini.
I get it.
- Come on, let's blow this burg!
- The Enemy!
- Come up to LA, we'll talk some more.
- Bye!
- Bye, Opie.
- See you later, Jeff, Polexia.
- See ya, Dick.
- See ya down the line!
Scully, Ed. See ya, Mick.
Greg. Yeah, later, guys.
Bye, Opie.
Bye.
- Hey, Red Dog. I'll see ya later, man.
- Bye, fella.
"The Wheel." "Frosty."
Ainsworth. Ainsworth.
I'll see you around, man.
- Penny! Penny!
- Hey! Hey! Be cool.
Penny, you just missed Russell.
He said he's at the Riot House all week,
and for you to call him.
He's under the name Harry Houdini.
- You know about the Riot House, right?
- I think I've heard of it.
Right, well, he had a message.
He said,
"Tell her it's not California
without you.
We want you around,
like last summer."
No! No! He said, "Tell her it ain't
California without you, we want..."
- I get the gist.
- Right. Right.
So... how well do you guys
know each other?
Call me if you need a rescue.
We live in the same city.
I think I live in a different world.
Speaking of the world...
...I've made a decision.
I'm gonna live in Morocco,
for one year.
I need a new crowd.
Do you wanna come?
Yes. Yeah. Yeah.
- You sure?
- Ask me again.
Do you wanna come?
Yes. Yes.
- You've gotta call me.
- OK.
It's all happening!
It's all happening.
- You all right?
- Yeah. Yeah. Great.
And it's not about money,
and popularity...
And the chicks are great. Right?
- Hey, Darryl.
- Hey.
- So your sister's a stewardess now.
- Yeah. Yeah.
She and Mom are still sort of...
Well, I'd say, I'd say "not speaking,"
but I don't know that they ever did.
The things your sister and I used
to do inside these four walls.
That's OK. That's OK.
I don't want to know.
- It is my room now.
- We flew the friendly skies.
OK, OK. OK.
- You seem cooler.
- I am...
...I am thinking about going to Morocco.
Let me know if you need a little help
with your mom.
- A little may not be enough.
- Yeah, she still freaks me out.
- Yeah. Listen...
- She's famous.
Go ahead and do
whatever you were doing.
I'm just gonna
hang in here for a moment.
OK.
I worry about drunk drivers.
Mom, I'm 15.
- Right?
- Yes, you're 15.
And here's that money I owe you.
Your father's favorite joke.
I don't do it as well.
No, I thought that was pretty good.
Keep the small bills on the outside.
And call me if anyone gets drunk.
I will call you if anyone,
anywhere gets drunk.
- Good.
- And don't take drugs.
Very funny.
See? Sense of humor.
Funny joke. Have fun at the dance.
- I'm glad you're making friends.
- Mom, stay.
- OK.
- Love you.
Bye.
I always tell the girls,
never take it seriously.
If you never take it seriously,
you never get hurt.
If you never get hurt,
you always have fun.
And if you ever get lonely,
you just go to the record store,
and visit your friends.
- So, you and Russell...
- No!
Russell has a girlfriend,
and I can't even say her name.
It's all happening.
I'm about to use you as protection.
These guys are with Alice Cooper. I'm
gonna pretend like I don't know them.
Penny! Hey!
Does Alice know you're here?
I'm just showing my very dear,
very wonderful friend,
William Miller, around.
He's a very important writer.
He knows Lester Bangs. And I'm
responsible for his moral conduct
- while he's abroad.
- Penny Lane!
- God's gift to rock and roll!
- I'm retired. And don't argue with me.
- Retired? Again?
- Penny!
It's Reg! That's Humble Pie's
road manager, right there.
- Hi!
- Come to Portland where there's love.
- Have we met?
- "Have we met?"
I've made a decision.
I'm going traveling to India
and then I'm going
to learn to play the violin.
And then, I'm going to college.
For one year!
There's nothing they could
teach you in college, darling!
Right on! Call Alice. He's staying
under the name "Bob Hope."
- I heard you're with Russell Hammond!
- Please. I throw the little ones back.
- I lost my head.
- Martin Bell's a fucking asshole.
- And I'm in love with Jeff Bebe.
- Polexia!
Opie?
- Are you OK?
- Harry Houdini, please?
- Houdi... Harry Houdini!
- Sable. It was Sable.
And we had this really great time.
And he said that it was
going to mean something and then...
- And I'm in love with Jeff. I mean...
- Jeff is...
I know.
I saw them on the 7th floor.
Mr. Jimmy Page, Mr. John Paul Jones,
Mr. Robert Plant.
Mr. Robert Plant signed...
...signed my T-shirt five minutes ago.
Please don't smear it. Oh, dear God,
please don't... Please don't smear it.
But five minutes ago,
he touched this pen.
- Vic is a Zeppelin fan.
- Right, I picked that up.
He tours with them,
but not, you know, with them.
Yeah, they're on
the 12th floor now, but...
There's no bigger Zeppelin fan than Vic.
Very dear, very close
friend of Lester Bangs,
William... Miller.
- He's a writer. He knows us.
- Hey! You're that comedian!
- Leonard.
- Blow me!
Come on, William.
OK. Time to put on the lampshade.
Ladies and gentlemen!
At this time, please extinguish
all smoking materials,
for the captain has turned on
the "No Smoking" sign.
Your seats and tray tables
should be locked
and in their full, upright position.
- Play on.
- Miss Penny Lane.
Oh, thank you, thank you.
Act One, in which she pretends
she doesn't care about him.
Act Two, in which he pretends
he doesn't care about her,
but he goes right for her.
Act Three, in which it all plays out
the way she planned it.
She'll eat him alive.
- We've got to stop them.
- Stop them?
You were her excuse
for coming here.
I need ice.
Hey, man.
I just worry about people using her
because she brings out the good side
in everybody else,
but what do they do for her?
Life kills me.
Do you have any pot?
No. Not on me.
- Do you smoke?
- No.
But... I grow it.
Yeah. Grow it.
You're funny.
Funny.
If only you were taller,
English, and rich,
and a guitar player, and older.
I'd... I'd be somebody else.
Yeah. Good point.
The Enemy.
I'm always around
if you want to talk some more.
- OK.
- All right.
Bless me Father,
for I may sin tonight.
- How does it end?
- What?
The story about the girl
who dumps the guy
who has the ex-ex-wife.
Calls her a hundred...
OK, five times,
and doesn't even leave a pass
in San Diego.
Wake up.
I'm retired.
I never believed you, anyway.
You're too good-looking
and too talented to be trusted.
And everybody knows that.
You're retired
like Frank Sinatra's retired.
Miss Penny Lane, let me tell you
what rock and roll will miss,
the day that you truly retire.
The way that you turn
a hotel room into a home.
The way that you pick up strays
wherever you go.
The way that you...
you know the words to every song.
Every song! Especially the bad ones.
And mostly the bad ones.
That green coat in the middle of summer.
The real name that you won't reveal.
I could keep going,
but my glass is full.
Damn.
- Come to Arizona?
- Never.
We leave Thursday morning, 9am.
And pack light this time. Jesus.
- Hello?
- William Miller?
- This is he.
- William, this is Ben Fong-Torres.
I'm the music editor
at Rolling Stone Magazine.
We got a couple copies of your stories
from the San Diego Door.
- Is this the same William Miller?
- Yes, it is.
"Voice of God, howling dogs,
the spirit of rock and roll."
- This is good solid stuff, man.
- Well, thanks.
Thanks. Thanks.
Listen, I think you should be
writing for us. Any ideas?
- How about Stillwater?
- Stillwater?
"Hard-working band makes good."
New album out, their third.
Starting to do something. Crazy.
Let's do 3,000 words.
You'll join the band on the road.
We'll set up billing.
Don't let the band pay for anything.
We can only pay,
let me see, 3,000 words...
Seven hundred dollars.
All right, a grand.
What's your background?
Are you a journalism major?
- Yeah.
- What college?
Honey, I need you to do that thing
that fixes the garbage disposal.
Well, I certainly know how my lady gets
when you don't snap to it.
- Crazy. Crazy.
- Crazy.
- Stillwater?
Beware, beware of
Rolling Stone Magazine
because they will change your story,
they'll rewrite it, you know,
turn it into swill.
But besides that,
what would be wrong with it?
You got starry eyes, my friend.
Look. Do the story.
Who cares, you know?
It'll be good for ya.
Remember this: don't do it
to make friends with people
who are trying to use you to
further the big business desire,
to glorify worthless
rock stars like Stillwater!
Don't let those
swill merchants rewrite you.
- "Swill merchants." That's good.
- Yeah, swill merchants.
Now, what are you listening to?
- Stillwater.
- Stillwater? The kid's doin' drugs.
No. No. No. No. No.
No more than four days,
and I want you to give me a phone
number where you are every minute.
I want you to call me twice a day,
and you do not miss more than one test!
And no drugs.
Oh, this is a big mistake.
Look at Tony the Tiger.
Come on, Doris, you darling bus.
You can make it.
- This is what I was talkin' about.
- Russell.
Excuse me. I was wondering
if maybe we could
find some time to talk
when we get to Phoenix.
I want to interview
everybody separately,
and I thought we'd start with
just you and me.
Absolutely.
Because I've got a thing
in a couple of days.
- What?
- It's a... a thing.
Where you go there to graduate.
School.
I never graduated
and look what happened.
You're here interviewing me.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Don't put that in Rolling Stone, man.
Our bio says that we all graduated.
Him with honors.
We'll figure out something better later.
Just enjoy the ride.
- Keep playing that song.
- All right, man.
I may need to stay in your room tonight.
Russell's in a bad mood.
He's very Bob Dylan
in Don't Look Back today.
- He's trying to write.
- Yeah. Sure.
- Yeah?
- Sure.
- You OK?
- Yeah.
Could you put a "Do not disturb"
on my phone?
Here's your key. Here's your room key.
Larry, put this on. Bags in ten.
Hey, come by in a few minutes.
We'll do that interview.
- All right?
- Sure.
Is this Mr. Miller?
Yeah.
You have a message from Elaine.
Your mother. She's a handful.
- I know.
- She freaked me out.
Tell her to stop.
They threw me out of my room.
I'm worried, man.
No, you can trust him. He's a fan.
But it's Rolling Stone.
He looks harmless,
but he does represent the magazine
that trashed Layla, broke up Cream,
ripped every album
Led Zeppelin ever made.
Don't forget the rules, man.
This little shit is The Enemy.
He writes what he sees.
If I don't get into a room,
and take a Valium...
Although, it would be cool
to be on the cover.
Oh, my God!
Simon Kirke from Bad Company
is by the pool.
Housekeeping.
Go away!
Should I come by later?
Yes. I'm in too truthful a mood.
- Maybe that's a good thing.
- Go away!
- You OK?
- Yeah.
- Go away!
- Don't worry.
- Come to the radio interview tonight.
- Go away!
- OK.
- Bye.
So rude!
The guitar and songwriting
of Russell Hammond.
The vocal stylings
of Jeff "The Babe" Bebe, Jeff Bebe.
- The Babe.
- Bebe.
Bebe. Fever Dog.
The band is Stillwater.
Watch with your mind
as they materialize.
Look at the dogs
wearing the funny hats,
juggling just for you,
freaks and family.
It's Quince with Stillwater here, live.
It's The Night Circus.
Every minute a baby
is born somewhere.
Life. Death.
Hermetically sealed bags
of human emotion.
Bags of love, bags of kindness.
How'd you all get together?
Well, not to get into a "me" thing,
but I did start the band,
some time, actually, ago.
And I placed an ad in a magazine
called Peaches,
- and Russell Hammond answered.
- Peaches.
I think he was a gift
from God, actually.
- Nobody plays like Russell Hammond.
- Shit, man. Thank you.
Oh, my... Might want to hit
that delay button there, Quincy.
Quince?
Now we're talking, right?
Right?
Why the fuck do you have to wait
till an interview in Arizona
to say something nice about me, man?
Why don't you say it to my fucking face?
'Cause I tell you every time
I think you nailed something.
Everybody pays you compliments.
It's not my fucking job
to kiss your fucking ass.
Seriously, then whose fucking job is it,
because my ass is dying for a kiss, man,
and I know yours is, too.
It's my fucking job
and I think you're all geniuses.
And I'd just like to say
to the folks out there,
I'd like to leave you this thought:
smegma.
Nice! Fellows?
Feces.
The name of the song is Love Thing.
Your mind is starting to take effect.
They've all come
to watch you swallow fire.
You scream. Soundlessly.
On The Night Circus.
I thought that went well.
- Yeah.
- Yeah. Absolutely.
- Pronto?
- May I speak with William, please?
He's still down in the bar
with the band.
They just got back
from the radio station.
Is this Maryann, with the pot?
Hello?
No. This is not
Maryann with the pot.
This is Elaine. His mother.
Could you give William
a message for me, please?
Tell him to call home immediately,
and also tell him
I know what's going on.
All right. OK. But I'm just gonna
say this, and I'm gonna stand by it:
You should be really proud of him.
'Cause I know men,
and I'll bet you do, too.
He respects women,
and he likes women.
And let's just pause and appreciate
a man like that.
I mean, you've created him out of thin
air, you know, you raised him right.
He's havin' a great time.
He's doin' a good job.
And, don't worry, he's still a virgin,
and we're all lookin' out for him.
You know? That's more than I've ever
even said to my own parents.
So there you go.
This is the maid speaking, by the way.
Can you please hold it down?
Russell! So, what is it
you love about music?
Shut that thing off for a second,
and I'll tell you the truth, all right?
Look... Fuck. I trust you,
so I'm just gonna lay this right on ya.
Just make us look cool.
I will quote you warmly and accurately.
Well, that's what I'm worried about.
You see, some of us, we got girlfriends
back home, you know?
Some of us have wives.
And some of the people
that you meet on the road
are really amazing people.
Like you.
Yeah. But some of the stuff
that happens, it's good for
a few people to know about,
as opposed to, say...
...a million people.
- Understand what I'm tryin' to say?
- Yeah.
'Cause see, you're dangerous.
You see everything.
Most people,
they're just waiting to talk.
But you listen.
See, I grew up with these guys,
but I can't play all that I can play.
I'm past them, as musicians,
but the more popular we get,
the bigger their houses get,
the more responsibilities,
the pressure, you know,
the harder it gets
for me to walk out on 'em.
Then you forget,
forget what it's like to be a fan.
You hear it in bands all the time.
Doesn't sound like music anymore,
you know?
Sounds like...
...lifestyle maintenance or something.
"Lifestyle maintenance."
I used to be able to hear...
...the sounds of the world.
Everything, to me,
it sounded like music.
And now I don't hear it,
you know, anymore.
But do you understand
what I'm trying to say?
- Yeah.
- Come to the party!
- Where'd my hat go?
What am I doing?
I'm telling secrets to the one guy
you don't tell secrets to.
No. No, we'll...
We'll do the interview tomorrow.
- OK.
So, tonight, it's...
- Well, friends.
- Right.
We trust ya.
Larry Fellows,
how would you describe your role
in Stillwater?
What is the chemical
you add to the chemistry?
I'm the bass player.
Right.
And when you take that away,
what would be missing?
Stylistically, what chemical?
The bass?
OK.
Stinkin' roads!
- Hey, hey, what's goin' on?
- Russell just got electrocuted!
Hey, everybody be cool. All right?
Come on, come on. Let's get on the bus.
Let's go, let's go.
This is bullshit, man. Who's takin' care
of us? Who's responsible for the gear?
I'm gonna deal with it.
Get on the bus. Please, everyone.
- Come on, let's go, let's go!
- Hey, cowboy.
- Hey. You the manager of this band?
- Yes! That and more!
Yeah, well you didn't finish
your full set, man.
Listen, pal. Your shoddy stage setup
almost killed my guitarist!
Yeah, well you trashed
my fuckin' dressing room,
and you didn't do your 25 minutes.
You don't fuck with
my band's safety, ever!
Fuck you. I'm gonna report you
to every promoter in this country!
I'm gonna talk to
Frank Barcelona tonight!
- You don't even know Frank Barcelona!
- You're a bunch of amateurs, man!
- You want it?
- Come on!
What do you got? What do you got?
Take it.
- Fuckin' go, all right?
- Hey, watch the shirt, fuck!
- Now I'm gonna kick your ass.
- Take it easy!
Take it easy, man. All I know is,
I hope you got a good lawyer, buddy.
Hey, you better make a live album,
'cause this is your last fuckin' tour!
What? What? What is that?
What are you, Bruce Lee?
Come on!
- Take it easy!
- Let's go!
Lock the gates!
- Let's go through the fucking gate.
- That's your last fucking tour, man!
Lock the gates on these fuckheads!
- Where's my goddamn car?
- William?
William? William. William!
I forgot to tell you.
Your mom called.
She says you gotta
call home immediately.
And she says to tell you,
"I know what's going on."
So, I'll see you guys in Topeka, OK?
Amateurs!
You don't know who you're dealing
with here! Lock the gates!
- You wanna buy a gate?
- Yeah!
You just bought a gate!
Hey, give that to me, William.
Give me that!
Russell, wake up.
Wake the fuck up, man.
- It's a girls' running team.
- Goddamn.
Let it go, Fellows.
Let it go, buddy.
Dick, when do we get
into Topeka, man?
Larry, you're a sick individual.
Leave it alone.
Wake up, man. Look at all these fucking
tasty-looking high school girls.
We can't stop the bus
every time you see a girl in shorts.
Hey. When we go to Morocco,
I think we should wear
completely different clothes
and be completely different people.
What will our names be?
What do you think of Russell?
I like him. But that's between us.
Because I am a professional.
You should give him a break.
There are real problems in the band.
- Off the record.
- What problems?
OK, I got it. Your name should
be Spencer and mine will be Jane.
- I can't keep up with you.
- Oh, no one can.
- You're comin' to Cleveland, right?
- Cleveland, Ohio?
Oh, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
I have to get my interview with Russell
before Greenville.
- You've got to help me, OK?
- Here's the thing about Russell.
He's my last project.
I only do this for a very few people,
and I think we should do it together.
Because all the guys are good,
but he could be great.
What's your real name?
All right, let's go!
Oh, it's OK. I'm easy to forget.
Just leave me behind!
I'm only the fucking lead singer!
Hey!
So, Ed Vallencourt,
what do you love about music?
OK, OK.
You told me you would
tell me where you were every minute.
call me twice a day.
You told me you wouldn't
miss any more than one test.
- I'll be home for graduation. Mom...
- Where are you?
Right now, Topeka.
Then, Greenville, then home.
What about graduation?
We had an agreement, William.
I'm sorry I didn't call you yesterday.
I guess I just miss you.
And I don't understand why
I've driven my two kids
so far away from me.
By all practical rules,
don't I get you for another three years?
- Was I not fun?
- Yes.
William! This is Beth from Denver.
She's one of the legendary,
original Band Aids.
- She's clairvoyant!
- I can't read your mind or anything.
I mean, I pick up things here and there.
Estrella says hi.
She says I can stay in your room.
- Sure.
- Great!
I've got some hydroponic pot!
- Wow, your aura is really fantastic!
- Hey, hey!
- It's this beautiful purple color.
- I love you.
I missed the last thing you said.
- Mom?
- Your aura is purple!
- I love you.
- What?
- Purple, it's purple.
- Mom, what?
- Your aura is purple.
- I miss you and I love you!
I love you.
That way, you don't get one of those
little creases, know what I'm saying?
Yeah. All right,
so this has to be straight here?
All right.
Fire away. I'm ready.
Do you have to be depressed
to write a sad song?
Do you have to be in love
to write a love song?
Is the song better
if it really happened to you?
Like Love Thing. Where did
you write that? Who is it about?
When did you get so professional?
Gentlemen, your first
T-shirts have arrived.
Yes!
Oh, man.
It's the record company's mistake,
and they will pay.
T-shirts are gone.
Band happy, all right?
Can we just skip the vibe and go
straight to us laughing about this?
- Yeah, OK.
- Because I can see by your face
- you want to get into it.
- How can you tell?
I'm just one of the out-of-focus guys.
Here.
Take it. Let's take
a good look at it, all right?
See, you love this T-shirt.
It lets you say
everything you want to say.
- Well, it speaks pretty loudly to me.
- It's a T-shirt.
Do you give a shit about a T-shirt?
I'm just hungry, man. Let's just go out
and find some barbecue or somethin'.
Look, I'm always
gonna tell you the truth.
Are you doing coke again?
Oh, yeah, all the time.
This is big stuff, man.
From the very beginning,
we said I'm the front man,
and you're the guitarist with mystique.
That's the dynamic we agreed on.
Page, Plant, Mick, Keith.
Blackmore, Gillan.
But somehow it's all turning around.
We have got to control
what's happening!
- There's a responsibility here.
- Excuse me,
but didn't we all get into this
to avoid responsibility?
I can't say any more
with the writer here.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
You can trust him. Say what you want.
He won't write it.
Look, I work as hard, or harder,
than anybody on that stage.
You know what I do? I connect.
I get people off!
I look for the one guy
who isn't getting off,
and I make him get off.
Actually, that you can print!
And yet, why do I always end up
feeling like I'm a joke to you?
Look, you want to pretend this
isn't gonna be a very big band?
Well, it is! You call yourself
a leader of this band,
but your direction
allowed this T-shirt
when you allowed Dick to manage us.
'Cause he's your friend!
Don't you see, man,
the T-shirt is everything.
All right, is it my turn now?
Because I think we should, for once,
- say what we really mean.
- This is the part where you quit!
- Right. I'm so predictable.
- Deal with it.
And let me just say what
nobody else wants to say.
- What?
- Your looks have become a problem.
All right, OK. Enough!
What?
Break it up. Everyone out
of the room for five minutes.
Hey! Yeah. William. Sorry.
Come on, man. Come on.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Let's go find something real.
From here on out, I'm only
interested in what is real.
Real people, real feelings.
That's it. That's all
I'm interested in from here on out.
- You're real.
- Thanks.
You know, you know all about us
and I don't know shit about you.
Tell me, what's your family like?
My dad died of a heart attack
and my sister believes
that my mom is so intense
that she had to escape our family.
And they can't seem to find
a way to get through it.
I mean, they don't even
speak to each other anymore.
Plus, she gave me all her albums
and now she's a stewardess.
It's good to talk about.
Really good.
But here I am,
telling secrets to the one guy
you're not supposed to
tell your secrets to.
You're Russell from Stillwater.
Yeah, on my better days
I'm Russell from Stillwater.
You wanna go to a party with me
at my friend Aaron's house?
I know you're a big rock star and all,
but do you want to hang with some good
people looking to have a good time?
We're just real Topeka people, man.
No.
Thanks, man. You, too.
Oh, my God. Holy shit.
I grew up with that lamp shade, man.
I love this kitchen.
I fucking love this kitchen!
That's William over there.
Hey, William!
You, Aaron, are what it's all about.
You're real. Your room is real.
Your friends are real.
Real, man. Real, you know?
Real.
Real, you know?
You're more important
than all the silly machinery.
The silly machinery.
And you know it.
In 11 years it's gonna be 1984, man.
Think about that.
Wanna see me feed
a mouse to my snake?
Yes.
Hey, can I have that bitchin' belt?
Take it.
- Thanks, man.
- Thank you, brother.
Russell, we should
probably get back with the others.
- Oh, it's over, daddy.
- Hey.
There's acid in the beer
that's in the red cups.
That's mine.
Topeka. Check it out!
Please don't give him any more acid.
Thank you.
Dick. Dick, I got him.
He's OK. He is on acid though.
I can't really tell.
How do you know
when it's kicked in?
I am a golden god!
- Yes, you are!
- I am a golden god!
Hey, Russell, don't jump!
And you can tell
Rolling Stone Magazine
that my last words...
...were...
...I'm on drugs.
Russell, I think we should
work on those last words.
OK. Oh, I got it. I got it. I got it.
I got it. I got it. This is better.
Last words.
I dig music.
I'm on drugs!
Look, just come on down
and we'll go back to the hotel.
- OK.
- Jump!
- He's not coming up.
- Something's wrong.
- Somebody, help him.
- I'll save you, Russell.
They've been crying for you
like a bunch of whimpering pussies.
Oh, the band's over.
This is my family now.
- Yeah, that's right, man.
- Definitely.
He's staying with us.
Let's just ride on down to Greenville,
we'll listen to some great music,
we'll finish the tour,
and we'll leave those
ungrateful fools behind.
Then we'll come back here
where you'll live.
- And he can stay in our basement.
- Yeah.
I see what you're doing and I like it.
OK, good. Come on.
I got it, man. I got it.
That felt kind of good though.
Excuse me, kids.
Look at him.
He's taking notes with his eyes.
How do we know you're not a cop?
- The Enemy! Stop fuckin' looking at me!
- Easy!
He's your guardian angel, all right?
Don't worry.
He only means half of what he says.
Which half?
Dick, just help me get my interview.
I have to go home, Dick.
Dick, I have to go home.
Look, you've saved the tour and that's
good enough for now. All right?
- Come on, big fella. Let's go.
- I hurt the flower.
Did you, man? Did you hurt the flower?
That's nice.
Come on, on the bus.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the evening is over.
We hope you all enjoyed yourselves
and we'll see you all again in 1974.
- Good evening!
- We love you, Stillwater!
I have to go home.
You are home.
In Carl Jung's opinion, we all
have a sixth sense, intuition.
When you meet someone
and you suddenly feel like
you can't live without them.
This could be the memory of a past love
from the collective unconscious.
Or it could just be hormones.
I'm sorry, I can't concentrate.
Rock stars have kidnapped my son.
On the whole, I'd say most
of the fuck-ups in the world
come from the brain
and not the instincts.
My whole thing is to try and make my...
My whole thing is to try
and make my brain go away.
But I can't, except onstage.
The brain, I think, should be a
softening influence on the instincts,
but the instincts should drive.
Trying to reconcile the brain with urges
that come out of millions of years ago,
the way the brain interprets
these instincts, is a heavy trip.
While I've got you, you getting
on the fucking bus or what?
Come on, come on.
Let's get on the fucking bus.
Usually, I'm brain
and Russell is instincts.
But on the days
when we're both instinct,
that's when we've made the music
people know best.
Because it's the best!
Show me any guy who ever
said he didn't want to be popular,
and I'll show you a scared guy.
I've studied
the entire history of music.
Most of the time,
the best stuff is the popular stuff.
It's much safer
to say "popularity sucks"
because that allows you
to forgive yourself if you suck.
And I don't forgive myself. Do you?
Lester, Rolling Stone is calling me.
I don't have my key interview.
I don't know what to say.
Days are just going by out here.
You're flipping out.
It's good. All right.
This is how you blow their minds.
He's gonna ask you...
This is Ben Fong-Torres, right?
Yeah, yeah.
He's gonna ask you how the story's
going and this is what you do.
Tell him...
...you know, it's a think piece...
"A think piece."
...about a mid-level band
struggling with their own limitations
in the, you know,
harsh face of stardom.
"Harsh face."
He'll wet himself.
All dressed up and no place to go.
Greenville. I'm bored.
I have to pee.
Wow, they're cute.
Let's deflower the kid.
Hold on. Hold on. Wait.
I should leave.
- Things are going backwards for me.
- Backwards?
I don't know. I just...
I thought maybe we could hang out.
You know, do some stuff back home,
like regular stuff.
Get to know each other
a little bit better,
and then I'd see you pee.
I mean, that's just
the way I usually do it.
You're one of us.
If you come to Cleveland,
Bowie's gonna be at Swingo's,
the greatest hotel in America,
and I'll introduce you to him
and his security guard, Dennis.
Don't you have any regular friends?
Famous people are just
more interesting.
Well, I would be worried
that they were using me.
Boy. If this was the real world...
Not that anybody's using you.
No. Hold on.
I'm not famous, but...
- Your time has come!
- Did Russell call?
- Deflower, deflower.
- Opie must die!
- Oh, no. Stop. We're talking.
- Pants him, girls.
Opie must die.
No. No.
- OK.
- No.
Up, up.
Guys, come on. I have to write.
No.
Come on, Penny. Join us.
Take a vacation from yourself.
- Leave this up to professionals.
- Don't worry, William.
I've seen the future
and this all works out reasonably well.
Reasonably?
Hello.
Hello. This is Ben Fong-Torres
calling from Rolling Stone.
Hi, Ben Fong-Torres
from Rolling Stone.
Hello, hello.
- You have such a sexy voice.
- Hello, Ben.
William Miller,
this is your editor at Rolling Stone.
- How's the story?
- I'm getting good stuff out here.
- Yeah, it sounds like it.
- Man, I need some...
Now, listen. Get it together, man.
We're both professionals here, OK?
I don't need to tell you this.
You're not out there to join the party.
We already have one Hunter Thompson.
You're out there to interview
and to report. You got me?
Now this isn't Creem magazine.
This is Rolling Stone.
We need this story in four days.
Now, I want to know how it's shaping up.
It's a think piece
about a mid-level band
struggling with their own limitations
in the harsh face of stardom.
That's great.
I like what we're saying.
Let me try and get you
a thousand more words.
It's in consideration for the cover,
but don't tell the band.
The cover of Rolling Stone Magazine.
Crazy.
- ...some coffee.
- Me, too.
Greenville is so boring.
You know, any other city in the world,
and you'd still be a virgin.
- Oh, God. Oh, God.
- What?
I've never written anything more
than a few pages in my whole life.
- Don't worry, baby. You will.
- I gotta find Russell.
Will you take the laundry?
"Take the laundry"?
What am I to you?
Tell me. Tell me right now.
Excuse me, sir.
Would you mind signing for this?
Good morning.
Please go the fuck away!
Hey, man. We'll do
the interview in Cleveland.
No, no, no, no.
I can't go to Cleveland.
Come on, man. We'll have more
time there. Don't be tense.
Come to Cleveland.
- Come to Cleveland.
- I can't go to Cleveland.
- Hey, can we help it
- if we like having you around?
- Come to Cleveland.
- Come...
Look, I don't wanna
go to Cleveland. OK?
I want to go home.
That's good, man.
I like it when you yell.
But I'm not gonna let you miss out
on the rock mecca of the Midwest.
- "Rock mecca."
- Hey, you're with us. Rock and roll?
- Rock...
- ...and roll.
- It's all...
- I know. I know. It's all happening.
Oh, my God! It's Stillwater!
Hi, welcome to Swingo's Celebrity Inn.
You must be Stillwater.
Memory of a Free Festival,
Wild Eyed Boy From Freecloud.
I mean, that's vintage Bowie, you know?
I mean, the new stuff,
Ziggy Stardust is good,
but it's mass media, you know?
It's hamburgers for the apocalypse.
It's Bowie! Bowie!
Good-looking cake. All right.
That's doubles.
Jeff and Russell are
the figureheads of the band,
but I think the true Stillwater fan,
your absolute Stillwater fan,
knows the, the purity, the essence,
the core of Stillwater's music
comes from Silent Ed Vallencourt.
Hi, Mom. I'm gonna
fly back Monday morning.
No, no, no. I'll only miss one test.
I'll be back for graduation.
Tell her you're a slave to the groove.
You can't help it.
Lis... No. Russell.
No. Russell, Russell.
Hey, Mom, it's Russell Hammond.
I play guitar in Stillwater.
How does it feel to be the mother of the
greatest rock journalist we've met?
Hello?
Look, you've got a great kid here.
There's nothing to worry about.
We're taking good care of him.
You should come to the show sometime.
Join the circus.
Hey, listen to me, mister.
Your charm doesn't work on me.
I'm onto you.
- Of course you like him.
- Well, yeah.
He worships you people. That's fine by
you as long as he helps make you rich.
- Rich? I don't think so.
- Listen to me.
He's a smart, good-hearted,
15-year-old kid with infinite potential.
This is not some apron-wearing mother
you're speaking to.
I know all about
your Valhalla of decadence
and I shouldn't have let him go.
He's not ready for your
world of compromised values
and diminished brain cells
that you throw away like confetti.
- Am I speaking to you clearly?
- Yes, ma'am.
If you break his spirit,
harm him in any way,
keep him from his chosen profession,
which is law, something
you may not value, but I do,
you will meet the voice
at the other end of this telephone
and it will not be pretty.
Do we understand each other?
Yes, ma'am.
I didn't ask for this role,
but I'll play it.
Now go do your best.
"Be bold and mighty forces
will come to your aid."
Goethe said that.
It's not too late for you to become
a person of substance, Russell.
Please get my son home safely.
You know, I'm glad we spoke.
Song and bong
It sounds like lots of fun
Won't you get on my back
for a piggyback ride
Get on my back
For a piggyback ride
- All right, boys.
- All right.
Your mom kind of freaked me out.
She means well.
From Troy, Michigan,
would you please
welcome to Cleveland,
Stillwater!
Russell.
So, Russell, when you play
a great show like tonight...
OK, I need everyone's attention, please.
Girls, I need five minutes
with the band alone.
Well, it seems the rumors are true.
The record company has sent
a big-time manager here
to try and talk you into replacing me.
His name is Dennis Hope.
I know you've all heard of him.
He's got all the big bands.
He's outside right now and
he wants five minutes with you.
And I think we've gotta do this.
- Well, send him in.
- Yeah, bring him in.
- We'll send him out on a rail.
- All right.
We'll finish the interview in Maryland.
You can fly home from Maryland.
- Hi.
Hey, we've already got a manager, man.
He's been with us from the beginning.
Respectfully. We all have our roots.
I believe in bands
holding onto their roots.
But those roots need to be augmented.
I'm gonna tell you the truth.
I may enrage some and enthrall others.
I don't really give a fuck.
Your manager here needs a manager.
Example: if you hadn't run out
on your contract in Phoenix,
we could have sued
over Russell's hand.
But you left, negating the contract,
forfeiting the deposit.
You effectively traveled a long way to
pay that promoter to electrocute you.
Your damages have put you
way in the hole for this tour.
Right now you owe the record company
more than you've got.
But your record's selling.
There's money to be made.
So I brought a plane in.
We add more shows to make up
the difference, respectfully.
- We travel by bus.
- Doris is the soul of this band.
That bus has been our home since we
were the Jeff Bebe Band. No way.
I'd travel on a pogo stick
if I thought we could make more money.
You could play more dates with a plane.
Well, it's not about money. It's about
playing music and turning people on.
Clearly. Respectfully. But
on the distasteful subject of money,
just know that
you're all making it right now.
And it's all out there.
I'm just talking about
bringin' it back here.
Why should we pay you for something
we can do ourselves?
Do you know how to keep
from getting charged for the ice
below the floorboards
at Chicago Stadium?
Do you know how
to do a headlining tour?
Do you know Clay Rothman
at the LA Forum?
Do you know Bobby Cowan,
Danny Marcus, Lisa Robinson?
Do you know Frank Barcelona?
This is Cleveland!
Where's Kid Leo? Where is he?
Do you know how to get
a record not pressed, but played?
I didn't invent the rainy day, man.
I just own the best umbrella.
And as much as you may believe that
this is gonna last forever, it does not.
Your biggest fan right now...
Your biggest fan.
Soon they're gonna
want to go to college.
Gonna want to buy some clothes,
spend that money some other way.
And you know what?
They'll tape your record
from a friend's copy.
You gotta take what you can,
when you can, while you can,
and you gotta do it now.
That's what the big boys do.
If you think Mick Jagger
will still be out there
trying to be a rock star at age 50,
you're sadly mistaken.
Yes, well, thank you, Dennis.
- We'll think about what you said.
- Oh, no, you...
You... You don't understand.
I'll think about it.
I'm not auditioning.
I came here to decide
whether I want to represent you.
So I'll stand outside for a moment
and think about whether I want to stay.
It was a good show.
I miss him already.
You're coming along at a very
dangerous time for rock and roll.
The war is over. They won.
And they will ruin rock and roll
and strangle everything
we love about it.
Put them up. All right.
- I don't know what that was.
- It was a donkey dick, man!
I'm sorry. No matter where you come
from, a donkey dick is funny.
- Hey.
- Can I help you?
- Is Russell Hammond here?
- Hey, The Enemy.
Come on in, son.
Hey, welcome to the road manager
poker party.
The game has been going on for
two years. Come on. Find a spot.
This is Mick, he's with The Who.
Raymond, he's with The Eagles.
Reg, he's with Humble Pie.
I think you know Red Dog.
Hi, brother.
We've been developing this system
of poker over the years
so you can play it in any condition.
We only let Russell in
because he brought the hash.
- Easy, easy. The press is here.
- Don't mention me or The Eagles.
- Well, I'm done.
- I'm out.
- I'm in.
- All right, all right.
Side proposition to the winner.
For 50 bucks
and a case of Heineken,
I'll throw into the pot
three lovely ladies,
including Miss Penny Lane
of the famous Band Aids,
who have to leave the tour
before New York.
- Russ, is that OK with you?
- Russ is getting soft on us.
- Is that OK?
- OK.
It's a deal. Show them.
Three lovely ladies in the custody
of Humble Pie. Be good to them, Reg.
All right, so we owe you $50
and a case of Heineken. All right.
- Joint?
- Know how I know this is good stuff?
- How's that?
- This is from Crosby.
- Is that Crosby weed?
- Yeah.
- I'm in.
Look, nobody's feelings
are getting hurt here.
She already knows that Leslie's coming
to New York tomorrow.
Everybody understands.
This is the circus.
Everybody's trying not to go home.
Nobody's saying goodbye.
Quit looking at me like that.
Yeah, that's it, Larry!
Yeah, baby. Go get him.
Go get him. Go get him!
Larry Fellows, he's down...
Happy, happy birthday
Happy, happy birthday to you
I'm making a wish.
So...
"Penny, our friend,
has gained another year.
But long ago she threw it in gear.
She rocked the South,
the East, the West.
Could we please get off
this endless tour
where we're Black Sabbath's
fucking special guest?"
Yeah!
"She says she's retired,
but we've heard that before.
She chose us.
In Penny Lane we trust.
She is a fan of this band.
Much more so than us."
- Cut the cake!
- Yeah!
- Who wants it? Who wants it?
Cut the cake!
- Cut the cake!
Thank you, baby.
Who wants the "P" in "Penny?"
- Happy birthday.
- Oh, thank you. Here you go.
I'm sorry the plane isn't bigger.
I'll take a piece.
- It's good.
- Yeah, it's fucking great.
Cut the cake.
Who didn't get cake?
Any extra plates?
Anybody?
You think you can fool me.
I can read you.
I know what you're thinking.
What's that?
You're worried about me and Russell.
Yeah, I gotta work on that.
You're so sweet.
God, if there was
more of you in him.
Don't tell me this stuff.
I want to like him.
Did you miss a test or something?
You have no idea.
I know I'm not on the plane. And I'm not
going on some other band's bus.
I could go with the road crew,
but that would be pathetic
and the girls are all
going with Humble Pie.
So if you could
find out from Russell...
- Penny.
- Forget it.
I'm flying to New York myself.
I've got a bunch of partial tickets.
I know his ex-wife
current girlfriend thing...
- I'm not sure that's a good idea.
- What are you saying?
- Did Russell say something?
- No. No, I don't know anything.
Well, I know he wants me there.
Wake up!
Don't go to New York!
- Why are you yelling at me?
- I thought we were going to Morocco.
There is no Morocco.
There's never been a Morocco.
There's not even a Penny Lane.
I don't even know your real name.
If I ever met a man
in the real world who looked at me
the way you just looked at me...
When and where does this
"real world" occur?
I mean, I'm really confused here.
All these rules
and all these sayings and nicknames.
Honey, you're too sweet
for rock and roll.
Sweet?
Where do you get off?
Where do you get "sweet?"
I am dark and mysterious
and pissed off!
And I could be very dangerous
to all of you.
I am not sweet.
And you should know that about me.
I am The Enemy!
Look, you should be happy for me.
You don't know what
he says to me in private.
Maybe it is love, as much
as it can be for somebody...
Who sold you to Humble Pie
for 50 bucks and a case of beer?
I was there.
Oh, God.
I'm sorry.
What kind of beer?
Welcome to New York.
It's OK to be nervous.
You should be nervous.
All you can do is be yourself
and leave a pint of blood on that stage.
Hey, William. We showed you America.
Did everything but get you laid.
No. Yeah?
I'm from the Church of Lenny.
We bow to his will
and all that it represents.
He's the king of the king of kings.
- Maybe I could get an autograph?
- Who should I make it out to?
She's here.
- Russell, can I have your autograph?
- Yeah.
- Leslie. How you doing?
- Jeffrey.
Your room's fully stocked.
The air conditioning's on.
- And by the way, you look stunning.
- Thanks, see you later.
All right, bags in five.
Cars leave for the party at 6:00.
Oh, God.
There are lighter souvenirs, you know.
Well, I kept thinking I was going
to go home the next day.
Yeah. So did I, 15 years ago.
Oi, that's the wrong bag, you idiot!
- William?
- Vic.
It's all happening.
They're here. Zeppelin are here.
They are here.
They're at the Plaza.
Sapphire and Miss Penny Lane
are there, too.
They're all staying
under the name Emily Rugburn.
- Wait. Penny Lane is here?
- Emily Rugburn.
William Miller?
Sir, you have an urgent call.
Hello.
Hello, this is Jann Wenner,
publisher of Rolling Stone.
Congratulations, it's gonna be a cover.
Annie Liebowitz will
shoot them next week in LA,
but we are gonna need you
back in San Francisco tomorrow.
You can finish the story here, OK?
Talk to Ben.
You can tell the band.
Alison, our fact checker,
needs you to transmit whatever
you have of this story tonight.
There's a mojo at the Daily News
they'll let us use.
- A mojo?
- A mojo. It's a very modern machine
that transmits pages over the telephone.
It only takes 18 minutes a page.
Soon as a couple of people leave,
I can fit you right in, OK?
Right now, it's just...
Excuse me, you got an ID?
- No, thanks. I'm fine.
- No, no, no. You need an ID, man.
- Hey, man! He's cool.
- Hey, Dennis. How you doing?
Great! Everything's great. Far out.
He's with you guys? Well, enjoy!
- Opie!
- Hey!
I'm going to England with Deep Purple
and we leave in an hour.
Don't forget me, OK?
It's all happening,
but I must vamoosh!
Hey, The Enemy!
Hey, we got a table back there.
Why don't you come on over?
They're all looking for you.
Guys!
You're gonna be on the cover
of Rolling Stone.
Are you serious?
The cover of Rolling Stone.
And we made it together.
And they don't just put somebody
with one little hit
on the cover of Rolling Stone
fucking magazine, man.
Damn it, I'm gonna enjoy this.
When I first bought the magazine,
The Beatles were on the cover.
The Beatles. Four of them, four of us.
Thank you.
Who is that girl?
She's creeping me out.
She's not with any of you guys, is she?
Yeah, she's with me.
So who's gonna shoot it?
I want Annie Liebowitz
or Neal Preston.
I love Annie's stuff. She does
great stuff. I'll call her up.
I'm no good at goodbyes.
And you are the last...
...of my old-time friends.
Polexia. Polexia went
to England with Deep Purple.
Can you believe that?
Even Sapphire went someplace else.
While all she left
was her Quaaludes.
- Oh, wonderful.
- Where's Beth?
Where's my friends?
Where are all my friends?
Front desk?
Could you please send a doctor?
Room 537.
- Penny, get up.
- I'm up.
My wife's had an accident
with some Quaaludes.
- So tired.
- You gotta get up, Penny.
- Penny, get up. Get up.
- So... You know that.
You know that I'm retired.
I've always been.
I'm retired and I'm tired.
Jane Abbot.
Miss Jane Abbot.
Miss Judy Stanton.
Congratulations. Congratulations.
- Raymond Sanchez.
- Mr. Raymond Sanchez.
- As time goes on
- Seats and tray tables.
- Seat backs and tray tables locked.
- And our pending graduate,
William Miller, not present.
Why doesn't he love me?
And to the class of 1973 we say,
don't forget to remember
yourselves as you are today,
full of hope and the dream
that everything is possible.
And remember this
20 years from now,
when we all own home computers,
and we all travel
in shiny electrical cars
that move swiftly high above our city,
that the key to the future
is keeping today alive. Forever!
Forever! Forever!
- Penny, no. Wake up! Wake up!
- I'm up.
Well, now that I have your attention,
I know you've heard this before,
and I've never said this to anybody.
Well, nobody who didn't legally
have to say it back to me,
but...
Oh, God. Why am I so nervous?
You'll never remember this.
I love you.
And I'm about to boldly go where...
...many men have gone before.
- What've we got? What's her name?
- Emily.
OK, sweetheart. Sit up, sit up, sit up.
Good girl, good girl.
- What did you take, sweetheart?
- I'll get her legs.
- What did you take?
- I don't know.
Yes, you do. Tell us what you took.
Emily, we're gonna have
to pump your stomach, OK?
- Emily, wake up.
- I got the tubes. There we go. Water.
All right, now you're gonna have
to swallow this tube.
Open, open, open.
- Don't fight us. We're trying to help.
- Emily, Emily.
- Relax.
- Come on. Swallow, swallow.
I know, I know. Swallow this down.
No, don't bite on it. Swallow.
Emily, Emily. Come on. Swallow.
- Very good. That's it. All done.
- Got it.
All done. Very good.
Now we gotta... Come on...
Feed some liquid into your stomach.
You've never done half
the things you said you did.
It was in the middle
of Midnight Rambler.
And Keith Richards saw me,
came to the front of the stage
and he pulled me out
and they took me backstage
and gave me a Coke
with ice and a lemon.
And I never went home.
I've done twice
the things I said I did.
What about your mom?
She always said, "Marry up.
Marry someone grand."
And that's why she named me Lady.
She named you Lady?
Lady Goodman.
Lady Goodman. That's great.
Now you know all my secrets.
You got me.
See you back in the real world.
Thank you, William Miller.
Hey, Lady!
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to Eastern Airlines'
nonstop service to San Diego.
In preparation
for our departure today,
we'd like to ask please that you
extinguish all flammable items
and do return
all seats and tray tables...
May I have your attention, please?
...that your seat belts
are securely fastened.
Hey, why didn't you come back
last night? Bob Dylan showed up.
He was sitting at our table for an hour
or something, right, Dick?
Just rapping, Bob Dylan at our fucking
table. I was looking for you.
- I was gonna introduce you.
- What happened to you last night?
It's a long story.
Hi, this is Craig, your pilot.
It appears we've caught the edge
of that electrical storm.
- Oh, my God.
- Electrical storm?
Buckle up tight. We're gonna do
our best to get you out of this.
- Rock and roll.
- We shouldn't be here.
Whoa, baby!
Doris, we miss you.
Listen, we're gonna
try and land in Tupelo.
- We found a field to land in.
- A field?
I can't breathe, man.
It's gonna be kind of a rough set down,
but we should be fine.
Just hang in there
and we'll get you out of this.
Everyone says,
"It's so glamorous out here."
- He just told us we're gonna die.
- We're gonna die?
...Thy will be done on Earth
as it is in heaven.
Oh, my God!
If something should happen,
maybe I never said this enough,
I love all of you.
I once hit a man in Dearborn, Michigan.
A hit and run.
I hit him and just kept on going.
I don't know if he's alive
or dead, but I'm sorry.
Not a day goes by
that I don't see his face.
Oh, my God!
Look, I love you all too.
You're like family to me.
Especially since Marna left me.
And if I took an extra
dollar or two here and there,
- it's because I knew I earned it.
- Yeah. I slept with Marna, Dick.
I did, too.
I waited until you broke up with her,
Dick, but me too.
I also slept with Leslie
when you were fighting.
You slept with Jeff?
But it didn't count. It was the summer
we decided to be free of all rules.
- And you say you love me!
- I don't love you, man. I never did.
None of us love you.
- You act above us, you always have.
- Finally, the truth.
You just held it over us like you might
leave, like we're lucky to be with you.
And we had to live with it, man.
I had to live with you
and now I might die with you.
- And it's not fucking fair!
- Please, enough!
And I'm still in love with you, Leslie.
Oh, I don't want to hear any more!
Shut up, Jeffrey!
- Jeffrey?
- It's all happening.
Whatever happens, Bebe, you're dead!
Don't be self-righteous,
Russell, not now, man.
You were sleeping with Penny,
that fucking groupie!
Last summer up until yesterday.
Why don't you tell Leslie that?
- Shut up, I'm gonna kill you!
- I quit! I quit!
That groupie? She was a Band Aid.
All she did was love your band.
And you all used her, all of you.
You used her and threw her away.
She almost died last night
while you were with Bob Dylan!
You guys are always talking
about the fans, the fans, the fans.
She was your biggest fan
and you threw her away.
And if you can't see that,
that's your biggest problem.
And I love her! I love her!
Fuck it!
I'm... I'm gay!
Thank God above, we're alive!
We're alive! We're gonna make it!
Sweet relief! Hallelujah, dear God!
Write what you want.
- Just leave your package on the desk.
- Oh, I'm not a messenger.
I'm one of your writers.
William H. Miller.
He's just a kid!
Go right on in.
- You're William Miller?
- Yep.
Oh, baby.
Didn't anything happen, I mean,
after $600 in room service bills?
Didn't you get anything
on tape with Russell Hammond?
Where are you in this piece?
What did you want to write?
This reads like what
they wanted you to write.
You obviously saw more
than you wrote about.
Something must have happened.
I think we should push up
Flippo's Who cover.
It's gonna take me three days
to get through this research.
It's all handwritten
on little bits of paper!
- It's a puff-piece.
- Plus, they refer
to all the women as chicks. I mean,
as a woman, I have a problem with that.
You want them to like you.
It happens.
Ben, you told me to send what I had.
It's not finished.
Give me tonight to work on it.
Oh, man.
You made friends with them.
See, friendship
is the booze they feed you.
They want you to get drunk
on feeling like you belong.
Well, it was fun.
Because they make you feel cool.
- And hey, I met you. You are not cool.
- I know.
Even when I thought I was,
I knew I wasn't.
Because we are uncool.
Women will always be a problem
for guys like us.
Most of the great art in the world
is about that very problem.
Good-looking people,
they got no spine.
Their art never lasts.
Oh, they get the girls,
but we're smarter.
Yeah, I can really see that now.
Because great art is about
the guilt and longing,
and love disguised as sex
and sex disguised as love.
Hey, let's face it,
you got a big head start.
I'm glad you were home.
I'm always home. I'm uncool.
- Me, too.
- You're doing great, man.
The only true currency
in this bankrupt world
is what you share
with someone else when you're uncool.
Listen, my advice to you,
and I know you think
these guys are your friends,
if you want to be a true friend
to them, be honest
and unmerciful.
"I'm flying high over
Tupelo, Mississippi
with America's hottest band,
and we're all about to die."
- Dark, lively.
- Yeah, and it gets better.
Did this all really happen?
Give it to me. I'll call
and check the quotes.
Holy shit! I just got off the phone
with Rolling Stone.
They called me, too.
What's he using?
All, he's using it all.
This, according to the fact checker.
- So what?
- "So what?"
We come off like amateurs,
some average band trying
to come to grips with success,
jealous and fighting and breaking up.
We're buffoons!
"Rock and roll can save the world"?
"The chicks are great"?
I sound like a dick!
- You are a dick.
- I never said that!
Maybe we just don't see ourselves
the way we really are.
Is it that hard
to make us look cool?
This kid has you on acid screaming, "I'm
a golden god," from a fan's rooftop.
They used him to fuck us. They'll
probably just put you on the cover.
Wait. I never said,
"I'm a golden god."
Or did I?
We never took him seriously.
- Now it's serious.
- I liked him as a person.
He was never a person.
He was a journalist!
You! You had the right idea all along.
- How about the plane flight?
- It's all there.
Don't worry, it's
unspecific who says what.
No names are mentioned
in the more embarrassing sequences.
It's just completely obvious who's who,
and we're fucked!
I... I told him
he could write what he wanted.
Hey, hey.
They haven't talked to Russell yet.
You can always deny the key stuff
to the fact-checker.
One phone call.
Then they can't print it.
- Is that true?
- This is war, my friend.
If you'd have met me earlier,
he would never be around.
He'll live.
Look, let's identify the goals here:
T-shirts, foreign markets,
renegotiating your contract,
merchandising, happiness,
realizing your dreams,
money, cool, meeting The Beatles.
Let's put all of it in the pot.
It all depends on mystique.
Not giving too much away.
I'm going to LA tonight.
Call me if you need me.
But before I go, let me
give you a lesson in mystique.
You can only have one.
Which one do you want?
Which one are you gonna choose?
As long as you can't see
what's in this hand...
...you'll always want it more.
It's phenomenal, William,
to be quite honest with you.
It's sophisticated. It's intelligent.
We only have to cut out
a couple of 'graphs.
Jeff Bebe's mother sent over
a shoe box of childhood photos.
But it's really gonna look fantastic.
The band just denied 90 percent
of the story. It's a fabrication.
You weren't honest.
And worse, you wasted our time.
Did you talk to Russell Hammond?
Russell Hammond
is the one who denied it.
- Now, wait a second.
- Denied it.
We're going with The Who.
The manuscript's in my office.
He's just some fan.
What do you expect?
Ben, wait.
William?
You guys, this is my brother.
- Nice to finally meet you.
- You have a good day.
You guys, I'll deadhead back later.
I think I'm needed.
I'll see you.
You look awful.
But it's great. You're living your life.
You're free of Mom.
Hey, I'll take off work.
Let's have an adventure together,
you and me, finally.
Anywhere you wanna go.
Anywhere in the world.
This is not my idea of a good time.
- Just get me to my bed.
- I'll deal with her.
I forgive you.
I didn't apologize.
- Sapphire.
- Hey, boy.
- I hate goodbyes.
- Me, too.
All right. So I didn't like you much.
Do we have to like each other?
I sort of thought so.
I think it would have worked against us.
I really do.
You know what they say,
"All the great partnerships
- hated each other."
- We didn't hate each other that much,
- did we?
- No, maybe not.
I could work on it, though.
I just can't picture you with Leslie.
I'm the you they get...
when they can't get you.
- Sorry.
- Got it. It's cool.
- I'll get it, man.
- I'll see you later on.
- See you.
- All right.
Is Penny OK?
The Quaaludes incident?
Well, it wasn't pretty.
She could have died.
I always told her not to let
too many guys fall in love with her.
I guess I was wrong.
One of them ended up saving her life.
- William?
- What do you care?
I mean, we all know what you did to him.
And everybody knows,
even Penny Lane.
Something tells me
that 20 years from now,
we'll remember her,
and not much else.
Hey, Russell.
Can you believe these new girls?
None of them use birth control.
And they eat all the steak.
I mean, they don't even
know what it is to be a fan.
To truly love some silly
little piece of music
or some band so much
that it hurts.
Hello, Penny?
It's Russell. Don't hang up.
I can't really talk right now.
I'm in a room full of people.
Actually, I'm alone.
And I won't call again. I promise.
But I need to see you face to face,
because I'm never as good
as when you're there.
And I can see myself
the way you look at me.
And I'm sorry.
If we could just get together
and find some time to talk...
Let's say all the things
we never said.
Give me your address.
I'm coming to you this time.
Got a pen?
Hello, Penny. Hello, Penny.
Hello, hello, Penny.
I'm... I'm Russell Hammond.
So this is the famous
Russell Hammond.
Come in.
- Is she home?
- Who? Anita?
- Where am I?
- Hello?
Hi.
You know, when we spoke,
I felt that we connected.
Oh, man.
My son is very important to me, too.
And I do think you owe him an apology.
I appreciate you showing up.
No, no. I agree, ma'am.
There's hope for you yet, Russell.
Well.
Hi.
So, this is...
...where The Enemy sleeps.
You know, I think we both
wanted to be with her.
And she wanted us to be together.
You should give her a call.
You both live in the same city.
- You really think I should?
- Yeah.
That girl really cares about you.
Man, I never even knew her real name.
Oh, I called your magazine,
and told them the truth.
I don't know what
they're gonna do with it,
but I told them every word
you wrote was true.
We are gonna do this one more time.
So, Russell...
...what do you love about music?
To begin with,
everything.
- Tickets, tickets, tickets.
- How much?
Morocco.
A seat by the window, please.