Fire department Is anyone home?
Wait outside, please.
Whats the date on the mail?
The 9th.
The door's open.
They had a nurse
but I haven't seen her recently.
- Are you the one who opened the windows?
- No
Welcome to the
Theatre des Champs-Elysées.
Please kindly turn off your mobile phones
and we remind you
that audio orvideo tap ng is forbidden.
We wish you a wonderful show.
They used a screwdriver or something.
It doesn't look very professional.
- Who'd do a thing like that?
- I've no idea.
Why does anyone try to break in?
To steal something.
From us?
Why not?
If I tried, I could think of three or four people
we know who've been burgled.
Can't we call the concierge?
In the morning.
Don't et this spoil your good mood.
Orthe police?
Come on give me your coat.
Imag ne if we're in bed
and someone bursts in.
Why should I imagine such a thing?
It's horrible. I think I'd die of fright.
Me too.
Another drink?
I'm tired.
I feel like another drink.
Do as you wish.
Mathilde said that in her building,
the top-storey flat was burgled via the attic.
They made a hole in the wall,
cut the most valuable paintings
out of their frames
and disappeared wthout a trace.
That's a professional job.
Did I mention
you looked very pretty tonight?
What's come overyou?
Incredible semiquavers in the presto.
Such finesse!
Don't you think?
He did you proud?
What's wrong?
Nothing.
And next week?
No, but I'd like it fixed as soon as possible.
It might give other people ideas
and it looks pretty awful.
At what time?
Yes.
OK.
Will you bring varnish for the door?
A little primer, at least.
OK, fine.
Yes.
OK, thanks. Goodbye.
We can rely on him.
Let's hope so.
Last time, he kept us waiting,
if you remember.
Yes, he did. Thanks.
If I call a contractor though,
we'll wait at least two months.
You think?
The Frodons waited three days
when their toilet was blocked.
Not exacty pleasant.
The saltcellar's empty.
I don't know if he'll br ng the CD today.
Perhaps he won't come at all.
We could go to Virgin this afternoon
and buy it.
What do you say?
What's going on?
What's wrong?
Anne!
It's me.
Anne?
What's going on?
What's wrong?
Sweetheart, please...
Anne, look at me.
What's wrong?
What are you doing?
You had left the water running.
Whats going on? Are you completely mad?
Is this a joke?
Sorry?
Is this some kind of prank?
Are you playing a prank on me?
What prank? I dont understand.
Why that tone of voice?
What's gotten into you?
Stop playing games, Anne. Its not funny.
What game forgoodness' sake?
What's going on?
Why didn't you react?
To what?
To anything, to me...
- When?
- Just a moment ago.
Please tell me what's wrong.
I don't know what to say.
Are you sure you don't remember
what just happened?
What just happened?
You were sitting there
starting into space
and you didn't answer
when I asked what was going on.
I used this dish-cloth to dab your face
and you didn't react
Look, there are stil stains on your collar.
When was this?
Just now, two minutes ago.
And?
Don't give me "And?"
I went to the bedroom to get dressed
and go get some help.
- Help?
- Yes
Then you turned off the tap.
Yes, because you'd left the water running.
I don't understand.
Neither do I.
I should call Dr. Bertier.
Why? What can he do?
I don't know. Examine you.
I'm fine. Nothing's wrong with me.
Listen, Anne,
this is absurd.
We can't pretend nothing happened.
But what happened in actual fact?
I'm here, having my breakfast
and you're telling me things
I don't understand.
Can you explain how the dishcloth got here?
No.
- Who turned the tap on?
- You.
So you remember?
No.
You're trying to torture me.
Leave me a one!
Wouldn't it be better to call Dr Bertier?
No.
You know him.
He always has to see an idea through.
In the end, everybody was happy.
And it's a boost for ourfnances.
Were performing till the 28th,
then we break for 10 days,
then to Stockholm for four days,
then on to Kuhmo in Finland,
whereverthat is.
In the North Pole.
Geoff's been there before and oves it.
There, we'll play arrangements of Dowland.
And then t's back to London.
And the children?
Liz is at her boarding school and John...
He's doing his thing. He's 26.
Whats he doing now?
He works.
He's very independent.
We hardly ever see him.
A bit like Geoff.
They don't get along well.
Geoff's always trying to give him advice
and that annoys John.
Is he good?
I think so.
He's less impulsive
but conscentious.
That sounds almost pejorative.
Not at all. He's different than Geoff.
He's...
Calm but persevering.
I can see him making it.
The other day, he played the solo part
In Haydn's concerto
at the last Conservatory concert.
It was very good.
Geoff was there
and congratulated him at the end.
What about you?
What about me?
Have you reconciled?
You know what he's like.
In September,
he suddenly fell in love with a viola player
who'd been in our ensemble for years.
What can I say? It caused a huge drama.
She tried to kill herself.
He got scared and came back to me
riddled with remorse.
Over the years, I've got used to it.
What bothers me is that
the whole ensemble knows.
Do you love him?
Yes, I think so.
What was this operation for?
What do you want me to say?
They ran tests that revealed
an obstruction of the carotid
which required an operation.
She was frightened.
She was confused and frightened.
Shes always been scared of doctors,
you know
They said the surgical risks were very low
and that without an operation,
she'd have a more serious attack.
What do they say now?
That it didn't work.
That's all.
The 5% failure rate.
It's all terribly exciting.
Normaly, at this time, I'm asleep.
My blood sugar evel
is subterranean.
I'm really sorry.
Yes.
What can I do to help?
Nothing.
It's sweet of you to have come
with all the stress you have.
Seriously, you can t do anything.
We'll see what happens
when she comes back home.
We'll manage all right.
Perhaps I'll hire a nurse
or maybe I can care for her myself.
We'll see.
Weve always coped, your mother and I.
All this is stll a bit new.
It's funny.
Sorry if this embarrasses you,
but when I came in earlier,
I remembered listening to you two
making love when I was little.
For me it was reassuring.
It made me feel you loved each other
and that we'd always be together.
Mind your fingers.
Put those down near the window.
Sorry.
- For both of you.
- Thanks you
Goodbye then.
Thank you, Mr. Mery.
If you need anything just call down.
If we can help...
Everything's fine for now,
but I'll call your wife if we need help.
Were glad to have you back, Mrs. Laurent.
Yes, thanks you, Mr. Mery.
If you need anything...
Yes. Thank you.
Goodbye Madam.
And once again, we come home.
Goodbye, Sir.
Goodbye Mr.Mery. Thank you.
Where do you want to...
The living room.
Shall I make some tea?
Come and sit with me first.
Could you help me into the chair?
Yes, of course.
Come as close as you can,
put your knees against mine so I don't slip,
wrap your right arm around me
and lift me up.
I'm so happy that you're back.
Me too.
Promise me something.
What?
Please dont evertake me
back to the hospital.
What?
Do you promise?
- Anne...
- Do you promise?
Don't speak.
Don't explain.
Please.
What can I say?
Nothing.
Say nothing.
OK?
Thanks.
Thanks, Sweetheart.
Everything OK?
Everything's OK.
You don't have to hold my hand all the time.
I can look after myself, you know.
And don't feel guilty.
It would be absurd and oppressive.
For me too.
I don't feel guilty.
Good.
Go back in there now.
I'm not a cripple.
You can leave me alone for a minute.
I won't fall to pieces.
OK.
Did you buy the new book on Harnoncourt?
I've already read it.
And?
You want it? I'll get it for you.
Please.
I don't know where I put it.
It doesn't matter. It's not important.
It does matter.
Hold on...
I think I left it...
Here it is!
There's nothing keannfalible memory.
I thought I'd left it in the spare room,
when in fact I'd a ready put it away.
Tidy is as tidy does.
Thank you.
Right...
Now find yourself something to do.
Don't stand there to see how I hold the book.
OK?
OK.
I'll leave the dooropen.
Unfortunately
the strawberres were a ready mushy
but I'll get you some fresh ones
at the market tomorrow.
My husband will bring up the Evian later.
It's too heavy for me, with my back.
No problem.
It was 7640 euros.
Here's the receipt
and 23.60 back.
No, keep the change.
Thank you, Sir.
Right I'll be going.
Call me if you need anything.
I will.
Is yourwife feeling better?
Yes, she's recovering.
Good.
Give her my regards.
My husband and I are glad to have her back.
Yes, we are too.
Goodbye Mrs. Mery. Thank you.
Goodbye, Sir.
I'll bring you the strawberries
tomorrow noon if thats OK.
That's fine thank you.
Can you come please?
Yes.
A schmaltzy romance
between a nobleman
and a commoner's daughter
who can't marry and so,
through generosity of spirit,
they renounce each other.
Actualy, I'm not sure of the story any more.
I remember being overcome with emotion
when I came out of the film
and it took me a while to calm down.
Thanks you.
In the courtyard of Grandma's building,
there was a young man at his window
who asked me where I'd been.
He was a few years older than me,
one of those flashy types
and of course he intimidated me.
"At the cinema," I had said.
Because I was very proud that Grandma
had given me the money to go a one.
"What did you see?"
I started telling him the story
and, as I did so,
the emotion bubbled up again.
I couldnt very well cry in front of him
but I couldn't help myself.
I stood there in tears in the courtyard
and told him the whole damn story.
And?
What did he do?
I've no idea.
He made fun of me, no doubt.
I don't remember.
I don't remember the film either.
But I remember
those emotions.
I was ashamed about crying
and yet, telling the story,
the emotions and tears welled up again,
even stronger than during the film perhaps.
I couldn't stop crying.
That's sweet.
Why didn't you ever tell me?
There are still many stories
I've nevertold you.
You're not going to ruin your image
in old age, are you?
I'd rather not.
What's my image?
You can be a monster sometmes
but you are kind.
Can I get you another drink?
Five,
six,
seven,
eight,
nine,
ten.
We'll do fifteen.
Eleven,
twelve,
thirteen,
fourteen,
and fifteen!
- OK?
- Yes, fine.
Listen.
My horoscope.
"Motto...
"Vivacious but serious.
"Love...
"Superior distractions are what you need.
"Work...
"Your motivation's back,
but advance wth caution.
"Fitness...
"Shake off the rust with a ttle exercise
"to get your momentum back. "
You'll only have yourself to blame
you read that nonsense
Tomorrow afternoon's Pierres funeral.
You must go.
Yes, I think so.
But I really don't want to.
It's rare to want to attend a funeral.
I know some exceptions.
Annette can't wait to get dolled up.
- And that imbecle Francois...
- That's mean.
What would you say if no one came to yours?
Probably nothing.
Have you spoken
to Jeanne since I was taken to the hospital?
Does she know that I can't go?
Yes, of course.
What did she say?
She was shocked.
What do you mean?
I don't know.
What's anyone like when theyre shocked?
She was speechless she couldn't believe it.
I don't know.
I mean, not precisely.
You know I spoke to a lot of people.
I'm sorry.
I should be the one apologising.
I didn't mean it nastily.
But what's the point
constantly going on about it?
I constantly go on about it?
No.
I apologise.
What the...
How come you're home already?
What time is it?
Forgive me.
I was too slow.
Could you push me into the living room?
Yes.
You always were good at surprises.
Why did you come back early?
I didn't come back eary. I caught a cab.
There's not much traffic on Saturdays.
True.
How was the funeral?
How did it go?
Tell me.
It was pretty strange.
The priest was an idiot.
A former co-worker of Pierre's
stood up and gave a terribly pathetic speech.
His old secretary brought a long
a tape player, a mini-tape player,
and put on Yesterday by The Beatles.
You can't imagine.
Everybody turned to look at her.
Apparently, it was unplanned.
Pierre's grandchildren were there.
Of course, they started giggling
when the music began.
And then,
the turn was placed on a huge gurney
that was clearly designed to carry a coffin
and out we went into the rain.
They placed the turn on a small electric cart
that crawled along for an eternity
until it reached the small hole theyd dug.
A lot of people were laughing hard.
It must have been awful for Jeanne.
There's no reason to go on iving.
I know it can only get worse.
Why must I inflict that on us?
On you and on me.
You're inflicting nothing on me.
You don't have to ie Georges.
Put yourself in my shoes.
Haven't you ever thought
it could happen to me, too?
Of course I have.
But imagination and reality
have very Itte in common.
It's improving every day.
I don't want to go on.
Everything you're doing
to make it bearable is touching
but I don't want to go on.
For my sake Not yours.
I don't believe you.
I know you.
You think you're a burden on me.
But if you were in my shoes,
what would you do?
I've no idea.
I don't want to think about what I'd do.
I'm tired.
I want to go to bed.
Hello there!
What a nice surprse!
Forgive the intrusion I tried calling
several times, but got no answer.
Sorry, I only pick up
when the number's in the memory
and I know who's calling.
Come on in.
I'm terribly sorry
I couldn't drop by after the concert.
I was so glad you could make it.
Come in.
Yesterday, my agent called me
because I'm making a record in June
and I had to choose a studio a piano...
So I caught the morning flight to Paris
and when I got to my hotel,
I decided to drop by
It's nearby.
It's nice of you.
These are for your wife.
Thanks you.
Is she in?
She is. I'll go and get her.
Please have a seat.
I hope this isn't a bad time?
Not at all. It's good to see you.
Have a seat.
We were so thrilled by your concert,
my wife and I.
We were looking forward
to seeing you again.
Can I get you something to drink?
- Tea?
- No, thank you.
I'll just put the flowers in water
and tell her that you're here.
I won't be a moment.
Alexandre!
How delightful It's overly to see you.
Mrs Laurent,
the pleasures mine.
Have a seat.
Go on have a seat
and don't look so a armed.
I'm extremely proud of you.
We were in raptures after your concert.
The very next morning
Georges said he wanted to buy your new CD.
Oh dear.
I meant to bring you one and totally forgot.
I left in such a haste.
- I'll try to find one today and...
- No, please.
Let us contribute to your success,
even fit's only 20 euros.
You've already made a great contribution.
I owe you a lot.
You owe it to your hard work and talent.
You rememberthe first time
you asked me to play Bagatelles?
I was 12.
With my youthful arrogance I asked,
'Why some Bagatelles?"
Remember?
You realy chewed me out that day.
What happened to you?
I'm paralysed down my right side.
It happens with age.
How?
Let's change the subject, shall we?
Sure.
Don't be offended,
but I want to make the most
of your lovely surprise visit.
Of course.
You still haven't told us all that's happened
since your concert in Paris.
I've been in London most of the time,
except two concerts in Copenhagen,
Schubert again
The Impromptus and Moments Musicaux.
My life revolves around Schubert right now.
Ideally I'd like to record a the sonatas.
But the last ones can wait a few years.
Will you do me a favour?
Yes.
Would you play the Bagatelle in G Minor?
I haven't played tin ages.
I'm not sure I remember it.
If you want, I can try but...
Try.
What's wrong?
What are you doing?
Have you lost your mind?
I don't believe it.
Look what you've done.
Can't you call me
when you need something?
- I'm sorry.
- Yes.
Me too.
Sorry.
The amp's broken, too.
Yes?
Who's there?
What's going on?
Who's it?
Is anyone there?
Georges? What's going on?
What's wrong?
Calm down.
What was it?
Eva.
They'I be here on the 12th.
How come?
Don't ask me.
Apparently, shes coming with Geoff.
When?
I don't know exactly Whats today s date?
I'll check.
I don't want that.
- What?
- For Geoff to come. It's not necessary.
I don't need any comments on my state.
His Brtsh humour
is bearable only in small doses.
"Dear Mrs Laurent and Mr Laurent,
'I spent a beautiful
and sad moment with you.
I hope with all my heart
that everything works out.
With the deep affection
of your former pupil,
Alexandre.
Turn the music off.
Where are the photo albums?
The photo albums?
I don't know.
In the spare room, I think.
Why?
Can you bring them?
Now?
Why now?
I'd like to look at them.
Please.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
It's beautiful.
What?
Life.
So long.
Long life.
Stop observing me.
I'm not observing you.
Of course you are.
I'm not that stupid just yet.
'... from the twin angles
of style and substance
"Benjamin Netanyahu
will at last be granted
a state visit with full honours,
"photo and handshakes
"and joint press conference
intended as a conspiculous demonstration
of the reconciliation between
"Israel and America. "
You're soaking wet.
How come?
Hold on.
It's no big deal.
Come on.
Don't get annoyed.
Calm down.
Perhaps it's better to invest the money
in buildings to rent
If inflation takes off again
property is the safest option.
At the moment,
savings accounts pay 1.75%.
That's a good rate.
Four years ago,
Geoff bought some stock
with a little nest egg
and everything collapsed.
So now we're worred, obviously.
At the same time,
other people had the same idea.
House prices are booming.
Since I got back from Scandinavia,
I've become addicted to the classifieds.
We'll see.
It takes time. We'll find something eventually.
I've...
Grandmother...
Woman with house...
Not...
House...
After...
Money...
I'm sorry, Mummy, I don't understand.
I don't understand what you're saying.
Right away...
That's all...
House sale...
Not...
In a snap...
So fast...
God its hard...
To say...
House sold...
Money gone...
Gone...
As well as...
The house...
What house?
As we I...
Grandmother...
Three tmes a week.
I have no experience with it.
We'll see if t's enough
How much is she asking?
It's paid by the hour.
We'll see.
What about her?
Anne?
It's hard to explain.
Sometimes it's as if
she's totaly unaware of herstate.
A moment ater, it's the opposite.
What does the doctor say?
She's talking gibberish.
What's going on?
We can't leave her lying there like that.
She's unrecognisable. It's mad.
We can't do anything for now.
She's under treatment, she has medication.
There's nothing else we can do.
Nothing else we can do?
Why not hosp talise her?
She had a second stroke.
Bertier examined her
and thanks we can spare her
the battery of routine hospital tests.
They wouldn't keep her anyway.
They'd send her to a hospice.
What they do there, we can do here.
She's not going into a home.
I promised her that.
Don't you think you're taking on too much?
Do you have a better idea?
I can't believe that these days
there aren't more effective treatments.
Nothing's stopping you from finding out.
I presume you understand
that I love your mother as much as you.
So please don't treat me like a moron
who can't even do the sensible thing.
I didn't say that.
I simply wonder if this
is the best solution.
How about a second opinion?
OK, stop it both of you.
Another doctor came by.
He agreed with Bertier.
Starting Monday, a nurse will come
three times a week.
Happy?
Can we talk about something else now?
Such as?
...behind the shoulder
and push on her buttocks.
Hold her like that with the elbow
and put the nappy on.
You have to push behind her.
Push hard.
And then slowly back.
Stretch her leg out.
There we are.
Now can you grab the sheet? I'll help.
Pull...
Now, pull the nappy
like this.
That's right.
And now on our back again.
Put the nappy on
and attach it with the little straps.
Here you go, Sweetheart. I hope you'll like it.
I added a little peach juice.
It tastes quite good.
Come on, Sweetheart,
you only ate three mouthfuls.
Come on.
Sorry.
Mummy...
At concert...
No dress.
No dress Mummy at the concert?
Hurts!
Let's do the other side.
We're done Let's rinse you off.
Is the temperature OK?
I'm going to top you forward.
Don't be scared, I'm here.
Very good.
She could do 8:00-12:00
and I'd do 2:00-6:00 in the afternoon.
Or 300-700.
Let me think about it.
Shell need some notice.
Of course.
I'll let you know in the next few days.
Very well.
I'd better be going.
Thanks for the coffee.
My pleasure.
I'll see you out.
Don't take it to heart.
Generally they always say something.
She cou d just as easiy
be saying, "Mum, mum mum!"
It's a reflex.
I know.
Goodbye, Sir.
I'd like to hire another nurse.
They could work in shifts.
That would simplify things.
What do you think?
Hurts.
Would you put them in the kitchen?
I'm home!
Thank you very much.
Can I do anything else Sir?
No, thanks you. You've been a big help.
It's nothing. Thanks you very much.
I'll call you if necessary.
With pleasure, Sir.
Goodbye.
May I make a remark?
Yes.
My wife and I...
We're very impressed
by the way you're coping.
Hats off to you.
That's very kind. Thank you.
See you soon.
- Give my regards to your wife.
- I certainly will.
Hello Eva, how are you?
Were fine.
There you go.
You want to look your very best
so everybody can admire you.
There.
You want a look?
Hold on.
Well?
Isn't she beautiful?
Get out!
Whatever you say, Sir.
I don't know if you realise,
I gave up another job to work here.
You should've thought through
if you needed a second nurse.
Then, I had no idea
how incompetent you are.
What does that mean?
I won't discuss t with you
and you wouldn't understand anyway.
Nobody has ever
complained about me before.
Good for you. How much do I owe you?
780 euros.
This has never happened to me.
Who do you think you are?
I've been doing this for years.
I don't need you to teach me my job.
Do you have 20 euros?
- No.
- Take the 800 and leave.
You're a mean old man.
I pity you.
I sincerely hope that one day somebody
treats you like you treat your patients
and that you have no way to defend yourself.
Now get out of my sight.
Get out Go.
Fuck you, you old prick!
Open your mouth.
Come on...
Please!
Please...
Stop that.
If you don't drink, you'll die.
Is that what you want?
Please.
For Chrst's sake.
You can't force me to let you die of thirst.
If you keep this up,
Bertier will hospitalise you.
They'll feed you artf cially there.
Is that what you want?
I promised to spare you that,
but I need your help.
It's too much for me.
Come on, Anne.
Drink it now.
There you go.
That's good.
Go on drink it!
I'm sorry.
Forgive me.
- Who's there?
- It's me.
Eva?
Yes.
Just a moment.
What was the problem?
Nothing, I was in the toilet.
No come in.
Why the surprise visit?
Whats going on with Mum?
Nothing.
Should something be?
Wont you sit down first?
How come you're in Paris?
What's going on with Mum?
Why dont you ever answerthe phone?
Since we spoke, I've left four messages.
Why haven't you called me back?
I'm sorry, I don't sten to the messages.
Doesn't it occur to you that were concerned?
Your concern is of no use to me.
Don't take it personally.
I'm not crit cising you.
I don't have time to deal with your concern.
Dad!
No, let's stop this conversation.
As was to be expected,
your mothers in a bad way.
Shes increasingly like a defenceless child.
It's sad and humiliating for both her and me.
She doesn't want anyone to see her like this.
When you both came last time,
she didn't want you here.
You two have your Ife and that's fine.
Leave us ours.
- OK?
- Dad, whats gotten into you?
Nothing I'm just surprised by your visit
and it annoys me to see you breeze in here
saying what's right.
Who do you think you are?
Stay here please.
Please.
Mum?
Are you out of your mind?
- Sit down.
- I don't want to see What's going on here?
Nothings going on.
I just want to avoid unnecessary drama.
I imagine your mother's asleep.
She sleeps all day.
She wakes up at night though.
If you insist, we'll look in on her later.
Now, come and sit down.
Every day, we do our speech exercises
or we sing together.
I usually wake up around 5:00.
At that time, she's not asleep yet.
We change her nappy.
I put cream on herto avoid bed sores
and around 7:00, I try to conv nce her
to have something to eat and drink.
Sometimes I succeed sometimes I don t.
Sometimes she talks about her ch dhood
or she calls for help for hours on end.
Suddenly, she'll burst out aughing
or she'll start weeping.
None of all that deserves to be shown.
You can't ban me from seeing her.
No.
It's me Mum.
Can I do anything foryou?
The tea's not very hot
but it warms you up.
Thanks.
It was silly of me to lock the door.
I'm sorry.
I was surprised.
What happens now?
What happens?
The nurse comes three times a week.
Every two weeks,
Dr Bertierand the hairdresser come.
Is that what you wanted to know?
What happens now
is what's happened until now.
It wll go steadily downhill
for a while and then one day it'll be over.
You can't go on ke th 's Dad.
- I cant?
- No.
What do you suggest?
Can't we have a serious talk about it?
What do you ca I a serious talk?
You want Mum to live with you?
You want to pack her off to a home?
Is that what you want?
Go on,
talk seriously with me.
Really long...
Yes, swinging back and forth.
Back Forth...
You.
Very serious...
Like that...
Serious...
Yes, I was very uptight.
Yes... Uptight...
It was...
Nice.
Hurts!
What's wrong?
Where does it hurt?
What's the matter?
Is it the nappy?
Is it full?
No.
Where does it hurt?
It's all right.
I'm here.
Everything's all right.
Let's...
Shall I tell you a story?
But you have to stay quiet
because I can't talk too loudly.
It tires me out.
When I was very young...
Actually, I wasn't that young.
I think it was
at the end of primary school.
So I must have been about ten.
Mum and Dad sent me to a summer camp.
They thought it'd do me good
to be wth children my age.
The camp was based in an old castle
in the middle of a forest in Auvergne I think.
No, I can t remember.
In any case, it was the oppos te
of what I'd expected.
We had to get up at 6:00 in the morning
to go fora swim in a lake.
It was a little lake
near the castle
that was fed by an ice-cold mountain stream.
We had to run and jump into tin pairs.
You know I was never very sporty.
The whole programme was designed
to keep us on the move all day long.
It was probaby intended to
nip in the bud
any potentia pubescent impulses.
The food was the worst part.
The th rd day afterwe arrived,
for lunch,
we were g ven rce pudding.
I hate rice pudding.
We were sitting at long tables
in an immense hall.
I didn't want to eat the stuff.
A counselor
sad to me
You're not leaving
until you finish your plate.
Afterthe meal, everybody got up and left
and I was left alone
in tears.
Mum and I had made a secret pact.
I was to write her every week.
I was to send her a postcard.
If I was enjoying camp,
I was to draw flowers on it
and if I wasn't,
stars.
She kept that card.
It was
covered in stars.
Afterthree hours,
I was fnally allowed to leave.
I went up to my room
and got into bed.
I was runn ng a feverof over40.
It was diphtheria.
They took me
to the nearest hosp tal
where I was kept in isolation.
So when Mum came to see me
she could only wave to me through the glass.
Somewhere a ong the line, I ost the card.
It's a shame.
I'm a most done.
You can put your shoes on f you want.
Thank you.
You're not taking a coat?