Go on, soak them.
The wetter they get, the better I like it.
There´s no money under those umbrellas.
Lot of goops crawling around in the rain.
That´s a laugh.
I ain´t even got an umbrella.
Seven bucks...
...The Last of the Mohicans.
Looks like I gotta promote something.
Look at her gol
Come on, baby, roll them outl
That´s what this town is...
...a dice game.
Come on, you seven. Rain me a seven.
Don´t get any sevens holding out a tin cup.
There must be a seven
rolling for me somewhere.
You found out.
Yes, we found out.
$3,000 stolen by my friend.
My old friend...
...a man l took off the streets
when he didn´t have a job.
What are you going to do?
Go on, call the police.
Remember when you came to me and said,
´´Hopper, she loves me.
´´This beautiful woman loves me...
´´...and we´re gonna get married.´´
Shut up.
Don´t talk about her.
Did you ever ask me up to your house
after you got married?
No, not once.
You were ashamed of me in front of her.
l wasn´t good enough for her.
Then comes the laugh.
You weren´t good enough, either.
But Hopper´s money,
that was plenty good enough.
The money that the fat man made
by working hard, night and day.
That was fine for her.
She didn´t mind stealing this money, huh?
She didn´t steal anything, it was me.
Look at him, he still loves her.
Answer me, you still love her?
She gave the money to Mr. Morgan,
didn´t she?
That´s what you stole money for,
so she should give it to the man she loves.
Here´s his announcement.
´´We are pleased to announce the opening
of Dan Morgan´s beauty parlor...
´´...March 30.´´
You´re going to see her tonight again,
free this time, shouldn´t cost me anything.
You´re going to tell her
that Hopper wants his $3,000 back.
You´ll tell her
that if Hopper don´t get it back...
...he´ll call the police to send his partner
and his partner´s wife to jail.
Both together.
l got the right. l got the evidence.
That´s all.
Tomorrow morning at 6:00,
l´ll be sitting in my office...
...and you´ll bring me the money from her.
Tell her Hopper isn´t at her feet crying...
...but standing up
with a policeman beside him...
...waiting to arrest you and her together.
6:00 in my office.
$3,000.
-Where to, mister?
-Uptown.
-$5, got anything smaller?
-That´s all right, keep the change.
Check your things, sir?
Coat, please.
Excuse me.
Cigarettes?
-$20. Just a moment, l´ll get your change.
-Never mind, keep the change.
Gee, thanks.
-Have you any reservations?
-No.
Emil...
...find a good table for this gentleman.
Right this way, sir.
Have a good time, sir.
Wasn´t that the strangest thing?
$20, without even giving me a second look.
l thought he was some sort of a tramp.
Just goes to show
you can´t trust your eyes in this town.
-Do you know him, Vincent?
-No, l never saw him before.
But l knew he was somebody
the way he looked at me.
Hello. Sunset Hotel? Room 1007, please.
Bill O´Brien calling.
Hello, Dutch? Bill O´Brien.
l´m over at the Pigeon Club
taking in the sights...
...and l ran into something
that l thought might be of interest to us.
An out-of-town job
came snow-shoeing in here a while ago...
...and throwing money around
like birdseed.
Never saw him before, strictly a hick.
Say, l wouldn´t fool a pal like you, Dutch.
l tell you this is a blue plate special.
l thought l´d bring him over
for a little get together...
...on the same percentage as last time.
Bill O´Brien, what about him?
Nice guy, chief.
He´s got a room down the hall.
He used to be a bellhop at the St. Martin,
got a lot on the ball.
Okay, chief, 12:00 at the Sunset.
Excuse me, are you Mr. White?
No.
That´s very funny,
l could have sworn you were Mr. White.
-Do you mind if l sit down a moment?
-No.
l´m not intruding, l hope.
They have a nice show here.
Very artistic, isn´t it?
l´m not trying to pull anything, really.
l´ll be frank, l knew you weren´t Mr. White.
ln fact, there is no Mr. White.
lt´s just a name l made up.
l´m really looking for Mr. Hugo.
He puts on the show here,
engages all the talent.
l knew Mr. Hugo some time ago,
being in one of his units.
No use waiting in the lobby,
he never comes out.
As for hanging out, you know how they are
if you don´t have an escort.
They don´t care about your feelings.
My name is Nina Barona. l´m a Russian.
But this season everything is Latin,
completely Latin.
Hello, how are you? Glad to see you again.
Pardon me, won´t you?
Don´t tell me
you don´t remember me, Nina.
l think you have a slight advantage
over me.
lt´s Nina Barona, isn´t it? Russian?
l never forget a face
if it´s beautiful enough.
Bill O´Brien is the name,
in case your memory is playing tricks.
l hope you don´t mind
my barging in on you.
l´m on the town with nothing to do
but throw money away.
´´Have fun and make friends.´´
That´s my motto.
Waiter.
-Yes, sir?
-Check.
Honey, l can´t see,
please make him sit down.
-Sit down, old boy.
-Sit down, we can´t see.
One moment and l´ll leave you
to your tawdry revels.
Very sad.
Venus was never an epileptic.
l leave you heroes at your periscopes.
That was Eugene Gibbons, the playwright.
Really? Do you know him?
Sure, known him for years. Nice guy, too.
Too bad about his last show.
l read about it. No good was it?
Three years ago, the white hope
of the theater. Today, a mug.
That´s New York for you.
Put you on the Christmas tree
and then the alley.
Here we are.
How long are you gonna be in town?
Not very long.
Here´s hoping you enjoy your brief stay.
Gene! So good to see you.
My beautiful.
l´m so sorry l didn´t get to see your play.
l heard it was charming.
Do come around sometime, Gene.
l´m giving a little party Saturday--
Put your scissors away, Delilah,
my hair´s all cut.
ls this stylish fellow my successor?
-Gene, you´re drunk.
-Darling.
You understate the case by three bottles
and a thousand tears.
Avaunt.
What is the idea
of giving me a midget´s coat?
Or is the management
handing out straitjackets...
...as it should?
Sorry, Mr. Gibbons, we have a new boy.
Just a second, please.
Mr. Gibbons´ coat, Frank, that brown one.
´´To whom it may concern.´´
l´m in receipt of a communication.
´´This is to inform the police
that l have ended my own life.´´
-Vincent!
-Yes, Mr. Gibbons?
-Whose mantle is this?
-l don´t know his name, sir.
He´s a stranger who came in a while ago.
A stranger out of the night.
Where is he roosting?
You can find anything you want
in New York...
...if you know where to look for it.
Romance. Adventure.
l know that goes on where you´re from.
But in New York,
it´s with an all-star cast and a fast show.
Seven million people all on one skyrocket,
that´s New York.
What do you say
we slip out and have a look?
Thanks.
Thanks very much,
but l have another engagement.
Come on, it´s early yet.
Your engagement will keep.
Let´s have a little fun first,
what do you say?
Mr. Engle, l believe?
Yes.
How do you do?
My name is Gene Gibbons...
...the distinguished playwright.
l am glad to see you, Gene.
Won´t you join us?
With pleasure.
Do not misunderstand the word
´´distinguished,´´ Mr. Engle.
lt refers to my misdeeds.
Allow me to present Miss Nina Barona
of the Russian ballet.
Miss Barona, you are enchanting.
What´s your name, son?
Come on now, Gene. l´m Bill O´Brien.
To be sure, one of the O´Briens.
Listen, Brien, will you do me a favor?
For old time´s sake.
l want to discuss a matter
of personal importance with Mr. Engle.
Always glad to do anything
to oblige my distinguished friends.
Come on, Nina.
We need a little privacy ourselves.
Let´s go.
-How did you know my name?
-This letter, sir.
Fine, fine.
l no longer have to order drinks.
l just attract them.
He shall have liquor wherever he goes.
As l understand
from your communication, Mr. Engle...
...you´re on the brink of self-destruction.
May l shake your hands, a brilliant idea.
l speak as one who has destroyed himself
a score of times.
l am, Mr. Engle...
...a veteran corpse.
We are all corpses here.
This rendezvous is one of the musical
graveyards of the town.
Caters to zombies
hopping around with dead hearts...
...and price tags for souls.
Will you join me, sir?
lt is the custom here
for the dead to drink...
...heavily.
Allow me to present my credentials, sir,
as a fellow cadaver.
l´m being divorced by my wife
whom l love dearly...
...in my own nasty way.
l was disemboweled by another woman.
l have written three bad plays in a row...
...and next year l´ll write a worse one.
l have neither a home, a single hope...
...nor a shred of curiosity left.
Bankrupt and broke.
l´ve destroyed myself in becoming famous.
l am no longer a man, Mr. Engle.
l´m an epitaph over an ash can.
And now, sir...
...what´s your story?
You appeal to me.
There´s something innocent about you.
No, l don´t mean really innocent.
-You mean a little dumb.
-Not dumb, just good-natured.
Yes, l´m very good-natured.
-No kidding, where you from?
-Brooklyn.
-Where are you from?
-Me?
l fell out of a policeman´s whistle
in Times Square.
Having fun?
Yes, it´s fun dancing with someone
who knows everybody.
Come on.
-Gee, it´s wonderful here.
-Sit down.
-You think l´m a big shot, don´t you?
-Not necessarily.
l could sell you a penthouse of mink coats,
then you´d never see me again.
Just another dream that never came true.
-You´d fall for that, wouldn´t you?
-Not necessarily.
l won´t keep you in suspense, Miss Barona.
l ain´t a millionaire.
-No penthouse?
-No penthouse...
...and no carfare.
This is a big disappointment to me,
Mr. O´Brien.
The sorrow is all mine, lady.
Millions, millions everywhere,
and not a cup of coffee.
Do you want to make some real dough?
lt depends.
Maybe l´m the sap,
but l´m going to let you in.
-Oil wells?
-No, no kidding.
There´s a seven rolling for me tonight,
and l could use a partner.
Here, sit here.
Did you ever hear of Dutch Enright?
The gangster?
What do you mean, ´´gangster´´?
The gambler.
Don´t you ever read anything?
Runs the biggest poker game in town.
Didn´t you hear about the chump
who lost his hotel on four nines?
Got in all the columns.
So what?
l´m the guy who steered him up there
and got a grand for my cut.
Don´t get excited. That was five months
ago and all l got left is this suit.
-lt´s very becoming.
-Save the jokes, now, this is serious.
l´m thinking of taking Engle up there
tonight.
What´s the ´´oh´´ for?
He´s stuffed with dough, ain´t he?
ls he?
A money tramp. l happen to know.
Sorry.
What´s the difference
if he gets took for a little?
A guy like that can afford to lose...
...and besides, he gets a kick out of
meeting important people.
You want to help?
l don´t see what use l would be
in that direction.
All you got to do is play up to him a little.
When he starts to get personal,
you say you live at the Sunset Hotel.
We all go up there for a party,
then l take over.
All you gotta do is act sweet, that´s all.
Like a gun moll?
You´re scared, huh?
Who, me?
A tragic tale, brother.
A little confused and badly constructed.
l speak as one who eight years ago
won the Pulitzer Prize for drama.
Finish your drink,
while l examine this sad plot.
l disapprove of your death, Mr. Engle.
Nobody has any right
to kill himself for $3,000.
That´s being short-sighted.
My boy, that´s killing yourself for peanuts.
Not that you wouldn´t be better off dead,
you and l both.
lt´s a world anyone would be better out of.
lt´s a rotten world...
...dancing and murdering.
Were l a philosopher, l´d say:
´´An idiot with a gun in one hand
and a clarinet in the other.´´
ln fact, l did say it,
and the play closed Saturday.
l do not approve of your exit, Mr. Engle.
lf you will be patient
and have faith in a dramatist...
...who once was second to none,
l´ll rewrite your last act.
Our present plot problem is money.
$3,000.
A straw that destroys.
My boy...
...remove your cerements.
l found you a new godmother.
l refer to the lady
with the pneumatic shape.
That creature loved me madly
three months ago.
As you can see from the jewels
that festoon her battle front.
Mine, all mine.
Homage to love eternal.
Kindly notice that Kohinoor
at the left sector.
We´ll get that back, son,
in a flanked movement.
Wait here, pilgrim.
l´ll be back, Charlie, my lad,
with a bauble called Life.
lsn´t that Mr. Hugo over there by the wall?
Yeah.
-Would you mind introducing me, please?
-We ain´t got time for that?
Excuse me.
Mr. Hugo...
...l don´t know if you remember me...
...Nina Barona. At the Monkey Club?
l did a specialty,
the slave routine with the chains.
But l´m much better now,
if you´re remembering, l mean.
l know you´re busy,
but if you´d give me an audition...
...it would only take a few minutes.
l´ve still got the costume and the props.
The chains and everything.
What are you doing tonight?
Why, nothing.
Come on, kid,
we´ll go someplace and talk this thing--
There you are! Hello, madam.
l´ve been combing the joint,
your husband is trying to find you.
-What?
-Yeah, he´s breaking dishes.
Come and cool him off
before he starts smacking waiters.
Wait a minute, it´s a lie.
You´ve got a lot of nerve, wasting my time.
l know, Mr. Hugo.
Of all the dirty tricks l ever saw....
Just when l get a break.
This is the most contemptible thing
anybody ever did.
He would have given me a job!
-You fool!
-Maybe, but l figure it wasn´t worth it.
You figure?
Listen, you know-it-all,
l don´t need you or anybody else to figure.
Take it easy, you´ll attract attention.
l´ve always taken care of myself,
understand?
l don´t need help from any amateur crooks.
Go on, l´ve had enough of you.
Please, beat it.
l´m no gun moll.
You ain´t no buzzard´s dish neither...
...not while l´m around.
May l say, those were
the five most wonderful weeks of my life.
l hope you haven´t forgotten them,
my sweet.
The little farmhouse in Maine...
...winter and the snow...
...and the little stove
burning in the room, as l recall.
And the light on the wall that night.
The only light in the world.
Lonely, and the wind blowing.
And outside, the snow like a white horse.
The little stove burning in the dark...
...like the eye of dreams.
Please, Gene, you´re drunk.
l don´t want to talk about that now.
Where is the little stove of yesteryear
and the white horse?
Gone, huh?
Burnt out and run away.
What are you doing?
Taking back one humble little gift of love.
Just one, for a good cause.
See?
Sylvia, do you want me to do anything?
Who wants to do something?
You, sir.
Control yourself, son.
Tell this madcap how hard l can hit.
Never mind, Stevie.
lt´s quite all right.
Thank you, beautiful.
He giveth and he taketh back...
...in a good cause.
Thank you.
Hello, Mr. Engle.
You can dismiss your hearse.
Manna!
This trinket was obtained from Cartier´s
for $12,000.
You can raise $3,000 on it
from any financier.
lt´s yours.
Live, little man, and suffer.
lt´s hard to understand.
A man you never met before comes along
and does a thing like this.
l didn´t think a thing like this
could ever happen.
Your drink, Mr. Engle.
-Here´s to tomorrow.
-Tomorrow!
Tomorrow.
Take it easy, Lazarus.
l don´t know what to do.
You call on Mr. Hopper in the morning...
...and you hand that moth-eaten nemesis
the $3,000...
...and then you spit in his eye.
Applause.
But that´s not the question.
Allow me to explain, sir, the secret of life.
Yesterday´s pain...
...is tomorrow´s joke.
And you´ll always end up laughing...
...if you can manage
not to cut your throat first.
That´s the message of my last three flops.
You´re a wonderful man, Mr. Gibbons.
l don´t know how to explain it.
lt´s like when you meet somebody
on a dark street and he smiles at you.
You don´t feel frightened for a minute.
For a minute, you feel all right.
l´ll tell you what l´m going to do.
Yes, l´m going to do it.
l´m going to call her up.
We´ll sit here until his nibs goes back
to his table.
Then you step in.
Really, l step in?
That´s right.
What am l supposed to do, lasso him?
Do just what you did last time.
Last time? What last time?
The last time
you got some fellow to fall for you.
l don´t see why l´m wasting my time
to get insulted.
Cut it out.
This is business, so don´t hand me any line.
l know your type backwards.
You do?
lf you don´t care to talk to me
like a gentleman--
Nix, nix, let´s have none of that.
lf we go into partnership,
let´s go in with our eyes open.
All l´ve got on my mind is to grab
some dough and get in the money.
l don´t care how l get there.
As for you, baby,
l´ve known dozens like you...
...sappy kids with a heart like a cur-dog,
that answers whistles...
...and figures they´re having a good time.
l´m a little better than you think,
Mr. O´Brien.
That wouldn´t be hard.
l ain´t trying to insult you,
just analyzing things, see?
The trouble with you is
that you´re a born sucker.
All you know is
how to let people take advantage of you.
What do you think you´re doing?
Reform me into a gangster´s assistant
so l´ll end up shooting policemen?
-That´s very funny.
-lt is, huh?
l´m trying to show you something else than
nickels to grab and buzzards to run with.
l used to be like you: Two bits
and l´d start bowing like a Chinaman.
Baby, you´re worth more than two bits.
You don´t think so, but l do.
l´m getting a little confused.
You´re not trying to make love to me
by any chance?
Baby, when l start making love to you,
it won´t be any guessing game.
She was crying
as she answered the phone.
l didn´t have a chance to tell her.
She wants to see me in the morning.
Do you know what l think?
She´s through with him, this Morgan.
Why would she be crying?
Sure she´s through with him,
she hates him.
l´ll see her in the morning.
We can go away and start all over.
Not with Hopper. Some place else.
A fellow like me can always get a job.
l know how to do lots of things.
lt´s nice, isn´t it?
Quite a joke, Gene, isn´t it?
Hello, my dear.
Are you joining us?
New flagship.
Draw right up, Admiral.
You were always so witty,
such wonderful pranks.
Then so contrite the day after.
lf you are not going to sit down to chat,
pardon me.
l don´t want your conscience to bother you
in the morning when you sober up.
l don´t want you to feel badly
about being a thief and a swine.
You really didn´t steal anything.
That pin is only paste.
l paid $10 for it
while my other was being made over.
You know,
it was terribly funny, your taking it.
You´re quite welcome to it.
Please never mind calling me up
about giving it back...
...or about anything else.
You stupid, drunken fool.
You should give up drinking,
Gene old boy...
...if you want to turn into a Raffles.
Come.
My stupidity begins to amaze me.
Poor little Engle...
...in the hands of an idiotic drunk.
Well...
...we must find other means.
Hello, Mr. Engle.
Do you mind if l have my purse back?
-Thanks so much for guarding it.
-How are they coming, Gene?
My boy,
you wouldn´t happen to have $3,000...
...to spare?
Who, me?
That´s a laugh.
Say, what´s going on here?
Mr. Engle needs $3,000 very badly.
ln fact, desperately.
lt´s a matter of life and death.
-What? Why, l thought that he--
-ls that true, Mr. Engle?
-l mean, are you really broke?
-Face to face with disaster.
-Thanks for trying to help me.
-lt´s going to be all right.
Got to think awhile.
Excuse me for laughing,
but this is too funny.
Cut it out.
The phony. There´s nothing to laugh at.
-lt´s a funny joke, Mr. Gibbons--
-Shut up.
-Anybody´s liable to--
-Maybe you can put it in a play.
Mr. O´Brien thought
Mr. Engle was a millionaire.
That´s what he´s been telling me.
He was going to introduce Mr. Engle
to some crooked gamblers.
And he, Mr. Engle,
was going to be trimmed.
For $30,000 or $40,000, wasn´t it,
Mr. O´Brien, playing poker?
We were going to clean up,
l and Mr. O´Brien...
...on our cut for steering him up there.
Mr. Engle, the millionaire.
You fell out of a policeman´s whistle...
...you think.
What you fell out of was your cradle
and right onto your head.
Okay, copper.
Going to make a fortune for me...
...swindling a poor fellow without a dime.
Somebody give me a drink,
this is too funny.
l´ve got an idea.
You´ve given me the finest plot turn
since the Tower of Babel.
-Take it easy, Gene.
-Quiet!
As l understand it,
your crooked friends are waiting...
...for Mr. Engle with felonious intent.
Waiting to swindle him
in a poker game, right?
Forget it. She´s talking through her hat.
No lying, we haven´t time for it.
Your undivided attention, Mr. O´Brien.
This is perfect.
You´re taking our millionaire, Mr. Engle,
to your gamblers´ den.
Your greedy friends will let him win at first
as a come on.
Let him win, shall we say, $3,000.
At that point, he will excuse himself
for a moment and vanish into the night...
...solvent and with a new lease on life.
Wait a minute. Let´s get out of here.
We´ve got another date.
Never mind your paltry dates.
l´m rewriting you, my Broadway scavenger.
You´ll become a hero, from Gyp the Blood
to Galahad in one lesson...
...and you, too, my little moth. Rise.
Heroine, l need you both.
Where is my little man Engle?
Hey, waiter, where did my little man go?
You haven´t seen
a rather sad-looking man...
...in an ill-fitting overcoat,
walking in the rain, have you?
-l ain´t seen anybody all night.
-That´s too bad.
You stay here while l reconnoiter.
That doorman couldn´t have been wrong.
l didn´t say it wasn´t interesting.
All l said was that
a guy committing suicide is no novelty.
Please, don´t talk to me.
l´m gonna pull a fast one
on Dutch Enright and the mob...
...for a total stranger.
No wonder he writes flops,
with ideas like that.
-Are you going to keep crying all night?
-l asked you not to talk to me.
For a nickel, l´d leave you flat.
Why don´t you?
l don´t happen to have any other dates.
Besides which, it´s raining.
l doubt if l could do much better
on a rainy night.
Cut it out, will you?
There´s nothing to cry about.
That poor man.
l never knew anyone who wanted to die.
Except myself.
-l guess a lot of people are like that.
-Like what?
With a pain inside them they can´t stand.
l´m getting one now.
-You´re cruel and mean.
-Yeah?
l stick to my own troubles to cry over.
You make me sick.
Throwing yourself away on any buzzard
that comes along.
Living like a floozy on a raft.
And now you´re crying
about somebody else.
-That´s laughable.
-Let me alone.
lf you don´t want to buy something,
what´s the idea of coming here to fight?
This is a store and not a theater.
All right, give me some gum.
-What kind you like?
-Don´t want any.
Okay, one package.
l don´t know why every nut in town
picks out this store every time it rains.
You said it.
-Did you find him?
-Not yet, come on.
-Have a heart, Gene, she´ll catch cold.
-l´ve got a cab outside.
l want you two to cruise up and down
and keep your eyes open.
l´ve got to find Engle before it´s too late.
-What about you?
-l´m at my best on foot.
Meet me at the 43rd St. Theater.
The doorman will let you in.
lf you find him, take him there and wait.
lf not, l´ll bring him there myself.
-Have you got that?
-Sure.
Very well. Come along and good luck.
-We really didn´t look enough.
-We looked plenty.
$3 worth.
You didn´t finish telling what happened
after you left the Monkey Club.
Why, nothing.
-You didn´t get another job?
-No.
Just been knocking around
ever since with....
l´ve kept trying continually.
l mean, for a job.
That´s what l was doing tonight, trying.
Yeah. l know all about tonight´s try.
-Are you Mr. O´Brien?
-Yes.
Mr. Gibbons telephoned about you.
He said you should wait on stage.
This way.
l´ll go turn on a light.
Don´t move around
or you´ll bump into the mountain.
A mountain, what mountain?
lt´s called the Acracoronian Mountains,
although there´s only one of them.
l´ll put the light on
and you can see for yourself.
l´m beginning to understand
the whole thing.
lt´s the open season for cuckoos.
Really? Just who are you referring to,
Mr. O´Brien?
l´m referring to Mr. Engle, Mr. Gibbons,
this guy here with the mountain.
And last, but not least, you.
lt´s a bad sign if you start to think
everybody but you is crazy.
Don´t you think?
l wish he´d hurry up with the lights.
What are you nervous about?
Do you think l´m going to
make a grab at you?
Well, l ain´t. You can relax.
lt might be a kind of a novelty at that.
Alone with a guy for an hour
and no passes.
Don´t worry, Mr. O´Brien.
l´m getting a little used to it,
and to your insults, too.
l see. lt´s insulting
when somebody don´t make a grab at you.
l apologize.
l don´t know
why you want to make me feel bad.
You keep asking me about myself.
When l tell you the truth, you get mad.
-Don´t start crying again, will you?
-Why not?
You said it was all right to cry for yourself.
You make me feel
like the most horrible person in the world.
l´m sorry.
l must be nuts.
l tag after you like a puppy
and every time l look at you l get sore.
Tie that.
Okay.
We´re friends, huh?
Sure.
Let´s go see what´s happening.
What´s going on here?
Maybe you´re upset having to take
Mr. Engle up to the gambling den.
l know it´s going to come out all right.
Really.
l can just feel it.
Listen.
One thing l ain´t upset about
is taking Mr. Engle to the gambling den...
...or anywhere else.
Don´t get any false ideas in your head.
l ain´t here for Mr. Engle or Mr. Gibbons.
l´m here strictly on my own business.
Whatever that is.
l wish you wouldn´t talk that way,
it´ll be so easy.
-lt´s going to be easy. Forget it for now.
-No, l´m serious.
They´re bound to let him win.
Even l´ve read that crooked gamblers
let you win at first as a come on.
You´re reading the wrong books, baby.
To find out what happens to nice guys,
don´t read books, just read the headlines.
What happened to the Poles,
the Finns and the Dutch?
They were nice little guys. Did they win?
-They will sometime.
-Forget it.
´´Every guy for himself.´´ That´s my motto.
Look, the old guy isn´t crazy at all.
There is a mountain.
Of course, this isn´t the regular lighting.
lt makes a pretty setting
when it´s rightly lit up.
A snow-capped mountain in Thessaly.
Thessaly was part of Greece.
-The old Greeks--
-We know all about them.
Hear that noise?
That´s the rats.
Always performing....
lf they left this scenery here,
they´d eat it up.
Eat the whole theater up,
if it wasn´t for the actors.
The hollering frightens them.
´´Had l but served my God
with half the zeal l served my King...
´´...he would not in mine age
have left me naked to mine enemies.´´
Go, you!
Get out of there!
Go away! Go away!
Now they´re silent.
He ain´t crazy, you say.
Gee, it´s a beautiful theater.
lf l only had my slave costume
and my chains.
Hey, that ain´t safe.
You´ll break your neck.
lt´s wonderful up here.
Any objections?
Not particularly.
There´s something funny
about you and me.
Maybe it´s just me.
No kidding,
something just keeps me from kissing you.
You don´t have to keep harping on
the fact you don´t like me.
Don´t play dumb.
l don´t like that side of you, that´s all.
What side do you mean?
l don´t understand, honestly.
Sure you don´t, because
l´m talking like a chump, that´s why.
l´m pretending
there´s something swell about you.
This delusion came over me
while we were dancing.
You know,
when you look into a girl´s eyes...
...and you think you see something
that isn´t there?
Well, that´s what l saw.
Maybe it was there. Maybe--
This is just my night for seeing things.
First l see a millionaire
by the name of Engle...
...then l run into a dream girl.
-Come on, it´s all phony baloney.
-Bill.
There´s no seven rolling for me tonight.
Let´s go someplace sensible.
Hello, there!
This way, Mr. Engle.
Joe, a couple of glasses with that bottle.
Enter our hero.
-You found him, l´m so glad.
-There you are, pilgrim.
The snow-capped peaks of Thessaly...
...or rather, according to the critics,
a molehill.
Thank you.
What do you think of that set, Mr. Engle?
-lt looks like a real mountain.
-lt was, until the critics nibbled it away.
The rodents! Here, my boy, drink that.
-lt will give you character.
-Thanks.
You know something?
lt´s going to be all right.
They think l´m rich and they´ll let me win.
-Okay, this is where l came in.
-Where are you going?
-Bye-bye.
-You´re not going to take me there?
He´s full of pipe dreams.
That´s how he makes his living,
making up pipe dreams.
You know what Enright would do to me
for playing a joke like this?
He´s got six killers on his payroll,
hopheads with ice picks.
An alarmist.
How will he find out?
Mr. Gibbons told you what to say to Dutch
after Mr. Engle gets away.
l sit in a chair while they slap me dizzy...
...reciting Gibbons´ idea of dialogue
under such conditions.
lt´s a lot better than you could make up.
These are the wings of the Angel Afriel...
...a very good actor.
-But you can´t run out, you got--
-l got to stick my neck out? For what?
Where´s my percentage?
Where do l come in?
lt´s giving somebody a chance to live.
lt´s giving them a chance to start over
and be happy.
Why should l give anybody a chance?
Who ever gave me a chance, or you either?
l know this town.
l used to work in hotels, all kinds.
Fleabags and flops with gold elevators.
l´ve heard them screaming
and crying behind doors...
...seen them kicked out
when they couldn´t pay...
...seen them jump out of windows
when there was no place to go.
There´s nobody passing out any chances.
lf anybody wants to jump, let him.
l´m looking out for one guy only. Me.
-l didn´t think you were like that.
-l´m strictly a percentage player, that´s all.
For dough, anything. But for....
Wait a minute.
What is it?
l´m dumb.
l´m even dumber than you.
What if this hairpin should win
more than $3,000?
What if they let him win $6,000,
or even $10,000?
l get a split on everything over $3,000.
l´ll talk to Engle and try to make a deal.
-Hey, Mr. Engle?
-Time to be going, gentlemen.
-l got to talk to Engle first--
-You´ve been chatting long enough.
There´s a taxi waiting outside
with the meter running.
l´ve got something to say.
-Listen, Mr. Engle--
-You have nothing to say.
l haven´t?
Say, who do you think you are? God?
Exactly.
l´m glad you see through me, finally.
But you´re still a little short in your vision.
We´re all of us God, my boy.
All creatures full of light and miracles.
Come on.
Thank you.
Omnipotence often needs a little support.
They´re waiting for me
to give them the offers. Then they´ll come.
Who are they?
The big one´s Eddie Burns,
used to be a prize fighter.
l ain´t so scared of him, though.
But the other one....
He´s the brain trust for Dutch Enright.
Louie Artino.
Make up your mind. What do you want?
Shall l flag him?
One minute.
l´m ready, l´ve got it all down.
-Got what down?
-What l´m going to say.
A little more reserve, Mr. Engle.
You´re a very rich man.
You´re so rich you don´t have to talk.
ln fact, you´re so rich,
you have nothing to talk about.
That´s your character.
l´m afraid l´m confusing you.
No, l can act like a rich man.
Don´t worry, Mr. Gibbons.
Won´t do.
l want you to act like a poor man.
Just remember all your troubles
and you´ll look exactly like a rich man.
-l see.
-Good.
All right, Mr. O´Brien.
Curtain.
-Hello, Bill.
-Louie, ain´t seen you in a long time.
Getting along.
Allow me.
Miss Barona, this is Mr. Artino...
...Mr. Engle, Mr. Gibbons. Eugene Gibbons.
How do you do? Yeah, the playwright.
l thought l recognized you.
Glad to meet you.
l´ve always been an admirer.
-And this is Eddie Burns.
-Pleased to meet you, l´m sure.
Join us, Louie. We´re having a drink
and trying to figure out where to go.
You look like a man of the world, sir.
Maybe you can help me persuade Mr. Engle
that show business needs men like him.
New money, new actors, new ideas.
That´s what the theater needs, Mr. Engle.
You smile, sir...
...because you think
l´m talking through my hat.
Nonsense.
Let me repeat, Mr. Engle.
For $30,000, you´ll get one half of the play.
For a paltry $30,000,
you can come backstage...
...whenever you like and see the men
pull the curtain up and down.
l´m not in the mood for business tonight.
l´m trying to have some fun, Mr. Gibbons.
Fine. Excellent.
Beautifully said.
That´s what we´re all trying to do,
Mr. Engle, have some fun.
-Am l right, Mr. Artino?
-Sure.
We ought to take care of your friend, Bill.
Yeah, l was telling him
about the club upstairs.
lt´s a sort of private little affair.
We happen to be having a meeting tonight.
Just a get together for a few friends.
l was telling him we might drop in,
if it´s not too late.
Not at all. Come on up, Mr. Engle.
Always glad to entertain
any friend of Bill O´Brien.
Thanks.
l´m glad to have met you, Mr. Gibbons,
and you, miss.
l hope you put your deal over.
See you later.
You were wonderful. l knew you would be.
Never mind about me,
l´m playing a percentage.
lt´s all right, Mr. Gibbons, they´ve gone.
What do you mean, ´´it´s all right´´?
He ain´t acting. He´s out cold.
Come on, Engle, give me a lift.
l´m all right, thanks.
Ain´t Grand Central Station,
but it´s big enough for me.
Everything is going to be all right.
-Where´s that Engle?
-Here.
-Now, you understand your part, my boy?
-Yes.
Little man against the fates.
They will deal you hope off the bottom
and let you win at first...
...then you get up and slither off.
Tell them you´re coming back.
You´ve got to see me.
Your friend is very drunk, dangerous,
might set fire to the hotel.
Who knows?
They´ll think, as they watch you go,
´´He´ll come back´´...
...but you flee.
You´ll live happily ever after...
...as l ordered it.
-Mr. Gibbons?
-He´s really out this time.
-The mastermind folds in the stretch.
-Please, he´ll hear you.
He ain´t going to be hearing anything
but pink elephants for some time.
You got a fine pal, Engle.
Passes out on you in the finish.
That´s his trouble as a playwright,
according to the critics.
Starts off fine, then loses track.
l can see what they mean.
Sure lost track of this production.
-Hurry, they´re waiting.
-They´re waiting. l know all about that.
But first, l wanna have a little talk to you.
-You´re going to back out?
-Nobody´s backing out.
l´m willing to help...
...but not on account of the fates
or any of that gabble he pulled.
l write the finish different to him.
l write it over for Bill O´Brien.
l´m in this, but l want a cut.
-A cut?
-Yeah.
Everything you take over $3,000 is mine.
But how can l get any more?
How do you know
how much they´ll throw at you?
l´ve seen as much as $15,000 in one pot.
That hotel owner, they let him win
more than $8,000 before they....
Say, even if it´s only $5,000...
...l take all over $3,000.
Okay?
Sure, that´s all right with me.
All l want is $3,000.
Fine, now there´s some sense
to the whole thing.
Me, sticking my neck out for nothing
and for no reason.
-Are you ready for the lion´s den?
-Yes.
Wait a minute.
lf you only had a fur collar or something.
You sure can´t go in there
with those five-and-ten-cent cuff links.
Take them off.
A fine millionaire you´d look like
with that tin on you.
l didn´t notice
but there´s some guys smarter than me.
Here, put these on. They´re rubies.
lt´s just wasting time.
l´m handling this from now on.
l know what l´m doing.
Those guys got eyes like sharpshooters.
And take off that pushcart tie, partner.
Carvet, $5 a throw.
-Here´s some more props.
-His suit isn´t pressed.
That´s nothing.
They´ll think he´s an eccentric.
Cato´s. Handmade. lt´s a honey, ain´t it?
Here.
Here´s the clincher.
Class, eh?
´´To Gene, my first, last and only.
Harriet, June, 1924.´´
lt´s his wife. She´s suing him
for divorce now, isn´t she?
Hurry, we´re losing time.
´´My first, last and only.´´
lmagine a dame writing that
and meaning it.
No, l suppose you can´t.
Wouldn´t look so hot on a rain check,
would it? Come on.
-Bill.
-What?
-Don´t hate me.
-You´re all right.
l mean, if anything goes wrong.
You just take a powder
and kindly omit flowers.
You´ll be back?
Those are my plans.
-l´m jumping inside.
-Come on, buck up.
lt would be funny, wouldn´t it,
if it turned out like l told you.
We make just as much money
saving a guy´s life...
...as we would have had for trimming him.
Come on.
There´s the stairs.
Keep right on going, all the way down.
Don´t stop for a taxi in front of the hotel.
-lf there ain´t one there, keep on going.
-Yes.
Well, here it is.
Are you ready, diablo?
Hello, Tony. lt´s okay. Come on.
-Hello, Jack. Hello, Eddie.
-Hello, Billy.
Tell Dutch l´m here with Mr. Engle,
will you?
Okay, come on in.
After you, Mr. Engle.
-Mr. Enright, this is my friend Mr. Engle.
-l´m glad to meet you, Mr. Enright.
l´m glad to see you again.
You two know each other?
This is the gentleman
l was telling you about.
-Looking for a little fun?
-l don´t mind.
We got a little club like this back home.
-ls that so? Where´s that?
-ln Cleveland.
Fine town.
-Have a chair.
-Thanks.
lt´s getting kind of late for me.
What time have you got?
1:30, that´s all.
l see you´ve changed your tie.
Yes, you might as well dress up
for a party.
We don´t usually let strangers
into the club...
...but we´re a little shorthanded tonight.
As long as our friend Mr. O´Brien
brought you, it´s okay if you take a hand.
Mr. Engle was worried downstairs
he didn´t have any cash.
l told him that the members
usually play for cash.
No cash?
No, but l got my checkbook with me.
l´ve only used up half of it.
You know the story about the guy
whose bank told him he was overdrawn?
He called up the bank and said,
´´How can that be?
´´l haven´t used up all the checks
in my checkbook yet.´´
You see, he thought he was still rich.
l get it.
-Cleveland, eh?
-Yes.
Cleveland Bank.
No, it´s the New York Bank.
l have money in the New York Bank
and in Cleveland and Chicago.
lt makes it easier
when l´m traveling around.
-All right with you boys?
-Sure, Mr. Engle´s all right.
l guess we´ll take your check.
How much do you want, $5,000?
That´s a little bit steep for a starter.
l mean, l´d rather have...
...$3,000 to begin with.
That ought to be enough to have fun with.
Okay. Here you are.
-You start it, Mac.
-What limit do we play?
Table stakes, Mr. Engle,
and all the fun you want.
That suits me all right.
l got Gibbons into my room finally.
He was out on his feet
when he was talking to you.
Lucky l didn´t bring him.
He was crashing around like a goat.
-Who´s that?
-Mr. Gibbons.
The writer l was telling you about.
Pass.
l open for $100.
l´m in.
Mr. Engle?
-No. Pass.
-ln.
-How many?
-Give me three.
One.
Three.
l bet $500.
Up $500.
l call.
l´m out.
Three queens.
Always beats two pair.
A little action, huh?
Short and sweet.
Regent 4-6-0-7-1.
Hello, who is this?
Hello, Anna.
l want to speak to Mrs. Gibbons, please.
Her husband, tell her.
Hello, sweet. How are you?
Harriet, l´ll tell you, not so good.
l´m drunk, as usual.
At least l think l am. lt´s all mixed up.
l thought l had an idea for a new play...
...but l don´t seem to remember
what it was.
Please, darling, don´t get sore.
l want to talk to you.
l want to come home.
l don´t know, sweet.
Some fish trap as usual.
lt´s a hotel, l guess.
Listen, sweet, l need you.
l want to come home.
l don´t seem to be able to write
anywhere else.
You are sweet.
That´s very kind of you.
No, it´s nothing, dear.
Just a little cold, l guess.
Listen, darling...
...the only warm place l have ever been
is in your heart.
You´re the only light
that didn´t go out on me.
All the others went out.
But not you.
Thank you.
l can find my way home.
l know the way.
Thank you, sweet.
l might have known l wasn´t alone.
You must pardon my bad manners.
l don´t usually run out on a lady,
but l have business in the night.
You remind me of something.
l don´t seem to remember what it was.
This is all very confusing.
l haven´t done anything wrong, have l?
No.
Well, l can find my way home all right.
Thank you.
Goodnight...
...Snow White.
-Where´s he going?
-Home.
He´s walking out? He´s picked a fine time.
No, don´t! lt won´t do any good.
Let him go.
-What happened?
-Nothing.
He doesn´t remember anything.
He´s forgotten.
He didn´t know who l was.
What´s happened in there?
-Everything´s going all right.
-Tell me.
He´s laying back, as per instructions,
waiting for the come-on.
-There´s something wrong?
-No. Nothing´s wrong.
l suppose it´s worth it.
lt´s certainly making money the hard way.
lt´s like being shot out of a cannon.
-Have you ever been to Miami?
-No.
You ought to go swell down there...
...with the celebrities, in a bathing suit.
Who knows?
You may end up with a real tycoon.
Be my luck, just as l´m getting used to you.
Somebody would wave a diamond collar at
you and l´m left alone in the cabana.
What´s that for?
For a nickel, l´d flatten you.
You make me sick
with that phony look in your eyes.
You and Gibbons both grandstanding!
Don´t you try it!
You just be yourself and l´ll be myself, see?
l´m in this for a split.
You´re what you´ve always been,
only this time it ain´t for dimes.
lf you don´t like it, go look for
that last buzzard of yours, Mr. Hugo!
Listen, l´ve got things on my mind.
Cut it out, will you?
Pass.
You´re not getting much of a play,
Mr. Engle.
l guess the deck´s a little cold yet.
-Who´s got a cigarette?
-l´ve got one. Right here.
Thanks.
-Your name ain´t Gene, is it?
-No.
That´s what l thought.
That belongs to Gibbons, don´t it?
Gene Gibbons?
Yes.
Yes, he let me have it.
l guess he wanted to make me feel good,
so l´d put money up on his play.
Deal them already.
Let´s have a little action.
Of course, he was pretty drunk.
ln fact, l´m kind of worried about him.
He looked pretty sick to me.
That play might be...
...a good idea, though, you know?
l understand you only....
l understand you put up only $30,000
for a show...
...and sometimes you make a fortune.
Pass.
Open for $500.
l´m in.
l stay.
Out.
l´ll play.
Pass. How many?
Give me three.
One.
l didn´t hear you. How many?
-One card, please.
-There you are.
Check.
lt´s up to you, Mr. Engle.
Well, l´ll bet all l´ve got.
There´s $2,500 there, l think.
Pass.
-l´m out.
-That´s a pretty good bet.
l thought we could bet
as much as we wanted.
Sure. That´s right.
$2,500, eh?
Your call, Mr. Engle.
-What have you got?
-l have three aces and a pair of sevens.
Beats a flush, your pot.
That deck´s not so cold now, eh?
No, it looks like
they´re beginning to run for me.
l pulled in that extra seven,
or you would have beaten me.
-Like a drink?
-Thanks.
Looks like we´re beginning
to have some real action.
-Pass.
Mr. Engle.
Pass.
-Open for $200.
-l´ll play.
l´m passing.
-Play.
-Pass.
-Cards?
-l´ll play these.
Dealer takes one.
Go ahead and bet them.
Bet $2,000.
-What you got?
-A straight, queen high.
Good pot.
You´re right, Mr. Engle,
they´re beginning to run.
l´ll keep my winnings separate.
lt looks like l´m going to be here
for quite a while, so...
...if you don´t mind,
l´d like to take a look at my friend...
...Mr. Gibbons, before l settle down.
Where is he?
He´s just down the hall,
in Mr. O´Brien´s room.
l´m kind of worried
about how he´s getting along.
He looked a little bit sick to me. So...
...l wonder if you´d mind
dealing me out a couple of hands.
Sure, it´s all right
if you want to go take a look.
Yes, it´s sort of on my mind.
-lt´s all right if l leave this here, l suppose.
-Sure.
l´m probably losing a lot of money
by stepping out, even for a few minutes...
...but l´ll show you some real playing
when l get back.
What´s the matter? You lost?
l forgot the number of the room.
lt´s 1020. That´s it, right there.
Yes, that´s right.
-Get out of here quick, you sap.
-l can´t.
-Got the money?
-Yes.
-Get down the steps!
-The big one´s there.
-Eddie?
-Yeah.
-So he tailed you, huh?
He was right behind me.
l didn´t notice him at first,
l couldn´t get rid of him.
-How much you got?
-$3,000.
-No more?
-No, that´s all.
l had to leave the rest on the table,
l couldn´t take it.
That´s swell.
That´s fine.
Grabbed it all for yourself, huh?
A lot of good you´ll get out of it.
-Will he go away?
-Not him.
What can l do?
Wait a minute.
l got to figure this out, see where l stand.
l got the money.
-l got the money here.
-Shut up, will you?
-You´ve got to go back into that game.
-No.
That guy out there is a killer.
He´ll beat your brains out if you lam.
-l´ve got to take a chance--
-What about me?
-You know what they´ll do?
-Let me go!
Go where?
They´ll murder you and me.
What´s in it for me?
-They´ll punch me silly--
-There´s a fire escape l can get down.
You´re not going to get out
and leave me behind.
-l´m going out and call Eddie.
-No.
l´ll tell him you´re a phony
and l took a tumble.
You tried to get out and l stopped you.
lt´s my only chance.
-No!
-What do you mean, ´´no´´?
-You´re not gonna do it.
-Why not?
-You don´t want to.
-l don´t want to?
l wanna get my insides kicked out?
-Where´s Mr. Gibbons?
-He went away.
-Bill.
-He´s gone?
-Please, listen.
-Never mind. He did his best.
-l guess l´m just not lucky.
-You give up quick, don´t you?
l don´t give up. But what can l do?
Nothing.
Look, just listen to me.
There´s only one way to play it.
-Cut out that Gibbons stuff, will you?
-lt´s not Gibbons, it´s me.
l can tell you don´t want to give him away.
l know what you want to do.
Why don´t you do it?
You´ve been calling me names all night.
l didn´t answer because it´s too easy.
Anyway, the names are all true.
Yes, they´re all true.
l´m just somebody you picked up in a cafe,
that´s all l´ve ever been.
You´re the same kind of nobody.
We´re all nickels and dimes,
you, me and Engle.
l knew it wouldn´t turn out right.
l mean, when we were dancing.
l knew, because there are some people
that never make money or get anywhere.
That´s us.
But, Bill...
...l don´t know how to say it.
There´s other ways of making good.
Bill, why can´t we just once
pretend we´re big shots?
Come on.
Let´s play it like big shots.
Just once.
Go on, open the window.
-lt´s stuck.
-l´ll get it open.
-lt´s too late.
-Hurry up!
Who´s there?
Me, Eddie.
Bill, keep him out there a minute.
Hello, Eddie.
They´re waiting for him.
Who, Engle? He´s all right.
He´ll be coming right out.
Boss said l should hang onto him.
Thought he was copping a sneak.
No, he´s all right.
He told me he´s going back there
and clean up $100,000.
You salted him good.
He said he´s just been sitting back
watching the play.
Boss said to get him and bring him back.
Before you go in, l want to talk to you
about something, personally.
What about?
You know this guy Gibbons in there.
The fellow with the D.T.´s.
He writes shows.
-You´ve heard of him, ain´t you?
-What about him?
He´s writing this show about prize fighters.
That´s why l brought him over.
l figured to introduce him to you,
and you could give him some material.
Now, what l want to know is,
will you split with me if l introduce you?
Nothing doing.
You can tell him about when you killed
the guy in the ring, remember?
Ace Johnson.
That´s the time.
That´s the stuff he likes, dramatic.
You´ve got a lot of stuff like that.
You can tell him about--
So, that´s what?
Engle went down the fire escape.
Go downstairs, cut him off.
l´ll take care of this guy.
Next time l see you, it´ll be the Tombs.
Twenty days. Take him away.
Next case.
Charles Engle.
This man was picked up in a gunfight,
Your Honor.
We found $3,000 on him.
-Who was shooting?
-The other fellow.
-Got away, huh?
-We´re after him.
What are you doing carrying $3,000?
Don´t you know this is New York?
Your Honor, you see,
the money doesn´t belong to me.
lt belongs to Mr. Hopper. Joseph Hopper.
-You can call him up.
-What´s his number?
Union 2-3-1-2.
Hello.
Yeah, this is Mr. Hopper.
Who?
l want to ask you a few questions,
and l want straight answers.
l wanna know
if you know a fellow named Engle.
ls that so?
Now just a minute. Yeah, we got him.
l want to ask you this:
He´s got a little money on him,
he says belongs to you.
lt does, eh?
How much would you say it was?
$3,000.
lt´s mine. Ask him, he´ll admit.
l´m waiting for it. lt´s from the business.
lt´s mine, every penny.
That´s fine.
Yeah, l´ll wait here.
Tell him from me, l´m glad.
lt stopped raining for a change.
A lot of good rain does.
$3, all night in the rain.
l ask you, what´s a guy living for?
Here, keep the change, buddy.
lt´s your turn to get rich.
You feel better now, don´t you?
-Yeah, l feel fine.
-lt doesn´t hurt so much anymore...
...does it?
l guess l´ll go then.
l guess you don´t need me anymore.
For what?
One beating a night is plenty for me.
-lf you want my phone number, l--
-l don´t want anything.
l´m sorry you feel this way.
Really, l am.
l´m sorry for only one thing:
l butted into your romance with Mr. Hugo.
Otherwise we´d have both been
where we belong.
And better off.
You can´t be nice, can you?
Even if you want to.
You´re afraid you won´t seem
like a wise guy if you´re nice.
Okay, Mr. O´Brien.
Something wonderful happened tonight.
l´ll remember it for a long time.
When things don´t seem so wonderful...
...l´ll remember Mr. Gibbons
and Mr. Engle...
...and you.
And that people aren´t really mean.
They can be better than they are
if they want.
lf they´ll let themselves.
Even if it doesn´t last.
They can be better than they are.
So long.
-That will be $35 out of $50.
-Keep the change.
Hey, you seven!