It's almost new.
Three hundred cartridges.
The guy who
gave it to me said...
you can hit
as far as three kilometers.
How much are you asking
for all of this?
One thousand dirhams.
One thousand dirhams?
I'll give you five hundred.
And a goat.
With this rifle, your sons
will kill plenty of jackals.
Here, let one of your boys try.
Let Yussef shoot.
Dad, I want to shoot first.
This is the safety.
Push it in when you're ready.
If he doesn't hit the jackals,
at least he'll scare the shit out of them.
Your turn Yussef.
He shoots better than you.
Good luck,
have a good day.
God bless you.
Kill at least three jackals.
Make sure no one
sees you with the rifle...
if you see someone coming, hide it.
What are you doing?
I told you,
don't spy on her.
What do you care?
Move it.
Five to two.
There's a jackal.
Where?
Over there.
What are you doing,
you idiot?
Zohra doesn't mind.
She doesn't, but I do.
This is between her and me.
You're both pigs.
Next time I'm going to tell Dad.
Stay out of this.
If you want me to stay out of it,
don't do it.
What are you doing?
Hassan said this bullet
could reach three kilometers.
That rock didn't move.
You don't know how to shoot.
Give me the rifle.
See.
Yeah, but that's not
three kilometers.
I bet the bullet
can't hit that far.
These bullets are lame.
You're not aiming right.
What'll you give me
if I hit that car?
I'll shoot.
You see? Nothing.
Let me shoot.
Shoot at it.
See... nothing.
You're right, they're useless.
Where are these kids?
Where are you?
I'm coming to get you...
You win.
Did you brush your teeth?
Sleep with angels, my darling.
Sleep well, sweetie.
You are already sharing a room...
didn't we agree
to sleep with the lights off?
There's nothing to be scared of.
No, that won't happen to you.
How can I be
in two places at once?
I'm just asking you
to take them for today.
I can't, the mister is still home.
And they aren't going out?
No, I don't think so.
Okay, I'll talk to you later.
I can't Amelia.
Please, it's my son's wedding.
Just for the day, Lucia.
I'll be back for them tonight.
And what do I say to Mrs. Catherine?
I don't know.
Tell her they're your nephews.
Right, because they look
so much like me...
with my American looking face!
What's up?
Hi Auntie.
Great to see you, Santiago.
They're really shy.
What? These kids
are coming with us?
I couldn't find anyone to watch them.
Their parents won't return tonight.
Why bring them?
They'll drive you crazy.
Don't worry,
they're very good kids.
Don't you want to
leave them with somebody?
I know a girl who
can take care of them.
Are you crazy?
I have to take them with me.
I can't leave them
with just anybody.
Are you sure, Auntie?
The ball was out.
That was out.
No, it was good.
I'm deaf, not blind.
You're out.
You shouldn’t have lost your temper.
We lost the game.
It wasn't my fault,
it was the ref.
If you hadn't been thrown out,
we would’ve won the game.
Why are you
in a bad mood?
She's always in a bad mood
because nobody's fucked her yet.
I'm gonna fuck your dad
to get rid of my mood.
I'll see you at the J-Pop.
What do you want to eat?
I said I'd meet my friends
from the team at J-Pop.
Didn't you tell me
we would have lunch together?
Dad, I told you I was
going to eat with them.
You never pay attention to me.
My mother always
paid attention to me.
Why do you want to fight?
I miss your mother too.
I'm doing the best I can.
Don't forget
the dentist at three.
Take care.
Do you have a table?
Why all the way in the corner?
Isn't the view nice?
Do you like him?
Hello.
Can I play with you?
Or you can
have a drink with us?
Tell him to speak slowly.
Can you say that
a little slower?
You assholes,
how embarrassing.
What's the matter?
They look at us
like we're monsters.
Oh, come off it.
What are you doing?
Now they're going to meet
the real hairy monster.
Don't forget your appointment
with the dentist. Papa.
I have to go.
I'll see you at your place, then.
What are you doing here?
Something we ate
gave us a stomach ache.
The goats will die
if they don't eat.
Wash your face
and take them out again.
My stomach hurts.
There are other
chores to do then.
Move it. Let's go.
God bless. Bye, bye.
Thank you,
I'll see you tomorrow.
Tell your mother
to prepare dinner.
Did you kill any jackals?
We shot at them,
but didn't hit any.
You have to kill them.
If not, they're going to eat all the goats.
Why did you come home late?
They closed the road,
we took the long way.
Apparently some terrorists
killed an American tourist.
An American?
Yes, the terrorists attacked
a tour bus on the road.
No, there aren't any terrorists here.
You never know.
How do you know
the American died?
That's what they were saying.
The police are looking for the culprits.
Yes, this is Mexico.
Yeah... it's full of Mexicans.
Don't talk like that.
It's not true.
How wonderful, you made it.
You decided to bring them?
Hey, what's up?
Oh, son, look how handsome.
You look like Julio Preciado.
Forget Julio Preciado,
he looks like Luis Miguel.
These are the kids
I take care of.
Say hi to Luis.
Lucio, come here.
This is Mike and Debbie.
Take them to play.
Mom, I don't know how you did it,
but it zipped up perfectly.
And it's been 15 years
since I wore this dress.
You haven't changed a bit, Ma.
Working dear, hard work...
that's what keeps you young.
What are you guys laughing about?
Nothing Ma, nothing.
I'll give a buck to the first
who catches a chicken.
Careful with the 'huevos.'
Very good, Debbie got one.
Debbie's the winner.
Okay, now we need another five.
So we have five chickens here.
Okay, now who's going to help me?
You? Okay, come.
Hold it tight, like this.
Grab it right.
Everyone back up...
give me some room.
I need your phone.
I will pay.
The bullet didn't
touch her spine.
If she stays like this,
she will bleed to death.
Is there anything
we can do?
I have to stitch up the wound
to stop the bleeding.
And tell him
her clavicle is broken.
We have to
hold her down.
Here are the sterilized drill bits.
You have cavities
in two molars.
What are you doing?
What's wrong with you?
Get out.
Get out right now.
Yes, I'll let him know.
That's Mr. Wataya's daughter.
Thank you.
Are you Yasujiro Wataya's daughter?
She's deaf-mute...
Face her when you speak
so she can read your lips.
Are you Yasujiro Wataya's daughter?
We are Yoshjo Hamano and Kenji
Mamiya of the Metropolitan Police.
We would like
to see your father.
No, it's nothing bad.
We just want to talk to him.
Do you know
where he is?
Please tell him to call.
Don't be scared.
We just want to talk to him.
Thank you.
Chieko, I waited for you.
I have a meeting so I'll be back late.
I left you a bento box. Papa.
I'm on my way to your place.
Where are you?
Hurry up!
Moroccan officials
are investigating suspects...
in the shooting of
an American tourist.
Officials said the shooting
took place...
Are you ready?
Yeah, I'm just going to get my bag.
The cops came again?
Yeah. They hadn't come in nine months.
But these were different cops.
Did they come to ask
about your mother's death?
No, but they're probably going
to ask my dad about the same things.
They're just not convinced,
are they?
Believe it or not,
I liked one of the cops.
Idiot.
Did you put on some panties?
Are you sure
it was here?
An American stopped me.
I was scared.
He was covered in blood.
Where was the bus stopped?
Over there.
Captain Alarid... Captain Alarid.
I found cartridges.
We found four.
Here's one.
Did you search all over?
Yes, the whole mountain.
They're from around here.
Find out who has
a .270 caliber rifle.
Hassan Ibrahim?
-Yes.
-Drop your weapon.
I don't have a weapon.
Drop it now.
I told you to drop
your weapon.
This is just my knife.
Get on the ground.
What did we do?
Get down on the ground...
face down.
Don't look at me.
What did we do?
Take these skins to Najib,
see if he wants to buy them.
Why did you shoot at the bus?
I didn't shoot at anyone.
Then who?
It wasn't me.
That was your rifle.
I sold it yesterday.
Who did you sell it to?
Do you know where
Abdullah Adboum lives?
Yes.
You have to go over those mountains.
Who lives
in this area?
We live here with our mother.
Abdullah lives on the other side.
If you're lying, I'm going to
come back and cut your balls off.
You can come back
anytime you llke.
Don't walk
between the graves.
Papa... Papa...
What happened?
The pollce...
they're looking for you.
Me? Why?
No, not for you...
they're looking for us.
Looking for you?
Why?
Because of the tourist.
What tourist?
The American...
Yussef killed her.
Liar, we both did.
What are you saying?
Yussef started shooting
at the cars...
because Hassan said
that the bullet could go far.
Liar, you started shooting at the cars.
But you killed her.
What are you saying?
Yussef killed the American
and he spies on Zohra naked...
and Zohra lets him watch her.
That's garbage.
It's not garbage.
She's a street girl and he spies on her.
Time to drink!
This song is dedicated
from Luis to Patricia...
the most beautiful bride
in the world.
I think Aunt Amella has to dance.
Amella, can I have this dance?
I don't think your wife
would llke that.
Ohh, she passed away 10 years ago.
Come on Amella.
Let's go dance... You have
something white on your face.
Don't get excited,
it's only cake.
Today, near Tazarine,
there was an incident.
An American was shot.
Authorities say it
could have been a robbery.
But, the American government was
quick to suggest a terrorist llnk.
Minister Hassan HazaI
has said...
that terrorist cells have been
eradicated in our country...
and one act
of vulgar banditry...
followed by superficial evaluations
the U.S. places on it...
cannot ruin our image
or the economy.
You have to turn on the
air-conditioning, my husband is ill.
No air-conditioning,
no gasollne near. I'm sorry.
Please, it's too hot.
We can get dehydrated.
Who are they?
My cousins.
Is he deaf-mute
llke us?
No, but he understands some.
What is your name?
Chieko.
My name's Haruki.
It's whisky.
Do the cops come around here?
Sometimes.
You smell good.
Welcome home... may I help you?
Are you sure
you want him to come now?
Is this Detective Mamiya?
The deaf-mute girl you met this
afternoon asked me to call.
Yes, her.
She says she needs to talk to you,
alone... about her father.
Why did you do this?
Answer me, damn it!
We were testing the rifle.
Are you idlots?
You killed a woman.
And you....
You got naked
so your brother could watch?
Zohra got naked lots of times
so Yussef could watch her.
Is it true or not?
Why did you do this to us?
Where's the rifle?
I told you,
a hunter gave it to me.
What hunter?
A Japanese hunter...
gave it to me.
I've got a picture.
She can get it.
Go get it.
He's holding the rifle
he gave me.
We're going to Najib's house.
If the cops come,
tell them we went south.
This Abdullah doesn't llve
in the area you told us.
Are you playing with us?
He llves in the area
he told you.
He llves there?
You're going to take us.
They're over there.
The pollce, the pollce.
Run... run.
Get down.
Mom, stay here tonight.
I can't, I have to get these kids home.
It's almost dawn.
But this fucking guy
is really drunk.
Drunk my ass. I'm fine.
I'll be right back.
Stay a llttle whlle,
the party's just starting.
I would llke to, but these kids
have soccer practice tomorrow.
See you soon, Son.
Congratulations, my darllng.
Take care of my grandchlld.
I'm dying to be a grandmother.
Seriously, you're not drunk man?
Drunk my ass.
I'm fine. I'll be back.
Remember, they got you once already
and you got in a lot of trouble.
Bye, Ma...
If things don't work here,
I'll meet you with the 'gringos.'
Hey, be careful.
I'll cross the border
through Tecate...
that will get us to
San Diego super fast.
Don't say anything.
Let me do the talking.
But you're provoking him.
I was just kidding.
What now?
Motherfucker...
What's that?
I heard you... stop shouting.
Don't shout at me.
Stop shouting at me.
Easy Santiago, please.
What are you doing?
What are you doing, Santiago?
What are you doing!
See, I told you!
You shouldn't have brought them.
Santiago, stop acting llke a
madman and stop the car.
Please, Santiago, stop!
Shut those kids up!
Shut them up!
Please stop, Santiago.
Motherfuckers, fucking gringo assholes,
here they come.
Get out. Get out.
Are you crazy? Where?
Get out. If they catch us,
we're all screwed...
I'll lose them,
then come back for you.
Get out, for Christ sake!
Santiago, calm down.
Aunt Amella, get out...
for the love of God!
Santiago is going to
come back soon and...
the sun is going to rise.
Why can't you call
another ambulance?
They just told me
the ambulance isn't coming.
And you know we don't
have another ambulance.
He wants to know how
he will get his wife out of here.
Tell him they said
his embassy will deal with it.
The Americans
stopped the ambulance.
They want to send a hellcopter,
but there are problems.
Good evening.
The doorman called to say
you wanted to talk to me.
I don't understand.
could you speak slowly?
I'm sorry.
What was it
you wanted to tell me?
Do you have tea?
"My father had nothing to do
with my mother's death."
What's this?
When your mother jumped off the
balcony, your father was asleep?
You saw her jump?
You've already told the other officers?
What are you talking about?
Does your father still hunt?
There was an incident involving a rifle
in your father's name.
That's why we want to talk to him.
Understand?
Your father isn't going to jall.
We just need to talk to him.
I have to go.
I really have to go.
What are you doing?
Please stop.
No, this is wrong.
You're just a girl.
Enough, stop it!
Give me that rifle.
They're going to kill us.
I killed the American. I was the
only one who shot at you.
They did nothing... nothing.
Kill me, but save my brother, he did
nothing... nothing.
Save my brother...
he did nothing.
They're alone.
They are chlldren,
they will die.
There's no need to apologize.
Mr. Wataya, this officer
has been looking for you.
Good evening, I'm Lieutenant Mamiya.
Good evening, how can I help you?
Sir, there was an incident and...
I'm sorry to bother you, but...
do you own a .270 callber
Winchester M70 rifle?
Registration number...
UK-9023.
I don't remember the number,
but I did have a rifle llke that.
Is it true that you gave that rifle
to a Mr. Hassan Ibrahim...
who llves in Morocco?
Hassan Ibrahim?
He says he was
your guide in a hunt.
Hassan? Yes,
I remember him well.
He was a good guide and a very
good man, I gave him the rifle in thanks.
Did anything happen?
That rifle was used
in an attempted murder...
and the Moroccan pollce want
to confirm it's not off the black market.
No, I gave it to him.
Is Hassan ok?
I don't know about that.
Am I legally involved?
Not for the moment, but can you
come down to the station tomorrow?
I have a few questions.
Can I leave now?
Good night.
Excuse me.
I heard from your daughter...
about your wife on the balcony.
I'm very sorry.
What balcony?
About how your wife killed herself
by jumping off the balcony.
My wife never jumped off a balcony.
She shot herself in the head.
My daughter was the first to find her.
I've explained it
to the pollce many times.
Don't bother us with that anymore.
I'm very sorry sir, we won't
bother you anymore.
Good night.
Another shochu.
Susan Jones, who was wounded
in a terrorist attack in Morocco...
was discharged from a Casablanca
hospital this morning, local time.
The American people finally have
a happy ending, after five days...
of frantic phone calls
and hand wringing.
In other news...