As we end up here?
This place is horrible
Smells like hell
We do not belong to this hole fucking
Hey Sam
Popeá... what kind of, shut up!
- Hello cari—
What type of flowers you said
you wanted to?
Camellias, are something that smells good
You know?
Something that...
- All sounds like Kim Chi
Ok, then something that is
looks good, what is less roses
Hate to make this work
Ok
Riggan all the note I for 1-4
they are ready for you
Riggan are ready for you
Oh hello friend, as these?
Well, you already know
I would go better if I could do
Ralph leaveá
Act
Beá well
Screaming, I love you, I love you
Bitch
You do with a love like that?
As that is... that is not love
And t what you know, because you insist
calling it love?
You can say what you want
But I know what that was
That there are of you?
That sounds like love to you?
Lametón be late
Look, I'm the person to equivocad
to whom to ask
I've only known this as well from last
Not sabría
You need to know the details, but I think
that what you say is
Love is all
If
The kind of love of which I speak is
That guy in the you're not trying to
kill people
It was love, seriously, what was
I don't care what they say
...l was ready to die for it
Pregntale or did
after that dejó
Got a shot in the mouth but
also what did he do wrong
Poor head
Poor head, my balls
The guy was dangerous
As he did so bad if they are shot
in the mouth?
Solía carry a 22-gauge solíamos live
as fugitives, then
Ralph, Ralph, Ralph
The fugitives are afraid
Están on the run
So many times we have to
You may give me a little más that?
Fear
It is a great idea
We live as fugitives
at that time
Never sabía if saldría
detrás bush
Or a car and you start to shoot,
the man was crazy
It was capable of everything
Christ, that nightmare
If
Solía call me at the hospital
And decía, "son of a bitch
Your days are numbered.Ò
It was too much?
I pass I realize because
I just want to give you a range
Someone call 911
This breathing?
That pasó, where salió?
To dónde are you going?
Someone call emergency
- Let's call the ambulance
That beingá a demand
- Ok, dónde are you going?
We have to be ready
in 5 minutes
You will needás to forget it
we have to cancel
But we are exhausted tendríamos
to reimburse all the...
Just do it
- That step?
As the está Ralph?
Beá well
- Wait, wait
You may expect?
- Escchame
Without exagerares the worst actor
I've seen in my life
The blood coming out of his oídos is what
más creíble that has been done up to now
It is not so bad
Ok, it's terrible
But listen t you don't have to
press in your walk-in closets
I do not know what they diré
- Well, we veré to do
Waiting
That was not an accident
What do you mean?
I did that happen
Oh ok
These drunk?
Only encuéntrame an actor
a good one
Kenny...?
- Willy Harris
Está doing The Hunger Games
Michael Fassbender
- Está doing X-Men
Such Jeremy Reynold?
Who?
- Jeremy Reynold
He was nominated
It is an interesting type
- This is an adventure
Crap, I have Him also?
I can't believe it
I don't care, just find
someone
Ralph we sueá
What hará and has a case
Just make it go away
Look, you're my lawyer
You're my producer, my best friend
Truth? Now
Go and do what you were born
to make
I don't care cómo, just go
And as you expect it to do so?
That clown has neither the
half of your talent
And you are earning a fortune in that
costume tin man
You are the real thing, Riggan
Ok...
- What we had all
What regalaste
You gave these fakers keys
of the kingdom
Breathe...
- Listen to Me?
Inhale and exhale
If
Acéptalo
But you know that I do not iré
You know I have razón
Look at that
These people do not know what
you are able to
Because someone iría to be the hero
in a franchise of comics
Act of Raymond Carver
in the scenario
As you probably know
Barthes said that the cultural work done
in the past
By gods and demigods
Now it is done in the commercial
detergent
And people of strips of comics
If it is, absolutely
Absolutely
You know?
As you said
That
Barthes said
Go to Birdman as Icaro
Ok, wait, wait
Who is this such Barthes
In that Birdman was?
Roland Barthes was a French filósofo
And if you knew something of the
story of the century...
Now, it is true that you've been
injecting semen of pigs bebés?
Apology?
- As a topic of facial rejuvenation?
Where leíste that?
He was sent to Twitter by
"Whispers of PróstataÒ
It is not true
- What sé, but what did you do?
Not, I did not
- Ok
You say that is not true
- Then don't you deny it
Writeán that is,
why you write something?
I don't...
Do not write what she said
I did not do it, I haven't got
Pigs bebés...
These aware that the people dirá
that harás this work
To fight against the impresión that
you are an actor forgotten...
Absueltamente not, absolutely not
that is why
20 years atrás
I negué to make Birdman 4
Birdman 4?
Harás Birdman 4?
Thanks, can come in,
thank you, thank you
Wait for good works
The boys of advertising
Want a movie that is the
worst idea right now
That you are doing?
- I don't want to see this
That was a gift from the team
Don't mess with those guys
Are the union
- I don't care
As I was?
Well
They talked about Ralph?
What I did, you know?
The bastard did it
To sue us even
I hope to get out of the hospital
That you said?
- I said?
If
- I said hey bastard
I threats?
I swear that if I get though
whether a letter of attorney
The press receiveá imágenes
of your computer, that I said
Imágenes?
Him like the nuns
In pañales
That matter to you?, Not deberías know
nothing of that anyway
The point is that I did everything
this disappeared
True, that's great
YES, it is fantáforecast
Except one thing
- That?
We don't have an actor
And if we cancel the first preview
The press sniffá blood
And we can't afford to
miss más money
For nothing
- Ok
Who do you think you should do?
Well we hired a practitioner,
usémoslo
Riggan escchame for the love of God
Listening
Our actor soñado not to touchá
that door and dirá
ÒHey friends when I start?Ò
Can I speak to you a second?
If that happens?
Did you find another actor?
Not
- Ok
Well, Mike is available
What is?
- Mike what?
Pensé I was doing...
- What was the...
What dejó or he was fired
Michael who?
- That was resignation or dismissal?
He said that the two
- Mike who?
Seiner
- If!
Jake...
- God mío, as you know it?
We share a vagina
You think you want to do that?
As you know it?
- Because I said that quería
Jake, Jake
Pregntame if you sell tickets
The sells tickets?
- Sell tickets as fuck
Now pregntame if the critical
the theatre is love
The critical love him?
- Want to sleep with the
Hey
Can't live without the
- All for a razón, no?
You can come this afternoon?
- What llamaré to know
Call your agent
Annie, clean theaters
Addressed to all dinner
And give me something of lights
We have something good tonight
Who is it?
Because it really
Intimidating, no?
Do you have any idea of the people who have
walked in these tables
Before your
Geraldine Page, Hellen Haze
Jason Robardson
Marlon Brandon and now
Riggan Thomson
Thank you for coming so soon
Mike I really appreciate it
This is what I do
Your wrote this?
- If
Además want to go, and proceedings in this
It is ambitious
Well, thank you
Good
It is a good theater
I can't speak for your work but
Let's do a bit of it, yes?
Oh, I don't expect that you commit...
- The preview is mañana, let's work
Ok, good
Siéntete free to make the script
- No, only
Let's make something out of it
Well, ok
Hey échale a look at the
página 20
I'm fine, I don't need this
Why?
- I don't need the script
Just give me an entry
- What are you talking about?
Give me a line
Cómo?
- Give me a line
Ok, está well
Ok
Déjame think
If
Hey I'm the wrong person
to whom to ask
Ok? I don't conocía man
Just listen to his name, number
Not what is
Do not listen to the details, but
I think what you say
Is that the love all
That is what I'm saying? I say that
love is all?
Yeah, ok, yes!
The kind of love that I speak
It is absolute
Not trying to kill people
As you know the lines?
It is one thing that I have, I don't know how
it is a gift
Come on, man, I've been away
of this for a month
Well, they're good
- These lines are...
Well
We go again
- Ok
Look, I'm the wrong person
to whom to ask
Not conocí the man really
Just listen to his name in passing but
Not sé
I do not know the details
I think that what you say is
Can I make a suggestion?
If, if, dale
For nothing
Forget that, just...
- Ok
Quédate with me
- If
I am the wrong person to the
which to ask, He says, but
What is that, which is the intención
in that?
Uncomfortable with the topic for that
what changes?
It mirrors the fault
On the marriage and this is the thing
You have 4 lines
After that
They all say the same thing
I didn't even conocía man
Just listen to his name last
Not sé
I don't know the details
The details, I say
It is something that diría my grandmother but
The point is
You don't know the type
- If
What we understand
Do it work with a single line
Even conocía the type
Well?
- If
Listen, you know my lines also, isn't it?
We can not stay hung
in-line annoying?
If, if
- We can work this
Do well, be
Then dámelo again but
córtalo, inténtalo
Ok
Hey I am not the right person to ask
- Oh, no, but that is the thing
You see? I am the right person to ask
then that is
To which I say? Fuck you, go to the
shit I don't put yourself in that place
Don't make me feel consents
about my marriage
While my wife is sitting
same here!
If
I can sit?
- If, siéntate
Good idea
If
- Then dámelo as vetea fuck
Trátalo, we will
If
- Only hagámoslo
Come on, dámelo cógeme strong
Come on, don't talk, just say so
you are the wrong person
Wow, not even conocía the
man, ok?
Cuál is your point?
Cuál is my point?
- If, cuál is your point?
That you say? Escpelo
That you say?
That you say? The love
it is absolute?
If, if!
The kind of love that I speak
It is absolute
You don't want to
Your not trying to kill people
If, well
I don't know how, what do you think boss?
Ok
- You want to do this
With me?
What do you think?
All have become
It is time to mate
Tomaré that as a yes
Then, who are you t?
Is Sam, my daughter
Your daughter? It is amazing
don't look anything
What will you do?
Is my assistant partial
And
She speaks
And is expressed?
- What makes
Yes, you can even sit
To stay or even roll
if you give him candy
Hey welcome aboard, Mike
Thank you capital andán
I'm Mike Seiner by the way
Be who you are
I saw you at Hot House
At the Geffen
You were great
- Thanks
Your ass is great
Friend
Seriously?
Seeás that I was...
- Larry
Larry
This is the theater cariño not be
so inhibited
This here
It was time to dress this actor
As you have been Larry?.
Well time that these here,
sácate clothing
Let's see...
You only are you going to stop it?
This is the theater will not be
so inhibited
We will need to start
zero
We have less than 24 hours
Take this pruébate
Demons, that pasó?
And t underwear?
Under the bed at home
Not
Ok, ok
Everything is very pequeño
Not bromeas
That is good
Well done Larry like my
son of 5 years
None of the two has clothes
interior clean
Or hair pbico imagine
Ok
Good además of the costume we need to
new trusa and shirt
Among other things
What will you do?
I hope Larry
Finish
And I'm just standing with
my penis outside
Good vístete
The daughter of Riggan está by here
And I don't need to look...
- Lesley
Let Mike do not have always seen this
for here miráby giving us
As a stalker
I...
- I do not know if drugs are
They have fried your brain, or that
But I don't want to go running
his father
Saying that you showed
your package
Then ask deberíamos
go
Oh God, seriously?
Sammy?
- Sam
Sam
- Shit!
Lesley
Listen, when I said that
- Do not worry
It is a lot of work, isn't it?
How is it that you always find a
way to humiliate me?
To be fair you do too fácil
What demons down here?
Brought Me here
And quedó?
- Well it is a little...
Listen To Mike
This is Broadway
And I'm here finally
Now please just do me a favor
I beg of you, don't fuck around
Lesley
See here
Play with my balls
Tendré to go shopping again
Just something about más
- Give him what he wants
Está asking for 4 times what
we pagaos the other
He deserves it, Jake
Since we spend in fog
Casts átrees false
Is a sequence of átrees, Jake
Are dwarves
Don't say that you can't
offend them as well
It has been
Don't you see what I just saw
I can tell you that this type
it's the real thing
I can feel it in my bones
Is the actor that we have been
waiting
Let's just do the contract
please, Jake
I conseguiré the money
Ok, I haré
- Ok
Remove that smile from your face scare me
Sorry
Is it true?
- If
Seriously?
- Fuck
Dónde está?
- Here with Larry right now
Hello chics
I'm going to Starbucks, want something?
- I'm fine, I'm fine
She has a good rear
If, so is
That goes for you also
Look I can not do this now
Seriously
- There came to me two times already
I think that really is going
Good
It is good or bad
Riggan!
- It is good
It's good, it's great
As I gave something more
Ok
Safe is mío?
Well you already know these your
Jake, and recién used condoms
if I believe that it is yours, if
Idiot
These excited?
- If
I also
Why?
You're not funny
Hey
- That?
First preview mañana
Here we go
Music, outside
34, 35
Ready
It was the double of a normal head
- That happens?
It is incredible
- If
I think that drink gin from truth
Why?
Pregntale Nick, I want you to
you ask
Why you think that
Doing what?
Déjame tell you
Déjenme tell you something about
the love of truth
Listen well, all deberíamos
be ashamed
When we speak as if supiéramos
what we are talking about
When we talk about love
For the love of God, you're going
to get drunk?.
I don't have to be drunk
to say what I think
We're not drunk, just a few drinks
- Exact
T have taken más a few
Perhaps these counting?
Déjala in peace, but these drunk
don't talk as if you
Cállate!
Do me a favor, for once
in your life
Honestly, cállate for a moment
In order to
As decía
Speaking of real love
he had a couple of elderly
In an accident on the interstate
Some drunk guy
Stamp the truck of his father
Against the car of the couple
For when he arrives at the hospital
The guy, a fucking teenager
He was dead
So we took the couple of
elderly emergency
And we work like crazy
in them
The greater part of the night
For when
We ended up with them,
us only...
You know, we had právirtually
plastered full body
The husband
The old
I was depressed
For a long time even
after that I said
Look at your wife managed to
'an was depressed
Then
I went to Him and asked
And I said
That was because he could not
See it
In the eyes
It could not be to see his wife
You may imagine
You say
The corazón of this type
rompía because
It could not be flip t damn
head
And see his wife
Fuck
And what was killing
I'm tired of this
- What was killing
Replaced my gin
With water?
No!
We will
- We will qué?
These drunk
- I'm drunk?
Of course I am, it is assumed
I am
Because not estás t?
This is Carver
You leave a piece of your liver on the table
every time you write a fucking page
If I need to drink gin
Who the fuck you are t to
touch it?
Escchame, you get with
the periods
You get with the plot and you can
to have the best line
Déjame the tool that I need
Let people
They are not as patéticos
Stop seeing the world through the
screen your cell
To have an experience of truth
Someone cares about the truth
apart from me?
I say the scenario is false, the plátano
it is fake
There is No fucking in this
cartón of shit
The only thing real that I see in this
scenario
Is this chicken
So trabajaré with the chicken
It was interesting
Lower the telón
This good friend
Sáquenlo of here
As you want to do that?
Hey, wait
What I want out
- Not
What?, We can not do that
Of course we can
It is our show
Escchame
- No, your escchame
Sácalo of my fucking work
I'm not going to stand here
It's crazy, no matter the preview
it doesn't matter until the Times
Sitting here in the night
opening
Get rid of Him, I don't care...
- Only cállate and escchame once
Or well, we announced that the entraría,
sales doubled
In less than a day
We can't afford to lose más money
and much less to Mike
This is about respect and validate
do you remember? That you told me
So I got involved in this shit
You are the director, put it in order, ok?
Fuck
This is no longer the years 90
Your closure está down
Fuck
Friend
Your
You were very good
Hey
See you in the theatre in 10 minutes
- Do not think about it too much
What demons happens it up?
Not sabía that estarías auqui
tonight
That guy is a imbécil
If you do here?
Sam and I go to eat something
after you finish
No, I say, here now
Good
Sé cuát does this mean for you
Oh
Thanks, I appreciate it
Then that happens?
The work? Since the dress
No, you and Sam
Oh
You know, it's great
The same
You spoke with her?
If
We speak
You know, has been a craze here
And...
You understand dónde está your mind?
If of course
She tries to get away from it all
And all that put in rehabilitación
in the first place
If
- Then, you already know
What sé, seriously
What I understand, I understand
But it is all that has taken
- If
This confused
- What I understand
Look sé these gotten
in all of this
But you have to
- Stop?
You know what I mean
Riggan you don't have to be
a great father
Right now
You just have to be one
Oh, I'm sorry
As it going?
I don't want to talk about it
Shots?
I take a beer
Ok
Then
That happens to you?
With me?
- If
Nothing
Everything is the same I guess
Volveré to enseñar
Oh yeah?
Hey
I am thinking of refinancing my
house in Malib
Why? Sorry?
I'm thinking of refinance
- Not
You just needed escuché
a moment
That beingá Sam's house
Why...
For this work?
I need the money
Have you any idea what
crazy that sounds like that?
What can I say? The house duró
más that the money
You already know
That happens
Riggan mírame
I have the opportunity to make
something good
Should I take it
I have to
That's funny I was here
esperándote
And nothing
It could not be recalled because
we ended up
You know the last time I came
here from THE
George Clooney was sitting
Two seats in front of my
Well-dressed
And that mentón speaker
We ended up flying for a
Horrible aerolínea
And He was wrong, trembling
And
When subió on board was
crying, I say
Crying, praying, yes?
I alone senté here
The crying and I sit here
And I thought
Oh go
The próxima mañana
When Sam looks at the periódico
That name looks on the page
front?
The mío not
You know?
You know that Farra Faucett murió the
same day that Michael Jackson?
It's not crazy?
Where we ended up?
Because I threw a knife
kitchen
And a time más late I decías
how much you loved me
You know just because I did not like
that ridícula comedy
With Goldie Hawn's not meant
that is not loved you
Is what you always do
You confuse love with admiración
It's your house, do what you want
with her
Just make sure to be here
for your daughter
What haré
You're not Farra Faucett, Riggan
We had to make this show a reality
they offered us
The Thompsons
Cállate
- It would have been nice
A daughter crazy and addicted to drugs
A wife with nice tits stops
The people would have wanted to
see that
Cállate
- Is más this shit
The sun bed is here
What does that mean?
- Means that
There is a tanning bed it outside
They deliver here in
Who ordered a tanning bed?
Mike says that is part of the development
your character
Fuck
It is a peasant
Son of a bitch
We will
Let us walk
- To dónde are we going?
We're going to take café
I did something for missing the respect?
Not yet
Look, I have a lot bet
in this fucking work
Don't tell me
- If?
People know who I am
And...
- Tonterías
Don't know
Or your work, you know
the type of the work of pájaro
Who goes and tells stories
on Letterman
Sorry not to be popular
- I don't care, popular?
The popularity is the premium slippery
the prestige
Well, I don't know how, nor that shit
does that mean
Take
It means that my reputación está
at stake in this, and it is worth
Much, is worth a lot!
Exact, fuck you
If, if this does not work
You return to your study and your genocide
cultural perpetrate,
A imbécil is born every minute
That said inventó the circus
And not much has changed, if they get
some shit.
The people hará line and payá view
But long after you've gone
I estaré in that scenario
Ganándome life
Loading my soul
Struggling with emotions
complex human
That haré
- Then
If, that is trató all?
Struggles with complex emotions?
We are going is not the great thing, Riggan,
in New York we do things well
Adónde are you going?
Have coffee here
Thanks Tommy
Is reían in my damn face
- This night is reían
Mañana what mayán on Twitter
That will be the shit,
who cares?
This is the people that pay half of
price to see us rehearse
Stops..
- This is a drama
Will Raymond Carver
You don't know that it is
this work
You don't know
For this reason they are the previews
That's why they are called previews
Here is where you realize
what is the work
I say
Ok, look, look
Escchame
You see the woman in the end
of the bar?
It seems that the lamio
back to a pauper?
If
The only thing that matters
Is what she writeá in 500 words,
it is...
Tabitha Dickenson, if
And créelo or not
The only opinión that matter
In the theatre of New York is yours
If you like us
We continue to
If this is not so, we're screwed
If it seems that you lamió the rear
a hobo
Do me a favor
Don't aloques by a damn
preview
In something as well, and don't tell me
as does my work
This is my city
And to be honest
People don't care
a shit here
You are Riggan Thomson, isn't it?
We importaría taken a
photo with us?
No, No
- Thanks
We importaría?
Why?
- The botón está down
Who is this guy?
- Solía be Birdman
Ok
Great
That handsome, thanks
It is very sweet
- Thanks
Handsome
We will
We are already good?
It is time to go home
Well, I see you mañana
I want to know something
Why Raymond Carver?
Had a guy
In the secondary
During a work
I was in the audience
And the
Envió this back
After
Thanks for a good presentación
Ray Carver
- If
If?
So it's like I knew that it would be
an actor
Same here
That is so funny?
Nothing, it is just a cocktail napkin
- Yes, and?
I was drunk
You're going to Hollywood, Mike?
Not
No, Hollywood comes here, Tabi
Good luck with that
A man becomes
a critical
When you can't be an artist
In the same way that a man
it becomes an informant
When you can't be a soldier
Flaubert, no?
Is a clown of Hollywood
in a suit, expensive
If, what is
But mañana after 8
Pay offá on that stage
to risk everything
That harás t?
You're not concerned that you of a
bad criticism
Insurance harás
If I give you a bad presentación
Ms. Dickenson
Mr. Seiner
Hey
- Hey
Do you even here?
Nothing
Your costumes están the dressing room
Great
- Conseguí coconut water that querías
If you want to do another thing... why?
I'm not sure
I said thanks
Why?
- For all
I mean, you've been doing for a
good job
And you already know
Honestly
I've been so worried
With all...
- If
Ok, good
Only quería say that
Why is that?
That smell
What is it?
Mírame
Mírame!
- That?
Why?
Come on, you must be kidding
Papá
- Where is?
We can not do this please?.
Papá
Dónde está?
I can't believe it
Why is this?
Butter maní
This, this
Why is this?
Is marijuana
Reláfeast
Reláfeast?
You may not like this to me
To you?
- Cállate, you know what I'm talking about
If you talk about it
No, don't do that thing
Don't think in my
I try to do something that is
important
This is not important
It is important for my
Ok?
Déjalo to your friends cínicos
Whose only ambitions
It is to be viral but
For my
This is
God mío, this is my career
It is my opportunity to do something
that really amount
Will amount to who?
You had a career, papá
Before the third movie of the comic
The people empezó to forget who I was
in this disguise of pájaro
Do a work-based
in a book
Writing for the past 60 years
For people old white and rich
Whose only concern is to take
coffee and eat cake at the end
Nobody gives a fuck
más that you
And enfrentémoslo, papá
You do not do this for art
You do this because you want to feel
relevant again
Good guess
There's a world of it outside where people
fight to be relevant to daily
And your acts as if there were no
Things happen in a place
your ignaros
A place that apparently no
you have forgotten it
I mean, who the fuck are you t?
You hate bloggers
Teasing Twitter
You don't even have a
página Facebook
You are the one that does not exist
You do this
Because these terrified to death
Like the rest of us
No matter
And you know what?
You have razón
No matter
It is not important, ok?
T you are not important
Acostmbrate
Papá
Lesley
Why?
- I think that I'm hard
It is not so, just that sometimes not
consider the feelings of the demás
No, No, I'm getting
hard, feels like this
Are you kidding?
Hagámoslo real, let's take
Estás crazy?
Beá real, very real
Suéltame Mike
Let Mike
- Do not call me Mike
Llámame Mel, Mel
Báfeast
Suéltame
Ed
- Why?
You do here?
I just need you to tell me because
Tómalo with calm,
cálmate, sé that is hard
Cállate
Do not do anything estpido
Eddie please
I have wrong?
Why people don't love me?"
Eddie, please give me the gun
Mírame
He was drownedándome only am I not
to be able to...
You deserved to be loved, Eddie
Seriously
Only quería be that t querías
Now I spend every minute praying
for being someone else
Someone who I am not
Who is
- Ok
Just put down the gun.
Ed, it's only because he doesn't love you
You love Me, right?
Not
And never harás?
Sorry
I do not exist
I'm not even here
None of this even matters
I don't exist
Ed?
- I don't exist even
Ed!
Don't do that
You are a imbécil
Are you kidding? It was the best
sex scene
Fuck
It is as if my head were
bañada of boloñesa
Give me the blood Rig
I arreglaré
Estáwe were in a hotel
- You must be kidding
You can't stop it in 6 months and now
you want to fuck me in front of 800 people?
I needed to feel it real
Ok?
I need that intensity
you know that on my
Fuck you
- From the beginning
I was sintiéndome only pensé
t also
That's never stopped you before
Brilliant, brilliant
What the fuck is wrong with you?
I want your shit outside of the department
Why? No, wait, look
Look at what I feel
Sorry, we can...?
- No, we can not Mike
Maybe here above are the
Mr. Truth
But in the real world where yes you matter
you are a fucking fraud
Such that truth, imbécil?
It is a imbécil
- Who made it that far?
Nothing, he wanted to fuck me in front of
the whole audience
God mío
Truth?
- It is sexy
Why I have no self-respect?
You're an actress, cariño
I am patética
Look
You know what?
I've always soñado to be
an actress of Broadway
Since I was a pequeña and
Now I'm here
And I
I am not an actress of Broadway
I'm still a niña
I've been waiting for someone I
say that I have attained
Hey
What you have achieved
What did I do?
Unfortunately it was with Mike in
a fake hotel with a lot of people...
Cállate
Oh God
Hey, está well?
She beá well
Look
None of this is your fault, ok?
Ok, look at
You're beautiful
You are talented
And I'm lucky to have you
Ok?
Ok
That was something that was sweet
If
What happens?
Nothing
2 years and He has never let me
said anything like that to my
Hey
You're beautiful
And you are talented
And I'm lucky to have you
Ok?
- What disgust
That you are doing?
Nothing
Do it again
We can talk about this like two
artists adults?
I say, which is really the
big problem...
Lárgate
You are not ready then
Está well
Actresses
Fuck
Riggan
Your weapon
It is ridícula
I see the red cartridge in the
cañón
So you see yourself as a niño with
a toy pláforecast
When pointing to my
I don't feel threatened
For nothing
Get a better,
please self-respect
Please
Apart from that, I think it was
a hearing very fun
I don't think that is enough
high
I didn't
You do up here?
Adrenaline?
I just got out of rehabilitación
It is the nearest that I get
to a drug
Went to rehabilitación?
If
Great
It was not a big deal or anything but
That guy from American Pie
was it
If?
Cómeme
I love this city
If
Because acts as a imbécil
all the time?
What do you do to antagonize
to the people?
Maybe
In reality you don't care a shit
if you fall well to the people or not?
Not really
That's great
What is it?
I don't sé
Hey
- That?
Let's play something
A game?
You have 8?
And t 78?
Truth or consequence
- Oh, come on
Not
-Truth or consequence
Truth
When we met for the
the first time
You made a comment about
my rear
Why did you do it?
You have a great rear
And I realized
And only comenté about the
Truth or consequence?
Result
Seriously?
- If
Ok
There is a bald passing below
and I want you to escupas
Not
Said result
Truth
No, it is too late
Happy?
If
Truth or consequence?
Truth
You are boring
The truth is always
interesting
You want to mess with me?
Not
Seriously?
Why not?
This is a second question
It is the second part
I am afraid that I could
stop
That's not pareció be a problem
for you on the stage
That is because nothing is a problem
for me on the stage
I want to ask you another question
You've done
A more
Forward
But you had fear
That you would love me?
You sacaría the eyes of the head
That is sweet
The pondría in my own cráneo
And miraría for it to be able to
See the street, the way in which the
to when I had your age
Good night
Do not kill the messenger
It is a imbécil
I told you so
Your fucking
Está playing with you, Riggan
What is?
Página 12, página 12
Where is the rest?
There is No rest
Don't worry someone will useá for
pick up dog shit mañana
How can you be so calm
Another opción I have?
Have No fear for nothing?
About what?
On being humiliated it out
Not would be the first time
Of course not
You are a imbécil
By the way, I'm not pregnant so
you should not worry about that
Olvídate of it
Is robó your front page
It robs you of your show
It says that you are a joke
Now 2 million people están
according to Him
Maybe if you were, Riggan
Perhaps that is what you are
A joke
What demons happens?
That hurts
- Levásit
Receding
- So by Carver you are an actor?
Why?
- Escchame
This is my fucking show
I did the work, recaudé the money
I brought the whore press
Oh, Jess
They called me to me by
an interview
I told them the first thing that
I ocurrió
Seriously?
The sección of the art culture
Come on, fuck the sección
art
Tell them the first thing that
you ocurrió
Truth, because that's you Mike
Not?
You are a natural kind, to those who do not
care about anything, no?
That is the truth of the moment
Do you think that matters?
- Cállate the fucking mouth
Not harás nothing in my scenario
unless I say so
Your scenario?
Oh, déjame to tell you something
This scenario has belonged to
many good actors
But t you're not one of them
- Seriously?
So measure your length, ok?
Did a few changes and divagaste
some things
But even so come to me
No one cares
piece of shit
Anyone?
- If
My erección had 58 thousand views
I bet that a dildo obtendría
más that lárgate of here
I don't care
- If, mind you
You mostraré, oh Mike you are
so honest
So true, listen to
Escchame, you said that your father was a
drunk as Carver, is it true?
Is it true?
- Not
Not
- Because my father if
My father is a drunk bastard
You understand?
- Ok
Stuck us
Está well because while stuck us
at least I didn't think
Take us to the tool shed
Because in that shed...
You have No idea
These are things that I don't even want to mention
You want to tell?
I gané a name
for me same
But... my poor sister
Ok, ok
Ok, hey
Hey, hey
Hey
God
I didn't know
Sorry
Sorry, that's horrible
- If
Nor is it true
You can see I also can't pretend
Don't mess with me, Mike
You say
- These a little crazy
Deberías start using that
in the scenario
Maybe I said that, but
If, perhaps
We will
- If?
If
Why don't you go by your wings and
your estpido suit bird?
That look, that harán?
I replace?
You think you're a fucking Ryan Gosling
or something as well?
You are patético, Riggan
Passándote with that faggot
theatre
And 700 people sitting
they see it as well
Now if you've goofed
You destroyed a good book with that child
adaptación now you're going to destroy
What is left of your career
It is patético
Larguémonos of here
while we can
This is not true, it is a
mental problem
Enough with that shit
It is not a mental problem
I am you, imbécil
Déjame in peace
You were a movie star, remember?
Happy
I was not happy
- Ignorant
But charming, now
You are a sucks cocks insignificant
Damn miserable
Always miserable
- If
Always miserable in Hollywood
You're trying to deprive?.
That you're an artist?
Because you're not
- Fuck you!
No, t vetea fuck
Coward
Missed billion
Gives you hesitating to that?
Always lose billions, and that
that makes it good?
I do not know if you've noticed
But that was in the 1992
You may get yourself in that outfit
if you would like to
We're not dead
- Mírame
Look
I look like a turkey
I'm disappearing
You can't
It's like a game of Trivia Pursuit here
You're not an imposter
You are a watcher, you know
I told you already, you are dead,
please
We're not dead
Please only quédate dead
- Stops shall speak unto thee plural
There is No us
I'm not your
Borraré your whore consciousness
Not
You're Birdman
Because without my
All that's left is you
The sad, egoísta and mediocre actor
That clings to the last
pieces of his career
Why demons did you do that?
I liked that poster
Always beá ÒweÒ, brother
Fuck you
Déjame in peace
Hey, what happens?
Good
One hour until the telón
Yes, great
The money already llegó I just need to
transfer it to the account
Here you have, thanks
- Well
It's great
- Then...
If, iré
Haré that
- Thanks for coming
If
- Ok
You know that I'm proud of you, no?
This tomó balls
Not estás dead, ok
What sé
I think that we should cancel
the preview
Why?
I'm tired, friend
Since I can not do this
I can not
Are you kidding
You know?
I do not believe this to beá for my
Is ríen of my
There is a block of three rows of
people esperándote
It is a full house, we are
exhausted
Seriously?
- If
And the French ambassador comes
And príncipe of saudi arabia to bringá
one of their wives
And not quería tell you this, but
Martin Scorsese
Está organizing the distribution
of his new movie
And you already know
Don't say anything
Ok?
Ok, if
If I can do it
I can do it
Well
- Thanks
Cómo está?
Beá well
Poor creature
Is it true?
Scorsese?
If
And I was appointed as the new
Pope also
You are a imbécil, Jake
I am the only one who keeps
this afloat
Hey
Estás well?
If
I think I cut the hand
afeitándome
Well, I only say quería
Sorry
Why?
Good
Sé of what he was capable of Mike and
I brought him anyway
No, No
You did well, you did well
Are you kidding?
You did well
Mañana is my
First night of opening
on Broadway
The mía also
I just want you to know that without
matter what happens
That
I am very grateful to you
No, No, I also
Hey, this is exciting
Además we have a full house
Jake I just say
YES, it's great
For the mother fucking,
jumps from one time
As you know that estaría here
up?
Well not sabía but
I hoped that maybe what you were
Where is Lesley?
Lesley
Lesley está moving forward
Smart girl
Oh, thank you, I appreciate it
It is important to
Ready for your final preview
Of course, if
Who did you that?
It could have been anyone I guess
If
I'm sorry if molesté Lesley
Well it was not Lesley
God mío
Are you kidding?
- Not
Jesus christ
No, I...
The...
- I think that I maybe...
Hey
Fuck
Tell me something
That is the worst thing that He has
fact
Seriously
...l was never near
If
I say, and why?
That was all?
No, it was
As intentó reward
Trying to convince me
constantly
That was special
Ok
Look
Mírame
...l had razón however
About what?
On that you are special
You know
You've been by here
Trying to be invisible with that routine
of unsuccessful
But I could not
You are anything but invisible,
you are great
You are a great disaster
It is like a candle burning
at both ends
But it is beautiful
No amount of alcohol
or bad attitude, what to hideá
I'm happy to be a actor
and not a writer because that was
As
Oprah
Hallmark
R. Kelly, so wrong
I don't quería...
Truth or consequence?
Truth
Not
Truth or consequence?
Have you any idea adónde are you going?
Absolutely not
As you do?
To do what?
- As sales it all night
And you pretend to be someone else
In front of the whole
such people?
Not I like to pretend it outside
I told you already
I feign in almost all places
but not here
What is worth
We do here?
What do you mean?
I say, what do we do here?
The blood should be fine
- Ok
Prepárate to leave in a minute
- Takes
That was amazing
Well, the truth?
- If
To tell the truth goes well
If
Hey
I think we need to talk
No, No
YES, I think you have razón
But I mention it because it's the chance
to tell you that I'm sorry
I'm really sorry
We were able to be good parents
Horrible
Terrible hubiéramos raised...
- Serial killers
Justin Bieber
Really quería be a mother
But my body does not seem to
agree
When I imagine being on Broadway never
pensé see a deer bailarín
Nice touch
Hey Jim, you have a cigar?
You Are Riggan Thomson?
To fuck...
Don't be an idiot, give me a autógrafo
You're great!
Oh shit
Señor to dónde going?
What will you do?
- Waiting for Jake
This is my lawyer, Mr. Roth
Why?
- We seek remuneración financial
By the wounds that...
I don't have time for you
- Apology?
You do here?
Why?
I just need you to
't say why?
Tómalo calmly, Ed,
sé this is hard
Cállate shit
Cállate
Eddie please
I have wrong?
Why people don't love me?"
Eddie please, just...
Please just give me the gun
I just quería be what
your querías
I spent all week trying to be
something más, something that I am not
Lower the gun, she doesn't love you
Hello?
Who?
Ok, no, please
What are you talking about?
That wheelchair?
Ok, Mr. Roth esccheme
Listen to Me?
Do not hang up
Do not hang up, ok, listen
Give me 10 minutes to get ordained
and we can...
Please do not hang up
Damn!
Papá
Hey
These well?
Why?
You see something
No, I'm fine
I'm fine, this is good
You want a little?
Not
Ok
You think really that beás
ready for the opening mañana?
If, if
If you, good
I say
The previews are crazy not
we seem to overcome without a
A fire or a erección
I'm broken
I don't sleep like, you know,
For nothing
And
This work
You start to feel like
A versión
Miniature and deformed
of me the same
That follows me everywhere
Hits Me in the balls with
A pequeño hammer
Sorry, cuál was the question?
No matter
This night was not bad
What sé
- It was weird but
It was great
Do you think that they gustó?
- Yes, I think so
If you, good
You do by the way?
Task
No, I do not
Not
In rehabilitación we made do this
- Seriously?
What is it?
It is...
The points represent the 6 billion
age of the earth
So that each one represents
a thousand years
And...
This is
Few years the human
have been here
150 thousand years
I think that trying to remind us that this is true
our ego and self obsesión
I was a father of fuck not?
No, you were
You were well
If
Exactly, only I was good
I can not
Papá?
- Why?
Oh shit
Sorry
You just clean with
the human race
Here goes
Sorry
Hey
You are becoming a topic
fashion
Seriously?
- If
Probably you should decírtelo
before another person to do so
350 thousand views
In less than an hour
Créelo or not this is to be able to
That anger to Mrs. Dickenson
Hey
I pagó, is a friend mía
Ok
Thanks
That was
20 years before I came
that damn suit
I don't care
Ok
I just
You know, before you come mañana...
No matter
Ok
I'm going to destroy t work
But even you have seen it
I did something to offend you?
In fact, if
You took a theatre that debió be
used for something más valuable
Ok, good
I mean, you don't even know if
it is good or not
I don't...
- It is true
I haven't even heard a word
of it or seen something
But for mañana haré the worst criticism
there is
And I'm going to close t work
I would love to know why
Because I hate you
Everything that you represent
Engreídos, egoístas niños
Totally without preparación
Without verse
Unable to try to produce
art of truth
Dámore awards each
other by cartoons
And pornografía
By measuring its value in the end
week
Well, this is the theater
And you can't come in here to claim
write, direct and act in your work
Without going through my first
So esfuérzate
You know, that happens in the life of a person
to become a critical anyway?
You write, another reseña?
Is it good?
What is it?
It is bad?, You've gone to this work even?
Déjame read
Llamaré the police
You're going to call, let's see
Terrible, Terrible is only a label
Low
Another label
Marginal
Marginal, seriously?
Sounds like you need to penicillin
to heal you of that
It is another tag
These are all tags
Only labels all
You're a fucking lazy
You are a lazy malnacida
You're a...
you know what is this
't even know what that
is this?
You don't know
You know why?
Because you can't see it but
you have a label for it
Cofundes all those pequeños
noises in your head
With true knowledge
You finished?
- Not yet
There is nothing here about
technical
structure
There is nothing here about intensity
It is only a montón of opinions
fuck
Supported in comparisons
an worst
Truth? A couple of párrafos
You know what? None of this
you costó nothing
You risk nothing,
nothing, nothing, nothing
I am a fucking actor
This work I costó all
So you diré something
Take this
These words cowards
Your reseñas of shit written
without pasión and métetelas
By t creased and adjusted rear
You know you're not a celebrity?
Let us be clear on that
Mataré to your work
Give me a flat of whiskey
6.30, friend
Cómo?
- 6.30
It takes only...
Tómalo
Adónde are you going?
It was a lot?
Just trying to give you a range
It is much I can tell because
Your...
God
You see yourself done fuck brother
You seem to have a dog run over when
these hungover not?
If
We will
We will, levásit
It is a beautiful day
Olvídate of the Times
All the world has done
Let, párate
Then you're not a big actor
Who cares?
You are much más that
You are better than these imbéciles
theatre
You're a movie star, friend
You're another batch
Don't you understand?
You spent your whole life doing
a reputación
And the volaste
Good for you
Fuck
We will make a return
Están waiting for something giant
So give them that
Aféitate that beard patética
Get surgery
50 is the new 30, bastard
T were the original man
You painted the way for these
other clowns
Give the people what they want
In the form of porn apocalíptico
Birdman, the penis upward
Seeás cómo, shit in
the pants
Around the world guaranteed
You are más larger than life
Saves the people of their miserable lives
The harás should she dump in your pants
all you have to do..
I'm talking about
Big guns, heavy missiles,
look at these people, look at their eyes
As shine, love this shit
Love the chaos, the performance
Nothing tonterías spoken
and filosóficas
If
And the próxima time chillies
Exploitá in millions of
tímpanos
Brillaras in thousands of screens
all over the world
Another box-office Success
You are God
What do you see? Here you go, bastard
The severity or even
applies to you
Waiting to see the faces of those
they thought that estáwe finished
Escchame
Let us return once and mostrémosles
what you're made of
We must finish it under
our own terms
With a grand gesture
Flames, sacrifice
Icaro
Because doing so
You listen to Me?
You are
Birdman!
Hey, this is real, or these
filming a movie?
A movie
You're full of shit
Hey, dude, can I help you?
You have to be careful
Sorry, I can not speak
It's late
Music
These well?
Want me to call someone for you?
You know dónde go?.
If
Sé to go dónde
What do you see?
Here is where you belong
Above all
For the music
Hello, señor?
You need to pay me
This deaf, idiot?
I don't pagó, está crazy
It wasn't bad the first act, no?
- Good for nothing
You are doing very well...
Just came to say hello
Está going well here outside,
you are very good
I mean seriously
Thanks
For the final scene, Riggan
look for the final scene
Look at all these roses
And you hate roses...
Estás well?
You seem to
You seem, I don't know how...
Unusually calm
I am calm
I'm great actually
You know?
I have a voice that speaks to me
sometimes
He tells Me the truth
It is comforting to
Something scary but it is complicated
Fingiré not escuché say that
Ok
Don't believe itás all the people there are,
people paid up to $500 for the ticket
Hey
Can I tell you something funny?
Clear
Do you remember our last party
anniversary?
Seriously, you're going to ruin a
good time
You remember it?
The party where you picked up Janet
Roseback in our bed?
Skip that part
- Oh, with pleasure
And did you get to all the guests
the house
And you threw everything out the window
What I remember
And you encerraste in the baño
- Riggan
Why we talk about this?
- I was here
Malib
And I only senté on the beach
for a time
Looking at the ocean
Riggan
And I
I metí direct the water
I tried to kill myself
It was up to the chest when
was the first in my back
As if someone would like to pull
but he burned up and then
I was in my chest and in
my legs
The water was full of malaguas
They were on top of my
I had to go out fighting
water
And I went to the
Beach rolling as
A madman in the sand
Crying
You said that you habías
burnt by the sun
If, sé
T I creíste
To be honest I don't
importó a shit
I love you
I've never known how to say it
What sé
I really would love to not
think about both
Why?
Because
I perdí of the time
I don't have it
Debí have been here
With the two of you, you know?
Only the three together
But not what I was
Even I was present
in my own life
And now I don't have
Never the tendré
But you have to Sam
Not really, I don't want to sound
bad but...
No, don't listen to it, only this
What I understand, seriously
She needed a father
And in its place recibió
to a type that
It was a sensación viral
in 3D
It was so patético
We will not, there are things more
patéticas that
If, as?
Your moustache
Riggan, we are in the motel
The last scene has begun
Not estás here
The last opportunity to
positions
Better go back to your seat
Carrie, Carrie!
Eddie, you do here?
Why?
Just tell me why?
Just tell me why
Cállate
- Eddie please
That happens with me?
Tell me, what happens?
Why I always end up begging
for people to love me?
Cariño please, just give me the gun
Understand was drownedándome
was not able to
You deserve to be loved, Eddie
Seriously
Only quería be that t querías
Your
And I spend every minute trying to be
something más, something that I am not
Just lower the gun, Ed
She no longer loves you
Don't do it?
Not
And never harás?
Sorry
I do not exist
I do here?
I don't mind
Hey
If?
Already reaccionó?
Just waking up
Pensé that you had lost, friend
What demons pasó?
I was viéndote on the stage, and then
Out of nothing
Tenías a strange look in your eyes
And you were like...
That happens to you?
...l está...
- Happy!
Está live, my best friend
está live
And
It happens that it is the man of the hour
Who is that?
You must be kidding
Léelo
I don't think so, "The unexpected under
of ignorance"?
Léelo
Léelo aloud
Thomson unintentionally has given life to a
new way that can only be described
As
Sper realism
Blood was shed, both
literally as metafóricamente
By the artist and the audience
Blood of truth
The blood of fact
has been missing
The veins of the american theater
These happy about this?
Happy? I'm fuck...
This is the type of reseña that becomes
legends to the people
Is disparó the nose of the face
Has a new nose!
And if you don't like we will get another
We will use Meg Ryan but
who cares
Están lighting candles by the
in Central Park
Turn on the TV, where está...
Están praying for the
in all the country
What did, what did you do!
I have been born again, brother
And I can see the future
This work lastá forever
Opená in London, in paris
The study callá once again,
we will make treatment of books already seeás
Then you can see the future?
Yes, I can see the future
Such that?
Dresses come to that?
Why don't you say anything?
This is what querías, no?
Riggan, this is what querías
If
Yes, this is what quería
Listen to you are going to accuse of carrying
a loaded gun, ok?
If someone speaks to you about that
It was an accident
- Ok
That's what that was?
An accident?
An accident
Listen, lárguense
Váyanse of here
Violet
You ríes?
If
- That is so funny?
I can not smell
What will you do?
Pondré a picture on your page
Twitter
I have a?
- Yes, the armé day today
Déjame see
- Of course not
No, you look horrible
Oh, Wow, thank you
I appreciate it
It's a joke
Not really, if you look horrible
You have 80 thousand followers
In less than a day
Seriously?
- If, asustaste all
Déjame see that
Is alreadyá done
Iré to find a vase for the flowers
Ok
Oh go
Goodbye and fuck you
Pope
Pope?
BY V1NC3