We're all very proud of
Judah Rosenthal's philanthropic efforts.
His endless hours of fundraising
for the hospital, the new medical centre,
and now the ophthalmology wing which,
until this year, had just been a dream.
But it's Judah Rosenthal, our friend,
that we most appreciate.
The husband, the father,
the golf companion.
- Naturally for a medical problem...
- You're blushing, darling.
..weekends or holidays.
But you can also call Judah to find out
which is the best restaurant in Paris.
Or Athens.
Or which hotel to stay at in Moscow.
Or the best recording
of a particular Mozart symphony.
My father is so nervous
about having to get up and speak.
I knew he was nervous when you didn't
eat any of those cocktail weenies.
He was so courageous all week,
then suddenly, tonight, stage fright.
Really, Judah, you were fine
till you got home from work today.
- Any mail?
- It's exactly where I left it this morning.
I haven't had a free second all day.
If you're gonna take a shower, you better
do it, because I have to use it, too.
I dread making that speech tonight.
Dear Miriam Rosenthal.
I'm at the lowest point of my life
as I write you this letter.
I wish to cause no suffering
but, because I'm going through pure hell,
I ask if you can meet me one time.
Your husband and l
are more than intimate friends
and have been deeply in love
for over two years now.
This must be faced, as there are so many
ramifications and complications.
Many promises were made, etc.
I need an open exchange
with you to clear things.
For all three of us to go on,
the situation has got to be
confronted in some fashion.
Please contact me at this number.
I want what's best for everyone.
Dolores Paley.
That the new ophthalmology wing is now
a reality is not just a tribute to me,
but to a spirit of community, generosity,
of mutual caring
and answered prayers.
Now, it's funny I use the term "answered
prayers". You see, I'm a man of science.
I've always been a sceptic.
But I was raised quite religiously.
And while I challenged it, even as a child,
some of that feeling
must have stuck with me.
I remember my father telling me
"The eyes of God are on us always."
The eyes of God.
What a phrase to a young boy.
I mean, what were God's eyes like?
Unimaginably penetrating,
intense eyes, I assumed.
And I wonder if it was just a coincidence
that I made my specialty ophthalmology.
I'm so proud of you, Judah.
Sharon is. We all are.
Let's get one of
Miriam and Judah together.
- Why did you write that letter?
- You know why.
- You wanna destroy my life? My family?
- I want her to know what you're like.
It was lying on the table all day.
By a miracle, I got it first.
You told me over and over again
you'd leave Miriam.
- I didn't!
- You did!
- I gave up business opportunities.
- Pipe dreams.
- And other men wanted me.
- What do you want from me?
- You think this was easy?
- I want what you told me you wanted.
T o be together. Otherwise
I don't know what I'll do.
I'll jump out the window, I swear!
You've been my whole life for two years.
I can't go back to the way things were.
I was at a low point when we met.
You changed that.
I never said I'd leave Miriam.
It's wishful thinking.
"There's no passion. It's boring."
Those are your words.
Unless you were lying to me
or there's more to this that I don't know.
- Have you met someone else?
- What? Oh, come on.
- For God's sake, Dolores. Dolores...
- What?
Now, look. I've lived with her 25 years.
The roots are very deep.
I can't go on leading two lives.
Well, you're not doing her any favour by
pretending. I'm not gonna be without you.
I'm not gonna let this happen to me
without a fight. I wanna speak to Miriam.
- Dolores, nothing is happening. All right?
- No!
Yes! Now listen to me, please. Just
bear with me. We'll work something out.
Let me get my thoughts together.
Just don't do anything rash.
Dolores...
What?
It's gonna be OK.
Oh, God.
You were gonna throw me aside
like a squeezed lemon!
- Don't dramatise this!
- I've given you the best years of my life
and you were willing to go on and on.
Get out of here.
I know you for what you are.
I'm lucky I found you out.
Those are my clothes!
That was great, wasn't it?
With the tuxedos and the evening gowns.
- Great.
- It was wonderful to live like that.
This is awful. Let me see
if I can get a cab. You stay here.
- Wanna see a movie again tomorrow?
- Sure, Uncle Cliff.
Jesus.
Unless... Maybe we should make it
a museum day. You know?
I promised your father on his deathbed
I'd give you a well-rounded education.
We probably shouldn't go to the movies
every day, just once in a while.
Even though I'd love to. You know?
So while we wait for a cab,
I'll give you your lesson for today. OK?
Your lesson is this: don't listen
to what your schoolteachers tell you.
Just see what they look like. That's how
you'll know what life is gonna be like.
You heard it here first. I think I see a cab.
If we run quickly, we can kick the crutch
from that old lady and get it.
- I'm back!
- Where were you?
You know. Just out and around.
- You took your niece to the movies again.
- I'm crazy about that kid. She's just great.
My brother's in town. He wants us
to join him for a dinner party tonight.
Jesus.
- Please. You gonna make another scene?
- I didn't last time.
You did. You were not nice
and your resentment showed.
I don't resent him. I told you that.
I think he's a pompous ass.
You don't see it 'cos you love him.
- What are you muttering?
- Nothing.
You are. You're running down Lester.
- Hey, I like your brother Ben.
- Sure. You're not jealous of Ben.
You think I'm jealous of Lester
cos he's a TV producer?
No, because he's a much-honoured,
highly respected multimillionaire.
- And he does what you'd like to be doing.
- I can't watch his stuff. It's sub-mental.
- He wants to talk to you about a job.
- I don't need a job.
I got honourable mention
at that festival in... in...
Cincinnati? The documentary film
festival? This is what you're clinging to?
Everybody got honourable mention
who showed up.
Boy, things have really
changed around here.
Wendy, Cliff, come here.
I want you to meet Lisa.
My sister Wendy.
My brother-in-law Clifford.
Lisa Crosley.
She's starring in my new series.
- Not really starring.
- You're one of the stars.
It's an ensemble.
Tell 'em who you're playing.
- Hello, Lester.
- Hi, darling. So glad you came.
Thank you for inviting me.
It's a beautiful party.
Thank you. Why don't you have a drink?
Be right there.
She gave a bundle
to the Museum of Broadcasting.
She plays a...
A lawyer for the ACLU, with a husband
who writes for a conservative magazine.
- It gives us a chance to get into issues.
- We'll try to be fair but, knowing Lester,
- it'll be heavily slanted to the left.
- Let's hope so.
- You know we're gonna shoot it here?
- You'll be here? I couldn't be happier.
Me, too. I love this town.
Out there it's such a Mickey Mouse
environment. I'm not interested.
- That's why I'm in this week.
- Hello, Lester.
I wanna talk to you. Don't go away.
A bunch of us are getting together
to build major studio space
for production right here in the city.
In fact... I'm sorry.
Just give me one second.
Idea for series:
A wealthy builder always trying to realise
grandiose dreams a la Donald Trump.
- T o be shot in New York.
- Look who's here.
This is my brother Ben.
Ben. Carol. Come here.
Hi, Cliff.
- How are your eyes?
- Not so good. It's not so optimistic.
- You're kidding.
- I've been seeing Dr Rosenthal.
Lester, I'm sorry. Don't you
want to talk to Clifford?
Yeah. Step into my office.
- Hi. I'm Lisa.
- Hi. We didn't meet. I'm sorry.
So, are you in TV, too?
No. No, I'm a rabbi.
You don't have to wear
an outfit or anything?
Public television wants
to do a documentary on me.
Follow me around,
the way I talk, the way I think.
It's part of their Creative Mind series.
So... I told them about you.
Thank you. But I'm workin'
on a thing of my own. A little film.
Yeah, Wendy told me. A film about some
philosophy professor, which is admirable.
But I'm offering you the chance to earn
decent money and reach a big audience.
The last thing you need
is for me to be your biographer.
I make these little films
on toxic waste and starving children...
Look, I'll be frank with you.
You're not my first choice.
I'm doing this for Wendy. She says
you haven't worked in a long time.
I've worked. It's just that
nobody's paying me.
Look, I know you don't respect what I do.
But I've got a closet full of Emmys.
OK, you think that's bullshit. Fine.
I understand.
I don't know. Maybe I could
use the money to finish my movie.
I do have some debts and things.
Idea for farce:
A poor loser agrees to do
the story of a great man's life
and in the process
comes to learn deep values.
- What are you doing in Boston?
- I'm lecturing at a symposium.
Incidentally, my name's Dolores.
- Hello, Dolores.
- Hello.
- Pretty name.
- Thank you very much.
- Do you go to Boston often?
- Not very often, no.
- I don't know anyone in Boston, actually.
- Really?
- Good morning.
- Hi. Miss Paley called. Said it was urgent.
Why did you phone me?
I told you I'd call you.
I couldn't help it.
I was going out of my skin.
I have to see you later. I have to.
OK.
After work is OK.
I see it.
Yeah. I see it.
Oh, God.
What?
I need to take a minute.
What's wrong, Judah?
I'm in such trouble, Ben.
What is it?
I need to talk to someone.
Sure.
We've known each other many years.
You're a religious man. OK, I'm not.
We've differed on many points,
but you're somebody I do respect.
- May I confide in you?
- Of course.
Go ahead. Everything's confidential.
I've done a foolish thing.
Senseless, vain, dumb.
Another woman.
Maybe I was flattered, vulnerable.
Maybe because she was
helpless and alone.
Now my life's about to go up in smoke.
- Can't you break it off?
- The woman won't allow it.
She's young. She's very unstable.
She's an hysteric.
And vindictive.
And it's my fault.
I instigated it. I prolonged it.
Many times I tried to back off
but I was too weak.
But I promised her nothing.
Or did l?
See, I don't even know any more.
In the heat of passion, you say things.
But, after two years of
shameful deceit in this double life,
I awakened as if from a dream
and realised what I'd be losing.
It's called wisdom.
It comes to some suddenly.
We realise the difference between
what's real and deep and lasting
versus the superficial
payoff of the moment.
You know, I kidded myself about
loving her but deep down I knew.
And knowing, I behaved selfishly.
For pleasure, for adventure, for lust.
Sometimes, when there's real love
and true acknowledgement of a mistake,
there can be forgiveness, too.
I know Miriam.
Her values, her feelings. Our place
among our friends and colleagues.
But what choice do you have
if the woman is going to tell her?
You have to confess the wrong
and hope for understanding.
Maybe Miriam was responsible
in some ways, too.
You have to discuss it
and hope for the best.
Maybe you can never
go back to the old life,
but maybe there's a new one with
maturity and understanding. Maybe...
Maybe even a richer one.
You know what's funny?
Our entire adult lives,
you and I have been having this same
conversation in one form or another.
It's a fundamental difference
in the way we view the world.
You see it as harsh and
empty of values and pitiless,
and I couldn't go on living
if I didn't feel with all my heart
a moral structure with real meaning and
forgiveness,
and some kind of higher power.
Otherwise there's no basis
to know how to live.
And I know you well enough to know that
the spark of that notion is inside you, too.
Now you're talkin' to me
like your congregation.
It's true. We went from a small infidelity
to the meaning of existence.
Miriam won't think two years of scheming
and dishonesty is a... is a small infidelity.
How can you do it? I give up.
God, you're in such wonderful shape.
- For a man my age?
- For any age.
- I was quite athletic as a young student.
- You still make love like a young student.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
You know, I don't think
we should do this here.
- Why not? We're all alone.
- I don't know. I feel a little self-conscious.
Let's go back to the cottage and light
a fire. You can play me the Schumann.
Schubert. Schumann is flowery.
Schubert is...
He reminds me of you. The sad one.
Schubert. God, you have to teach me all
that. I'm so ignorant in classical music.
I'll teach you.
Someday we'll have a lot of time.
Would you like a drink?
Yeah. Fix me whatever you're having.
Why'd you call the house last night
and hang up, Del?
I'm not playing games, Judah.
Just because you've decided we're
through doesn't mean I'll roll over and die.
What the hell happened to us? I mean...
We had a wonderful few years.
We both knew it couldn't go on for ever.
- I gave up things for you.
- Come on. That's poppycock.
Don't give me that, will ya?
For God's sakes.
There were no business opportunities.
It's all in your head.
No lovers beggin' for your hand.
I prevented nothing. I...
Can we not argue? I just wanted to talk.
I'm just so rattled.
I had an idea.
I thought if we could get away, just
for a little while, on one of our trips.
Our trips are
the warmest memories I have.
Not just in our relationship, but
some of the loveliest times I've ever had.
You're always so much more relaxed
away from home.
You come to life.
Your whole face changes.
I thought if we could just get away
to Boston or Washington,
- just without any preconceived notions.
- I can't go away, Del.
- Just a weekend.
- I can't, Del.
- Why not?
- I can't.
- You won't.
- Of course I won't. Right.
Why not?
Because you're very unrealistic.
You know that?
Sit... Sit down for a second. Let's talk.
Look. I've been...
I've been thinking, too.
And it occurs to me,
if I caused you to miss any opportunities
that might have been lucrative for you,
I'm perfectly prepared to reimburse you.
- I don't want to feel I've cost you any...
- I'm not after your goddamn money.
I want to speak to Miriam.
It's her problem, too.
- I want her to know the truth.
- Keep her out of it. All right?
I think she should know
her husband is a liar and an embezzler.
Don't you dare call me an embezzler.
I'm not blind. I know what went on with
those philanthropies and your stocks.
I took nothing. Not a nickel.
My conscience is completely clear.
You needed money
to cover your losses. I was there.
OK, OK. I needed some temporary help.
I mean, for Christ's sake.
After a life of hard work, a man doesn't
let himself go down the toilet. Does he?
And moving funds is not stealing.
Without telling anyone?
Every cent was accounted for,
with interest.
I don't think they would see it that way.
So this is what you plan on doing? You're
gonna hold on to me with threats, right?
Stupid threats and slander.
This is your idea of love, right?
I will not be tossed out.
I want to speak to Miriam.
Think, for Christ's sake! Think what
the hell you're doing to me. Please.
I can't figure it out.
I need you.
Del...
I love New York.
I was born in that building.
Behind the guy... the statue there.
The guy on the pedestal.
I love New York. It's like thousands of
straight lines just lookin' for a punch line.
And what makes New York
such a funny place is that
there's so much tension and pain
and misery and craziness here.
And that's the first part of comedy.
But you gotta get some distance from it.
The thing to remember about comedy is:
if it bends, it's funny.
If it breaks, it's not funny.
So you gotta get back from the pain.
See what I mean?
They asked me up at Harvard, a bunch
of kids asked me "What's comedy?"
So I said... And this is part of
what I said about getting back from it.
I said "Comedy is tragedy plus time."
Tragedy plus time.
The night Lincoln was shot, you couldn't
make a joke about it. You just couldn't.
Now, time has gone by,
and now it's fair game.
See what I mean? It's tragedy plus time.
- OK, we're out.
- That's it? So fast?
I shot up ten rolls on your first question.
I've gotta get to CBS anyway.
We'll start this again tomorrow.
Just remember what I was saying.
What do you think?
- Excellent. Absolutely.
- I think I'm too cute.
I'll be more relaxed tomorrow.
I'll do that tragedy stuff.
- This is Halley Reed for Mr. Kurnitz.
- Would you excuse me one second?
Listen, if you play your cards right,
you could have my body.
- Wouldn't you rather leave it to science?
- I offer you my heart, you squash it.
Come on. When are you gonna quit
this organisation, come work for me?
- You'd fire me. I'm much too opinionated.
- No, no.
- That's OK. I'll wait.
- I like mental stimulation.
- You tried shock therapy?
- That's good. That's funny.
- Listen, Lester. We've gotta go.
- OK. I'll be right with you.
- It's five o'clock.
- Wait in the car.
- Would you please come?
- Yes. Wait in the car, Arthur.
Yes, I was holding for Mr. Kurnitz,
please. It's Halley Reed.
Why don't you come with me
down to Barbados?
We'll swim, we'll get some sun.
Sorry. I freckle.
That's my best shot. I can't do any better.
- That's OK. I'll wait.
- Think about it. OK? Please.
Talk to you tomorrow.
Yeah, it's Halley Reed. You cut me off.
- OK.
- Excuse me. We haven't officially met.
- I'm Halley Reed, an associate producer.
- I'm Clifford Stern.
Can I ask you what I asked the producer?
What do you bother with this guy for?
He's such a pompous bore,
and your show does such great profiles.
Just between you and me,
I wanted to do Gabriel Garcia Marquez.
- That's perfect.
- They like a little variety.
- He is an American phenomenon.
- Yeah, but so is acid rain.
Boy, you really don't like him, do you?
I love him like a brother -
David Greenglass.
So why are you doing this? It's unusual
for them to bring in an outside person.
Yes, I know. I'm doing it
strictly for the money.
I'm trying to make my own documentary.
I'm doing a profile on a guy who'd be
absolutely perfect for your show.
- Yeah? Who's that?
- His name is Louis Levy.
Do you have a little time?
The unique thing that happened
to the early lsraelites
was that they conceived a God that cares.
He cares but, at the same time,
he also demands
that you behave morally.
But here comes the paradox.
What's one of the first things
that that God asks?
That God asks Abraham
to sacrifice his only son,
his beloved son, to him.
In other words,
in spite of millennia of efforts,
we have not succeeded to create
a really and entirely loving image of God.
This was beyond our capacity to imagine.
- Boy, he's really interesting.
- A fascinating guy.
- He could be wonderful for the series.
- You wanna dump Lester and do him?
- Cos I would love to...
- We can't dump Lester.
But I think I could talk them into
a little financing for you.
And if all this comes together right,
and it should,
we got some free spots
in the fall schedule.
Wonderful. For me to get on your series
would be such a feather in my cap.
That would be
the biggest audience I ever had.
Great. Let's work on it.
Let's make it happen.
Really? You know, even though we just
met, I've taken an instant liking to you.
And I to him.
Hi. I thought I'd come by
on my way home. I got Jenny a present.
- Is that you, Uncle Cliff?
- Yes, Jenny. I got you something.
I got you a great book,
an absolutely terrific book.
How are you? I got you this great book
with great pictures of old New York in it.
- Look at this. This is old Fifth Avenue.
- This is great.
Carriages and top hats. I told you.
There's a section on speakeasies,
which is really interesting.
That's the Flatiron Building,
which is very famous.
I'm in a great mood.
I had a creative breakthrough.
I heard you got some action
on your ad in the personals.
- This is the old Madison Square Garden.
- Jen... Don't you have some homework?
- Yeah, I have to go do that.
- We'll look at this later. Great pictures.
Cliff...
What's the matter?
- I'm a wreck.
- What is it?
- Barbara...
Barbara, what's the matter?
I feel sick.
- What is it?
- I've been shaking like this for days.
What's wrong?
I've been going out with this man
that I met through the personal columns.
Very attractive.
It was very nice.
I went out with him three times.
He was never fresh.
He was always a perfect gentleman.
So... we both came back here,
and Jenny was away.
She was sleeping over
at a friend's house.
And it was, like, one o 'clock
in the morning or something
and we both had had a little to drink.
You know, I wanna tie you to the bed.
- Really?
- And rip your dress off.
Have you ever been bound up,
tied up and made love to?
I'm.... I'm a...
I'm a sensible gal.
No more you're not.
God, Murray. God...
Barbara, I'm shocked at what I'm hearing.
You're my sister.
A nice, middle-class mother.
What are you telling me?
I couldn't move.
I was tied tightly to the bedposts.
Jesus. By a stra...
a guy that you didn't know?
And now you're gonna tell me
that he robbed you, right?
No.
He got on top of me and... and...
- And what?
- I can't say it. I just... I can't say it.
What? Tell me. What's so terrible?
He sat over me...
and went to the bathroom.
That's so disgusting!
Oh, my God! That's the worst thing
I ever heard in my life.
- Then he took his clothes and left.
- Barbara! You idiot!
This guy could've cut your throat!
Murdered you!
- I would've preferred it.
- Jesus. You're such a dope!
I wish I could have sympathy for this.
That's so easy for you to say,
but I'm so lonely.
You don't know what it's like
to be by yourself all the time.
I'm sure you're lonely. I know it's painful.
But promise me that you're never gonna
place another ad again. It's ridiculous!
My whole life is passing me by,
and I don't have anyone to love.
I know that's so hard for you
to comprehend because you're married.
But it's so lonely out there.
I mean, you have a wife,
and you love her, and that's so nice.
Let me tell you. Things are not so good
between my wife and myself,
just so you don't get any illusions.
We've been coming apart for the last year.
It's just that neither of us has the energy
to do anything about it. It's not so great.
A strange man defecated on my sister.
Why?
I don't know.
Is there any reason I could give you
that would answer that satisfactorily?
You know, it's just so...
Human sexuality is just...
it's so mysterious.
Which I guess is... you know.
I guess it's good in a way.
Yeah, well, I gotta be up at seven.
I knew it had to be some deep,
dark secret for you to stoop to call me,
- to actually invite me to your home.
- Jack, who should I turn to but a brother?
- I've been there for you.
- I'm here, aren't l?
Don't make sharp cracks. I didn't
stoop to call you. I'm in serious trouble.
She won't take money.
She won't listen to reason.
I even thought of telling everything to
Miriam, but she could never live with it.
Add to that her blabbing
about my financial indiscretions.
Not that I stole, but I was indiscreet.
And, if they look hard enough,
who knows what they'll find?
- What would you like me to do?
- I don't know, but she's killing me.
Want me to have somebody talk to her?
- Like what?
- Straighten her out.
What do you mean? Threaten her?
That's all I need.
How else do you expect
to keep her quiet?
I don't know. Jack, I don't know.
- Well...
- Christ, Jack. What are you suggesting?
What did you call me for?
I don't know. I hoped you'd have
more experience with something like this.
You called because you need some dirty
work done. That's all you ever call for.
Look how bitter you are.
You've staked me plenty of times.
I don't forget my obligations.
Threatening will only make it worse, Jack.
OK. Forget about it.
What do you want me to say?
How the hell can I forget about it?
I'm fighting for my life.
This woman's gonna destroy
everything I've built.
That's what I'm saying. If she won't listen
to reason, then you go on to the next step.
Threats? Violence?
What are we talking about here?
She can be gotten rid of. I know people.
Money'll buy whatever's necessary.
I won't even comment on that.
That's mind-boggling.
What did you want me to do
when you called me?
Not to do dirty work,
despite what you think.
Anyway, it's gone beyond
just Miriam now.
She's talking financial doings.
I'm out of ideas. I don't know what l
expected from you, Jack, but some help.
You know, you're not aware of
what goes on in this world.
You sit up here with your four acres and
your country club and your rich friends.
- Out there in the real world, it's different.
- Come on.
- I've met a lot of characters...
- I've heard these stories before.
..from Seventh Avenue, from Atlantic City.
And I'm not so high-class that I can avoid
looking at reality. I can't afford to be aloof.
You come to me with a hell of a problem,
and then you get high-handed on me.
I don't mean to be high-handed.
I haven't been sleeping. I'm irritable.
OK. Forget I said anything.
Let me just get something straight here.
Am I understanding you right?
Are you suggesting getting rid of her?
You won't be involved.
But I'll need some cash.
What will they do?
What'll they do? They'll handle it.
I can't believe I'm talking about
a human being. She's not an insect.
You don't just step on her.
I know. Playing hardball
was never your game.
You never liked to get your hands dirty.
But, apparently, this woman is for real,
and this thing isn't just gonna go away.
I can't do it.
I can't think that way.
Don't tell me.
I don't wanna know anything about it.
This is a work of art.
The ropes come off. I tie sash weights
to her ankles with soft catgut.
- Please! That's a horrible word.
- Get the angle on this.
She disappears. Two weeks, maybe three.
Then up she pops. None of this stuff
on her any more, no marks. A suicide.
- Now isn't that beautiful?
- It's loathsome.
- Be sure no one sees you.
- Don 't worry.
This only happens in the movies.
Listen, we should get back.
Lester's gonna be leaving the hotel soon.
We'll make it. We've been shooting Lester
all week. I'm tired of it. We'll catch him.
I shouldn't have told you my weakness
is going to the movies in the daytime.
I go all the time with my niece.
It's wonderful. It's like playing hooky.
You said that yesterday and we were late.
We weren't late. We didn't miss anything.
Have another cheeseburger.
It's our lunch hour.
I've got everyone up at the network
very excited over Professor Levy.
I have some great stuff to show you later.
Listen.
I bought you a present.
Great. Now I can get rid of
my few remaining teeth.
~ Happy birthday to you
A treadmill. Are you trying
to tell me something?
- You said you were bored with the bike.
- You may find this just as boring.
- I think you're in great shape already.
- Yeah, for a man my age.
Great to see you enjoying yourself.
You've been so depressed.
This thing's great for tension.
- I'll go get it.
- It's just like the one you saw at the club.
- Where are we gonna put this?
- I'm gonna have 20 men take it upstairs.
- It looks like a kinetic sculpture.
- It's not gonna stay down here.
- It tells you how many calories...
- Dad, it's for you.
Miss Paley.
- She's a patient.
- On this phone?
Yeah. She's going through a crisis.
I'll be right back.
- Why couldn't the service pick it up?
- It's probably an emergency.
I'm calling from the gas station
down the road from your house.
I can be there in five minutes.
I'm going to,
unless you meet me right now.
No, Judah. No, Judah.
No. I wanna talk to you in person,
or I'm coming over.
- Just calm down, OK?
- You said we were going away.
I wanna be alone with you.
And when we get back,
I want you to bring everything
to a conclusion with Miriam.
I can't go on like this! I can't wait for ever!
You don't know what it's like!
Maybe it would help if you
talked to somebody, like a therapist.
Don't trick me, Judah! Christ, I'm shaking.
Listen.
I brought you a birthday present.
I know how much you love Schubert.
Sometimes, when there's real love
and true acknowledgement of a mistake,
there can be forgiveness, too.
I know Miriam.
Her values, her feelings. Our place
among our friends and colleagues.
But what choice do you have
if the woman is going to tell her?
You have to confess the wrong
and hope for understanding.
I couldn't go on living
if I didn't feel with all my heart
a moral structure with real meaning and
forgiveness,
and some kind of higher power.
Otherwise,
there 's no basis to know how to live.
And I know you well enough to know that
the spark of that notion is inside you, too.
Could you really go through with it?
What choice do I have, Ben?
T ell me.
Give the people that you've hurt
a chance to forgive you.
Miriam won't forgive me. She'll be broken.
She worships me.
She'll be humiliated before our friends.
This woman plans to make a stink.
- Did you make promises to her?
- No.
Maybe I led her on more than I realised.
She's so emotionally hungry.
- But it's deeper than just Miriam now.
- Meaning financial improprieties?
No.
Maybe l... Maybe I did
make some questionable moves.
Only you would know that, Judah.
I don't any more, Ben.
Sometimes it's worse than...
worse than jail.
It's a human life.
You don't think God sees?
God is a luxury I can't afford.
Now you're talking like your brother Jack.
Jack lives in the real world.
You live in the kingdom of heaven.
I managed to keep free of that real world
but... suddenly it's found me.
You fool around with her for pleasure
and then, when you think it's enough,
you wanna sweep her under the rug?
There's no other solution but Jack's, Ben.
I push one button and
I can sleep again nights.
Could you sleep with that?
Is that who you really are?
I will not be destroyed
by this neurotic woman.
But the law, Judah.
Without the law, it's all darkness.
You sound like my father.
What good is the law if it prevents me
from receiving justice?
Is what she's doing to me just?
Is this what I deserve?
Jack? It's Judah.
I think we should move ahead
with what we discussed.
How much will you need?
Not funny. It's not funny, guys.
No, it's not. You're not thinking funny.
You gotta think with your ear.
Do you understand what I'm telling you?
Here's the difference. It's very easy.
If it bends, it's funny.
If it breaks, it's not funny.
It's very simple. Wait a minute. Here.
- Jeff, this is Alva.
- Hi. Pleased to meet you.
Don't... Don't shoot this part.
Alva will play a small part in the new
series. I don't know what. I just want her.
- It's wonderful. You look great.
- Thank you.
They love you. Wonderful. Be right out.
OK. Don't do that while they're shooting.
It's messing my hair up.
Understand what I'm saying?
Think of Oedipus. Oedipus is funny.
That's the structure of funny, right there.
"Who did this terrible thing?"
"Oh, God - it was me." That's funny.
But the difference is... Not while they're
shooting. What the hell are you doing?
You will notice that what we are aiming at
when we fall in love
is a very strange paradox.
The paradox consists of the fact
that, when we fall in love,
we are seeking to re-find
all or some of the people
to whom we were attached as children.
On the other hand, we ask our beloved
to correct all of the wrongs
that these early parents or siblings
inflicted upon us.
So that love contains in it
the contradiction:
the attempt to return to the past
and the attempt to undo the past.
See? No limos, no bimbos,
no awards or anything.
This guy's just a thinker, an intellect.
I was just thinking, when you show this to
the people that make the final decision,
you should emphasise
his overall view of life.
It's great. It's life-affirming.
They love a positive statement.
See, this is what I need. A little interest
in my work. A little encouragement. It's...
Let me ask you something. I got a bottle
of champagne as a prize, from Paris.
I got honourable mention for a little
documentary I did on leukaemia, and...
- You want some champagne?
- I never say no to champagne, or caviar.
OK. That's perfect. I have no caviar.
I have oat bran. It's better for your heart.
He was very eloquent on the subject
of love, didn't you think?
Yeah. I wish I'd read him
before I got married. You know?
Would've saved me
a gall bladder operation.
- What did you say?
- Nothing.
You know, he wrote a very interesting
book on human relationships.
He speaks very, very highly
of love at first sight.
My ex-husband and I fell in love at first
sight. I should've taken a second look.
No. Actually, it was my fault
as much as his.
I notice you still wear a wedding ring.
Any reason for that?
Well... I don't know. I guess
I'm just not ready to take it off.
It's good. It keeps me
from being asked out on dates.
You must have had a terrible marriage
if you don't want any dates.
Well, no... I mean, he was great.
He was very brilliant. He's an architect.
Real handsome and everything.
But if you're gonna have an affair, not
with my best friend in my four-poster bed.
And they didn't have to finish
all my pistachio nuts.
That inconsiderate?
I hope it hasn't soured you
on marriage or men.
- I can hear myself sounding like a bore.
- Just the opposite. Hello.
Yeah, she's here. How'd you know?
Hold on one second.
It's Lester.
Hello.
Yeah?
Sure, if you want me to.
OK. At the office? At what time?
- Nine?
- Nine o'clock? The building'll be dark.
The floor's dark. There's nobody
at the office. The office is closed.
You'll be in a dark room with Lester.
Yeah, the office is
kind of spooky at nine o'clock.
- Definitely.
- Sure. The hotel's even nearer.
- Don't go to the hotel.
- What was that?
OK. Room 1911. Sure.
OK, I'll see you there. OK.
You're not gonna go to the hotel with him.
It's crazy. I'd better go with you.
- Come on. Don't be ridiculous.
- He won't keep his hands off you.
He'll get you in a room, read you your
Miranda rights and tear your clothes off.
- He wants to produce something of mine.
- Your first child.
I've never been seduced by a guy
who wears loafers and no socks.
- Much less one who says "nucular".
- He also says "foilage".
- I don't like this.
- Why have you got Singin' in the Rain?
It's the one print that I own.
It's a very good 16mm print. I play it every
couple of months to get my spirits up.
You know, I saw it I don't know how many
years ago. I remember loving it.
They play it on television frequently.
You wanna watch it? I could
play it on this thing reel by reel.
- Wanna have dinner?
- Don't you have anything to do?
No, no. And, you know,
you got till nine o'clock.
Why not? There's an lndian restaurant
right near. I'll send out. We could...
~ All I do is dream of you
the whole night through
~ With the dawn, I still go on
dreaming of you
I love this lndian food.
It's great.
Want some more tandoori mouse?
Just kidding.
- You want some of the curry?
- Too hot, too hot.
My teeth are melting.
Boy, this is the perfect way
to see this movie.
It's great, isn't it?
When you see Lester later, be careful.
This guy tells you
he wants to exchange ideas
when what he wants is to exchange fluids.
- Yes?
- I have a delivery of some flowers.
So Chris and you
can't agree on your honeymoon.
We can agree. We've talked about a lot
of different places. It's just that...
I told Chris, and I told you before,
I want to go someplace warm.
But I also wanna do things like hike...
- You know, I hadn't thought of Australia.
- Not Australia.
I should've done what my friends told me.
Just go where we first wanted to go.
- Where did you first wanna go?
- We wanted to go to ltaly.
Dad, it's Jack. He's on the phone.
- Who?
- Jack.
Well, go to Venice, Florence, Rome,
and do what you want to.
We can have sun, we can have snow,
we can have everything we want.
- All my friends have gone to ltaly.
- You won't go there cos your friends did?
I just wanted you to know
everything came out fine.
It's over and done with,
so you can forget about it.
Oh, my God.
I'm in shock, Jack.
Judah, I'm telling you,
it's like the whole thing never existed.
It's a small burglary. Nothing more.
Yeah. So go on back to your life
and... put it behind you.
I can't speak.
I need a drink.
What am I gonna do?
I've got guests here now.
Jack... God have mercy on us, Jack.
Mom, you told me that Mary
has been having acupuncture.
- She's tried it.
- Yeah, for a few months.
She hasn't gone back. She stopped.
Is everything OK, sweetheart?
You look kind of upset.
I'm fine. It's just Jack.
She still wears a collar when she drives.
She can't look around.
- But it's done a lot. I'd consider trying it.
- What about Oriental medicine?
I have a friend who consulted
a Chinese physician with an eye problem.
And he inserted a cat's whisker
into her tear duct.
She's been tellin' this story all week long.
- Well, it cured her.
- It did?
But you told me also he uses wires, too.
In acupuncture, you use needles.
- But very fine.
- That's a different procedure.
What do you think, Judah?
Judah?
Judah, what do you think?
I think I've done
a terrible thing.
What's wrong, honey?
I...
I left these papers at the office
which I absolutely need tonight.
I can't believe I did this. How negligent
of me. I've never done this before.
- I've got a major conference tomorrow...
- No, darling, you can't get them tonight.
I have to because
I've got an hour's work to do.
- But we're in the middle of a dinner party.
- I'm so sorry. Please forgive me.
- Don't apologise.
- I don't like him driving at night.
Stanley, I'm so sorry about this,
but I have to get these papers.
- Would you like some company?
- No, not at all.
- Darling, forgive me.
- Chris will take you.
It was a wonderful evening,
and if you're here when I get back...
- Thank you.
- Don't worry. We're fine.
I do apologise. Let's just finish the coffee,
sit down and... he'll be back.
I'll say it once again:
the eyes of God see all.
Listen to me, Judah. There is
absolutely nothing that escapes his sight.
He sees the righteous
and he sees the wicked.
And the righteous will be rewarded,
but the wicked will be punished
for eternity.
Hello?
Hello. Hello?
I want your opinion. I'm doing a special
on jazz. I'd like to know what you think.
I admire her opinion so. Did you tell him
I wanna produce your idea for a series?
- No.
- It's great.
She wants to do a different Chekhov story
every month. He wrote a million of 'em.
- That's very sweet of you.
- I'm putty in your hands.
- What'll I do with a handful of putty?
- She's always got a zinger.
This vixen, this minx.
We should be going cos we have to pick
up those airsick bags we talked about.
I've got to get up at dawn
and teach Emily Dickinson to
upper-middle-class crack addicts.
- One of my favourite poets.
- Me, too.
- Because I could not stop for Death...
- He kindly stopped for me.
The word "kindly", right?
The carriage held but just ourselves
And lmmortality.
We slowly drove, he knew no haste,
And I had put away
My labour, and my leisure too,
For his civility.
- Lester was a great English student.
- Not that I graduated.
It's amazing. I couldn't graduate, and
the same school now teaches a course
in existential motifs
in my situation comedies.
- Really?
- Where'd you go to college, Halley?
- Columbia.
- You went to Columbia?
- What'd you major in?
- Law. I graduated from the law school.
- You didn't practise?
- Yes, I did. But then, you know,
I met my husband and...
we moved to Europe for a while.
It's a long, boring story.
I wish you'd go back to your old job.
I used to edit newsreel footage so...
You know, floods and fires
and famines. It's depressing.
- We don't all have to go, you know.
- No, I do.
We'll go. You two stay.
You have business to talk over, right?
- I could go with you, if you like.
- Let's just go, OK?
- Let's go someplace quiet for a drink.
- I wouldn't mind that.
- I'm just exhausted.
- From what? It's early.
- Some other time.
- One little drink.
Really. Some other time.
Jesus. Lester was so pushy tonight.
He comes on with Halley like
it's business, but he's after her.
Oh, please. She really likes him. I can tell.
- You've gotta be kidding. She likes him?
- What's not to like?
- He's attractive, he's rich, he's charming.
- He's your brother. You're prejudiced.
She put him down pretty good
when he said "Let's go have a drink."
I loved the way she said
"Some other time."
- Fine. Enough already.
- That was pretty witty.
- What makes you think she likes him?
- Didn't you see her staring at him?
She probably can't believe her eyes.
You wouldn't pick up on it
if it hit you over the head.
You're not at all romantic.
That's the problem.
Hey, honey, you're the one
who stopped sleeping with me.
It'll be a year on April 20. I remember the
date exactly, cos it was Hitler's birthday.
I'm not discussing that any more.
I don't wanna talk about it.
I'll bet she's having a drink with him now.
For how much?
I'm serious. For how much?
You really know how to get my goat!
Hi. It's Clifford.
Yes, I knew you'd be in.
I just... You know.
Tonight was a lot of fun.
Wasn't Lester... so silly?
I mean, the guy is so self-important.
He was pushing all night.
I was frankly embarrassed for him.
What is he doing there?
You're talkin' business at 12 midnight?
Well... Gee, that could be very dangerous.
You want me...
You want me to come over?
OK. If you can handle it.
OK. I'll see you tomorrow.
I'm completely in love with Halley,
and Lester is startin' to make his move.
He wants her just
for a conquest. I can tell.
You know, it's so shallow,
and I'm crazy about her.
How can I compete with the guy?
He's rich and famous and successful.
- Come on. He's no competition for you.
- God bless you for saying that.
But you'll find, as you go through life, that
great depth and smouldering sensuality
does not always win, I'm sorry to say.
Meanwhile, his brother Ben, the rabbi,
he's a wonderful guy.
He called me last night. He's going blind.
He's got a terrible eye disease.
He's gonna be blind in a few months.
And he's got a great attitude.
He's really a mensch.
All right. Look left.
Now straight ahead, Ben.
Now to the right.
That's good.
My mother said that
I should go to the doctor,
because I was... My eyes weren't so good.
Well, you're an ophthalmologist.
Do you agree the eyes
are the windows of the soul?
Well, I believe they're windows,
but I'm not sure it's a soul I see.
My mother taught me I have a soul,
and it'll live on after me when I'm gone,
and if you look deeply enough
in my eyes, you can see it.
So what's the verdict?
Cos I'd like to get this resolved
before my daughter's wedding.
- Julie's getting married?
- Time passes quickly, doesn't it?
Remember she was just a baby?
Well, yours, too.
- Yes.
- Are you OK, Judah?
- Yeah.
- You don't look so good.
I'm fine.
I just haven't been sleeping that well.
Tell me... if I'm not prying... did you ever
resolve your personal difficulties?
Yes, actually.
It resolved itself.
The woman listened to reason.
Did she?
That's wonderful. So you got a break.
Sometimes to have a little good luck
is the most brilliant plan.
Judah, relax. You're white.
You're gonna have a breakdown. It's over.
What do you expect me to be?
My old self?
I jump when the phone rings.
- No good can come of this, Jack.
- Don't be so guilty. I kept you uninvolved.
The guy who's responsible is gone.
He's back in New Orleans.
It's pure evil, Jack.
A man kills for money.
He doesn't even know his victims.
He kills, you pay him
and then he... he kills again.
What was your alternative?
How did I get in so deep? I...
What dream was I following?
Judah, you said it yourself a million
times. You only go around once.
Jack, I went to her place after.
I had to retrieve
some incriminating things.
I saw her there... just staring up.
An inert object.
There was nothing behind her eyes
if you looked into them.
All you saw was a
black void.
Can I help you?
I used to live in this house once.
Really? When?
Many years ago.
My brother and l
used to race through these rooms.
He was a wonderful kid, my brother.
We were very close in those days.
My father had high hopes for him,
but it never seemed to... work out for him.
Would you mind if I just take a minute?
Everything seems to be
flooding through me.
Sure.
Come on, Sol. Get on with it. I'm hungry.
- Do you mind, May?
- It's nonsense anyway.
Why put us through this mumbo jumbo?
Bring on the main course.
I apologise for my disrespectful sister.
This is the twentieth century.
You have young boys sitting here.
- Don't fill their heads with superstition.
- The intellectual. The schoolteacher.
Spare us your Leninist philosophy
just this once.
Afraid if you don't obey the rules
God'll punish you?
- Not me, May. He punishes the wicked.
- Who? Like Hitler?
- We're having a Seder!
- Six million Jews burned to death
- and they got away with it.
- How did they get away with it?
Come on, Sol, open your eyes!
Six million Jews and millions of others.
- And they got off.
- How could humans do such a thing?
Because might makes right.
- Until the Americans marched in...
- I don't like this talk at my Seder.
OK, OK! All right!
I think this is interesting.
You know, there's this joke about
the prizefighter who enters the ring.
And his brother says to the family priest
"Father, pray for him."
The priest said "l will.
But if he can punch, it'll help."
What are you saying, May? You challenge
the whole moral structure of everything?
What moral structure? Is that the kind
of nonsense you use on your pupils?
Do you not find human impulses
basically decent?
- There's basically nothing.
- Such a cynic, my sister. A nihilist.
- Back to Russia!
- Well... Listen.
I happen to agree with May
when it comes to all that mumbo jumbo.
How can you say that? You come
to every Seder. You pray in Hebrew.
Yes. I'm going through the motions.
It's like any ritual. It's a habit.
What are you saying, May? There's
no morality anywhere in the whole world?
For those who want morality,
there's morality.
- Nothing's handed down in stone.
- Sol's kind of faith is a gift.
It's like an ear for music,
or the talent to draw.
He believes. You can use logic
on him and he still believes.
Must everything be logical?
And if a man commits a crime,
if he... if he kills...
- One way or another he will be punished.
- If he's caught, Sol.
If he's not, that which originates from a
black deed will blossom in a foul manner.
- You're relying too heavily on the Bible.
- No, no, no.
Whether it's the Old Testament
or Shakespeare, murder will out.
- Who said anything about murder?
- You did.
Did l?
And I say,
if he can do it and get away with it
and he chooses
not to be bothered by the ethics,
then he's home free.
Remember,
history is written by the winners.
If the Nazis had won, future generations
would see World War ll quite differently.
Your aunt is a brilliant woman, Judah,
but she's had a very unhappy life.
And if all your faith is wrong, Sol?
Just what if, huh? If?
I'll still have a better life
than all of those that doubt.
Wait a minute. Are you telling me
that you prefer God to the truth?
If necessary,
I will always choose God over truth.
I agree with him.
I say what goes around comes around.
- Are you OK?
- Yes.
- I was worried. It's late.
- I had some business.
- Mrs. Ames is waiting.
- Any messages?
Yeah. An odd one.
A Detective O'Donnell called.
He wanted to talk to you about something.
I tried to get him to tell me what,
but he said he only wants to talk with you.
~ He says "Murder", he says
~ Every time we kiss,
he says "Murder", he says
~ Keep it up like this
and then "Murder", he says
~ In that impossible tone
~ Will bring on
nobody's murder but his own
That was not such a great movie,
but it was fun.
Yeah, I liked it. I think maybe
when l' m older, I wanna be an actress.
Don't be an actress. I want you to be
on the Supreme Court, or a doctor.
You know, show business is dog-eat-dog.
It's worse than dog-eat-dog. It's dog
doesn't return other dog's phone calls.
Which reminds me,
I should check my service.
Though I haven't had a message
in seven years.
I call up and I hear the girls giggling.
- How's Halley?
- She's great.
I'm gonna make my move there, I think.
But I have this ethical dilemma cos I'm
married. You shouldn't know about that.
Clifford Stern. Any messages?
Can you check, please?
My heart says one thing.
My head says another.
Very hard to get your heart and head
together in life. Let me teach you that.
Mine aren't even friendly.
Yes.
Really?
No.
OK, thank you.
What's wrong?
Professor Levy
committed suicide.
But we must always remember
that we, when we are born,
we need a great deal of love
in order to persuade us to stay in life.
Once we get that love
it usually lasts us.
But the universe is a pretty cold place.
It's we who invest it with our feelings.
And, under certain conditions,
we feel that the thing
isn't worth it any more.
I came as soon as I heard.
I thought you might not wanna be alone.
God, it's been terrible. You know?
I called... The guy was not sick at all.
And he left a note, a simple note:
"I've gone out the window."
This is a major intellectual, and this is
his note. What the hell does that mean?
This guy was a role model.
You'd think he'd leave a decent note.
Did he have family or anything?
No. They were all killed in the war.
That's what's so strange.
He's seen the worst side of life.
He always was affirmative.
Always said yes to life. Yes, yes.
Now today, he said no.
Can you imagine his students?
How shattered they're gonna be?
I don't know from suicide.
Where I grew up in Brooklyn,
nobody committed suicide.
Everyone was too unhappy.
Boy, this will put a damper on the show.
I got 600,000 feet of film on this guy
and he's telling how great life is,
and now what am I gonna do?
I'll cut it up and make it into guitar picks.
I was thinking. No matter how elaborate
a philosophical system you work out,
in the end, it's gotta be incomplete.
I've been so annoyed all day.
I'm sorry for seeming cranky.
- I understand.
- This was such a blow.
I just thought
you might want some company.
No, don't do that.
It's something that
I've wanted to do now for weeks.
- You must know that.
- You're married.
Yes, I'm married,
but that's not gonna... last.
- I mean, you know...
- Well, you know, I'm... I'm not ready.
Is there something you're not telling me?
- No.
- Is there anybody else?
- I just don't want you to say it's Lester.
- It's me. It's just me.
I... I guess I haven't
gotten over my divorce yet.
And also, I feel unsettled about my career.
You don't know this
but I'm very ambitious,
and that's an area
that I'd like to get consolidated.
I just feel, you know, unsettled.
- Don't confuse me.
- I'm not trying to confuse you.
I don't know what I'm doing.
I better go. I should just leave.
- You just got here.
- I know, but l... you know.
- I'm sorry. I didn't mean to...
- No, that's OK. It's not... I'll see you soon.
I'll just... I'll be seeing you.
Please come in.
We read about it in the paper.
It's a terrible thing.
She'd been coming here for years.
- Please sit down.
- Thank you.
Just a couple of questions, Doctor.
The record shows that she phoned you
here and at your home a number of times.
She was worried about her eyes.
- What was she suffering from?
- Nothing serious. She...
She had light flashes
and they alarmed her.
I could never find
anything very wrong with her.
And I told her that
it's just a common occurrence.
- She was a hypochondriac?
- No, I wouldn't say that but
she was concerned.
And there's nothing she ever said
that might be relevant to the case?
Personal life? Friends?
No. Not really.
How did she come to you?
You know, I honestly can't remember.
- Possibly another patient.
- Can I get that name?
Well, it was a while ago
and l... I treat so many patients.
Might it be in your records?
No. No, l... I doubt it very much.
- Well, I'm sorry to take up your time.
- That's all right.
If you remember anything,
will you give me a call?
Sure.
- Thank you.
- Pleasure.
Judah, you're having a breakdown.
The police know she phoned me.
I lied, but they saw through it.
- I can't take this, Jack.
- Pull yourself together or you'll blow it.
I did it, and it's irrevocable,
and now I'm gonna pay.
I had to fight an urge to confess
to the police. I want this off my mind.
Listen. I'm in this with you. I helped you
out and I don't wanna go to jail for it.
You may not care if you drag me down
with you, but I'm not letting that happen.
- What the hell is that? A threat?
- Just be a man. You're in the clear.
- You'll rub me out, too?
- Don't talk nonsense.
What did you mean by saying
you won't let it happen?
You're my brother.
You've helped me out financially.
I did you a favour when you needed it.
Now all of a sudden you want to confess?
The time to confess was to Miriam,
about your mistress. Not about this.
This is murder. You paid for it,
I engineered it. It's over. Forget about it.
One sin leads to a deeper sin.
- Now you sound like Papa.
- Adultery, fornication, lies, killing.
- Shut up already.
- Or you'll have your friends shut me up?
One phone call,
like pushing a button, right?
Judah, I don't know what's wrong with
you these days. You're a different person.
I believe in God, Miriam.
I know it... because without God
the world is a cesspool.
You're drinking steadily and every day.
You never used to. It's something new.
- God, it's hot in here.
- Well, maybe we should go.
- Don't tell me what I should do, dammit!
- Judah, will you calm down!
I don't feel well. I'm gonna get a little air.
No, you stay here.
Look, this story on the homeless,
it's too long.
I want five pages. Make sure
he gets five real pages out of it.
He tells the secretary to type it tighter.
He doesn't take anything out.
I want Joe Hanson off the show.
He doesn't write funny. If he has cancer,
I'll send him flowers. I want him off.
Jesus! Doesn't anybody
know how to write funny any more?
Am I supposed to write it myself?
Direct it myself? Produce it myself?
I can 't believe this! Look at those people
out there! Look out the window at them.
These people are lookin '
for something funny in their lives!
You're givin' 'em straight lines!
They're waitin' for something funny!
This is terrible.
What are you doing to me?
This is supposed to be
the profile of a creative mind.
It's tough for a woman in this profession.
I can make it easier for you.
What is this? When did you shoot that?
I was lurking around the corner.
I couldn't resist.
I don't wanna do it in kind of a vulgar way
and just take it off what I see here.
I wanna find out what's in here,
so I gotta spend some time with you.
We 'll have a little dinner together, just...
OK, step aside. I' m taking over this film.
- What? You can't finish my film.
- I can't? Read your contract.
- You promised.
- Look, the idea was to show the real me.
I may not be perfect, but I don't promote
values that... Let me quote you exactly:
"that deaden the sensibilities
of a great democracy".
You're fired, Cliff!
You're out! Get outta here!
Go! Thank you! Goodbye!
If it bends, it's funny. If it breaks, it isn't.
Come on now. Don't get discouraged.
You have your own personal vision.
Why is he so upset? You'd think nobody
was ever compared to Mussolini before.
I had no idea you would cut the film like
this. I'd have told you they'd never use it.
They want an upbeat profile of Lester.
Now he's gonna re-cut it
and make himself into a saint.
Wendy's right. I'm probably jealous
of him. His limos, his money, his women.
You have your own style.
Hey, listen. Marry me. I'm serious.
That's the only thing that'll satisfy me.
I'm crazy about you. You're single.
My marriage won't last.
I gotta talk to you. Can we just...
Can we sit down here for a second?
I'm not joking. I'm really nuts about you.
I'm going away.
Yeah? Meaning what?
I've... I'm... I've got a chance
to produce a couple of shows in London
and I couldn't say no.
So how long are you going for?
Well, probably three or four months.
Three or four months?
Jesus, you're kidding.
What a discouraging thought.
But, you know,
I think it's a good thing, because I ne...
Well, it'll give me a little distance.
About 3,000 miles, to be exact.
- When are you leaving?
- I guess... ten days or so.
God, I'm...
God, I'm gonna miss you.
I don't know what to say. I just...
I'm not gonna see you
for three or four months?
I feel like l... you know,
like I've been handed a prison sentence.
Ben, your daughter
will make a beautiful bride.
This is Barbara,
the sister of my brother-in-law.
Congratulations.
I wish your daughter all the happiness.
Jesus. I'm so self-conscious.
Every single thing on me is rented.
I got a rented tux,
rented shoes, rented underwear.
You look terrific. Cliff, do me a favour.
This is your last occasion with my family.
Could we try to get along?
And this is Dr Rosenthal.
I'm Miriam.
- And this is Marion, and this is Peter.
- How do you do? A pleasure to meet you.
- Judah?
- Yes, Ben.
Judah, I'm so glad you could make it.
It means a lot.
What is the matter with you?
You seem so depressed.
Wendy and I finally decided
to call it quits.
Even though the last couple of years have
been terrible, it just makes me feel sad.
- I'll have a vodka and tonic.
- I'll have one, too.
But, you know, you told me
it's been platonic for a year.
And I say once the sex goes, it all goes.
It's true. Last time I was inside a woman
was when I visited the Statue of Liberty.
Look at your father.
He's celebrating enough for two.
He and Ben will get high
and argue about belief and God.
My father takes after his Aunt May.
She rejected the Bible because she said
it had an unbelievable central character.
I walked in. I said "The Waldorf-Astoria.
The centrepieces." Did you see them?
- Beautiful.
- Everything matches. Lester paid for it.
Hard to believe
a brother would pay for a wedding.
Hard to believe, but that's the sort of thing
Lester is always doing. Isn't it?
He must be a good brother.
I'm gonna get one like that.
It's much better. This is very square.
- Hi, Cliff.
- Cliff. Hello.
Lester. How are you? Good to see you.
- My fiancee, Halley Reed.
- Congratulations. My wife Nancy.
- When'd you get back?
- Got back this morning.
- I've been trying to call you all day.
- I finally won her heart.
What a romantic story.
We ran into each other in London
and I sent her white roses
around the clock, all the time, for days.
For days. And then
I found out she was allergic.
- Hi, Lester.
- Hi. Good to see you.
So, I started pleading with her. I begged
her. I just... begged her day and night.
And I think it was the caviar that did it.
I tell you, I've envied this guy for years.
He'd show up with a beautiful woman
every time. But I envy you more now.
Thank you.
Standing here in the presence of God,
the guardian of our homes,
ready to enter into the bonds of wedlock,
answer each of you in reverence for God
and in the hearing of the assembly that
have gathered here so joyously with you.
- I know the perfect guy for you.
- Who?
- He's brilliant. He's attractive.
- There's a hitch. I'm waiting.
There's a hitch, but it sounds
worse than it is. He's in prison.
- Rita, I would say that's a drawback.
- Nothing terrible. Insider trading.
He made a fortune in the market.
And he'll be out soon.
Very soon. A couple of years.
You mean with good behaviour.
Cliff?
I wanted to talk to you.
What is there really to say?
You know, I'm just stunned still.
He's not what you think.
He's wonderful. He's...
He's warm and caring and...
- romantic...
- He's a success. That's what he is.
- He's rich and he's a success.
- Give me a little credit.
I always did give you
a little credit, until today.
We used to laugh at this guy. The silly
shows he puts on, the way he talks.
He's endearing.
This is my worst fear realised.
I wanted to give you this letter back.
- It's my one love letter.
- It's beautiful.
I'm just... the wrong person.
It's probably just as well.
I plagiarised most of it from James Joyce.
You probably wondered
why all the references to Dublin.
Look, l...
I hope we can always be friends.
Off by yourself, huh? You're like me.
I always get sad at these kind of events.
You look very deep in thought.
I was plotting the perfect murder.
Yeah? Movie plot?
Movie?
Ben... That's what Ben told me.
He says you make films.
Yeah, but not that kind... You know.
A different kind.
I have a great murder story.
- Yes?
- Great plot.
Yeah.
Hey, I've had too many to drink.
I mean, forgive me.
I know you want your privacy.
No, it's OK. You know.
I'm not doing anything special.
Except my murder story has
a very strange twist.
Yeah?
Let's say there's this man
who's very successful.
He has everything.
- Let me ask you something.
- What?
Am I a phoney?
- Am I a phoney?
- Are you a little high or something?
- No, I'm... I think he hates me.
- Who hates you?
- Your annoying husband.
Every time I'm with him, I get tense.
- It's just that he's angry.
- At what?
Are you kidding me? He's got these
fantasies about changing the world.
He makes these films
and they come to nothing.
Listen, honey. He's gotta grow up.
This is the real world. This is the big time.
They don't pay off on high aspirations.
You gotta deliver.
Not to mention... You're still young.
You're not gettin' the life that you deserve.
Lester, I met somebody.
That...
That is music to my ears.
And after the awful deed is done,
he finds that he's plagued
by deep-rooted guilt.
Little sparks of his religious background,
which he'd rejected,
are suddenly stirred up.
He... hears his father's voice.
He... imagines that God
is watching his every move.
Suddenly it's not an empty universe at all,
but a just and moral one, and...
he's violated it.
Now he's panic-stricken.
He's on the verge of a mental collapse.
An inch away from confessing
the whole thing to the police.
And then, one morning, he awakens and
the sun is shining and
his family is around him and
mysteriously the crisis has lifted.
He takes his family on a vacation to
Europe and as the months pass he finds
he's not punished.
In fact, he prospers.
The killing gets attributed to a drifter who
has several other murders to his credit
so, what the hell,
one more doesn't even matter.
Now he's scot-free.
His life is completely back to normal.
Back to his protected world
of wealth and privilege.
Yes, but can he ever really go back?
Well... People carry sins
around with them.
Maybe once in a while
he has a bad moment, but it passes.
And, with time, it all fades.
Yeah, but... so then, you know,
his worst beliefs are realised.
Well, I said it was a chilling story, didn't l?
I don't know. It'd be tough
for somebody to live with that.
Very few guys could actually
live with that on their conscience.
People carry awful deeds
around with them.
What do you expect him to do?
Turn himself in?
I mean, this is reality.
In reality, we rationalise, we deny,
or we couldn't go on living.
Here's what I would do.
I would have him turn himself in.
Cos then, you see, your story
assumes tragic proportions
because, in the absence of a God,
he is forced to assume
that responsibility himself.
Then you have tragedy.
But that's fiction. That's movies.
You see too many movies.
I'm talkin' about reality.
I mean, if you want a happy ending,
you should go see a Hollywood movie.
Come on, darling.
Let's think about going home, huh?
Nice talkin' to you. Good luck.
Miriam, we're gonna make a wedding
like this for Sharon. And I can't wait.
She'll be radiant.
- You're looking very handsome tonight.
- And you look beautiful.
We are all faced throughout
our lives with agonising decisions.
Moral choices.
Some are on a grand scale.
Most of these choices
are on lesser points.
But we define ourselves
by the choices we have made.
We are, in fact,
the sum total of our choices.
Events unfold so unpredictably,
so unfairly.
Human happiness does not
seem to have been included
in the design of creation.
It is only we, with our capacity to love,
that give meaning
to the indifferent universe.
And yet, most human beings seem
to have the ability to keep trying,
and even to find joy,
from simple things,
like their family,
their work,
and from the hope that future
generations might understand more.