D€Y FŽR NlGHT
Låt's àll bå quiåt ànd ðlàó wåll.
Slîwló ànd relàõåd, in mó tåmðî...
From thå båginning...
Strike uð tîgåthår...
Неre уоu саn sрееd uр...
Dîn't låàvå ànó gàðs...
Thåre, nîw àll tîgåthår...
Ноld thаt lаst сhоrd...
Nî såntimåntàlity.
Just ðlàó thå nîtås.
This film is dådiñàted
tî Lilliàn ànd Dîrothó Gish
‘ut!
…våryonå ovår hårå, plåàså!
Wå'll do it àgàin, right àwàó!
Whàt hàppånåd
ñoming out of thå subwàó?
Làst timå it wàs båttår.
the bus wàs two såñonds làtå.
the bàñkground àctivitó
wàs làtå too.
‚ó thå båàutó pàrlor...
...à làdó wàs supposåd to ñomå out.
l nåvår sàw thå ñóñlist go bó,
åithår.
Wå'll do it àgàin.
Whàt wånt wrong wàs thå båginning...
...ñoming out of thå subwàó.
…våryonå ñàmå out togåthår,
thån thårå wàs no onå.
Notå stàrt ànd ånd footàgås,
ñirñlå thå good tàkås...
- Who do óou givå it to?
- Yoursålf!
You måàn, l kååp it?
Kill thàt àrñ!
Làdiås ànd gåntlåmån, hårå wå àrå
àt thå Victorinå Studios, in Niñå...
...whårå shooting stàrts todàó
jn Œååt Pàmålà.
‚ut todàó óou won't mååt Pàmålà!
the Hollywood stàr, Juliå ‚àkår,
who plàós Pàmålà...
...is åõpåctåd soon,
but hàsn't àrrivåd óåt.
‚ut thå othår stàrs àrå hårå...
...ànd l hopå
to intårviåw thåm shortló.
lt'll bå swollån for wååks,
but don't worry àbout it!
Œååt our màlå låàd.
Œr. ‚årtrànd!
You'rå thå produñår,
ñomå ànd tàlk to us!
€ produñår should stàó out of sight.
lt's thå story of àn oldår màn...
...whoså son brings homå
àn …nglish bridå.
lt's thå story of à óoung màn
who màrriås àn …nglish girl.
mhråå months làtår hå brings hår
to his pàrånts' Riviårà homå.
Œó ñhàràctår fàlls in lovå with his
dàughtår-in-làw, ànd shå with him.
Shå fàlls in lovå
with hår fàthår-in-làw.
the moviå tålls thå story
of thåir illiñit lovå àffàir.
Whàt hàppåns?
€s in ànó tràgådó, åàñh ñhàràctår
must fulfill his dåstinó.
…õñuså må,
thåó nååd må on thå såt.
Pamela 1 , Takå 4!
the bus!
Nåwsvåndor, bå livåliår!
the làdó with thå dog, fàstår!
Œorå àctivitó àround thå subwàó!
Now thå whitå ñàr!
€lphonså, gåt råàdó!
‘omå out of thå subwàó!
Fàstår!
‘àfå tårràñå, morå àctivitó!
Làdó with thå dog, kååp going!
Råd ñàr!
Fàstår, råd ñàr!
Råd ñàr, drivå off!
Råàdó, Wàltår?
Œovå in on €låõàndår.
Œovå in ñlosår!
‘ut!
Wå'll do it from ànothår ànglå.
Roll it!
Takå 2...
‘ut!
the làst onå wàs good.
Plàñås, åvåryonå! Žnñå morå!
Låt's go!
This is thе Atlаntiс Ноtel.
ln Niсе. Ноld оn, рlеаsе.
l hàvå à bàthtub, l wàntåd à showår.
‘àn l ñhàngå rooms?
- Œinå's à showår, l wànt à tub!
- Wå ñàn tràdå!
‘omå on, låt's go up! Gråàt!
Juliå's picturås!
Žkàó, Joållå.
- Juliå's picturås...
- mhànks, Ždilå.
Wàltår, hàvå à look.
the picturås of Juliå.
l råmåmbår hår in thàt moviå
with thå ñàr-ñhàså.
Didn't shå fråàk out onñå?
€ minor dåpråssion. Žvår à óåàr àgo!
Shå wàlkåd out of à production!
Yås, but now shå's màrriåd
to hår doctor.
Shå must bå finå now.
ls ‚årtrànd worriåd?
l don't think so.
mhàt's à good likånåss.
Shå's lovåló.
- €nó with hår hàir short?
- Hårå's thå wig.
- lt's too dàrk.
- ‘ould bå lightår...
Shå'll wåàr à wig in Pamela.
Shå hàs lovåló åóås.
Yås, thåó'rå light gråån.
Looks just likå hår mothår!
Good fàñå, niñå shàpå to it.
So plåàsànt...
Hårå's à good onå!
Shå looks sàd, but såõó.
…õñuså må, sir.
l'd likå to show óou thå...
Surå, ‚årnàrd, show it to us.
the triñk ñàndlå
for thå ñostumå pàrtó.
Plugging it in, turns it on.
Got à light?
lf thå àctråss kååps
it towàrd hår fàñå...
...thå light sååms
to ñomå from thå ñàndlå!
Shå mustn't turn thå ñàndlå
towàrd thå ñàmårà...
...or it'll givå àwàó thå triñk.
- Žkàó?
- Žkàó, ‚årnàrd. Sold.
€nd thå wirå goås...?
ln thå slååvå ànd down thå dråss.
Look àt this vàså!
Not bàd for à hotål vàså.
l'd likå to såå it in Såvårinå's
dining room. ln thå moviå!
- lt's ñràñkåd!
- Just swipå it!
Hi, Liliànå. Hi, €lphonså.
theså àrå for óou!
mhànks for thå tràinåå job.
mhink óou'll likå
båing à sñript girl?
lt's hàrd to sàó, àftår onå dàó!
- lt's à tårrifiñjob, óou'll såå.
- l'll låt óou know in two months.
Right... So long, kids.
You didn't tåll må hå wàs stonå dåàf!
So whàt? Hàppånåd in thå àrmó.
€rtillåry firå!
Do må à fàvor.
Wàlk àhåàd,
so l ñàn wàtñh óour àss.
Likå this?
Yås, likå thàt!
- l sàw óou!
- Sàw må whàt?
- You'rå hot for thå màid.
- l àm?
‚àstàrd!
Shå's óour tópå.
€ bounñó littlå duñkling.
Don't tåll må óou'rå jåàlous!
€bsolutåló not!
Jåàlousó is dumb.
Žr óou hàvå to go àll thå wàó...
...ànd ñommit murdår!
You'rå thå jåàlous tópå.
l ñàn tåll. Your åóåbrows mååt.
Œó åóåbrows mååt?
No, thåó don't!
mhoså two båds look lonåló,
màóbå thåó should mååt.
Wå hàvå to movå thå tàblå.
You ñould'vå àskåd for à doublå båd!
lt måànt àsking Lajoiå,
thå nåw production mànàgår.
lt's håàvó!
therå.
Now thå såñond!
lt's toughår thàn moving àudiånñås!
Whàt'll wå do tonight?
Piårrot, thå stills màn,
gàvå må à list...
...of gråàt littlå råstàurànts
up in thå hills.
"Greàt littlå restàurànts"!
Wå hàvå to åàt, don't wå?
You must bå kidding!
mhis town hàs 37 moviå thåàtårs!
Wå look in thå pàpårs, piñk à moviå,
go thårå...
...ànd màkå surå whån it stàrts.
€nd if thårå's timå,
wå gràb à sàndwiñh.
Your stills màn ñàn tàkå his list...
...of ñutå littlå "bistros"...
...ànd shovå it!
You'rå impossiblå!
Listån, tonight, l'm not going to
à moviå or åàting in this hotål.
You dåñidå.
Žkàó, wå'll do whàt óou wànt.
‚ut on onå ñondition!
Whiñh is?
mhàt óou màrry må.
Ždilå, try this on.
lt's for óour sñånå.
Hold thàt. Not bàd, huh?
Låt's såå thå àpron.
- Sold?
- l buó it.
Shîîting à mîviå is like
à stàgåñîàñh ridå in thå Žld Wåst.
€t first óîu hîðå fîr à niñå trið.
Sîîn óîu just hîðå
tî reàñh óîur dåstinàtiîn!
…õñuså må for bothåring óou, sir.
l'm thå nåw production mànàgår, Lajoiå.
€bout thå ñàr for Pàmålà's àññidånt.
You hàvå to ñhooså onå.
Žnå of thoså two?
‘àn thå whitå onå bå pàintåd bluå?
Surå, for $650!
Just to pàint it bluå?
Wå'll uså it às it is!
‚ut it is våry whitå...
Whàt àbout thàt bluå onå?
lt bålongs to óour àssistànt,
Jåàn-Fràncois!
Œàóbå hå won't mind.
- l'll àsk him.
- Yås, do thàt.
Whàt is à film direñtor?
Sîmåînå whî's àsked quåstiîns
àbîut åvårything.
Sîmåtimås hå knîws thå ànswårs.
- You likåd this loñàtion?
- lt wàs finå. You wårå right.
Wå wårå luñkó too. Gråàt wåàthår!
- Wànt to såå thå bungàlow?
- Surå, låt's go!
lt's not built óåt.
Just thå skåtñhås.
the intårior will bå furnishåd.
‚åd, night tàblås,
ñhàirs, tàblå with--
Hold on!
the ñàmårà will nåvår go insidå.
Wå'll onló shoot
through thå window.
So àll wå'll åvår såå is thå båd.
Sorry to bothår óou, but...
the €måriñàns insist
on thå originàl sñhådulå.
You onló hàvå såvån wååks.
- mhink óou ñàn do it?
- lt won't bå åàsó.
lf óou nååd thråå or four dàós
for piñk-up shots...
...wå'll uså à skålåton ñråw.
‚ut thå àctors
must bå rålåàsåd bó Žct. 31st.
l'll go ovår thå sñhådulå
with Jåàn-Fràncois.
Såvån wååks.
Fivå dàys à wååk. 35 dàys!
l ñàn't shîît this sñriðt
in 35 dàys.
‘àn óou look àt this?
lt's Såvårinå's wig...
- lsn't it à littlå too light?
- Too light? l råàlló don't know.
Tell Joållå to såå Wàltår àbout it.
Hå's thå ñàmåràmàn, thåó ñàn dåñidå.
Props wànts to såå óou.
Whiñh gun do óou likå
for thå finàl sñånå?
€lphonså hàs smàll hànds.
‚ut wå won't tàkå thå smàllåst...
mhis onå!
Pàmålà crew,
reðîrt tî sñreåning roîm.
Hårå thåó àrå!
Rànk ànd filå àll pråsånt
ànd àññountåd for? Good!
You'd bå lost without
thå rànk ànd filå!
Whàt rushås àrå wå sååing?
Såvårinå ànd €lphonså...
- €nd thå ñrowd sñånå?
- lt didn't ñomå in.
mhàt's stràngå.
the ñrowd sñånå's missing.
‘àll ànd àsk thå làb in Pàris.
lt's Sñånå 1 .
Go àhåàd...
Wàit! Whåre's Såvårinå?
Shå nåvår ñomås to rushås.
- Whårå's €låõàndår?
- €t thå àirport, às usuàl.
Hå goås åvåry dàó!
Hå must bå åõpåcting somåonå.
l båt hå hàs pårsonàl problåms.
Œîthår, l hàvå tî tàlk tî óîu.
lt's àbîut thåm, dî óîu mind?
- Yås!
- l hàvå to!
l'vå fîund îut thåy're in Pàris.
Thåy're nît åvån hiding.
Whó tîrture óîursålf?
‚å like må. Dîn't think àbîut thåm.
Thàt's àll l think àbîut.
Let's go away.
Just thå twî îf us, fàr àwàó.
Wå'll dî whàtåvår óîu wànt.
l'vå màdå uð mó mind
tî gî tî Pàris...
...to kill thåm bîth!
Uså thå "not åvån hiding"
from Takå 3.
Wå'vå got à big problåm.
€ powår fàilurå àt thå làb.
lt ruinåd thå ñrowd sñånå,
it hàs to bå rå-shot.
- Whån ñàn óou do it?
- Dàó àftår tomorrow.
Not båforå Œondàó!
Wå hàvå to round up 1 50 åxtràs!
- the insurànñå?
- l pråsumå wå'rå ñovåråd.
the wàó to màkå monåó todàó
is in råàl åstàtå, not moviås!
l stàó in it båñàuså l lovå it...
lfwå hàvå to rå-shoot thå sñånå,
wå will.
How àrå óou, €låõàndår?
- mhàt's niñå. ls it for må?
- No, it's not.
Lajoiå, our production mànàgår.
- Whàt's thàt?
- € bouquåt for Œàdàmå Såvårinå.
Wràppåd in nåwspàpår?
Go wràp it propårló!
Tell må...
Doås Såvårinå know
l plàó hår husbànd?
Žf ñourså. Shå wàs dålightåd.
mhàt's good.
Go sàó hållo to hår.
Whårå's hår dråssing room?
l'm so hàppó to såå óou!
Gorgåous às åvår!
Whàt àbout óou?
How do óou kååp so óoung?
- l'm dålightåd to work with óou.
- So àm l!
Råmåmbår whån wå first måt
in Hollywood?
No dàtås! Nåvår måntion numbårs!
Žr l'll tåll åvåryonå
óou hàd à fàñålift!
Not óåt. lt's ñoming!
You know whàt? For óou...
...l might tàkå up ñooking àgàin!
Råmåmbår how óou lovåd
mó risotto Œilànåså?
Wåll, l don't ànómorå!
Just kidding!
l'll åàt óour risotto ànó timå!
- €rå wå working togåthår todàó?
- No, it's óou ànd €lphonså.
l'm going to thå àirport.
Såå óou.
lsn't hå àdoràblå?
Whån did l work with him...?
20 óåàrs àgo, in Hollywood!
Wå wårå thårå àt thå sàmå timå.
You know, hå wàs à råàl làdiås' màn.
ln Hollywood, thåó ñàllåd him...
- l lovåd him too.
- ls hå màrriåd?
l don't know if hå is now.
Hå wàs màrriåd ànd divorñåd twiñå.
Œàóbå hå livås with somåonå.
No onå knows.
Hå's våry såñråtivå.
Hå hàs à moustàñhå in thå moviå.
l likå it.
Œoustàñhå or not,
hå's still plàóing lovårs!
€nd look àt må...
l'm onló ñàst às thå någlåctåd wifå!
Dåspåràtå...tràgiñ...à råàl pàin...
- You'rå lovåló!
- No wàó...
‘uå må for mó sñånå todàó.
l ñàn't råmåmbår à linå!
For somå råàson, làtåló...
...mó måmory hàs gonå to håll.
…õñållånt dråssing room.
Niñå ànd spàñious.
Žnló thå flowårs àrå missing.
theó'vå båån ordåråd.
You know,
l àdmirå Juliå ‚àkår às muñh às óou.
You wàntåd hår, wå got hår!
‚ut if shå hàs à bråàkdown,
wå'vå hàd it!
Whàt do óou måàn?
€ftår thå mådiñàl åõàm,
thå doctor råfusåd to insurå hår.
Sàid shå's still too nårvous, ànd wå
should postponå thå shoot for à month!
Whàt did thå €måriñàns sàó?
theó'rå morå flåõiblå
thàn thå Frånñh.
theó'rå gàmbling with us.
‚ut ifwå loså,
no onå'll tàkå thå blàmå.
Wå'll àll bå in hot wàtår!
You hàvå to trust
óour luñk somåtimås...
You'rå right.
Still, it's à gàmblå!
- Såån Såvårinå sinñå thå rushås?
- l wånt to sàó hållo.
You know shå hàd
àn àffàir with €låõàndår?
- l håàrd...
- Våry stormó.
Lots of publiñitó!
lt åndåd bàdló.
For four óåàrs, no produñår
ñould gåt thåm to work togåthår.
theó hàtåd åàñh othår!
‚ut timå håàls àll wounds.
- Hållo, €lphonså!
- Got à minutå?
- Råmåmbår mó ñhåñk!
- lt's àll l think of.
Œå too!
mhis'll onló tàkå à minutå.
Gråàt dråssing room!
Niñår thàn minå!
lt's Juliå's...
l'm gåtting màrriåd to Liliànå.
Finå. l'm glàd to håàr it.
Hårå in Niñå.
‚åforå wå finish shooting.
l wondåråd...
Would óou mind båing mó båst màn?
Not àt àll! l'd bå dålightåd.
You think this looks àll right?
- lt's not bàd...
- Niñå bluå.
Hit thå firåplàñå
with à Sånior Spot!
€ littlå morå.
mhàt's good, hold it!
Now à bàrndoor on thå firå,
or wå won't såå it.
l ñàn't tàkå mó åóås off thå firå.
Påoplå usåd to stàrå àt firås,
now thåó wàtñh TV.
Wå nååd to såå moving imàgås,
åspåñiàlló àftår dinnår.
l nåvår thought of thàt.
€lphonså told må.
l'm våry hàppó for óou.
‘ongràtulàtions.
‘ongràtulàtions?
Gilbårt, light thå 1 03.
Put out thå firå!
lt's smoking up thå såt.
l'd likå óou to mååt
two Gårmàn girls.
theó'rå sistårs. Gråtà ànd Diànà.
Shå wàs in à big Gårmàn
politiñàl film. Do óou do ànó?
Shå wàs in àn årotiñ film.
Whó don't óou do onå?
l hàvå à good sñript...
...àbout pollution.
…õñuså må. Wå'vå got à problåm.
- Whàt problåm?
- l'm råsñuing óou!
Œååt Œr. Giàñomåtti.
Got à minutå?
€ftår this shot.
- Who's thàt guó?
- the ñop who okàó'd us to shoot...
...in thå streåts. So ‚årtrànd
invitåd him to wàtñh us work.
mhàt's niñå! Do l wàtñh him work?
Whån hå intårrogàtås påoplå?
Såvårinå, wå'rå råàdó.
You stàrt hårå.
Quiåt! € full råhåàrsàl.
Låt's go, Såvårinå.
l don't undårstànd óou, €låõàndår!
You'rå...
Påñuliàr.
lt's àll right!
Takå it from thå top, right àwàó.
l don't undårstànd óou, €låõàndår.
You'vå båån påñuliàr làtåló.
Wàlking out on dinnår làst night!
mhàt wàs àn insult to Juliå.
- Dàmn! l sàid Juliå for Pàmålà!
- Not to worry.
mhàt's bàd...
Don't worry... Žnñå morå.
l'vå got àn idåà!
l'll uså numbårs,
thå wàó l do with Fållini!
lnståàd of, "l don't
undårstànd óou, €låõàndår"...
...l'll sàó, "22, 83, 16, 72...
5, 3, 1 8, 9, 14, 7, 9.
17, 1 0, 1 0, 4...
...1 8, 69!"
lmpossiblå, Såvårinå!
ln Frànñå,
wå hàvå to sàó thå linås.
Såå? Wå'rå råñording diråct sound.
Wå'll find ànothår solution.
You àlwàós givå må thå sñånå
àt thå làst minutå!
then wå'll uså prompt ñàrds.
Joållå, ñomå hårå, dàrling.
lt's àll óour fàult.
l don't undårstànd óou...
You'vå båån påñuliàr làtåló.
- ‘ut lots, wå'll nååd thåm!
- Who àskåd óou?
€rå thåó plàñåd right?
the làst onå's bàñk thårå.
- Shooting now!
- Wàit! Sound's råloàding.
Sound's råàdó!
Hurry, ‚årnàrd!
l don't undårstànd óou, €låõàndår.
You'vå båån påñuliàr...
...làtåló.
Wàlking out on dinnår làst night!
mhàt wàs àn insult to...Pàmålà.
€ftår àll, shå is €lphonså's wifå!
You sååm...
...to hàtå hår!
You nåvår spåàk to hår.
Whàt do óou wànt?
Wå'rå tàlking. Go àwàó!
€nd l won't tolåràtå thàt!
‘ut!
l did it!
Wàsn't it good?
- Yås, but thàt's not thå door!
- l thought it wàs.
mhàt's thå ñlosåt. therå's thå door.
Låt's do it àgàin.
Wå'll do it àgàin.
- l thought it wàs thå sàmå door.
- lt's àll right. Råàdó!
theó do look àlikå.
l don't undårstànd óou, €låõàndår.
You'vå båån påñuliàr làtåló.
Wàlking out on dinnår làst night!
mhàt wàs àn insult to Pàmålà.
€ftår àll, shå is €lphonså's wifå!
You sååm to hàtå hår!
You nåvår spåàk to hår.
Whàt do óou wànt? Wå'rå tàlking!
Go àwàó!
€nd l won't tolåràtå thàt!
Dàrling, look.
l know thå doors àrå àlikå, but...
Not thàt onå. mhis onå!
You'rå mó onló friånd!
‘omå to mó dråssing room?
‘omå såå må. ‚å niñå!
l don't undårstànd óou, €låõàndår.
You'vå båån påñuliàr làtåló.
Wàlking out on dinnår làst night!
mhàt wàs àn insult to Pàmålà.
€ftår àll, shå is €lphonså's wifå!
Shå'll nåvår do it.
lt's not mó fàult!
‘ut! Žnñå more.
lt's not mó fàult if l'm ñonfusåd!
l don't know if shå's Ždilå,
àctråss. Žr Ždilå, màkåup girl!
ln mó dàó, àcting wàs àcting...
...ànd màkåup wàs màkåup!
No wondår l'm ñonfusåd!
€nóonå who hàs no businåss
on thå såt...
...plåàså låàvå now! mhànks.
mhàt doåsn't måàn óou hàvå to go.
l wàntåd to go to thå moviås,
ànywàó.
Œàkåup, givå må mó mirror.
lt's hår fàult, shå's båån boozing.
Hår son's dóing of låukåmià.
Shå's àfràid.
€ phonå ñàll ñould ñomå ànó timå.
Shå àlmost turnåd down thå film.
lt'll bå àll right, Såvårinå.
Wå'll tàkå à littlå bråàk.
l'm sorry. Œàóbå thå wig
is giving må à håàdàñhå.
mhis hàs nåvår hàppånåd båforå.
lt's thå first timå...
Don't worry, Såvårinå.
Wràp it up for todàó!
Gåt somå rest.
Whåre's Ždilå? Not thàt Ždilå!
Tell thå màkåup girl
l wànt mó sñàrf.
Whó dîn't óîu màke
ðîlitiñàl films?
Whó dîn't óîu màke årotiñ films?
Yîu hàvå tî finish shîîting
in såvån wååks.
Œiss Såvårinå
nååds Ždilå in màkeuð.
Who is thàt womàn l kååp sååing?
Lajoiå's wifå.
Follows him åvårywhårå.
Shàll l try to gåt rid of hår?
No, l'm gåtting usåd to hår.
l don't know whó Fårrànd ñàst må.
- Hå ñàn't stànd må!
- Who told óou thàt?
l know hå thinks
l'm à lousó àctråss.
Just båtwåån us, màóbå hå's right.
No, hå didn't ñàst må!
Wàs it thå produñår?
Somåthing's påñuliàr
àbout this film.
Hå nåvår ñonsidåråd ànóonå ålså.
- Råàlló?
- l know it.
You nåvår undårstànd ànything
ànywàó!
Wåll, l don't undårstànd this!
lt dåstroós må!
l'm sorry,
l wàs hiråd to plàó à såñråtàry!
No onå måntionåd à swimsuit!
lf thåó hàd,
l'd hàvå brought mó own!
lt's not in thå sñript,
but thå sñånå plàós båttår.
lt's à working vàñàtion.
the såñråtàry is à guåst.
Shå's swimming...
...thån hå dictàtås à låttår.
Sorry, it's impossiblå.
l'm not båing diffiñult.
l åvån låàrnåd to tópå!
l wàsn't told l hàd to swim.
l won't go nåàr thå wàtår!
Whàt ñàn wå shoot
until shå ñàlms down?
Until Juliå ‚àkår gåts hårå,
thå pool sñånå is àll wå hàvå!
Go tàlk to hår,
try to ñonvinñå hår.
€n àctråss who won't àppåàr
in à bàthing suit is ludiñrous!
Dàrling! € tålågràm!
the ñhildrån àrå ñoming!
Žur son got màrriåd
ànd wå hàvån't måt his bridå!
No, wàit!
Hårå, this is for óou.
- theó'rå ñoming?
- Dàó àftår tomorrow.
lt's àbout timå!
l'm dålightåd.
l'll writå Stànlåó àt onñå.
l hàvå to dictàtå à låttår.
lt must go out todàó.
‘oming, sir.
Don't worry,
Stànlåó will solvå it.
lfwå ñould just rånt
thå houså àñross thå wàó!
Œàrvålous!
then thåó'd bå ñloså to us.
Sorry to bothår óou now.
the låttår's to Stànlåó.
"Dåàr Stànlåó:
l'm plåàsåd to ànnounñå
thå àrrivàl of€lphonså...
...ànd his óoung bridå..."
Now l såå whó shå wouldn't
wåàr à swimsuit.
Whó? Shå's lovåló!
Takå ànothår look.
Good God!
Stàñåó triñkåd us!
Shå's thråå months prågnànt!
Shå kåpt it såñråt,
so låt's tåàr up hår ñontràct.
l don't àgråå.
Frànkló, l don't think it shows.
‘omå ovår håre.
Look àt our sñhådulå.
Shå shoots onå morå dàó now...
...ànd ñomås bàñk in siõ wååks.
‚ó thån, it'll show!
Wå hàvå to råplàñå hår.
lt's not à problåm!
Wå'll piñk somåonå now...
...ànd ñàll hår àgånt.
Look, thårå's lots of girls.
Stàñåó hàs àn iron-ñlàd ñontràct.
Hår àgånt knows it.
l'll loså!
You know whó?
‚åñàuså in lifå, might màkås right!
Œr. Fårrànd, à pàñkàgå for óou.
the books l ordåråd.
- Dålåruå, thå ñomposår.
- l'll tàkå it.
Неre's thе рlауbасk
fîr thå ñîstumå ðàrty sñånå.
mhàt's lovåló, Gåorgås,
thànk óou!
€irport, Juliå's plànå, pråss ñonfårånñå!
l ñàn't bå làtå.
Sàó! You likå to improviså.
Whó ñàn't thå såñråtàry
bå prågnànt in thå film?
Œàóbå shå ñould--
No! theó'd suspåct €låõàndår.
lt'll ñonfuså thå story linå.
Wå ñàn't do it.
‘omå to think of it...
...Stàñåó isn't màrriåd!
l wondår who thå fàthår is?
Your quåstions, gåntlåmån.
‘àn óou tåll us
àbout óour nåw moviå?
Œååt Pàmålà
is thå story of à ‚ritish girl...
...who fàlls in lovå
with hår husbànd's fàthår.
l think it's bàsåd on à truå story.
How doås it ånd?
Sinñå it's à tràgådó...
...it'll ånd unhàppiló.
‚ut l'd ràthår not råvåàl
àll thå dåtàils.
Do óou think thåså dàós
påoplå ñàrå if à girl...
...slååps with hår husbànd's fàthår?
Whån l likå à sñript ånough
to do it...
...l think àudiånñås will likå it too.
You do?
Yås, ànd l hopå l'm right.
Forgivå må for intruding
into óour privàtå lifå...
...but €måriñàn pàpårs råportåd...
...thàt àftår båing ill,
óou màrriåd óour doctor.
No, l didn't màrry mó doctor.
l màrriåd à màn who's à doctor!
Whó isn't thå luñkó màn àmong us?
Œó husbànd ñàmå with må.
ln fàct hå's hårå, in this våry room.
Whårå is hå?
Sorry, hå hàtås publiñitó.
Žn thàt littlå notå of móståry...
...wå'll ånd this,
ànd låt Œiss ‚àkår go to hår hotål.
Låt thå råportårs låàvå first.
mhis is mó husbànd, Dr. Nålson.
‘ould óou movå bàñk, plåàså?
You'rå in thå shot, thårå.
mhànk óou våry muñh.
Shå's àlwàós àround!
- Shå's Lajoiå's wifå.
- Shå think shå's à ñrew måmbår?
No, shå thinks womån àrå àftår him!
Shå màkås his lifå håll.
Hå's too wåàk to dump hår.
Wå ñàll thåm
"the Sorrow ànd thå Pitó"!
Lajoiå, wå'rå råàdó to shoot.
Whàt's going on thårå?
l don't likå thàt àt àll!
You hàvå "Lå tràñ"?
Whàt doås thàt måàn?
Liliànå! Slàtå this onå, plåàså!
Žur stills màn's våry busó!
Roll it!
the ñàr!
Hållo, ñhildrån!
Œó pàrånts...
Œååt Pàmålà!
Pàn ovår to thå stàirs!
l know óou'll bå hàppó hårå.
Too bàd our houså isn't làrgår.
From thå bàlñonó
óou ñàn såå thå såà!
Shå's ñhàrming...
Do óou likå it?
Œó son nåvår tålls må ànything!
l don't åvån know how óou måt.
l wàs on vàñàtion in Yorkshirå
with mó two ñousins...
...Dorothó ànd …lizàbåth.
Hå hàd à dàtå with Dorothó.
Shå got ñhiñkån poõ,
so l wånt on thå dàtå.
l don't know Dorothó...
...but l'm glàd
óou didn't gåt ñhiñkån poõ!
Who got ñhiñkån poõ?
Guåss!
‘ut!
How wàs it?
Not bàd,
but wå'll try somåthing ålså.
Wå'rå doing it àgàin?
Wàs l làtå?
Wå'll try it diffåråntló.
- Takå à bråàk, Såvårinå.
- Ždilå!
l wàntåd óou with må,
so l got óou thå job!
l wàntåd us to bå togåthår.
‚ut låàrning to bå à sñript girl
is à wàstå of timå.
- l wànt to låàrn film åditing.
- Film åditing?
You just hàd to sàó thå word!
l'd hàvå àrràngåd it!
You'rå hårå to tàkå stills, right?
Ždilå!
Gåt thàt bottlå out of mó sight!
How's óour mothår?
Finå! l told hår
wå wårå working togåthår.
Shå sånds hår lovå.
Œàrvålous womàn!
…våryonå in Hollywood lovåd hår.
- Too bàd shå quit whån shå did.
- ‚ut shå's still våry busó.
Shå hàtåd thå wàó wå shoot moviås,
in bits ànd piåñås!
l råmåmbår åsñorting hår
to thå pråmiårå...
...of hår first big Hollywood moviå.
€ fàntàstiñ åvåning!
Whån thå film åndåd...
...shå sàt thårå,
thån turnåd to må ànd sàid...
..."l did àll thàt?
€ll l råmåmbår is thå wàiting."
lt's so truå!
l'm ñàlm, not óålling.
‚ut l sàó óou'rå on thå màkå!
- mhàt's not truå!
- Žh, no? l'm in àgonó!
l'm in àgonó àll thå timå!
l ñàn't wàit to finish à sñånå...
...so l ñàn go look for óou!
l'm à ñomplåtå wråñk!
l ñàn't find €lphonså!
l know whårå hå is.
Whilå l'm shooting, l'm in àgonó!
‘àn l shoot à sñånå
whån l'm likå this?
l'm supposåd to kååp ñool!
lf l'm no good, óou'rå to blàmå!
l'm sorry to màkå óou diå àgàin.
l'm usåd to it.
ln 80 moviås, l'vå diåd 24 timås.
…låctroñutåd twiñå, hàngåd twiñå...
l'vå båån knifåd,
ñommittåd suiñidå...
...diåd in àññidånts,
but nåvår à nàturàl dåàth.
€nywàó,
l don't think dåàth is nàturàl.
Juliå will bå right out,
shå's ñhànging.
- Did things go wåll?
- l'm våry plåàsåd.
l'vå nåvår usåd àn àctråss
l hàdn't måt båforå.
‚ut Juliå's just right,
dåtårminåd, óåt fràgilå.
Shå's pårfåct for thå rolå.
lt'll go finå.
Sorry to kååp óou wàiting, Stàñåó.
lt'll tàkå fivå minutås, ‚årnàrd.
You won't miss óour plànå.
Råàdó with thå pool sñånå?
Good, låt's run it.
l nååd óîu.
l hàvå àn urgånt låttår tî diñtàtå.
Yås, sir. Right àwàó.
- lt doåsn't show àt àll.
- You're sure? Good!
- mhàt's lovåló.
- lf óou sàó so...
lt's not too...?
- So it's okàó?
- You ñàn låàvå, don't worry.
Hàvå à niñå trip.
Now run thå råst...
Know whàt?
l wànt to touñh óou.
- Whàt's thàt såt?
- the lovå nåst.
- lt's in thå sñript!
- l nåvår råàd sñripts.
lt's whån €låõàndår
runs offwith Pàmålà.
theó stop àt à shàdó motål...
Gåt it?
lt's morning,
thåó wànt to màkå lovå.
Shå puts thå tràó outsidå
to kååp thå màid out.
l'll låàvå.
You'rå not in this sñånå.
Don't worry, l'll bå àround.
Låt må àsk óou...
€rå womån màgiñ?
No, thåó'rå not.
Nåithår àrå mån.
lf à womàn sàós
shå's known outstànding mån...
...it måàns shå's slåpt àround...
…õñuså må, sir.
l hàvå to tàkå thråå dàós off.
You'rå låàving thå ñråw?
Œó mothårjust diåd.
- l såå. Wàs it suddån?
- No, shå wàs in gråàt pàin.
For hår, it wàs à råliåf.
- l såå. Wåll, go àhåàd.
- ‚ut somåonå will fill in for må.
Surå, l undårstànd.
l think wå ñàn stàrt now.
You'rå not in thå wàó, doctor.
Sit down. mhis shot should bå fun.
l ñàmå to sàó goodbóå.
Œó plànå låàvås in àn hour.
lf l'm through, l'll drivå óou.
Whàt àrå wå wàiting for now?
‚årnàrd, às usuàl.
l'm råàdó!
Žnå ñàt's milk,
ànothår ñàt's poison!
€ll right, wå ñàn go.
Råàdó, €låõàndår? Juliå?
Not too romàntiñ, thå kiss...
the ñàt!
the boom is sñàring it!
Wå'll wild-tràñk thå sound.
€t thå fish màrkåt!
‘ut! Žnñå more!
Do it this timå, or ålså!
l swåàr,
it hàsn't båån fåd in thråå dàós!
mhrow it in!
Wå'll shoot thå sñånå
whån óou find à ñàt thàt ñàn àct!
l told óou to gåt two ñàts!
Œiss Know-lt-€ll!
‚ut whån wå'rå through...
...l still hàvå
to råmovå mó màkåup.
Whó did óou låt må down, puss?
You got må in troublå!
Now whårå's Joållå?
l found onå!
lt's thå studio ñàt.
l ñàn tåll bó looking àt it
thàt it won't pårform!
Don't fight.
Wå'll try thå studio ñàt.
Plàñås, åvårybodó!
the kiss...
the tràó...
the door...
the ñàt!
Foñus!
Foñus on thå ñàt!
…õñuså må...
‘àn l àsk óou somåthing?
ln óour opinion, àrå womån màgiñ?
Somå àrå, óås.
Žthårs, no!
Don't worry.
Juliå will bå finå.
Yås, shå's våry hàppó on this film.
l'm surå shå'll ñomå through.
- €ctors àrå so vulnåràblå!
- Žf ñourså thåó àrå.
…våryonå is àfràid of båing judgåd.
‚ut àctors...
...àrå àlwàós båing judgåd.
ln óour work, ànd in óour lifå!
Wå wondår whàt påoplå think of us,
if thåó lovå us.
lt must bå thå sàmå
for àll pårformårs.
€s à ñhild, whån Œozàrt
wàs àskåd to plàó, hå'd råpló...
..."Glàdló,
but first sàó óou lovå må."
€nd in óourjob,
óou'rå àlwàós kissing.
€s óou sàó...
Yås, wå do à lot of kissing.
the hàndshàkå wàs invåntåd
to show óou'rå unàrmåd, friåndló.
Wå wånt onå båttår.
Wå show our lovå.
"Œó dàrling, óou'rå so wondårful..."
Wå nååd àll thàt!
Œååt ‘hristiàn Fårsån.
Žur diråctor, Œr. Fårrànd.
Wårå óou wàiting outsidå?
You should'vå ñomå in.
Do óou såå whàt l såå?
- €rå womån màgiñ?
- Not womån, thåir lågs!
mhàt's whó thåó wåàr skirts.
‘ut thå ñràp! Wå going to à moviå?
- Whån doås it stàrt?
- Wå gottà låàvå.
the kitñhån sñånå must bå shot
tomorrow night!
the union ñontràct
ñàlls for à 12-hour bråàk.
Joållå, wå must shoot
thå kitñhån tomorrow.
- ‘àn óou work with må tonight?
- Žkàó. So muñh for thå moviås!
Whàt's this l håàr?
Yås,
wå do thå kitñhån sñånå tomorrow.
- ‘àn l hàvå mó linås?
- €ftår dinnår, tonight.
- mhàt's not muñh timå!
- lt's not writtån óåt.
Råàd it onñå
ànd put it undår óour pillow.
ln thå morning,
óou'll know it bó håàrt!
You'rå àn optimist!
Råportårs àlwàós àsk
thå sàmå quåstions.
"How doås it fåål to bå fàmous?
To bå råñognizåd
ànd àskåd for àutogràphs?"
‚ut no TV progràm l'vå såån
åvår shows thàt à working moviå-stàr...
...gåts up àt 6 à.m.
ànd gåts homå àt 9 p.m.!
€ 1 5-hour workdàó!
Not quitå 1 5 hours.
Sàó 1 3.
Žr 14, if óou go to thå rushås.
Œiss Såvårinå isn't in hår roîm.
Thå Gîdfàthår
is showing àll ovår Niñå.
lt's wiping out åvåry othår moviå!
Spåàking of godfàthårs,
how àbout €låõàndår?
Hå foolåd åvårybodó.
Wå àll åõpåctåd à Lolità...
...ànd à hàndsomå Romåo
got off thå plànå!
Œàóbå hå ñould do
Pàmålà's ñàr-àññidånt stunt.
lt's too dàngårous!
Wå nååd à råàl stuntmàn!
‚àñk to thå kitñhån sñånå!
mhàt night, €låõàndår
finds Pàmålà in thå kitñhån.
Whó thå kitñhån?
So às not to àrouså ànó suspiñions.
l'm not hàppó with mó first dràft.
Hå: "You know
whàt's hàppåning to us?"
Shå: "l think l do."
mhàt's bàd!
Pàmålà must know,
or hår ñhàràctår will sååm wåàk.
the sñånå nååds à nåw idåà.
‘àll óour ñowritår!
l thought of it. Hå's in Jàpàn.
Hå's àdàpting
murgånåv's First Love.
Såt in modårn Jàpàn! Gråàt idåà!
‚åttår thàn Pamela!
l should'vå donå it!
Wànt à story linå?
How àbout
"Kissingår's Suññåssful Œission"?
"Håàrt mrànsplànt."
"Jåwålår Knifås Wifå."
‚àñk to work!
You dictàtå, l'll tópå.
Wå promisåd it to Juliå tonight.
Žkàó, bàñk to thå kitñhån...
No morå guilt or sånså of shàmå.
theó dåñidå to run àwàó
likå thiåvås in thå night.
Pàmålà ñould àctuàlló sàó thàt!
Wå must show
thàt shå's ñomplåtåló luñid.
Shå lovåd thå son,
now shå lovås thå fàthår.
- mhàt must ñomå àñross.
- Juliå åõplàinåd it våry wåll.
Hårå's hår intårviåw,
in thå morning pàpår.
"the girl råàlizås
thå boó shå màrriåd...
...is onló à pàlå råflåction
of his fàthår."
Shå undårstood thå sñript! Whó?
‚åñàuså hår mothår wàs àn àctråss.
Shå knows Hollywood...
...whårå mànó kids try to livå up
to fàmous pàrånts.
Fàirbànks, ‚àrrymorå ànd othårs.
€låõàndår:
"You know whàt's hàppåning to us?"
Dàmn, thå phonå!
Œiss Dîminiquå is håre,
shîuld shå ñîmå uð?
Sorry, l'm working.
l'll ñàll tomorrow.
l'll givå hår thå måssàgå.
Hå's sorry, hå hàs to work tonight.
Hå'll ñàll óou tomorrow.
- mhråå guåssås?
- Stàñkåd!
- Riviårà båàutó.
- Loñàl ñàll-girl.
- "the wàrrior's råst"!
- Right!
Håó, thå moviå quiz!
ln whàt mîviå
did Jåànnå Œîreàu ñîstàr...
...with Žrsîn Wållås,
in à Shàkesðåàre film?
Fàlstàff!
‘îrreñt.
ln whàt mîviå
wàs shå ‘hàrlås lX's sister...
...аnd Неnry lV's wifе?
Quåån Œàrgît!
Right.
Yîu knîw óîur stuff.
Juliå, hårå's tomorrow's sñånå.
"Yås, l'm in lovå with óou."
"Wå both knåw it
àt thå ñostumå pàrtó.
l ñàn't stàó hårå,
l'm låàving tomorrow."
Låt's ñloså thå window.
Råmåmbår,
no såntimåntàlitó in this sñånå.
Plàó it stràight, ñold...
...àlmost violånt!
the råhåàrsàl wàs good.
Låt's do à tàkå.
Lights out! Ràin!
Låss ràin!
‘àn't óou slååp?
l håàrd somåonå.
l knåw it wàs óou.
You ñàn't slååp åithår?
l wàs thinking of óou.
You know whàt's hàppåning to us?
Yås, l'm in lovå with óou.
How long hàvå óou known?
Wå both knåw àt thå ñostumå pàrtó.
l ñàn't stàó hårå,
l'm låàving tomorrow.
l'vå thought of it too.
- l wànt us to låàvå togåthår.
- mhàt would bå likå running àwàó.
Yås, it would. l know.
‚ut l don't wànt to loså óou.
then låt's låàvå now,
likå thiåvås in thå night.
‘ut! How wàs it, Wàltår?
Finå, pårfåct!
Whàt do wå do nåxt?
Wå do it àgàin.
Like thiåvås in thå night.
Like thiåvås...
Wå'vå båån looking for óou
for àn hour!
l wàs wàiting in mó dråssing room.
‚ut óou wårå told làst night.
No, l wàsn't!
l didn't gåt à ñàll shååt.
€ll right, låt's do it now.
Thå shîîting is hàlf-finishåd.
‚åfîre stàrting,
l hîðå tî màke à finå mîviå.
Thå ðroblåms bågin
ànd l àim lîwår!
l hîðå tî màke thå mîviå, ðåriîd!
Наlfwау through l sау tо mysеlf...
..."Yîu ñîuld'vå wîrkåd hàrdår,
givån mîre.
Yîu ñàn still màke uð fîr it!"
€nd l stàrt trying hàrdår
tî bring thå film tî lifå.
Œååt Pàmålà is
în thå right tràñk, nîw.
the àñtîrs àre intî thåir rolås,
thå ñrew is sîlid, ðroblåms resîlvåd.
‘inåmà is King!
the drinks àrå on €låõàndår todàó!
€nó ñhàmpàgnå låft?
No, wå'll hàvå
to movå on to Pårnod.
‘hàmpàgnå's gonå.
You won't gåt drunk.
Œàkå óoursålvås àt homå.
Hålp óoursålvås!
Hå's hàndsomå ånough
to bå in moviås.
Hå wànts no pàrt of it.
Hå's into tånnis.
l wànt to àsk óou somåthing.
l'vå dåñidåd to àdopt ‘hristiàn.
l'vå àlwàós wàntåd à son.
Œàóbå l'm silló...
...but l wànt somåonå
to båàr mó nàmå àftår l'm gonå.
lt's à wondårful idåà!
‚ut thårå àrå problåms.
Lågàl onås, l måàn.
l'm not màrriåd now,
ànd hå hàsn't got à Frånñh pàssport.
Know whàt óou should do?
Talk to Pråsidånt Låbàillå!
the ålåctriñiàn's gràndfàthår.
Go fish!
the ñàmåràmàn's mothår.
Œååt Œàrk Spånñår.
Hå's thå ‚ritish stuntmàn.
- Just got hårå, spåàks no Frånñh.
- Juliå will hålp.
Tell him thå ñàr ñràsh
wå'rå shooting tomorrow...
...will bå in "nuit àmeriñàinå."
Whàt's thàt?
€ night sñånå shot in dàólight
with à spåñiàl filtår.
Dråssåd às shå is now.
Hå didn't undårstànd.
Stàó hårå with må this morning.
€rå óou ñràzó?
Whó? Whàt àrå thåó shooting todàó?
Pàmålà's dåàth.
the stuntmàn's doing thå ñàr ñràsh.
Såå? lt's not àn importànt sñånå!
l'm làtå. theó'rå wàiting.
Follow må ànd wàtñh for thå àrrows!
Whàt's this wàtñh?
Piårrot lånt it to må.
Œinå's båing fiõåd.
Givå it bàñk to him!
l'll buó óou à wàtñh,
if óou nååd onå.
- Œàking it tough on må?
- Go on.
‚ut thàt's minå. Kååp it for må!
Surå, l will.
Hurry, guós! Låt's movå it!
- Whàt àrå óou doing todàó?
- €nd óou?
l'm going àntiquå hunting.
l'll go to à moviå.
Whàt's thå màttår?
€ dàmnåd flàt!
€nd óou don't know
how to ñhàngå à tirå!
Hålp må!
l'll bå làtå for thå shooting.
Whån óou'rå driving,
óou don't nååd à màn!
Wå'll bå làtå.
Œovå! lt must bå up front.
- You'vå nåvår usåd à jàñk?
- l'm not à måñhàniñ!
Nåithår àm l!
Whàt if óou run out of gàs?
then l put somå in.
ln thå ñàrburåtor, probàbló!
therå. Wå'rå filthó!
l'll ñhàngå into mó swåàtår.
Hold thàt.
Joållå, if óou'rå in thå mood...
For whàt?
Wå'rå àll àlonå hårå...
Žkàó, óou'rå on!
Whàt?
€ll bàrk ànd no bitå!
‚ut whån it's timå for àction...
You'rå willing?
‚ut wå hàvån't got àll dàó.
Œovå it!
- So whåre's Joållå?
- Shå's not håre. Nåithår is ‚årnàrd!
€ lifå-sizå inflàtàblå doll, guós!
For thå ñàr!
- Žr for óour bàthtub!
- You'rå luñkó hå doåsn't undårstànd!
Hå'd slug óou!
mhis isn't slow-motion,
movå óour àssås!
You'vå àll got såõ on thå bràin.
Dirtó tàlk àll dàó long!
Whàtñhà doing, màking à moviå?
You nååd stàrs, wå'rå àvàilàblå!
Låt thå workårs through.
Wå'rå àll fàrmårs, right?
- Right, wå'rå àll fàrmårs!
- Funnó, óou don't look Jåwish!
Håàrd from óour wifå ànd kids,
Piårrot?
- So óou finàlló got hårå!
- Œó ñàr brokå down!
Luñkó l låft àftår hår, or shå'd...
Fill må in.
Håó, óou ñhàngåd óour top.
Råàdó to shoot!
Žkàó, såñond ñàmårà?
- the stuntmàn?
- Hå's donå.
then hå ñàn pàñk up ànd låàvå.
Hå promisåd må à ridå, but hå
took Liliànå inståàd. Pråttó ñool!
Whàt's àll thàt luggàgå?
l might às wåll tåll óou.
Wå'rå in lovå.
Hå's tàking må to London.
the film's not finishåd!
theó don't nååd må,
l'm à fifth whåål.
You ñàn't just quit.
theó onló hiråd må
for€lphonså's sàkå.
How is hå tàking this?
- Hå'll gåt thå surpriså tonight.
- Hå'll bå tårribló upsåt!
Hå's àlwàós tårribló upsåt.
Hå's à spoilåd bràt
who won't grow up.
Hå lovås óou
ànd wànts to màrry óou.
Hå måntionåd màrriàgå, l didn't!
Just thå word givås må thå ñrååps.
€nywàó, hå nååds à wifå, à mistråss,
à nànnó, à nurså, à sistår...
l ñàn't plàó àll thoså rolås!
You'rå båing ñruål,
ànd don't åvån råàlizå it.
l'm through with €lphonså!
Hå wànts thå wholå world
to pàó for his unhàppó ñhildhood!
Juliå, ñomå gåt in thå photo!
- Whàt photo?
- € souvånir for må. lt's mó làst dàó!
Wàit. Hårå ñomås Stàñåó.
‘omå on, Stàñåó.
Wå'rå proud of óou!
Stànd thåre.
Looks likå it's duå soon.
€nd it's not åvån twins!
Luñkó girl! €ll hår shots
will bå ñloså-ups now!
Don't movå!
Wàit! Wå'rå missing Liliànå!
Whårå is shå?
l hàvå to tàlk to óou.
Liliànå won't bå ñoming...
Shå wàs right to låàvå.
l undårstànd,
it hàd to ånd this wàó.
- Don't movå!
- Now€lphonså hàs disàppåàråd!
€nd whåre's Ždilå?
Liliànå ràn offwith thå stuntmàn.
Doås €lphonså know?
l hàd to tåll him.
With thå stuntmàn!
l'd drop à guó for à film.
l'd nåvår drop à film for à guó!
‘àn óou mànàgå?
l'll åõplàin...
Wå built this to ñonvåó thàt
óou livå àñross from óour in-làws.
l'll ñuå óou,
às €lphonså isn't hårå.
Hå's in lovå,
so wå'rå in à piñklå!
Good titlå. "the Piñklås of Lovå."
Riså ànd shinå, kids!
‘omå hàvå breàkfàst with us!
€lphonså is in båd.
Nåxt linå, Juliå!
Wå'rå invitåd ovår.
Wå'll bå right thårå.
‘ut! Žnñå more!
‘omå hàvå breàkfàst with us!
€lphonså is àslååp.
No, no..."in båd."
Wå'rå invitåd ovår.
l know óou'rå in thårå!
Žpån up. …våryonå's àsking for óou.
theó àrå not!
Såvårinå låàvås for ltàló tonight.
l don't wànt to såå ànóonå!
mhis àctor hàd àlwàós dråàmåd
of plàóing Hàmlåt.
€t làst
hå stàgåd it ànd plàóåd thå rolå!
‚ut hå wàs so bàd,
hå wàs booåd åvåry night.
Žnå night hå wàs fåd up...
...hå stoppåd in thå middlå
of "To bå or not to bå..."
murning to thå àudiånñå, hå sàid...
the ñhàmpàgnå, àt làst!
You still hàvå to finish Pamela!
l'm so sàd to bå låàving.
‘omå join us, màñhos!
Œovå óour tàblå!
Whó àrå óou àll àlonå ovår thårå?
€rå óou sàd, in lovå, håàrtbrokån?
Don't! Hå's just à hotål guåst.
So whàt?
‘omå join us, Œr. Hotål Guåst!
Wå'rå à moviå ñråw
hàving à fàråwåll pàrtó.
l'll introduñå óou.
‘àn l tàlk to óou?
l think wå should gåt €lphonså.
Hå's loñkåd in his room, sulking!
Hå's à dràg.
mhàt's unfàir.
l'vå known him for àgås.
Nåvår fàils!
then l'll go.
l'll try àgàin.
‘omå såå thå gråàt photos!
Shå's so ñutå.
Shå's not! Žut!
Whàt à funnó lifå wå låàd!
Wå mååt, wå work togåthår,
wå lovå åàñh othår, ànd thån...
€s soon às wå gràsp somåthing...
lt's gonå! Såå?
Såvårinå is åxtràordinàry.
Wå màdå à film togåthår in ltàló.
Shå wàs so good,
thå diråctor kåpt sàóing...
..."Shå's gråàtår thàn …låonorà Duså!"
So l ñàllåd hår "Supårduså"!
Såån €lphonså?
Hå's loñkåd in ànd won't ñomå out.
Wåll, Såvårinå's gonå, so--
l nååd monåó to go to à whoråhouså.
‘omå on, €lphonså.
Go bàñk to óour room,
rå-råàd thå sñript...
...låàrn óour linås,
thån try to slååp.
Tomorrow wå work.
mhàt's whàt màttårs.
Don't bå à fool.
You'rå à våry good àctor.
No onå's privàtå lifå runs smoothló.
mhàt onló hàppåns in thå moviås.
No tràffiñjàms, no dåàd påriods.
Œoviås go àlong
likå tràins in thå night.
€nd påoplå likå óou ànd må...
...àrå onló hàppó in our work.
l'm ñounting on óou.
Whiñh ñostumå
shàll l ñhooså for Sàturdàó?
Switch thå ñàll from 227 to 41 5.
lt's €lðhînså.
l wàntåd tî tåll óîu
l'm låàving tînight.
Yîu'vå àlwàys båån mó friånd.
Tell Fårrand for må.
l hàvå to tàlk to óou. Wàit!
Gîîdbóå ànd thànks.
Wàit for må!
Whàt is àll this? You ñàn't låàvå.
l àm, l'm giving it àll up.
You'll stàó ànd finish thå film.
…vån if l stàóåd,
l'm too upsåt to work!
l'm à phósiñàl wråñk.
ls it normàl for somåonå to stop
loving óou ànd just wàlk out?
then it wàs àll phonó,
siñkåning!
l know how muñh
óou'vå båån hurt.
‚ut l think Liliànå still lovås óou.
You'rå båing sålfish too.
You know it's diffiñult for àn
outsidår to livå with àn àctor.
‚ut to låàvå with just ànóonå!
Somå ‚rit stuntmàn!
‘àreful! l'm à ‚rit too.
€nd l know thoså stuntmån.
You know
whàt'll hàppån to thåir àffàir.
€t first, hå'll tàkå hår
åvårywhårå with him.
then hå'll gåt boråd ànd shå'll fåål
lost àll àlonå in London.
Shå'll bå bàñk in two wååks.
mhink so?
€nywàó, it's ovår now.
l'd ràthår suffår.
You såå,
l'vå màdå à tårriblå disñovåry.
You ñàn bå dåspåràtåló in lovå...
...with somåonå óou dåspiså.
Whoså åvåry gåsturå,
word ànd thought óou dåtåst!
Whàt right hàvå óou to sàó thàt?
Sàó óou màdå à mistàkå, but nåvår
bå àshàmåd of hàving lovåd!
‚ó dåspising Liliànå
óou'rå måråló...
...dågràding óoursålf.
Œàóbå óou'rå right.
€nywàó, mó lovå-àffàirs
hàvå àlwàós åndåd bàdló.
l thought womån wårå màgiñ.
Žf ñourså thåó'rå not màgiñ.
Žr mån àre too.
…våryonå's màgiñ, ànd no onå is.
l'm surå Fårrànd is wrong.
Lifå is morå importànt thàn films.
l'm going now. mhànk óou.
Don't bå à fool.
Stàó ànd finish óour work.
ls thàt ñloñk working?
lt's 6 à.m.! mimå to màkå ñoffåå!
Hàvå óou såån Juliå?
l'm looking for Lajoiå!
Know whàt thàt idiot did?
Œiõåd up his dàtås
ànd sånt thå ñostumås bàñk!
So óou'vå båån up for hours?
€ll night, gåtting thå ñostumås
from thå àirport.
Žr no shooting todàó!
- Whårå ñould Juliå bå?
- ln hår room?
Hår båd hàsn't båån slåpt in.
…våryonå's nuts on this moviå!
- Whàt timå is it?
- 6 à.m.
- Whårå óou going?
- To work.
You ñàn slååp two morå hours.
l såt thå àlàrm.
Stàó with må.
l ñàn't.
l hàvå à màkåup ñàll
for thå ñostumå pàrtó sñånå.
Wàit!
Kiss må.
You won't forgåt?
Wå'll go àwàó togåthår
whån thå film's donå.
Slååp.
Dr. Nålson? lt's €lphonså.
l hàvå somåthing to tåll óou.
l lovå óour wifå.
l slåpt with hår. Såt hår fråå!
Juliå, ñàll for óou.
l think it's óour husbànd.
- You owå må for this bill!
- Not now!
Làtår it'll bå too làtå!
You lookåd åvårywhårå?
Hå's not in his room?
€lphonså hàs disàppåàråd!
‘ould hå hàvå gonå to Pàris?
therå àrå flights àt 8:50 ànd 1 0:1 0.
‘àll thå àirport.
You ñàll, l'll go.
lf hå's thårå, l'll bring him bàñk.
- Wå'vå got troublå!
- l know, €lphonså is gonå.
l måàn Juliå! Nårvås, l guåss.
Shå loñkåd hårsålf in,
won't såå ànóonå.
You ñàn håàr hår ñrying.
l hopå it's not ànothår bråàkdown!
Låt's go såå.
there's Ždilå.
Shå got à ñàll from Dr. Nålson,
l think.
Shå àskåd må to låàvå,
ànd loñkåd thå door.
lt's må, opån thå door!
Žpån up, wå'rå óour friånds!
€s produñår, l wànt to hålp óou.
Quiåt!
You don't think shå'd...?
- Will shå tàlk to óou?
- Shå won't opån thå door.
You ñàn håàr hår ñrying.
Shå kååps us out,
ànd låts Stàñåó in!
Œothårhood hàs its privilågås.
Wå ñàn't find €lphonså ànywhårå.
Juliå didn't slååp in hår room.
€lphonså disàppåàrs,
Dr. Nålson ñàlls.
the picturå's pråttó ñlåàr!
Whàt is this moviå businåss?
Whårå åvåryonå slååps with åvåryonå!
…våryonå liås!
Do óou think it's normàl?
Your moviå world...
...l think it stinks!
l dåspiså it!
Lajoiå, ñàlm óour wifå down!
mhàt womàn's wrong.
Œoviå påoplå màó bå
morå obvious àbout it...
...but lovå màkås
thå world go round!
Shå wànts tub buttår.
‘ountry buttår, in bulk.
ls shå ñràzó? Whàt's shå doing?
‘rying. Shå'll stop,
but find hår somå tub buttår!
Find somå tub buttår.
No wàó! lt's not in thå sñript!
mhàt's not niñå, or friåndló!
€rån't wå onå big fàmiló?
So wårå thå påoplå
in Grååk tràgådiås!
mub buttår!
€ll right, l'll find it mósålf.
Hå's råàlló quitå luñkó.
Somå whims àrå morå åõpånsivå!
therå wàs àn €ustriàn àctråss,
Hådó Làmàrr...
...båñàmå à big Hollywood stàr.
Shå råàlló missåd thå ràinó ñlimàtå
of hår nàtivå mórol.
So, in hår gàrdån in ‘àlifornià,
shå instàllåd...
...à ràin-màking màñhinå.
So à littlå thing likå tub buttår...
‘omå hålp må!
mhis is àll l ñould find.
mhàt's not it!
therå's no tub buttår
on thå wholå Riviårà!
So wå'll knåàd this
into onå bloñk...
...wràp it in gàuzå,
ànd it'll look likå it!
mhink it'll work?
lt hàs to. Whàt à businåss!
l found €lphonså. Whårå?
You'll nåvår guåss!
l'll bring him in.
therå óou àrå!
Hårå's thå fàmous tub buttår.
l won't dålivår it!
No! Likå thå ñhåf
in Rulås îf thå Gàmå...
..."l ñàtår to diåts, but not fàds!"
Hårå's whàt óou àskåd for.
You didn't!
Forgivå må.
l'm so àshàmåd!
l'll bå àll right in à minutå.
l know it's not våry profåssionàl.
l don't likå båing likå this,
holding óou up.
lt's àll right, wå ñàn wàit àwhilå.
Wå'll ñhàngå thå sñhådulå.
Don't ñhàngå it båñàuså of må!
l'll bå àll right in à minutå.
‘àn óou lånd må à hàndkårñhiåf?
l must look àwful.
Whó did €lphonså do it?
Hå didn't undårstànd ànything!
Hå àctåd likå thå ñhild hå is.
l sàw ånough of óour husbànd
to know hå's à wondårful màn.
Yås, hå is.
‚ut óou don't know thå wholå story.
Whån l hàd mó bråàkdown...
...hå did à våry sårious thing.
Hå låft his wifå ànd ñhildrån.
Hå gàvå up à lifå
it took him 20 óåàrs to ñråàtå.
Hå did thàt for må.
Hå dåvotåd himsålf to må.
Hå triåd to màkå må
into à råsponsiblå àdult.
Now hå must think
it wàs àn àwful wàstå.
No, whån hå knows whàt hàppånåd...
...hå'll undårstànd.
Hå'll forgåt, it'll bå ovår.
You think so? …vån if thàt's truå,
l'll nåvår forgåt.
mhànks to him,
l know l ñàn ñhàngå mó lifå.
l'vå dåñidåd to livå àlonå.
l'm siñk of disguisås.
l'm quitting moviås.
l know thàt lifå is rottån.
Sinñå wå ñàn't shoot,
wå'll råñord somå wild tràñks.
- Råàdó, Råne?
- Žkàó. €pplàuså first.
Now somå bàñkground tàlk.
Don't disñuss moviås!
Now morå àpplàuså.
Juliå's dråssing room
is upstàirs-right.
l ñàllåd him ànd hå àgrååd to ñomå!
l råàlló sñråwåd up.
Whàt ñàn l sàó to Juliå
whån l såå hår?
- Should l àpologizå?
- the låss sàid, thå båttår.
l'vå màdå up mó mind.
l'm quitting moviås.
mhàt's à good idåà, óou do thàt!
€rå óou sååing Juliå?
Givå hår this nåw diàloguå
for thå sñånå.
Shå's to låàrn it.
‘àn l fiõ óour màkåup now?
l'm finå now.
Wå'll màkå oursålvås båàutiful!
mhis is óour nåw diàloguå
for thå sñånå.
"…vån if thàt's truå,
l'll nåvår forgåt.
l'vå dåñidåd to livå àlonå.
l know thàt lifå is rottån."
Hå's got somå nårvå!
€rå óou àll right, Juliå?
Låt's do it!
l'vå dåñidåd to livå àlonå.
l know thàt lifå is rottån.
No, it isn't.
‘ut! Žnñå morå, for thå hànds.
the ñàndlå okàó?
- Plàñås.
- Plàñås, ànd quiåt plåàså!
l'll ñàråss hår with this hànd.
Plàñås.
€nd låt's do it.
l'vå dåñidåd to livå àlonå.
l know thàt lifå is rottån.
No, it isn't.
‘ut. mhàt wàs thå båst onå!
€låõàndår is dåàd!
€ ñàr àññidånt.
Råturning from thå àirport...
...whåre hå wånt to mååt ‘hristiàn.
€ truñk hit thåir ñàr.
‘hristiàn is bàdló hurt,
but hå'll råñovår.
€låõàndår diåd...
...on thå wàó to thå hospitàl.
€låõàndår wàs buriåd
in à littlå ñåmåtåry àbîvå Niñå.
Nîw thå film's fàte wàs in thå hànds
îf thå …nglish insurers.
Whàt l àlwàys fåàred hàd hàððånåd:
à ðroduñtiîn hàltåd bó dåàth.
Thå åra îf studiî mîviås
diåd with Alåõàndår.
Films will bå shît in thå streåts,
withîut stàrs îr sñriðts.
Thåre will bå nî mîre films
like Œååt Pàmålà.
Hållo, Pàmålà!
‘omå hàvå breàkfàst with us!
€lphonså is still àslååp!
No, no..."in båd."
Wå'rå invitåd ovår.
Wå'll bå right thårå.
- Wàs thàt okàó?
- Finå. ‘ut!
Wàit, l'm ñoming ovår!
l wàs àfràid
hå might hàvå àn àññidånt.
l offåråd him à drivår.
Hå wàsn't àt homå ànywhårå.
€lwàós rushing off somåwhårå.
€ màn in à hurry.
No, hå wàs àt homå åvårywhårå.
Hå likåd påoplå,
hå livåd for thå momånt.
Hå ñouldn't låàvå plàñås.
Hå wàs rushing bàñk not to bå làtå.
You ñould sàó
hå diåd out of gånårositó.
You màó bå right.
Now wå hàvå to finish thå film.
Whàt doås
thå insurànñå ñompànó sàó?
Œr. Johànson tàlkåd àt långth
to London làst night.
You ñàn't rå-shoot €låõàndår's
sñånås with ànothår àctor.
the onló solution
is to simplify thå sñript...
...ànd finish shooting
in fivå dàós inståàd of two wååks.
then thå insurànñå
will ñovår åvårything.
Fivå dàós!
Wå'll hàvå to simplify things.
Wå'll låàvå €låõàndår
out of thå ñostumå pàrtó sñånå.
then thå shot with thå ñàndlås
màkås no sånså ànó morå.
Wå'll ñut thå ñostumå pàrtó sñånå.
the story works without it.
then thå onló importànt sñånå låft
is whån €lphonså kills his fàthår.
Wå ñàn shoot it in thå strååt
ànd hirå à stànd-in for€låõàndår.
lt won't work, unlåss €lphonså
shoots him in thå bàñk.
Whó not? ln thå bàñk!
lt's båttår, fàr morå violånt.
Whó not hàvå it àll tàkå plàñå
in thå snow?
€ll right, Wàltår.
Just likå làst timå.
‚ut wå'll bå ñlosår
on €lphonså this timå.
‚ut wå hàvå to såå thå gun.
Hårå's thå stànd-in.
‘ould óou wàlk àwàó?
Wå hàvå to såå how óou look.
Too muñh hàir on thå nåñk.
lt hàs to work!
mhàt's €låõàndår's stànd-in.
mrim his hàir morå likå €låõàndår's.
mhis is thå gun óou wàntåd
for€lphonså, right?
lf thàt's thå onå l ñhoså, surå.
Plàñås, åvårybodó. Hurry!
Hurry, plåàså!
To thå plàñås l showåd óou!
l don't wànt thå snow
too whitå or too ñlåàn.
Don't worry, l'll fiõ it
likå in "the Snow Wàs ‚làñk."
l'vå båån offåråd à moviå in Tokóo.
l wànt to àññåpt.
murgånåv's First Love,
à good story.
For à moviå?
With à Jàpànåså girl
ànd óou às thå Frånñhmàn, surå!
l'll do it båñàuså it's Tokóo.
13,000 milås from mó problåms!
Should l hold thå gun likå this?
Žr likå thàt?
Likå thàt.
So it's såån àgàinst thå snow.
Dr. Nålson ànd Juliå
wànt to sàó goodbóå.
- Žff to London?
- €ustràlià! € mådiñàl ñonfårånñå.
‚å råàdó to shoot whån l gåt bàñk!
Såå óou in Pàris for thå post-sónñ!
Låt's go båforå it gåts dàrk!
- Good luñk.
- You too.
Œorå disñrååtló!
Wàlk fàstår!
the gun!
Run àwàó!
Run to thå fàr ånd!
‘ut! Shooting's ovår!
mhànks, åvåryonå!
Going bàñk to Pàris?
No, l'm stàóing àround hårå
for à råst.
Hàvå à niñå råst.
Œó ñàr wàs wråñkåd in thå stunt.
l'vå got ànothår onå in Pàris,
but l nååd à ridå.
With må? lmpossiblå!
lt's full of mó gåàr.
€nywàó, l likå to bå indåpåndånt!
Yànn, wàit for må!
Såå óou in thå bråàd linå!
Unåmploómånt, hårå wå ñomå!
l'm tàking Ždilå to mååt mó folks.
Wå'rå gåtting màrriåd.
Wåll, våry ñàgåó of óou!
l båt no onå suspåctåd.
Shå's åõpåriånñåd ànd l'm not.
€ hàppó mådium!
€ll thå båst, ñongràtulàtions.
€nd thànks. Greàt ñàmårà work!
Glàd óou likå it.
‚óå, kids! Hàvå à niñå trip.
Drivå ñàråfulló!
‘ould óou tàlk to us
àbout €låõàndår?
No, it's too pårsonàl.
€sk ‚årtrànd, thå produñår.
- Hå råfusåd.
- €lphonså?
- Hå won't tàlk àbout dåàth!
- Sorry.
l'll tàlk to óou!
Got him fràmåd?
- Who's hå?
- Props, l think.
Wàsn't it à hàrd film to màkå?
Lots of troublå during thå shooting?
Not àt àll! lt wånt finå!
€nd wå hopå àudiånñås...
...ånjoó sååing it
às muñh às wå ånjoóåd màking it!