1
00:00:48,365 --> 00:00:51,421
Ryanair final call for passenger Wilton

2
00:00:51,497 --> 00:00:55,726
traveling to Brussels-Charleroi
on Flight FR-1014.

3
00:00:55,798 --> 00:00:58,491
Please proceed immediately to Departure Gate 6,

4
00:00:58,565 --> 00:01:01,031
where this flight is now closing.

5
00:01:01,099 --> 00:01:04,861
Do you want a car?
£ 10, Theatreland.

6
00:01:04,932 --> 00:01:07,057
Car? London?

7
00:01:14,167 --> 00:01:16,564
You want a taxi?

8
00:01:16,634 --> 00:01:18,963
Buckingham Palace.

9
00:01:24,268 --> 00:01:25,757
No one.

10
00:01:25,834 --> 00:01:28,097
Would you like a car, sir?

11
00:01:28,169 --> 00:01:30,031
Are you from Sajit?

12
00:01:30,902 --> 00:01:32,663
I'm not here to meet you in particular.

13
00:01:32,734 --> 00:01:33,859
I am here to rescue those

14
00:01:33,935 --> 00:01:36,424
that have been let down by the system.

15
00:01:36,502 --> 00:01:38,128
Okay.
Let's go.

16
00:01:38,203 --> 00:01:39,793
I'm over there.

17
00:02:30,741 --> 00:02:33,368
- Who's next?
- 2-9.

18
00:02:37,909 --> 00:02:39,966
Here.
My turn.

19
00:02:40,676 --> 00:02:42,108
Okay.

20
00:02:42,742 --> 00:02:43,902
Hey.

21
00:02:47,043 --> 00:02:48,703
Your name is now Mohammed.

22
00:02:48,777 --> 00:02:51,710
Thank you, Okwe.

23
00:03:01,678 --> 00:03:04,907
Hurry up, now, man.
Come quick, quick, quick, quick.

24
00:03:04,979 --> 00:03:06,445
Quick, now.

25
00:03:07,446 --> 00:03:09,912
Right.
You just come here.

26
00:03:24,782 --> 00:03:27,612
That bitch.

27
00:03:27,681 --> 00:03:30,772
This shit, dustbin city.

28
00:03:30,847 --> 00:03:33,746
So, what do I need, Okwe?

29
00:03:33,816 --> 00:03:35,508
Amoxicillin.

30
00:03:35,582 --> 00:03:37,811
You get that in Boots drugstore or not?

31
00:03:37,883 --> 00:03:39,940
- From a doctor.
- You're a doctor.

32
00:03:40,015 --> 00:03:41,879
I'm a driver.

33
00:03:42,884 --> 00:03:44,042
Look.

34
00:03:44,116 --> 00:03:46,548
They say you're a doctor, right?

35
00:03:46,617 --> 00:03:48,048
You get me something now.

36
00:03:48,116 --> 00:03:50,412
I can't piss fire another day, man.

37
00:03:50,483 --> 00:03:52,142
I'm a driver.

38
00:03:52,217 --> 00:03:55,513
It's for me wife's sake.
You know what I mean.

39
00:03:57,017 --> 00:03:58,177
Okay.

40
00:03:58,252 --> 00:04:01,706
So I'll get you all the jobs in South London.

41
00:04:03,052 --> 00:04:05,712
Okay.
I'll see what I can do.

42
00:04:05,786 --> 00:04:07,013
Let me kiss you, Okwe.

43
00:04:07,086 --> 00:04:09,950
Maybe in return,
you can get some soap.

44
00:04:26,722 --> 00:04:30,210
Early is as bad as late, Okwe.

45
00:05:04,858 --> 00:05:07,051
Hello.
Front desk.

46
00:05:07,125 --> 00:05:10,286
No, I'm afraid the kitchen
is closed from midnight.

47
00:05:11,694 --> 00:05:14,124
I'm sorry.

48
00:05:14,192 --> 00:05:16,317
Good night, madam.

49
00:05:16,392 --> 00:05:17,916
Good night, madam.

50
00:06:05,864 --> 00:06:06,627
What?

51
00:06:06,700 --> 00:06:08,688
Senay, perhaps today,
I can cook you lunch.

52
00:06:08,765 --> 00:06:10,459
No, Okwe.

53
00:06:15,900 --> 00:06:17,799
So that's true what they say.

54
00:06:17,901 --> 00:06:19,160
What is true?

55
00:06:19,199 --> 00:06:22,893
They say you and the Turkish
girl are nesting like birds.

56
00:06:22,968 --> 00:06:24,900
I rent her couch.

57
00:06:24,968 --> 00:06:27,628
In the morning,
when she's working here.

58
00:06:27,702 --> 00:06:29,223
We're never there at the same time.

59
00:06:29,300 --> 00:06:31,698
She has rules.

60
00:06:31,767 --> 00:06:35,462
You know, she's a Muslim,
which means she's a virgin.

61
00:06:35,536 --> 00:06:37,195
Like a little angel.

62
00:06:37,269 --> 00:06:39,997
Ivan, I think there's someone at the door.

63
00:06:44,302 --> 00:06:45,529
Can you believe it?

64
00:06:45,604 --> 00:06:48,070
One of the fuckers wanted to
put me on his Visa card!

65
00:06:48,136 --> 00:06:50,261
Oh, my bloomin' feet.

66
00:06:50,338 --> 00:06:52,634
Lucky I don't work standing up.

67
00:06:56,203 --> 00:06:57,863
What?

68
00:06:57,937 --> 00:07:00,564
Don't they have hookers where you come from?

69
00:07:00,639 --> 00:07:02,366
Where are you from?

70
00:07:03,204 --> 00:07:05,500
Somewhere with lions, I bet.

71
00:07:09,373 --> 00:07:11,100
I like lions.

72
00:07:13,340 --> 00:07:15,000
Right.

73
00:07:15,074 --> 00:07:15,903
Oh, yeah.

74
00:07:15,974 --> 00:07:18,837
You might want to send
someone to check on the room.

75
00:07:18,939 --> 00:07:21,566
- There is a problem?
- How should I know?

76
00:07:21,608 --> 00:07:24,767
I don't exist, do I?

77
00:07:24,840 --> 00:07:26,601
See you tomorrow.

78
00:09:24,746 --> 00:09:25,939
What's that?

79
00:09:26,013 --> 00:09:29,172
You're stealing stuff already, huh?

80
00:09:29,245 --> 00:09:33,043
Guy before you used to steal
whole pigs from the freezer.

81
00:09:33,114 --> 00:09:35,045
But you better hide it.

82
00:09:35,114 --> 00:09:36,806
If Sneaky sees that...

83
00:09:36,879 --> 00:09:37,970
Oh!

84
00:09:38,046 --> 00:09:40,037
Speak of the fucking devil!

85
00:09:40,115 --> 00:09:42,875
Where's the greeter here?

86
00:10:01,349 --> 00:10:03,780
This fucking place.

87
00:10:06,616 --> 00:10:08,105
Hey!

88
00:10:08,184 --> 00:10:11,014
Instead of smoking,
you clean this place up.

89
00:10:48,289 --> 00:10:51,187
Okwe.
Everything is all right?

90
00:10:54,556 --> 00:10:56,612
What's this?
Lunch?

91
00:10:56,688 --> 00:11:01,486
It was blocking the lavatory in Room 510.

92
00:11:01,557 --> 00:11:03,182
It is a heart.

93
00:11:04,156 --> 00:11:05,850
A human heart.

94
00:11:05,924 --> 00:11:07,321
What?

95
00:11:07,391 --> 00:11:10,151
What the fuck do you know about hearts, Okwe?

96
00:11:10,223 --> 00:11:13,156
Perhaps you should telephone the police.

97
00:11:15,524 --> 00:11:17,854
Police? You think I should call the police?

98
00:11:17,925 --> 00:11:20,483
Señor Juan, someone is dead.

99
00:11:20,559 --> 00:11:23,991
Okay.
You speak to them.

100
00:11:24,058 --> 00:11:27,685
You found it.
You do the talking.

101
00:11:27,760 --> 00:11:29,622
I'll introduce you.

102
00:11:33,294 --> 00:11:35,590
What's your full name, Okwe?

103
00:11:36,959 --> 00:11:38,950
And you never told me where you're from.

104
00:11:39,028 --> 00:11:43,357
Or even how come you're here
in this beautiful country.

105
00:11:43,427 --> 00:11:45,689
Hello? Police?

106
00:11:45,762 --> 00:11:48,352
Yeah, got somebody who wants to talk to you.

107
00:11:49,994 --> 00:11:51,823
Hello?

108
00:11:51,894 --> 00:11:54,190
Hello?

109
00:11:54,261 --> 00:11:55,387
Hello?

110
00:11:57,428 --> 00:11:59,258
You will learn, Okwe.

111
00:11:59,329 --> 00:12:02,853
The hotel business is about strangers.

112
00:12:02,930 --> 00:12:06,862
And strangers will always
surprise you, you know?

113
00:12:06,931 --> 00:12:11,988
They come to hotels in the night
to do dirty things.

114
00:12:12,063 --> 00:12:13,154
And in the morning,

115
00:12:13,230 --> 00:12:16,322
it's our job to make things look pretty again.

116
00:12:16,398 --> 00:12:18,126
For your trouble.

117
00:12:19,997 --> 00:12:23,020
You think if you don't take
the money, you are innocent?

118
00:12:23,098 --> 00:12:26,156
Take it.
Do something nice with it.

119
00:12:31,733 --> 00:12:33,221
No.

120
00:13:57,375 --> 00:14:02,069
It came to me last night
in a flash of inspiration.

121
00:14:06,076 --> 00:14:08,668
I can see.

122
00:14:08,743 --> 00:14:10,174
That's a good move.

123
00:14:11,543 --> 00:14:14,441
Guo Yi,
there's something I need.

124
00:14:14,510 --> 00:14:16,205
Amoxicillin.

125
00:14:16,278 --> 00:14:18,039
You got the clap?

126
00:14:18,111 --> 00:14:19,940
No.

127
00:14:20,011 --> 00:14:21,068
My boss.

128
00:14:21,144 --> 00:14:22,406
Which one?

129
00:14:22,478 --> 00:14:24,069
They're all the same.

130
00:14:24,178 --> 00:14:28,407
In this country,
the health service is free.

131
00:14:28,445 --> 00:14:31,411
You still driving cabs in the day?

132
00:14:32,178 --> 00:14:34,645
You're going to kill yourself.

133
00:14:34,712 --> 00:14:36,872
I do not care to sleep.

134
00:14:39,613 --> 00:14:43,603
When you go quiet,
it means you've won already.

135
00:14:43,680 --> 00:14:45,544
Go on, Okwe.
Don't be nice.

136
00:14:45,613 --> 00:14:47,410
Makes it worse.

137
00:14:52,048 --> 00:14:54,038
Well, shit.

138
00:14:54,115 --> 00:14:56,240
You want Chinese or English tea?

139
00:14:56,315 --> 00:14:57,372
Chinese.

140
00:14:57,448 --> 00:15:00,381
Don't know how you drink that stuff.

141
00:15:00,448 --> 00:15:04,347
I found it on a body.
It's blown my head wide open.

142
00:15:04,416 --> 00:15:06,042
You should read it.

143
00:15:06,116 --> 00:15:08,911
Medicine for your soul, Okwe.

144
00:15:11,183 --> 00:15:13,877
Guo Yi, today I also found something.

145
00:15:15,050 --> 00:15:18,108
In a lavatory in one of the hotel rooms.

146
00:15:18,184 --> 00:15:20,413
Someone's heart.

147
00:15:21,984 --> 00:15:23,679
A heart.

148
00:15:23,752 --> 00:15:25,979
A human heart.

149
00:15:26,051 --> 00:15:29,711
I'm only telling you
because you are a rational man.

150
00:15:29,785 --> 00:15:32,547
Maybe there's an explanation.

151
00:15:38,419 --> 00:15:42,285
Maybe some guy with one
of the girls had a heart attack.

152
00:15:42,353 --> 00:15:43,819
Rooms are down as empty.

153
00:15:43,887 --> 00:15:46,546
So the Spanish guy had to get rid of the body.

154
00:15:46,620 --> 00:15:48,212
Hotels hate dead people.

155
00:15:48,288 --> 00:15:49,776
- It was a healthy heart.
- So?

156
00:15:49,854 --> 00:15:51,649
So your boss was right first time.

157
00:15:51,721 --> 00:15:53,415
Somebody brought it with them.

158
00:15:53,488 --> 00:15:55,920
- Who carries human organs?
- Lots of people.

159
00:15:55,988 --> 00:15:58,387
- Name someone.
- Me. Okay? Me.

160
00:15:58,455 --> 00:16:02,012
I do it all the time.
I take my work home.

161
00:16:02,088 --> 00:16:05,613
What I'm saying is,
I could if I was weird.

162
00:16:05,689 --> 00:16:08,053
And this is a weird city.

163
00:16:09,423 --> 00:16:12,413
Why would anyone do that to a human heart?

164
00:16:12,490 --> 00:16:14,785
These sound to me like questions.

165
00:16:14,857 --> 00:16:17,688
I don't ask questions after 11 years here.

166
00:16:17,757 --> 00:16:19,723
And I'm a certified refugee.

167
00:16:19,791 --> 00:16:23,621
You're an illegal, Okwe.
You don't have a position here.

168
00:16:23,691 --> 00:16:26,748
You have nothing.
You are nothing.

169
00:16:27,958 --> 00:16:31,356
You wait outside.
I'll go get you those pills.

170
00:16:33,426 --> 00:16:36,449
Stick to helping people who can be helped.

171
00:16:53,361 --> 00:16:54,622
Fresh stuff.

172
00:16:54,695 --> 00:16:56,183
Thank you.

173
00:16:56,261 --> 00:16:57,660
Thank you.

174
00:17:25,364 --> 00:17:26,990
Senay.

175
00:17:27,065 --> 00:17:28,530
Senay.

176
00:17:29,898 --> 00:17:32,593
Senay, having only one key
is making this impossible.

177
00:17:32,666 --> 00:17:34,824
I do not want you coming in when I am there.

178
00:17:34,899 --> 00:17:36,330
At the hotel, we are friends!

179
00:17:36,399 --> 00:17:38,728
- Shh!
- I'm no different here.

180
00:17:38,799 --> 00:17:41,028
How would it look, Okwe?

181
00:17:41,100 --> 00:17:44,190
So it is better I always
chase you down the street?

182
00:17:45,067 --> 00:17:48,761
Wait five minutes,
then knock the door.

183
00:17:48,834 --> 00:17:51,391
Knock very, very quietly.

184
00:18:07,969 --> 00:18:09,993
Senay!

185
00:18:10,069 --> 00:18:11,696
Yes?

186
00:18:12,236 --> 00:18:15,601
Did you clean on the fifth floor
yesterday morning?

187
00:18:22,704 --> 00:18:25,399
Nothing works.

188
00:18:26,138 --> 00:18:28,229
Senay, did you clean Room 510 yesterday?

189
00:18:28,305 --> 00:18:31,965
What the hell are you talking
about the hotel for?

190
00:18:32,039 --> 00:18:34,266
Water, water, water!

191
00:18:34,339 --> 00:18:37,329
I was wondering if there was
a problem in 510 yesterday.

192
00:18:37,406 --> 00:18:39,564
You can fix these things?

193
00:18:40,973 --> 00:18:42,734
Okwe!

194
00:18:44,040 --> 00:18:46,028
You can fix...

195
00:18:47,540 --> 00:18:49,939
They were not clean.
Glasses need very hot water.

196
00:18:50,008 --> 00:18:51,133
So do women.

197
00:18:51,208 --> 00:18:54,640
Everything here is connected
to everything else.

198
00:18:56,608 --> 00:19:01,007
Okwe, in Africa, it is the man
who will cook and clean?

199
00:19:02,908 --> 00:19:05,035
Senay, this came for you.

200
00:19:06,209 --> 00:19:09,073
Why did you not tell me?

201
00:19:09,142 --> 00:19:11,132
I just told you.

202
00:19:14,710 --> 00:19:17,074
You have friends in New York?

203
00:19:20,578 --> 00:19:22,305
Your postcard.

204
00:19:22,378 --> 00:19:24,038
I have a cousin.

205
00:19:24,143 --> 00:19:26,940
Ever since I was small,
she has written to me.

206
00:19:26,978 --> 00:19:29,342
I sometimes wish London was more like New York.

207
00:19:29,412 --> 00:19:31,378
It would be easier to drive a cab there.

208
00:19:31,445 --> 00:19:34,003
You have been to New York?

209
00:19:35,479 --> 00:19:36,535
And you came back?

210
00:19:36,612 --> 00:19:38,737
I lived there for a time.

211
00:19:40,279 --> 00:19:43,439
In the winter,
they put lights in the trees.

212
00:19:43,512 --> 00:19:45,604
Is that true?

213
00:19:45,680 --> 00:19:47,771
And you can skate in the parks.

214
00:19:47,847 --> 00:19:51,279
And some of the policemen ride white horses.

215
00:19:51,347 --> 00:19:53,472
Not all of them, but some.

216
00:19:54,614 --> 00:19:57,172
What did you do there?

217
00:19:57,247 --> 00:19:59,008
I worked in a hospital.

218
00:19:59,081 --> 00:20:02,140
- You were a cleaner?
- I was there to study.

219
00:20:02,216 --> 00:20:04,409
So, why are you working in a hotel?

220
00:20:04,483 --> 00:20:06,676
It is an African story.

221
00:20:07,850 --> 00:20:11,474
I've noticed you never answer 'yes' or 'no.'

222
00:20:11,549 --> 00:20:13,879
You are very strange.

223
00:20:15,651 --> 00:20:17,343
You drink wine, Senay?

224
00:20:17,416 --> 00:20:19,541
Do you want to know why I left Turkey?

225
00:20:19,617 --> 00:20:21,584
Because you wanted to live like your cousin.

226
00:20:21,651 --> 00:20:22,242
No.

227
00:20:22,318 --> 00:20:25,409
Because I do not want to live like my mother.

228
00:20:26,285 --> 00:20:28,375
- Yes.
- Yes, what?

229
00:20:28,451 --> 00:20:30,542
I do drink wine.

230
00:20:49,388 --> 00:20:52,251
This is a recipe from Nigeria.

231
00:20:52,321 --> 00:20:55,718
In Nigeria, they do many
interesting things with pork.

232
00:20:59,322 --> 00:21:02,288
But, of course, I used lamb.

233
00:21:04,856 --> 00:21:06,082
Mmm.

234
00:21:17,156 --> 00:21:19,248
Take one three times a day.

235
00:21:19,324 --> 00:21:20,756
Avoid alcohol.

236
00:21:20,824 --> 00:21:22,882
In here. Come.

237
00:21:41,560 --> 00:21:43,685
So she's a popular lady.

238
00:21:43,760 --> 00:21:47,385
My warriors cannot work
with rotten balls, Okwe.

239
00:21:47,460 --> 00:21:52,053
My friend is just a porter
in the hospital crematorium.

240
00:22:04,629 --> 00:22:06,323
Hello.
Front desk.

241
00:22:06,396 --> 00:22:09,056
No, I'm afraid the kitchen
is closed from midnight.

242
00:22:09,130 --> 00:22:10,493
Psst! Hey!

243
00:22:12,596 --> 00:22:14,061
Hello?

244
00:22:14,831 --> 00:22:16,694
Yeah, room service.

245
00:22:26,765 --> 00:22:28,354
Sneaky doesn't know about this?

246
00:22:28,430 --> 00:22:31,363
Sneaky knows about everything.

247
00:22:31,431 --> 00:22:33,090
And you?

248
00:22:33,164 --> 00:22:35,256
You know everything that goes on in the hotel?

249
00:22:35,331 --> 00:22:37,195
Not so much butter!
Hey.

250
00:22:38,798 --> 00:22:40,890
You guard the door, lvan.

251
00:22:40,965 --> 00:22:43,625
You see who comes and goes.

252
00:22:43,699 --> 00:22:45,927
You would know if somebody came into the hotel

253
00:22:46,000 --> 00:22:47,762
but did not leave again.

254
00:22:47,834 --> 00:22:51,494
Why would someone not leave, Okwe?

255
00:22:54,201 --> 00:22:55,461
I don't know.

256
00:22:55,533 --> 00:22:59,466
You should remove the crusts,
like in the Ritz.

257
00:23:00,967 --> 00:23:03,298
Everyone leaves, Okwe.

258
00:23:03,368 --> 00:23:05,096
Some leave quickly.

259
00:23:05,168 --> 00:23:08,293
Some stay for long time.

260
00:23:08,369 --> 00:23:10,267
If you want to stay,

261
00:23:10,335 --> 00:23:15,200
don't concern yourself
with who comes and who goes.

262
00:23:17,837 --> 00:23:21,770
It's the little touches
that make the difference.

263
00:23:21,838 --> 00:23:24,099
That's capitalism.

264
00:23:24,205 --> 00:23:25,330
Now go.

265
00:23:25,371 --> 00:23:29,701
Don't forget.
You accept only cash.

266
00:23:31,604 --> 00:23:33,195
Room service.

267
00:23:35,704 --> 00:23:37,137
Thanks.

268
00:24:35,113 --> 00:24:39,010
Okay, you just make
yourself comfortable, and, uh...

269
00:24:39,078 --> 00:24:40,067
I'll go freshen up.

270
00:24:40,146 --> 00:24:41,668
All right?

271
00:24:44,580 --> 00:24:48,171
Fucking asshole.

272
00:24:57,447 --> 00:24:59,037
Oh, my God.

273
00:25:01,714 --> 00:25:03,943
Come on, babe. Hurry up.

274
00:25:05,483 --> 00:25:07,142
Okay, okay.

275
00:25:08,483 --> 00:25:11,277
Calm yourself, sweetheart.

276
00:25:12,783 --> 00:25:14,749
What are you doing?

277
00:25:14,815 --> 00:25:16,612
Have a drink first.

278
00:25:16,684 --> 00:25:19,582
You look fine.
Just get out here.

279
00:25:22,150 --> 00:25:24,413
Hey.

280
00:25:24,517 --> 00:25:25,448
Hey.

281
00:25:26,652 --> 00:25:28,140
Fuck!

282
00:25:41,220 --> 00:25:43,151
Enough. No more.

283
00:25:43,220 --> 00:25:44,709
Where the fuck did you come from?

284
00:25:44,786 --> 00:25:46,115
Leave now!

285
00:25:46,185 --> 00:25:48,015
Oh! Oh, fuck!

286
00:25:56,688 --> 00:25:58,210
You don't have concussion.

287
00:25:58,287 --> 00:26:00,253
How the fuck do you know?

288
00:26:00,322 --> 00:26:02,446
Christ, you must be bored.

289
00:26:02,521 --> 00:26:04,282
Getting your kicks spying on me.

290
00:26:04,354 --> 00:26:07,787
I was making sure the blockage
had not returned.

291
00:26:07,856 --> 00:26:09,446
Perhaps...

292
00:26:09,522 --> 00:26:11,010
It's Juliette.

293
00:26:11,088 --> 00:26:12,645
You should go home and rest.

294
00:26:12,722 --> 00:26:14,052
Rest?

295
00:26:14,123 --> 00:26:16,452
Got three more before morning.

296
00:26:16,522 --> 00:26:20,216
So, have you ever seen a lion?

297
00:26:20,289 --> 00:26:22,312
Oh, yes.

298
00:26:22,391 --> 00:26:24,016
On TV.

299
00:26:46,426 --> 00:26:48,450
I had it cut.

300
00:26:48,526 --> 00:26:50,389
It is yours.

301
00:26:51,661 --> 00:26:55,059
You were right.
This way is more sensible.

302
00:27:10,162 --> 00:27:14,061
Okwe, you must not tell them at
the hotel that you have a key.

303
00:27:14,130 --> 00:27:15,959
Senay, I tell them only the truth.

304
00:27:16,030 --> 00:27:17,120
Even so.

305
00:27:17,195 --> 00:27:19,129
And show them that your back hurts

306
00:27:19,195 --> 00:27:20,890
so they know you sleep on the floor.

307
00:27:20,964 --> 00:27:23,088
But that is not true.
I sleep on the couch.

308
00:27:23,196 --> 00:27:27,027
The couch is not as real as the floor, Okwe.

309
00:27:27,063 --> 00:27:28,586
Believe me.
I'm a woman.

310
00:27:28,665 --> 00:27:31,597
And some of those bitches
won't know what is a couch.

311
00:27:31,665 --> 00:27:33,926
But they know floor.
They clean floors.

312
00:27:36,731 --> 00:27:37,663
For you?

313
00:27:37,731 --> 00:27:40,095
Immigration-enforcement directive.

314
00:27:40,165 --> 00:27:41,688
Open the door.

315
00:27:54,768 --> 00:27:56,165
Forgive us.
Miss Gelik?

316
00:27:56,235 --> 00:27:57,962
Senay Gelik?
Turkish national?

317
00:27:58,035 --> 00:28:00,125
- Do you have your S.A.L. Handy?
- My what?

318
00:28:00,200 --> 00:28:01,962
Your acknowledgement letter.
Your I.D.

319
00:28:02,035 --> 00:28:04,797
Oh, yeah.
I carry it always.

320
00:28:04,869 --> 00:28:07,198
Neighbors, Senay.
They see things.

321
00:28:07,268 --> 00:28:10,359
In the last few days, they've
seen someone come and go.

322
00:28:10,435 --> 00:28:11,901
A man.

323
00:28:12,569 --> 00:28:15,659
Sometimes a woman in your
position can be exploited.

324
00:28:15,735 --> 00:28:18,634
There are people in London
without any kind of papers.

325
00:28:18,703 --> 00:28:20,897
- They prey on people like you.
- Prey?

326
00:28:20,969 --> 00:28:23,994
- There is someone living here.
- There is no one living here.

327
00:28:24,103 --> 00:28:26,229
You are aware that your E.L.R. Status

328
00:28:26,270 --> 00:28:27,964
means you are unable to accept rent.

329
00:28:28,038 --> 00:28:30,196
You're seeking asylum.

330
00:28:30,270 --> 00:28:33,828
Or engage in employment of any
kind for at least six months.

331
00:28:33,904 --> 00:28:36,894
- You're not working, are you?
- Mind if I use your bathroom?

332
00:28:38,039 --> 00:28:40,300
Your case is under review.

333
00:29:06,541 --> 00:29:08,508
Thank you.

334
00:29:08,575 --> 00:29:10,200
Thank you.

335
00:29:11,676 --> 00:29:13,107
Is that all you want?

336
00:29:13,175 --> 00:29:14,936
No, no, no, no.

337
00:29:16,677 --> 00:29:19,235
You know this stuff will
not only keep you awake.

338
00:29:19,310 --> 00:29:21,969
It'll blow your brains out.
You know that, don't you?

339
00:29:30,910 --> 00:29:33,605
Hey! Okwe!

340
00:29:34,311 --> 00:29:36,971
Keys.
There you are.

341
00:29:37,046 --> 00:29:39,273
Hey, Okwe.
What happened, man?

342
00:29:39,345 --> 00:29:42,470
Hey, somebody's husband came home early, right?

343
00:29:42,545 --> 00:29:43,603
Here.
Take this.

344
00:29:43,680 --> 00:29:47,510
We don't want the doctor getting sick, right?

345
00:29:54,313 --> 00:29:57,075
I played them one of these fellows' songs.

346
00:29:57,148 --> 00:29:59,580
And, actually,
they were very helpful.

347
00:29:59,647 --> 00:30:01,773
Had they already heard it or not?

348
00:30:03,714 --> 00:30:06,341
They were already very into funk and...

349
00:30:07,981 --> 00:30:09,948
It's bound to happen.

350
00:30:10,014 --> 00:30:12,141
You stay here too long.

351
00:30:12,215 --> 00:30:16,272
You start dressing like an Englishman, huh?

352
00:30:36,017 --> 00:30:37,916
Where is he, then?

353
00:30:37,984 --> 00:30:38,952
Who?

354
00:30:39,018 --> 00:30:42,643
I have a date.
Every payday, 4:45.

355
00:30:42,718 --> 00:30:44,583
Hey!

356
00:30:44,652 --> 00:30:46,243
Come on, lover boy.

357
00:30:46,319 --> 00:30:48,615
Okwe, will you help me?

358
00:30:48,687 --> 00:30:50,812
Hey, guy before you took £5.

359
00:30:50,886 --> 00:30:51,853
No, no, no, no.

360
00:30:51,919 --> 00:30:54,512
- But you watch the door, huh?
- Yes.

361
00:30:54,587 --> 00:30:55,847
Come, my little princess.

362
00:30:55,920 --> 00:30:58,385
Come, come, come, come,
lille princesso.

363
00:30:58,453 --> 00:31:02,784
Security room is out of bounds
for half an hour.

364
00:31:02,854 --> 00:31:06,718
Five minutes, max.

365
00:31:06,789 --> 00:31:09,687
Immigration-enforcement directive.

366
00:31:17,889 --> 00:31:19,617
Can I help you?

367
00:31:23,057 --> 00:31:25,489
What time do the maids clock in?

368
00:31:27,390 --> 00:31:29,856
- Wakey-wakey.
- 5:00.

369
00:31:32,157 --> 00:31:34,488
You mind if we wait?

370
00:31:35,324 --> 00:31:36,914
No.

371
00:31:54,826 --> 00:31:57,521
Excuse me, sir.
This is a nonsmoking area.

372
00:31:57,594 --> 00:31:59,286
If you wish,
perhaps you can wait

373
00:31:59,360 --> 00:32:02,020
in the designated area across the lobby.

374
00:32:35,064 --> 00:32:36,394
Hello?

375
00:32:37,431 --> 00:32:38,590
Shh!

376
00:32:39,898 --> 00:32:40,990
It's for you.

377
00:32:41,065 --> 00:32:42,964
Hello?

378
00:32:43,032 --> 00:32:45,260
Okwe. Okwe!

379
00:32:45,332 --> 00:32:47,388
But I am almost there!

380
00:32:47,465 --> 00:32:50,920
Senay will be here in two minutes.

381
00:32:50,999 --> 00:32:52,694
You must stop her.

382
00:33:58,273 --> 00:34:01,535
I have a medical condition.

383
00:34:01,607 --> 00:34:04,335
Lightning doesn't strike twice!

384
00:34:10,741 --> 00:34:12,105
Shh, shh, shh.

385
00:34:19,309 --> 00:34:21,969
Is that the last of them?

386
00:34:22,043 --> 00:34:23,703
Yes.

387
00:34:24,810 --> 00:34:27,105
This is an interesting place.

388
00:34:27,176 --> 00:34:29,700
Would you like to see a rate card?

389
00:34:50,613 --> 00:34:51,838
I have a friend.

390
00:34:51,912 --> 00:34:54,378
In her factory,
they always need people.

391
00:34:54,446 --> 00:34:56,310
It's a sweatshop.

392
00:34:56,379 --> 00:34:59,471
Is it any worse than cleaning up after whores?

393
00:34:59,547 --> 00:35:01,376
It's better money.

394
00:35:03,346 --> 00:35:06,040
Oh, you are so sad for me.

395
00:35:06,114 --> 00:35:08,343
I do not wish to cause harm to anyone.

396
00:35:08,415 --> 00:35:09,744
That is all it is?

397
00:35:09,814 --> 00:35:11,576
I will collect my things and go.

398
00:35:11,648 --> 00:35:13,739
- Go?
- How can I stay?

399
00:35:13,815 --> 00:35:16,509
Okwe, who will cook for me?

400
00:35:17,549 --> 00:35:20,811
If it's okay, I will call on you
if I have the time.

401
00:35:20,883 --> 00:35:23,610
But I'm owed three days' money by the hotel.

402
00:35:23,716 --> 00:35:26,513
I will see Señor Juan tomorrow morning.

403
00:35:26,550 --> 00:35:29,311
I have no money for food.

404
00:35:29,383 --> 00:35:33,372
I will see him today.
Meet me at the café at 4:00.

405
00:36:14,122 --> 00:36:16,611
You are here to see Señor Juan?

406
00:36:19,621 --> 00:36:21,350
Looking for work?

407
00:36:25,123 --> 00:36:27,918
Are you working?

408
00:36:27,989 --> 00:36:29,579
French?

409
00:36:29,656 --> 00:36:31,849
No, no.

410
00:36:31,923 --> 00:36:34,914
Help me.

411
00:36:34,990 --> 00:36:38,354
Yoruba.
You speak Yoruba?

412
00:36:38,425 --> 00:36:40,084
Bantu?

413
00:36:42,357 --> 00:36:45,086
What the fuck are you doing here, Okwe?

414
00:36:45,159 --> 00:36:46,623
Senay has decided to leave.

415
00:36:46,692 --> 00:36:48,782
She asked me to collect what she's owed.

416
00:36:48,859 --> 00:36:49,790
Oh, yeah?

417
00:36:49,859 --> 00:36:52,792
What, are you marrying her or something, Okwe?

418
00:36:55,593 --> 00:36:57,526
I'll get her money.

419
00:37:08,527 --> 00:37:11,016
No, no! It's okay.
I'm a doctor.

420
00:37:11,094 --> 00:37:13,356
I'm a doctor.
It's okay.

421
00:37:13,428 --> 00:37:17,918
No, no, no.
Please, please, please.

422
00:37:23,978 --> 00:37:25,911
You must get this man to hospital now.

423
00:37:25,978 --> 00:37:27,275
He must go straightaway.

424
00:37:27,345 --> 00:37:29,574
If you are a doctor,
you can do something.

425
00:37:29,647 --> 00:37:32,170
This is the wound of an operation.

426
00:37:32,247 --> 00:37:34,905
Where? Where did he have this operation?

427
00:37:34,979 --> 00:37:36,537
Which country?

428
00:37:36,613 --> 00:37:38,637
You must get this man to hospital!

429
00:37:38,713 --> 00:37:40,407
They won't go to hospital.

430
00:37:40,481 --> 00:37:42,572
- No, no!
- No hospital!

431
00:38:04,349 --> 00:38:06,145
Guo Yi is here?

432
00:38:06,983 --> 00:38:08,471
Shit.

433
00:38:24,586 --> 00:38:26,643
Sister. Hello.
It's my first day here.

434
00:38:26,719 --> 00:38:28,447
I was told to collect my overall.

435
00:38:28,520 --> 00:38:30,543
- Which shift are you on?
- Shift?

436
00:38:30,620 --> 00:38:34,211
Come on. Either you're late
or you're really late.

437
00:39:32,627 --> 00:39:34,593
You couldn't do the bins in the kitchen

438
00:39:34,661 --> 00:39:36,650
when you're done in here,
could you?

439
00:40:43,068 --> 00:40:45,693
Okay, okay, okay.

440
00:40:46,968 --> 00:40:48,901
You see these blue tablets?

441
00:40:48,968 --> 00:40:51,730
He must take two every two hours.

442
00:40:51,802 --> 00:40:53,291
Understand?

443
00:40:53,369 --> 00:40:56,801
He must take two blue tablets every two hours.

444
00:41:06,737 --> 00:41:09,135
You speak English?

445
00:41:09,203 --> 00:41:10,499
And Somali?

446
00:41:10,570 --> 00:41:11,763
A bit.

447
00:41:15,505 --> 00:41:18,960
He says to say, 'Thank you.
God is great.'

448
00:41:19,539 --> 00:41:22,698
Tell them he must take two
blue tablets every two hours.

449
00:41:28,773 --> 00:41:31,262
And one white tablet every six hours.

450
00:41:35,373 --> 00:41:38,362
It is very important
that you get this exactly right.

451
00:41:43,241 --> 00:41:47,005
Ask him which hospital they went
to to have the kidney removed.

452
00:41:52,342 --> 00:41:54,865
He says they didn't go to a hospital.

453
00:41:54,942 --> 00:41:57,238
Ask him where they did this.

454
00:42:01,677 --> 00:42:02,608
In a room.

455
00:42:02,677 --> 00:42:05,643
He had his kidney removed in the hotel, yes?

456
00:42:06,610 --> 00:42:08,838
How much did he get for risking his life?

457
00:42:13,145 --> 00:42:15,804
He is English now.

458
00:42:15,878 --> 00:42:18,471
He swapped his insides for a passport?

459
00:42:24,478 --> 00:42:26,138
The man at the hotel said

460
00:42:26,212 --> 00:42:28,644
it would be like taking out a tooth.

461
00:43:06,150 --> 00:43:09,140
- Can I get you something?
- I've been here one hour.

462
00:43:09,217 --> 00:43:11,274
An hour and a half.

463
00:43:15,751 --> 00:43:17,013
There.

464
00:43:17,086 --> 00:43:19,482
I will go and collect my things.

465
00:43:21,086 --> 00:43:23,142
Why won't you sit down?

466
00:43:29,919 --> 00:43:32,147
- Okwe, where have you been?
- Africa.

467
00:43:32,219 --> 00:43:35,344
- I thought you weren't coming.
- I would have got you the money.

468
00:43:35,420 --> 00:43:37,182
The money?

469
00:43:40,454 --> 00:43:42,443
Do you feel that?

470
00:43:42,521 --> 00:43:44,783
Do you feel anything?

471
00:43:46,155 --> 00:43:50,645
You know, I counted.
I've seen you laugh three times.

472
00:43:50,723 --> 00:43:52,119
Four.

473
00:43:56,588 --> 00:43:59,612
You think I'm so innocent.

474
00:43:59,690 --> 00:44:00,951
In my village,

475
00:44:01,022 --> 00:44:04,148
they chew those leaves to forget
how hard their lives are.

476
00:44:04,223 --> 00:44:05,779
I use it to keep awake.

477
00:44:05,856 --> 00:44:08,379
You know it makes you look...

478
00:44:10,090 --> 00:44:12,488
Senay.

479
00:44:12,557 --> 00:44:15,319
You should keep away from me.

480
00:44:15,391 --> 00:44:17,482
You lost your job.

481
00:44:17,558 --> 00:44:20,047
Because of me,
you are in a sweatshop.

482
00:44:22,892 --> 00:44:25,290
And now you are going again.

483
00:44:25,392 --> 00:44:27,187
Be sure you make it to New York.

484
00:44:27,225 --> 00:44:30,750
I will make it to New York,
Okwe, thank you.

485
00:44:35,260 --> 00:44:37,749
It's best if you don't show up
until after 5:00.

486
00:44:37,827 --> 00:44:40,884
Most porters are gone by then.
Only ghosts left.

487
00:44:40,960 --> 00:44:42,051
Showers are here.

488
00:44:42,127 --> 00:44:44,423
Water's not too hot,
but it runs.

489
00:44:44,494 --> 00:44:47,585
Couch in my office is pretty soft.

490
00:44:47,661 --> 00:44:50,684
Oh, I forgot.

491
00:44:50,761 --> 00:44:53,353
You don't sleep, do you?

492
00:44:53,429 --> 00:44:57,987
My friend, welcome to my hotel.

493
00:44:58,063 --> 00:44:59,858
Beautiful, isn't it?

494
00:44:59,929 --> 00:45:03,884
And the other residents are, uh, very quiet.

495
00:45:03,962 --> 00:45:05,553
It will only be until I...

496
00:45:05,630 --> 00:45:08,096
Until the world improves.

497
00:45:51,935 --> 00:45:55,299
Best truffles I've ever seen in England.

498
00:45:55,369 --> 00:45:58,199
Dug up 15 hours ago in Provence.

499
00:45:58,270 --> 00:46:01,201
Came through on the night train.

500
00:46:01,270 --> 00:46:02,326
Mmm.

501
00:46:03,436 --> 00:46:04,925
Mmm.

502
00:46:07,903 --> 00:46:10,029
Shall we say one thousand?

503
00:46:10,104 --> 00:46:13,400
I'm in the wrong fucking hotel.

504
00:46:13,471 --> 00:46:15,800
One thousand, Señor Juan.
What do you say?

505
00:46:15,870 --> 00:46:19,234
Okay.
One thousand.

506
00:46:20,971 --> 00:46:24,597
But if I give you that price,
I need a favor.

507
00:46:24,672 --> 00:46:27,160
There is a night porter.
African.

508
00:46:27,238 --> 00:46:30,602
He came from you, so I guess
he came through Amsterdam.

509
00:46:30,672 --> 00:46:33,332
Yes.
What about him?

510
00:46:33,406 --> 00:46:36,861
He's some kind of doctor.
What kind of doctor?

511
00:46:36,940 --> 00:46:39,838
I need to know what there is to know.

512
00:46:40,407 --> 00:46:42,838
Police! Police!

513
00:47:03,810 --> 00:47:05,469
Can I help you gentlemen?

514
00:47:05,544 --> 00:47:08,169
We're looking for someone called Senay Gelik.

515
00:47:08,243 --> 00:47:10,175
Thought she might be working here.

516
00:47:10,243 --> 00:47:13,676
Do you see anybody working here?

517
00:47:13,744 --> 00:47:17,643
If you see her, give us a call.

518
00:47:41,413 --> 00:47:43,436
You have been here for two days.

519
00:47:43,513 --> 00:47:46,877
And already because of you,
I'm in trouble.

520
00:47:46,947 --> 00:47:50,107
Maybe I should call lmmigration.

521
00:47:50,182 --> 00:47:52,841
Should I call them?

522
00:47:52,915 --> 00:47:54,541
You wouldn't do that.

523
00:47:54,614 --> 00:47:58,775
I need a good reason.
What can you give me?

524
00:47:59,682 --> 00:48:03,547
If they find out you've been
working, what will they do?

525
00:48:03,615 --> 00:48:06,241
They will put you in prison.

526
00:48:06,316 --> 00:48:10,147
And here,
they mix the men and women.

527
00:48:10,217 --> 00:48:14,149
So every night,
you will be raped.

528
00:48:18,284 --> 00:48:21,217
If you want to be like a Western girl,

529
00:48:21,285 --> 00:48:24,649
that's what happens to Western girls.

530
00:48:24,752 --> 00:48:27,877
If you want to go to jail, fine.

531
00:48:27,919 --> 00:48:30,442
If you can't give me a good reason,

532
00:48:30,518 --> 00:48:34,007
I will call the lmmigration.

533
00:48:34,086 --> 00:48:36,053
I'm a good man, Senay.

534
00:48:36,119 --> 00:48:38,779
I know where to draw the line.

535
00:48:39,853 --> 00:48:42,342
I don't want to take your virginity, Senay.

536
00:48:42,420 --> 00:48:46,546
I just want you to help me to relax.

537
00:48:56,421 --> 00:49:00,320
You have such a beautiful mouth, Senay.

538
00:49:07,523 --> 00:49:09,011
Achtung! Achtung!
(Attention!)

539
00:49:09,091 --> 00:49:11,488
My ladies and gentlemen,
your coach awaits.

540
00:49:11,557 --> 00:49:13,955
Please. Please.

541
00:49:14,024 --> 00:49:17,287
But you must take your own
luggage to the coach.

542
00:49:17,357 --> 00:49:20,152
Please. Thank you. Good evening.

543
00:49:20,224 --> 00:49:24,714
I will help only those
who cannot carry their own bags.

544
00:49:24,791 --> 00:49:27,223
Okwe, get up here.

545
00:49:33,259 --> 00:49:35,690
- This man is a doctor.
- I'm okay. I'm okay.

546
00:49:35,759 --> 00:49:38,089
She's okay.
She only needs to rest a minute.

547
00:49:38,159 --> 00:49:40,648
He qualified in Lagos.

548
00:49:40,728 --> 00:49:43,489
He worked for the Nigerian government.

549
00:49:43,560 --> 00:49:47,493
His name is Dr. Olusegun Olatokumbo Fadipe.

550
00:49:47,561 --> 00:49:50,686
We must hurry or we'll miss the coach.

551
00:49:59,395 --> 00:50:00,361
In the end,

552
00:50:00,428 --> 00:50:04,225
I find out everything
about everyone in this place.

553
00:50:05,830 --> 00:50:09,263
Here.
Take a look at this.

554
00:50:09,330 --> 00:50:12,319
French.
It's a work of art.

555
00:50:12,397 --> 00:50:15,363
There are two Lebanese I use
who are the best in London.

556
00:50:15,430 --> 00:50:17,158
You give them a photograph...

557
00:50:17,230 --> 00:50:20,663
I have no idea what you're
talking about, Señor Juan.

558
00:50:20,732 --> 00:50:25,061
If you were just some African,
the deal would be simple.

559
00:50:25,131 --> 00:50:28,495
You give me your kidney,
I give you a new identity.

560
00:50:28,565 --> 00:50:31,498
I sell the kidney for 10 grand,
so I'm happy.

561
00:50:31,566 --> 00:50:35,362
The person who needs the kidney
gets cured, so he's happy.

562
00:50:35,432 --> 00:50:37,262
The person who sold his kidney

563
00:50:37,333 --> 00:50:40,731
gets to stay in this beautiful
country, so he's happy.

564
00:50:40,799 --> 00:50:44,664
My whole business is based on happiness.

565
00:50:44,734 --> 00:50:50,065
But for you,
Dr. Olusegun Olatokumbo Fadipe,

566
00:50:50,134 --> 00:50:53,157
I've a better idea.

567
00:50:53,234 --> 00:50:56,224
I do not want to get involved,
Señor Juan.

568
00:50:56,302 --> 00:51:01,064
Each time you operate,
you get £3,000.

569
00:51:01,135 --> 00:51:05,126
A passport for you and one for Senay.

570
00:51:05,203 --> 00:51:06,499
Take her on honeymoon.

571
00:51:06,570 --> 00:51:09,661
I do not want to get involved.

572
00:51:09,737 --> 00:51:12,669
You could even go back to Africa.

573
00:51:12,737 --> 00:51:16,102
And no one would know who the fuck you are.

574
00:51:17,838 --> 00:51:19,269
Your choice.

575
00:51:19,337 --> 00:51:21,326
No rush.

576
00:51:21,404 --> 00:51:27,599
Just wanted to put a little wasp in your head.

577
00:51:38,172 --> 00:51:40,036
Unusual.

578
00:51:40,107 --> 00:51:43,800
Chinese guy with no family.

579
00:51:43,873 --> 00:51:47,034
Maybe he's from the back of a truck.

580
00:51:48,674 --> 00:51:52,902
I cut off his buttons so his spirit can escape.

581
00:51:52,974 --> 00:51:54,906
I'm sewing up his pockets

582
00:51:54,974 --> 00:51:59,930
so he can't take his bad luck
with him to the spirit world.

583
00:52:00,009 --> 00:52:01,406
If he's an atheist,

584
00:52:01,476 --> 00:52:04,909
I'm ruining a suit no one will ever see.

585
00:52:04,976 --> 00:52:08,738
If he's a Buddhist,
I'm giving him eternal happiness

586
00:52:08,809 --> 00:52:10,672
for the price of a piece of thread.

587
00:52:10,743 --> 00:52:13,733
I have found out why the heart was at the room.

588
00:52:13,810 --> 00:52:16,298
They are removing kidneys.

589
00:52:16,944 --> 00:52:19,502
One of their patients died at their hands.

590
00:52:19,578 --> 00:52:22,169
Another, I treated for
a staphylococcal infection.

591
00:52:22,244 --> 00:52:24,972
You're treating people?

592
00:52:25,078 --> 00:52:26,566
I hope you charge.

593
00:52:26,611 --> 00:52:28,770
Did you hear what I said?

594
00:52:28,845 --> 00:52:33,540
There's nothing so dangerous as a virtuous man.

595
00:52:33,612 --> 00:52:35,601
Well, Okwe,
if you're so concerned,

596
00:52:35,679 --> 00:52:37,373
you should go to the police.

597
00:52:37,446 --> 00:52:38,843
Get yourself deported.

598
00:52:38,912 --> 00:52:42,242
Do you think if it were for
deportation I would not do it?

599
00:52:42,313 --> 00:52:44,836
I'm a wanted man, Guo Yi!

600
00:52:46,447 --> 00:52:48,504
Wanted for what?

601
00:52:52,380 --> 00:52:56,779
Okwe, you didn't know people sold their organs?

602
00:52:57,848 --> 00:53:00,337
- Not here.
- What do you mean, 'here'?

603
00:53:00,415 --> 00:53:03,314
Here in London you think it doesn't happen

604
00:53:03,382 --> 00:53:05,371
because the queen doesn't approve?

605
00:53:05,449 --> 00:53:08,381
I heard in London it's 10 grand for a kidney.

606
00:53:08,449 --> 00:53:11,506
For that, people take risks.

607
00:53:11,583 --> 00:53:15,346
If I had the courage,
I'd sell my kidney.

608
00:53:15,417 --> 00:53:18,178
Just to get out of here.

609
00:53:18,751 --> 00:53:22,149
Just to save my brain.

610
00:54:14,456 --> 00:54:16,389
The problem with being on time

611
00:54:16,456 --> 00:54:19,480
is that you can always be tracked down.

612
00:54:19,558 --> 00:54:21,853
What do you think of the girl?

613
00:54:21,924 --> 00:54:25,119
She's my next customer.
8 years old.

614
00:54:25,225 --> 00:54:26,918
She's called Rima.

615
00:54:26,958 --> 00:54:31,254
Her family brought her over
from Saudi hoping for a miracle.

616
00:54:31,325 --> 00:54:35,690
If she doesn't get the new
kidney, she's going to die.

617
00:54:36,892 --> 00:54:38,825
The doctor we use is no good.

618
00:54:38,892 --> 00:54:40,222
If he fucks up again,

619
00:54:40,292 --> 00:54:43,520
there'll be another heart down the lavatory.

620
00:54:46,727 --> 00:54:50,159
Okwe?
You still there?

621
00:54:51,460 --> 00:54:53,983
So I'm an evil man, right?

622
00:54:54,061 --> 00:54:56,959
But I'm trying to save her life.

623
00:54:57,027 --> 00:54:58,994
That's weird, huh?

624
00:54:59,062 --> 00:55:02,426
Kind of thing that keeps you awake at night.

625
00:55:12,662 --> 00:55:16,720
Tonight, London is colder than Moscow.

626
00:55:16,797 --> 00:55:19,729
I heard it on the radio.

627
00:55:45,067 --> 00:55:46,464
Okwe?

628
00:55:47,433 --> 00:55:51,834
It is a crazy idea,
but we really can do it.

629
00:55:51,900 --> 00:55:54,026
You said you liked New York.

630
00:55:54,102 --> 00:55:59,329
But if not New York, then maybe
Boston or Los Angeles.

631
00:55:59,401 --> 00:56:02,799
I'm going there, Okwe.
What do you think?

632
00:56:02,869 --> 00:56:05,801
And, Okwe,
you could go there, too.

633
00:56:06,902 --> 00:56:10,767
Senay, are you okay?

634
00:56:10,836 --> 00:56:12,768
Senay, where are you?

635
00:56:12,836 --> 00:56:14,995
What has happened?

636
00:56:57,941 --> 00:57:00,463
I knocked,
but you did not hear me.

637
00:57:02,041 --> 00:57:04,064
Senay, are you okay?

638
00:57:04,842 --> 00:57:07,467
Senay, what has happened?

639
00:57:07,542 --> 00:57:10,031
The factory does not suit me.

640
00:57:10,109 --> 00:57:14,098
My hands are too soft.
I cut my fingers.

641
00:57:14,176 --> 00:57:18,768
So I have decided to go to America.

642
00:57:20,743 --> 00:57:22,801
For America,
you would need a visa.

643
00:57:25,944 --> 00:57:28,569
Or maybe a European passport.

644
00:57:30,145 --> 00:57:33,111
- You keep away from Señor Juan!
- It is like taking out a tooth.

645
00:57:33,178 --> 00:57:34,974
He's lying, Senay!

646
00:57:35,045 --> 00:57:37,875
Because you are poor, you will
be gutted like an animal.

647
00:57:37,945 --> 00:57:40,411
They will cut you here,
or they will cut you here.

648
00:57:40,479 --> 00:57:42,411
They will take what they want.

649
00:57:42,479 --> 00:57:45,639
One of the laundry girls did it.
And now she's free.

650
00:57:45,713 --> 00:57:47,373
Others are dead, Senay!

651
00:57:47,447 --> 00:57:49,413
So they are free, too.

652
00:57:49,480 --> 00:57:51,378
What would your God say?

653
00:57:53,047 --> 00:57:55,275
My God does not speak to me anymore.

654
00:57:55,348 --> 00:57:57,337
Don't break, Senay.

655
00:57:57,414 --> 00:57:58,845
Save money.

656
00:57:58,914 --> 00:58:01,608
Keep New York in your head and work hard.

657
00:58:03,581 --> 00:58:06,877
You know what kind of work I do?

658
00:58:17,916 --> 00:58:19,815
Lunch!

659
00:59:29,358 --> 00:59:33,121
Okwe, somebody's in
the back room looking for you.

660
00:59:33,191 --> 00:59:36,124
She look like a film star, boy.

661
00:59:42,425 --> 00:59:43,550
Senay!

662
00:59:43,626 --> 00:59:47,956
Look, Okwe, I know for sure
that this coat costs £300.

663
00:59:48,026 --> 00:59:50,083
- And this dress...
- Tell me what has happened.

664
00:59:50,160 --> 00:59:52,649
We can sell the coat for £200.

665
00:59:52,727 --> 00:59:55,319
Senay, where did you get these?

666
00:59:55,394 --> 00:59:56,984
I bit, Okwe.

667
00:59:57,761 --> 01:00:00,023
At the factory.

668
01:00:00,094 --> 01:00:02,720
He said he would report me to lmmigration.

669
01:00:02,795 --> 01:00:05,159
And he made me suck.

670
01:00:05,228 --> 01:00:07,888
But today, I bit.

671
01:00:07,961 --> 01:00:09,588
I bit.

672
01:00:11,062 --> 01:00:13,085
I bit.

673
01:00:37,231 --> 01:00:40,789
Señor Juan sometimes has rooms in the hotel.

674
01:00:40,865 --> 01:00:41,888
No, Senay.

675
01:00:41,965 --> 01:00:44,955
- Just for tonight.
- No.

676
01:00:45,032 --> 01:00:47,294
Through there is hot water and a shower.

677
01:00:47,366 --> 01:00:49,333
Hurry, Senay.

678
01:00:52,333 --> 01:00:55,299
What is this place, Okwe?

679
01:00:55,901 --> 01:00:59,061
It is a place where you can stay for tonight.

680
01:00:59,134 --> 01:01:00,827
So cold.

681
01:01:00,901 --> 01:01:04,834
If anyone comes,
you are a friend of Guo Yi.

682
01:01:26,171 --> 01:01:29,137
Tomorrow we will find you somewhere to live.

683
01:01:39,639 --> 01:01:43,503
So... it is in there.

684
01:01:48,573 --> 01:01:51,131
I can hear it.

685
01:01:52,406 --> 01:01:54,566
Your heart.

686
01:03:03,981 --> 01:03:05,810
Hello.
Room service.

687
01:03:19,149 --> 01:03:22,343
Buenos dias, negro.

688
01:03:31,551 --> 01:03:34,040
Come on.
Come on!

689
01:03:40,919 --> 01:03:43,283
She is nil by mouth the whole day.

690
01:03:43,352 --> 01:03:45,011
Please.

691
01:03:50,053 --> 01:03:51,349
Sister.

692
01:03:51,419 --> 01:03:53,613
Help me, brother.

693
01:03:58,087 --> 01:04:01,315
Stop acting like you've got a choice.

694
01:04:06,054 --> 01:04:07,452
Please!

695
01:04:08,555 --> 01:04:09,612
Put on your clothes.

696
01:04:09,688 --> 01:04:11,847
Son of a bitch!

697
01:04:11,922 --> 01:04:14,684
You came in a truck,
but you're going home in chains!

698
01:04:14,756 --> 01:04:17,449
- They'll deliver you like meat!
- No!

699
01:04:20,123 --> 01:04:23,681
The whole world is wrong except you, Okwe?

700
01:04:23,790 --> 01:04:26,517
What?
What, Okwe?

701
01:04:26,557 --> 01:04:31,513
You are going to cut me up and flush me away?

702
01:04:31,591 --> 01:04:32,818
Huh?

703
01:05:07,161 --> 01:05:09,593
I really don't know you at all,
do I, Okwe?

704
01:05:09,662 --> 01:05:12,128
- This is Senay. She is a friend.
- I'm not your friend.

705
01:05:12,196 --> 01:05:15,026
- She's been out here all night.
- I would rather freeze to death

706
01:05:15,095 --> 01:05:16,561
than go into that building again.

707
01:05:16,629 --> 01:05:18,652
You know, there are mornings I feel the same.

708
01:05:18,729 --> 01:05:19,820
Come.
It's cold.

709
01:05:19,896 --> 01:05:22,021
This is the house of the dead, Okwe!

710
01:05:22,096 --> 01:05:24,085
They're all dead!

711
01:05:25,298 --> 01:05:27,160
Okwe.

712
01:05:28,797 --> 01:05:30,786
Maybe this will help.

713
01:05:30,864 --> 01:05:34,262
My cousin has a room in Chinatown.

714
01:05:34,331 --> 01:05:36,695
I guess there's space for two.

715
01:05:38,698 --> 01:05:43,290
You know, Okwe, good at chess
usually means bad at life.

716
01:05:43,365 --> 01:05:46,627
You do realize that she's
in love with you, don't you?

717
01:05:46,699 --> 01:05:50,427
I've been with her 20 minutes,
and I know it.

718
01:05:50,499 --> 01:05:53,932
But then, I'm bad at chess.

719
01:06:02,434 --> 01:06:04,730
Senay, there is something I must tell you.

720
01:06:04,801 --> 01:06:07,494
- This is your religion?
- I have no religion.

721
01:06:07,569 --> 01:06:09,228
Senay.

722
01:06:10,701 --> 01:06:13,259
You have stopped chewing the leaf.

723
01:06:13,335 --> 01:06:15,358
I can see it in your eyes.

724
01:06:15,435 --> 01:06:18,527
You know, Okwe,
your eyes are quite pretty.

725
01:06:18,602 --> 01:06:22,330
- They're not bad-looking.
- Senay, listen to me.

726
01:06:24,369 --> 01:06:27,165
I come to this churchyard often.

727
01:06:27,237 --> 01:06:31,465
I come here to be alone
and to think about my wife.

728
01:06:33,304 --> 01:06:35,862
So now you see.

729
01:06:35,938 --> 01:06:38,131
What do I see?

730
01:06:38,206 --> 01:06:40,398
You should not see me anymore.

731
01:06:44,538 --> 01:06:46,505
Do you love her?

732
01:06:46,573 --> 01:06:47,539
Do you love her?

733
01:06:47,606 --> 01:06:49,232
There is a room above a restaurant.

734
01:06:49,306 --> 01:06:51,272
Immigration police do not go into Chinatown.

735
01:06:51,339 --> 01:06:52,965
- You will be safe.
- Do you love her?

736
01:06:53,040 --> 01:06:54,733
Here's money for the rent I owe you.

737
01:06:54,806 --> 01:06:57,637
There is more for the trouble
I have caused you.

738
01:06:57,707 --> 01:06:59,798
- Do you love her?
- Love?

739
01:07:02,607 --> 01:07:06,131
For you and I,
there is only survival.

740
01:07:07,274 --> 01:07:10,729
It is time you woke up from your stupid dream.

741
01:07:38,744 --> 01:07:39,971
Yes?

742
01:07:41,978 --> 01:07:43,774
Senay.

743
01:07:45,545 --> 01:07:48,137
Are you going on holiday or something?

744
01:07:50,046 --> 01:07:52,171
Señor Juan.

745
01:08:01,547 --> 01:08:02,808
Señor Juan.

746
01:08:02,881 --> 01:08:04,574
America, maybe?

747
01:08:22,416 --> 01:08:23,347
Come on.

748
01:08:23,449 --> 01:08:25,677
You cleaned up their shit so long.

749
01:08:25,716 --> 01:08:28,205
Now you can be one of them.

750
01:09:27,489 --> 01:09:29,648
Who is it?

751
01:09:29,723 --> 01:09:33,747
It's me.
I got some paperwork.

752
01:09:35,324 --> 01:09:37,449
Okay.
How old are you?

753
01:09:37,524 --> 01:09:38,922
22.

754
01:09:38,991 --> 01:09:40,957
How old do you want to be?

755
01:09:41,024 --> 01:09:42,718
22.

756
01:09:43,992 --> 01:09:46,457
Hey, Come on.
Relax.

757
01:09:46,525 --> 01:09:48,321
I can make you whatever you want.

758
01:09:48,392 --> 01:09:50,823
You want to be Spanish?
Or Greek?

759
01:09:50,892 --> 01:09:52,381
Italian.

760
01:09:52,993 --> 01:09:54,720
You're going to need a new name.

761
01:09:54,793 --> 01:09:57,316
Isabella Encarico.

762
01:09:57,394 --> 01:09:58,858
You're sure that's Italian?

763
01:09:58,926 --> 01:10:01,620
She owns a café in New York.

764
01:10:27,863 --> 01:10:30,853
Okay.
You are at New York lmmigration.

765
01:10:30,930 --> 01:10:32,056
What's your name?

766
01:10:32,130 --> 01:10:34,096
Isabella Fontana Encarico.

767
01:10:34,164 --> 01:10:36,187
- How old are you?
- 22.

768
01:10:36,264 --> 01:10:38,196
- Where were you born?
- Napoli.

769
01:10:38,264 --> 01:10:40,389
- Where in Napoli?
- Arenella.

770
01:10:40,464 --> 01:10:43,363
Right.

771
01:10:43,432 --> 01:10:47,262
The trick, Senay, is to believe
you are the new person.

772
01:10:47,332 --> 01:10:51,095
If you believe it inside, then
the lmmigration will believe it.

773
01:10:51,166 --> 01:10:53,223
Drink, Senay?

774
01:10:57,433 --> 01:11:01,196
What are you afraid of?
Okwe's gone.

775
01:11:01,267 --> 01:11:03,733
Got scared and go away.

776
01:11:05,734 --> 01:11:07,563
Go to hell.

777
01:11:09,701 --> 01:11:12,600
This is hell.

778
01:11:12,669 --> 01:11:15,361
I'm helping you to get away.

779
01:11:15,435 --> 01:11:16,526
Take off your robe.

780
01:11:16,602 --> 01:11:18,159
Come on.
Come on.

781
01:11:18,236 --> 01:11:19,758
Hey, hey!
Stop! Stop that!

782
01:11:19,835 --> 01:11:22,063
Stop that!

783
01:11:22,135 --> 01:11:24,431
I can't believe it!

784
01:11:24,536 --> 01:11:27,025
I'm arguing like you are my fucking wife!

785
01:11:27,070 --> 01:11:29,195
Let me explain something, Senay.

786
01:11:29,270 --> 01:11:33,862
Your robe, now, is what the
Americans call a 'deal breaker.'

787
01:11:33,937 --> 01:11:35,597
So...

788
01:11:35,671 --> 01:11:37,159
No.

789
01:11:39,705 --> 01:11:43,001
You are this close to New York,
and you said no.

790
01:12:00,974 --> 01:12:02,530
Wait.

791
01:12:07,308 --> 01:12:10,762
I want the whole thing.
That's the deal.

792
01:12:10,841 --> 01:12:12,932
Take it or leave it.

793
01:12:14,608 --> 01:12:17,439
You do not see me.

794
01:12:17,508 --> 01:12:20,066
You just do.

795
01:12:20,142 --> 01:12:22,005
Take it or leave it.

796
01:12:56,980 --> 01:12:59,605
So it wasn't so bad, huh?

797
01:12:59,679 --> 01:13:01,441
Nothing to cry about.

798
01:13:01,513 --> 01:13:03,843
I'm not crying.

799
01:13:03,914 --> 01:13:07,539
If you told me it was the first
time, I'd have cut a ribbon.

800
01:13:11,147 --> 01:13:14,875
I can't believe Okwe never fucked you.

801
01:13:14,948 --> 01:13:17,346
You kind of love him, huh?

802
01:13:17,415 --> 01:13:21,347
Women love men most who don't love them back.

803
01:13:21,415 --> 01:13:25,144
Well, you had a lucky escape.

804
01:13:25,250 --> 01:13:27,876
You know why he ran away?

805
01:13:31,483 --> 01:13:33,915
Because I found out that in Africa,

806
01:13:33,984 --> 01:13:36,177
he murdered his own wife.

807
01:13:43,985 --> 01:13:47,316
You don't eat or drink for 24 hours, okay?

808
01:13:47,385 --> 01:13:49,044
Doctor's orders.

809
01:14:16,221 --> 01:14:18,414
Senay is here?

810
01:14:20,256 --> 01:14:22,347
Senay is here?

811
01:14:39,224 --> 01:14:40,883
Senay.

812
01:14:50,758 --> 01:14:52,917
I will need a pill.

813
01:14:56,193 --> 01:14:59,956
There is a pill you can take the morning after.

814
01:15:01,959 --> 01:15:03,858
You're a doctor.

815
01:15:04,894 --> 01:15:07,917
At least you can get me a pill.

816
01:15:47,231 --> 01:15:49,993
I won't allow you to butcher her.

817
01:15:50,065 --> 01:15:51,997
You won't allow?

818
01:15:52,065 --> 01:15:54,826
I will operate on her myself.

819
01:15:54,899 --> 01:15:56,230
You'll do what?

820
01:15:56,299 --> 01:15:58,027
I will do it.

821
01:15:58,099 --> 01:16:01,066
It is the only way I can be sure
she will not die.

822
01:16:02,966 --> 01:16:05,489
In return, I want a passport.

823
01:16:05,567 --> 01:16:07,624
A new identity.

824
01:16:08,634 --> 01:16:11,532
Well, holy shit.

825
01:16:11,600 --> 01:16:13,567
So you are human, Okwe?

826
01:16:13,635 --> 01:16:16,692
I will bring you our photographs
tomorrow morning.

827
01:16:24,235 --> 01:16:28,191
Hi. I'm Juliette.
I'm a friend of Okwe's.

828
01:16:28,270 --> 01:16:31,065
He said that you needed these.

829
01:16:35,436 --> 01:16:39,926
So, he did not care enough
to bring them himself.

830
01:16:40,004 --> 01:16:42,937
Oh, Okwe's an angel.

831
01:16:53,238 --> 01:16:56,330
There.
Never happened.

832
01:17:01,907 --> 01:17:05,305
So, what did happen?

833
01:17:11,140 --> 01:17:15,335
Before, I was a virgin.

834
01:17:15,408 --> 01:17:17,340
Jesus.

835
01:17:17,408 --> 01:17:19,033
Mohammed.

836
01:17:30,110 --> 01:17:32,269
What a pair.

837
01:17:32,343 --> 01:17:34,968
The virgin and the whore.

838
01:17:43,011 --> 01:17:46,205
- Boss?
- The doctor needs a good car.

839
01:17:48,611 --> 01:17:51,475
Take it.
Last time, you were lucky.

840
01:17:53,212 --> 01:17:55,075
Black is black.

841
01:18:16,247 --> 01:18:19,112
Wash these again.
Please.

842
01:18:21,115 --> 01:18:24,343
Boil, boil, eh?
Hot, hot.

843
01:18:53,985 --> 01:18:56,042
Oh, dear.

844
01:18:58,286 --> 01:19:01,844
So this is how you do it right.

845
01:19:01,920 --> 01:19:04,852
There can be no guarantee against E. Coli.

846
01:19:07,086 --> 01:19:08,984
Wonderful.

847
01:19:09,053 --> 01:19:10,246
Oh, yes.

848
01:19:10,320 --> 01:19:12,377
No, no.

849
01:19:23,489 --> 01:19:27,387
Passports.
It's something I do right.

850
01:19:40,057 --> 01:19:41,647
No parking.

851
01:19:41,723 --> 01:19:44,087
Okwe wants me to wait here.

852
01:19:46,291 --> 01:19:49,156
I gave her a sedative an hour ago.

853
01:19:49,226 --> 01:19:51,623
She's only in a deep sleep.

854
01:19:51,691 --> 01:19:56,057
But now you are here, I can
administer the anesthetic.

855
01:19:56,126 --> 01:19:57,523
Now I'm here?

856
01:19:57,592 --> 01:20:00,423
You are going to be my assistant, Señor Juan.

857
01:20:00,493 --> 01:20:01,958
What the fuck is this?

858
01:20:02,026 --> 01:20:04,857
I have noticed that if you
do not drink, your hands shake.

859
01:20:04,927 --> 01:20:06,324
When you pass me the scalpel,

860
01:20:06,393 --> 01:20:09,588
I do not want you to cut off my fingers.

861
01:20:13,394 --> 01:20:15,860
Where will they come to collect?

862
01:20:18,328 --> 01:20:20,987
If you faint,
I will have only half an hour

863
01:20:21,061 --> 01:20:23,186
before the kidney begins to deteriorate.

864
01:20:23,261 --> 01:20:27,422
They come to the laundry bay.
Back of the kitchen.

865
01:20:28,497 --> 01:20:30,189
You better start.

866
01:20:30,262 --> 01:20:32,160
Go and scrub your hands.

867
01:20:32,229 --> 01:20:36,889
Yes. Professional.

868
01:20:39,163 --> 01:20:40,652
It's decided.

869
01:20:40,730 --> 01:20:43,094
It's fucking decided.

870
01:20:43,164 --> 01:20:47,096
You and me are going into business.

871
01:20:48,997 --> 01:20:51,589
You know washing dishes?

872
01:20:51,665 --> 01:20:56,963
You know when you forget
on Friday and come in Monday,

873
01:20:57,032 --> 01:20:59,931
and there is a pan with sauce?

874
01:20:59,999 --> 01:21:01,396
White. Green.

875
01:21:01,465 --> 01:21:02,453
Shit.

876
01:21:02,532 --> 01:21:05,260
That is...

877
01:21:05,333 --> 01:21:08,390
How they do things in the city.

878
01:21:11,967 --> 01:21:13,762
Jesus.

879
01:21:13,833 --> 01:21:16,561
Was I speaking English then?

880
01:21:16,634 --> 01:21:18,827
What you say?

881
01:21:18,901 --> 01:21:22,731
Why do you say?

882
01:21:22,834 --> 01:21:24,357
Senay.

883
01:21:37,436 --> 01:21:39,732
I don't understand it,
how the ice will help.

884
01:21:39,803 --> 01:21:41,269
Make you last longer, babe.

885
01:21:41,337 --> 01:21:44,360
I don't want to last longer.
It's not even payday.

886
01:21:44,437 --> 01:21:46,995
All right.
Make you harder.

887
01:21:48,338 --> 01:21:51,566
Think what happens to water
when it freezes, huh?

888
01:21:53,338 --> 01:21:55,100
There.

889
01:21:55,172 --> 01:21:56,933
Get a bucket.

890
01:21:57,005 --> 01:21:58,471
Bucket?

891
01:21:59,439 --> 01:22:01,530
Come on!

892
01:22:02,105 --> 01:22:06,198
Okwe, you have removed kidneys before?

893
01:22:06,273 --> 01:22:07,829
Many times.

894
01:22:07,906 --> 01:22:09,702
In pathology.

895
01:22:09,775 --> 01:22:11,865
What is pathology?

896
01:22:11,941 --> 01:22:14,702
It means the patient is already dead.

897
01:22:15,907 --> 01:22:18,499
Did he tell you things about me, Senay?

898
01:22:20,541 --> 01:22:22,439
No.

899
01:22:29,642 --> 01:22:33,097
Let me wipe your brow, Doctor.

900
01:22:48,678 --> 01:22:51,803
Juliette, put the ice
on the bed and put on the gown.

901
01:22:59,047 --> 01:23:00,807
Take the bag.

902
01:23:00,879 --> 01:23:02,311
Squeeze.

903
01:23:02,379 --> 01:23:03,742
Gently.

904
01:23:04,546 --> 01:23:06,409
We must go and scrub up.

905
01:23:13,514 --> 01:23:15,377
Cold tonight, huh?

906
01:23:18,248 --> 01:23:23,237
On the night like this,
who would want so much ice?

907
01:23:25,882 --> 01:23:28,712
You are Pylades.

908
01:23:28,782 --> 01:23:30,645
Pylades was the boatman

909
01:23:30,715 --> 01:23:34,478
who ferried the souls to the land of the dead.

910
01:23:34,549 --> 01:23:35,879
If you didn't put a coin

911
01:23:35,950 --> 01:23:38,143
under the tongue of your dead relative,

912
01:23:38,216 --> 01:23:40,943
Pylades wouldn't take them to Hades

913
01:23:41,016 --> 01:23:44,312
no matter how good you had been in your life.

914
01:24:00,552 --> 01:24:01,540
Knife.

915
01:24:10,687 --> 01:24:12,176
Oh, Jesus.

916
01:24:12,253 --> 01:24:14,516
Juliette, you are not allowed to faint.

917
01:24:59,500 --> 01:25:00,523
Is that it, then?

918
01:25:00,600 --> 01:25:02,260
No, no.
I must sew him up.

919
01:25:02,334 --> 01:25:03,823
Why?

920
01:25:06,068 --> 01:25:08,058
Fetch me stitches.

921
01:25:17,069 --> 01:25:20,263
Juliette, will you go and check
there is no one else waiting?

922
01:25:20,336 --> 01:25:21,427
Yeah.

923
01:25:38,171 --> 01:25:40,535
Where's Señor Juan?

924
01:25:40,638 --> 01:25:42,399
He's drunk.

925
01:26:07,508 --> 01:26:11,202
How come I've never seen you people before?

926
01:26:11,274 --> 01:26:14,604
Because we are the people you do not see.

927
01:26:14,675 --> 01:26:17,369
We are the ones who drive your cabs.

928
01:26:17,442 --> 01:26:19,465
We clean your rooms.

929
01:26:19,542 --> 01:26:21,667
And suck your cocks.

930
01:26:38,611 --> 01:26:40,474
In one hour, call an ambulance.

931
01:26:40,578 --> 01:26:42,669
Send them up to Room 510.

932
01:26:42,711 --> 01:26:44,177
Juliette.

933
01:26:45,645 --> 01:26:46,633
Thank you.

934
01:26:46,712 --> 01:26:48,507
Shh.
It's okay.

935
01:26:48,579 --> 01:26:50,601
- One hour.
- Okay.

936
01:27:01,780 --> 01:27:05,044
Handa?
Handa, it's me... Senay.

937
01:27:05,114 --> 01:27:07,080
You hear how good my English is?

938
01:27:07,148 --> 01:27:08,636
I'm coming to New York.

939
01:27:08,714 --> 01:27:11,647
I'm coming to New York!
I'm coming to New York!

940
01:27:11,715 --> 01:27:14,113
- My hands are shaking.
- So are mine.

941
01:27:14,181 --> 01:27:15,807
I don't have a driver's license.

942
01:27:15,882 --> 01:27:17,814
Hey. It's dead.

943
01:27:17,882 --> 01:27:19,348
It's the tunnel.

944
01:27:19,416 --> 01:27:21,644
I must tell her what time we land.

945
01:27:21,716 --> 01:27:23,807
Senay, what Sneaky told you was true.

946
01:27:23,883 --> 01:27:25,405
He did not tell me anything.

947
01:27:25,482 --> 01:27:28,608
I did not kill my wife myself,
but still it was my fault.

948
01:27:28,684 --> 01:27:31,583
- I was a pathologist in Lagos.
- Now we are someone new.

949
01:27:31,650 --> 01:27:33,445
A government official was shot.

950
01:27:33,517 --> 01:27:35,642
I was told to destroy the evidence.

951
01:27:35,717 --> 01:27:38,513
When I refused,
my house was firebombed.

952
01:27:38,585 --> 01:27:40,550
My wife was still inside.

953
01:27:41,551 --> 01:27:44,382
The police charged me with her murder.

954
01:27:47,052 --> 01:27:49,450
I had to run.

955
01:27:49,519 --> 01:27:51,712
But my daughter stayed.

956
01:27:51,786 --> 01:27:56,151
Valerie.
She's with my sister in Lagos.

957
01:27:56,653 --> 01:27:58,949
How old is she?

958
01:27:59,520 --> 01:28:01,748
7.

959
01:28:02,553 --> 01:28:04,520
I must go to her.

960
01:28:50,892 --> 01:28:53,052
Tell me about Lagos.

961
01:28:53,126 --> 01:28:56,251
Do they have hotels that need maids?

962
01:28:57,926 --> 01:28:59,449
When you arrive at the airport,

963
01:28:59,527 --> 01:29:03,425
you will see a whole line of yellow cabs.

964
01:29:03,494 --> 01:29:05,857
The car will take you across a bridge.

965
01:29:06,727 --> 01:29:09,558
When you have crossed the river,
you will see

966
01:29:09,628 --> 01:29:11,788
lights in the trees.

967
01:29:12,628 --> 01:29:14,959
Policemen on white horses.

968
01:29:15,028 --> 01:29:16,550
No.

969
01:29:19,262 --> 01:29:22,252
I know that it won't be like that.

970
01:29:26,130 --> 01:29:28,061
Goodbye, Okwe.

971
01:29:44,031 --> 01:29:46,259
Senay.

972
01:29:48,632 --> 01:29:50,598
Hold me.

973
01:29:53,499 --> 01:29:56,795
You must go.
Isabella.

974
01:29:56,866 --> 01:29:59,491
Always we must hide.

975
01:30:05,667 --> 01:30:08,758
This is the café where my cousin works.

976
01:31:16,709 --> 01:31:19,197
I love you.

977
01:32:15,715 --> 01:32:17,306
Hello?

978
01:32:21,415 --> 01:32:23,108
Valerie.

979
01:32:26,482 --> 01:32:28,346
Yes, it's me.

980
01:32:31,283 --> 01:32:32,943
At last.

981
01:32:35,717 --> 01:32:38,048
I'm coming home.

982
01:33:42,023 --> 01:33:47,388
' Now I'm wakin' at the crack of dawn '

983
01:33:47,457 --> 01:33:52,913
' To send a little money home from here, too '

984
01:33:52,990 --> 01:33:58,514
' The moon is risin' like a discotheque '

985
01:33:58,592 --> 01:34:04,081
' And now my bags are down
and packed for travelin' '

986
01:34:04,158 --> 01:34:08,252
' Lookin' at happiness,
keepin' my flavor fresh '

987
01:34:08,326 --> 01:34:14,418
' Nobody knows, I guess,
how far I'll go, I know '

988
01:34:14,493 --> 01:34:19,154
' So I'm leavin' at 6 o'clock,
meet in a parking lot '

989
01:34:19,228 --> 01:34:24,092
' Have in your hand a shot,
sunglasses on '

990
01:34:24,161 --> 01:34:32,822
' She waits by this glass
and concrete and stone '

991
01:34:32,895 --> 01:34:40,954
' It is just a house,
not a home '

992
01:34:41,030 --> 01:34:46,429
' Skin that covers me from head to toe '

993
01:34:46,498 --> 01:34:52,089
' Except a couple tiny holes and openings '

994
01:34:52,164 --> 01:34:57,427
' Where the city's blowin' in and out '

995
01:34:57,499 --> 01:35:03,090
' And this is what
it's all about, delightfully '

996
01:35:03,165 --> 01:35:06,962
' Everything's possible when you're an animal '

997
01:35:07,032 --> 01:35:13,296
' Not inconceivable
how things can change, I know '

998
01:35:13,366 --> 01:35:16,230
' So I'm puttin' on after-shave '

999
01:35:16,300 --> 01:35:18,130
' Nothing is out of place '

1000
01:35:18,200 --> 01:35:20,190
' Gonna be on my way '

1001
01:35:20,267 --> 01:35:22,755
' Try to pretend '

1002
01:35:22,834 --> 01:35:31,996
' It's not only glass and concrete and stone '

1003
01:35:32,068 --> 01:35:40,025
' And it's just a house,
not a home '

1004
01:35:53,738 --> 01:36:01,263
' And it's glass and concrete and stone '

1005
01:36:01,338 --> 01:36:08,500
' It is just a house,
not a home '

1006
01:36:08,573 --> 01:36:15,938
' And my head is 50 feet high '

1007
01:36:16,006 --> 01:36:24,633
' Let my body and soul be my guide '

