Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.MY-SUBS today
[Motorcycles Revving]
- [Man] Buenos días.
- [Man #2] Bueno, amigo.
[All Continue Speaking Spanish]
[Speaking Spanish]
[All Speaking Spanish]
Uh, okay.
[Spanish]
[Speaking Spanish]
[Hammering On Metal In Distance]
- [Dog Barking]
- [Chickens Clucking]
[Snorting]
- [Chuckles]
- [Dog Barking]
[Chickens Clucking]
[Spanish]
Pura vida, hermano.
[Chuckling]
Sí, pura vida.
Bueno.
[Spanish]
- Muchas gracias.
- Bueno. [Continues In Spanish]
- Eh? Bueno.
[Airplane Approaching]
[Tires Screech]
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Jet Engine Roar Continues]
?? [Rock]
[Man]
? You know I smoked a lot of grass ?
? Oh, Lord, I've popped a lot of pills ?
? But I've never touched nothin'?
? Mm-hmm ?
? That my spirit could kill ?
? You know, I've seen a lot
of people walkin' 'round ?
? With tombstones in their eyes ?
? But the pusher don't care ?
? Ah, if you live or if you die ?
? Goddamn ?
? Mm-hmm, the pusher ?
? Hey, hey, I say the pusher ?
? I said goddamn ?
? Goddamn the pusher man ??
[Motorcycles Revving, Idling]
?? [Hard Rock]
[Man]
? Get your motor runnin'?
? Head out on the highway ?
? Lookin'for adventure ?
? And whatever
comes our way ?
? Yeah, darlin'
go make it happen ?
? Take the world in a love embrace ?
? Fire all of your guns at once and ?
? Explode into space ?
? I like smoke and lightnin'?
? Heavy metal thunder ?
? Racin'with the wind ?
? And the feelin'that I'm under ?
? Yeah, darlin', go make it happen ?
? Take the world in a love embrace ?
? Fire all of your guns at once and ?
? Explode into space ?
? Like a true nature's child ?
? We were born, born to be wild ?
? We can climb so high ?
? I never want to die ?
? Born to be ?
? Wild ?
? Born to be wild ??
[Horn Beeping]
Hey, you got a room?
Hey, man!
You got a room?
You asshole!
? I'm going down to Mardi Gras ?
? I'm gonna get me
a Mardi Gras queen, yeah ??
- Oh, man. Wow. Mardi Gras.
- [Dog Barking In Distance]
That's gonna be the weirdest, man.
You know?
[Chuckles] You know what
we oughta do, man?
First thing, man...
go and get us a groovy dinner.
- Yeah, break out some of that cash, man.
- [Barking Continues]
[Imitates Dog Howling]
Out here in the wilderness,
fighting Indians and cowboys on every side.
?? [Imitates Guitar Twang]
What's the matter? You zoned? What?
You're really zoned, huh?
No, I'm... I'm just kind of tired.
Yeah, man, you're pullin' inside, man.
You're gettin' a little distance tonight.
You're gettin' a little distance, man.
[Chuckles]
Yeah. Well, I'm just...
gettin' my thing together.
Yeah, right.
[Footsteps Crunching]
[Wind Blowing]
Come on. It's checkout time.
Hey. Billy.
Oh, man. Don't do that.
[Exhales]
[Donkey Braying]
[Metal Clanging]
Howdy.
What can I do for you?
I'd like to fix my flat,
if you don't mind.
No, I don't mind.
- If you get in the barn there,
you'll find any tools you need.
- [Motorcycle Revs]
- [Whinnies]
- Whoa, baby. Hold on.
Now turn that thing off.
You're making my horse skittish.
[Engine Turns Off]
Yeah.
That sure is a good-looking machine.
- Yeah.
- [Metal Clanging]
[Grunts]
- Whew.
- [Coughs]
There you go.
Hey, you fellas can sit down here.
Uh-huh.
Would you mind, uh,
takin'off your hat?
We thank thee, O Lord,
for these, thy gifts...
received from thy bounty...
in the name of thy only begotten Son,
Jesus Christ, our Lord.
Amen.
Where you fellas from?
[Man]
L.A.
L. A?
Los Angeles.
Los Angeles. Is that a fact?
When I was a young man,
I was headed for California.
But... Well, you know how it is.
Well, you sure got a nice spread here.
I sure got a lot of'em.
My wife is Catholic, you know.
Honey, could we have some more coffee?
No, I mean it.
You've got a nice place.
It's not every man
that can live off the land, you know.
Do your own thing in your own time.
You should be proud.
?? [Folk Rock]
[Man]
? Oh, I'd rather go and journey ?
? Where the diamond crescent's glowing ?
? And run across the valley ?
? Beneath the sacred mountain ?
? And wander through the forest ?
? Where the trees have leaves of prisms ?
? And break the light in colors ?
? That no one knows the names of ?
? And when it's time, I'll go and wait ?
? Beside a legendary fountain ?
? Till I see your form reflected ?
? In its clear and jeweled waters ?
? And if you think I'm ready ?
? You may lead me to the chasm ?
? Where the rivers of our vision ?
? Flow into one another ?
? I will want to dive beneath
the white cascading waters ?
? She may beg
She may plead ?
? She may argue with her logic ?
? And then she'll know the things I lose ?
? That really have no value ?
? In the end, she will surely know ?
? I wasn't born to follow ??
[Billy]
Hey, man, what are you doing?
I gotta talk to you, man.
[Exhales]
Hey, man, everything that we ever dreamed of
is in that teardrop gas tank...
and you got a stranger over there
pouring gasoline all over it.
Man, all he's got to do is turn and look
over into it, man, and he can see that...
He won't know what it is, man.
He won't know what it is. Don't worry, Billy.
- Everything's all right.
- All right, man. All right. I don't know, man.
I do.
Everything's fine, Billy.
- Well, uh...
- [Sniffs] That's all taken care of.
I like that.
[Chuckles]
[Motorcycles Start]
?? [Folk Rock]
[Man]
? I pulled into Nazareth ?
? Was a-feelin' 'bout half-past dead ?
? I just need someplace ?
? Where I can lay my head ?
? Hey, mister, can you tell me ?
? Where a man might find a bed ?
? He just grinned and shook my hand ?
? No was all he said ?
? Take a load off Fanny ?
? Take a load for free ?
? And, and, and ?
- ? You put the load right on me ?
? Ooh, hoo, hoo, hoo-hoo ?
? I picked up my bag ?
? I went lookin'for a place to hide ?
? When I saw Carmen and the devil ?
? Walkin'side by side ?
? I said, Hey, Carmen ?
? Come on
Let's go downtown ?
? She said, I gotta go ?
? But my friend can stick around ?
? Take a load off Fanny ?
? Take a load for free ?
? And, and, and ?
- ? You put the load right on me ?
? Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ?
? Yeah, take a load off Fanny ?
? Take a load for free ?
? Take a load off Fanny ?
? And, and, and ?
- ? You put the load right on me ?
[Wind Blowing]
?? [Vocalizing]
?? [Ends]
[Coyote Howling In Distance]
[No Audible Dialogue]
- How much further we gotta go, man?
- I don't know.
- Huh?
- Not much further.
[Chuckles]
That's what you said this mornin'.
I sometimes say it all day.
[Billy Chuckles]
Really? You say it all day, eh?
- [Coughs]
- We don't have much longer. We'll be there soon.
We gotta get to Mardi Gras, man.
We're going to Mardi Gras.
Your little heart is set on that, huh?
We got a week.
That's a week away, man.
[Billy]
It's a long way to Mardi Gras, baby.
It won't take us a week
to get to New Orleans.
Wow.
- I think I'm gonna crash.
- [Billy Chuckles]
I think you have crashed, man.
[Chuckles]
[Billy Groans]
[Sighs]
- I keep seeing things jumping all over the place.
- [Laughing]
- Really?
- Yeah, look.
- What is it?
- It's... It's a moth.
- A what?
- Yeah, man.
Moth. Bug.
[Sniffs]
[Exhales]
It's a weird place, man.
Oh, man.
That smoke's getting to me.
- [Sniffs]
- But I notice you're not moving.
[Laughing]
[Billy]
Where you from, man?
Can I, uh... Can I have a light?
[Exhaling]
- Hard to say.
- [Chuckles] It's hard to say?
Where you from, man?
Well, it's hard to say
because it's a very long word, you know?
I just want to know
where you're from, man.
A city.
- From a city.
- Mm-hmm.
Doesn't make any difference what city.
All cities are alike.
- That's why I'm out here now.
- [Chuckling] That's why you're out here now?
- Yeah.
- Why?
'Cause I'm from the city, a long way from the city,
and that's where I want to be right now.
They know you in this place?
[Sniffing]
[Exhales]
This place we're coming to?
- No. Here.
- The place we're at now?
This place.
[Billy Laughs]
You're right on top of'em.
- I'm right on top of'em?
- Yeah.
The people this place belongs to
are buried right under you.
You could be a trifle polite.
"A trifle polite"?
[Chuckles]
A small thing to ask.
You ever want to be somebody else?
I'd like to try Porky Pig.
I never wanted to be anybody else.
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Dog Barking]
[Children Chattering, Shouting]
[Children Giggling, Chattering]
[Man]
Hey. Hey, hey, hey.
[Children Chattering]
[Child]
It's a dumbbell. [Laughs]
- [Baby Crying]
- [Children Chattering]
[Water Splashing]
- [Billy] Bam, baml Ahl
- We got you!
Pow! Pow! Pow!
[Imitates Gunfire]
Pow! Pow! Pow! Pow! Pow!
You can't hit me.
I'm invisible. I'm invisible.
[Children Laughing]
Hey, Sarah. How's it goin'?
[Goat Bleating]
Hey, Rudolph,
what are you eating?
[Sarah]
Thanks for the stuff you brought.
- [Man] How's it going?
- [Sarah] We just can't take any more strangers.
Just too many people dropping in.
Oh, I'm not talking about
you and your friends. You know that.
- [Rudolph Bleating]
- Like the week before...
Susan dropped in
with 12 people from Easter City.
She wanted to take
10 pounds of rice with her.
- [Man] Yeah?
- Well, naturally we had to say no.
- Right.
- So she gets all uptight...
and she breaks out some hash,
and she won't give us any.
Oh, and that's not all. The next morning,
they went outside to start their bus...
and they couldn't get it started.
[Man Chuckles] Sarah, I bet you haven't had
anybody around like me to rap to, have you?
I don't have to tell you how it is, Sarah.
You know I love you, and I want you to rap...
- Oh, God, I want you to rap, rap, rap!
- Cut that out!
I guess nobody else here is interested,
but, um, I would sure like to meet your friend.
I'll bet you'd like to do more than that.
- I think he's beautiful.
- He's beautiful.
Hey, what is that, uh,
weird thing up there on the hill, man?
Looks like a stage. You got
a light opera company here or something?
That-That's the mime troupe stage.
They've gone down to the hot springs to bathe.
Mime troupe?
[Chuckles]
- [Woman] Hey, Lisa?
- Oh.
What does this mean?
"Starting brings misfortune.
- "Perseverance brings danger.
- Ta-da!
"Not every demand for change
in the existing order should be heeded.
"On the other hand,
repeated and well-founded complaints...
- should not fail to a hearing. "
- [Lisa] Well...
- ?? [Guitar Strumming]
- [Man] Hear yel Hear yel Hear yel
We've come to play for our dinner.
Or should I say, stay for our dinner.
Or, even, slay for our dinnerl
- Oh, men at war. How ghastly, ghastly.
- [Chuckling] Ah.
- We've come to drink your wine...
- [Chuckling]
taste your food
and take pleasure in your women.
It's fantastic. The water in that river
is about 80 degrees.
You put your hand in about a foot away,
it's below freezing.
- [Sarah] Come on. I've gotta get dinner on.
- [Muttering]
Out? Who said "out" to me?
Unhand me! I've played communal...
Out! Out! Out!
Ye shall hear this.
Evil eye on this place.
A double whammy for all of you.
[Woman] When you lie down with dogs,
you get up with fleas.
- [Mime] Come, my dear. We won't play here.
- [Sarah] You two, come on.
Wow. Wow. Wow. Wow.
- Wow.
- [Growling Playfully]
- Get out.
- I like you.
- [Laughs]
[Children Laughing, Chattering]
[Man] You see, what happened here is
these people got here late in the summer...
too late to plant.
But the weather was beautiful,
and it was easy livin', and everything was fine.
And then came that winter.
There were 40 or 50 of them here
living in this one-room place down here...
nothin' to eat, starvin', out by the side
of the road lookin' for dead horses.
Anything they could get ahold of.
Now there's...
there's 18 or 20 of'em left,
and they're city kids.
Look at 'em.
But they're gettin'this crop in.
They're gonna stay here till it's harvested.
That's the whole thing.
You get much rain here, man?
I guess we're gonna have to dance for that.
Look at this, man.
A seashell, man. Dig.
You dig that?
This is nothin' but sand. They ain't gonna make it.
Ain't gonna grow anything here.
They're gonna make it.
Dig, man.
[Hammering]
- [Children Crying]
- [People Whispering]
[Woman Coughing]
- [Woman] Shh, Jessie.
- [Chickens Clucking]
[Crying Continues]
[Child Coughing]
[Rooster Crows]
We have planted our seeds.
We ask...
that our efforts be worthy...
to produce simple food...
for our simple taste.
We ask that our efforts...
be rewarded.
We thank you for the food we eat
from other hands...
[Child Babbles]
that we may share it with our fellow man...
and be even more generous...
when it is from our own.
Thank you for a place...
to make a stand.
[Sighs]
- [Man] Amen.
- [All] Amen.
[Child]
Amen.
Let's eat.
?? [Tambourine Beating]
[Woman]
Hal Hark ye, gentles. Hark ye, all.
- Time has come for a curtain call. [Squeals]
- [Man] Ah.
[Woman Ululating]
? How do you wear your hair
Does your hair hang low ?
? Do you tie it in a ribbon
Do you tie it in a bow ?
? Do you wear it over your shoulder
like a Continental soldier ?
? Does your hair hang low ?
? Hey, does your honey wear your hair
Does your hair hang low ?
- ? Do you tie it in a ribbon
Do you wear it in a bow ?
- [Man's Voice] Get a haircut.
?? [Singing Continues]
Are you an Aquarius?
- Pisces?
- [Chuckles, Sniffs] Mm-hmm.
- ?? [Ends]
- [Applause]
I guessed right.
- ?? [Singing Resumes]
- Do you like our place here?
Yeah.
? He will kill the old red rooster ?
? He will kill the old red rooster
when she comes ?
? And we're all gonna meet her
? We will all have chicken and dumplings
when she comes ?
- ?? [Singing Continues, Indistinct]
- ?? [Guitar, Harmonica: Blues]
?? [Blues Continues]
?? [Tambourine]
Who sent ya?
?? [Singing]
? Do you tie it in a ribbon
Do you tie it in a bow ?
? Do you throw it over your shoulder
like a Continental soldier ?
? Does your hair hang low ?
? Hey, does your hair hang low
Do you tie it in a bow ?
? Do you tie it in a ribbon
? Do you throw it over your shoulder
like a Continental soldier ?
? Does your hair hang low ??
[Grunts, Exhales]
Man, look.
I gotta get outta here, man.
I mean, we... we got things
we want to do, man, like, uh-uh-uh...
I... I gotta get outta here, man.
Hey, um, could you take me
and-and my friend, uh...
over across the canyon?
Yeah. Anything.
Hey, it-it won't be out of your way. Honest.
It's all right.
Hey, man, we're not no traveling bureau.
Man, why don't they get their own rides?
Hey. Hey. Hey.
We're eating their food.
[Sighs]
All right, man.
[Inhaling Deeply]
- Get 'em together though, man.
- Right.
- [Child] Look it.
- [Woman] Stop it.
- [Children Laughing, Chattering]
- [Woman] Jill, come onl
[Laughing]
[Child]
More waterl More waterl
?? [Folk Rock]
? Oh, I'd rather go and journey ?
? Where the diamond crescent's glowing ?
? And run across the valley
beneath the sacred mountain ?
? And wander through the forest ?
? Where the trees have leaves of prisms ?
? And break the light in colors ?
? That no one knows the names of ?
? And when it's time
I'll go and wait ?
? Beside a legendary fountain ?
? Till I see your form reflected ?
? In its clear and jeweled waters ?
? And if you think I'm ready ?
? You may lead me to the chasm ?
? Where the rivers of our vision ?
? Flow into one another ?
[No Audible Dialogue]
? I will want to dive beneath ?
? The white cascading waters ?
? She may beg
She may plead ?
? She may argue with her logic ?
? And then she'll know the things I lose ?
? That really have no value ?
? In the end, she will surely know ?
? I wasn't born to follow ??
When you get to the right place
with the right people...
quarter this.
- You know, this could be the right place.
- [Children Chattering]
Your time's runnin' out.
[Billy]
Hey, man. Heyl
If we're going, we're going. Let's go.
Yeah, I'm, uh...
I'm hip about time.
But I just gotta go.
?? [March]
[Siren Wails]
"Parading without a permit"?
You gotta be kidding.
I mean, do you know who this is, man?
This is Captain America. I'm Billy.
Hey, we're headliners, baby.
We've played every fair
in this part of the country.
I mean for top dollar too.
[Sighs]
Oh, man.
[Radio Changing Channels, Indistinct]
?? [Fiddle: Ballad]
[Billy Sighs]
Manl
[Sighs]
Weirdo hicks, man.
A bunch of weirdo hicks here.
[Scoffs]
"Parading without a permit," man
[Exhales]
[Man Mumbling]
[Groans]
Ah. Oh, no.
What did I do now?
Oh.
Oh, what am I gonna do now?
- [Groans]
- [Radio Static]
Oh, my head.
Oh.
All right, now, George,
what are you gonna do now?
I mean, you promised these people, now.
You promised these people,
and you promised these people.
- They're not gonna believe you, George.
- [Clangs]
Hey! Hey, man, would you mind?
- You just woke my friend up.
- Oh, yeah.
Well, I'm, uh...
I'm real sorry. I didn't realize.
I, uh...
[Clicks Teeth]
I didn't realize.
[Groans]
[Exhales]
My head.
Hey, man, if you don't shut your mouth, man,
you ain't gonna have a head.
[Yawning]
I see you're up, Mr. Hanson.
You'll feel a lot better after this.
Oh. Oh.
Thank you, Bob.
I guess I...
I guess I really tied one on last night.
Must've had a hell of a good time.
Wish I could remember it now.
Hey, man, um, you don't... you don't think
you could get me a cigarette, do you?
You animals ain't smart enough
to play with fire.
Oh, no, no, no. That's all right, Bob.
That's all right. They're good boys.
You can give 'em a cigarette.
Thanks, mister.
- You got a match?
- Yeah.
- [Sighs]
- Thank you, Bob.
[Coughs]
Listen, I'm, um...
You know, I'm sorry about, uh...
you know, the misunderstanding.
Oh, that's all right.
There's no misunderstanding.
We're all in the same cage here.
Um, you must be some important dude, man,
like, you know, with that treatment, right?
"Dude"?
- What does he mean, "dude"? "Dude ranch"?
- [Chuckles]
- Dude?
- No, no, no.
"Dude" means, uh, a nice guy. You know?
"Dude" means a regular sort of person.
You boys don't look like you're from
this part of the country.
You're lucky I'm here to see
that you don't get into anything.
- Anything?
- Well... [Clears Throat]
They got this here, see, uh...
"scissor-happy, beautify America" thing
going on around here.
They're trying to make everybody
look like Yul Brynner.
They used rusty razor blades on the last
two longhairs that they brought in here...
and I wasn't here to protect them.
See, uh, I'm a...
I'm a lawyer.
Done a lot of work for the A.C.L.U.
"George Hanson."
Listen, you think you can help us
get out of here with no sweat?
I imagine that I can
if you haven't killed anybody.
At least nobody white.
See there? Twenty-five dollars.
Not too bad.
And no razor blades.
You know what I mean?
- Very groovy, George. Thank you.
- "Very groovy." Very groovy.
See there?
I'll bet nobody ever said that to you.
Oh, by the way, Bob,
thanks for the aspirin before.
[Sheriff]
George, I'm gettin'to...
I'm gettin'to think
you're a regular regular around here.
I'm not gonna tell your dad.
I don't know, George.
You just gotta be more careful.
Yeah, well, Pat, that'd be real good
if the powers that be wouldn't hear about this.
I mean, the old man hadn't been
feelin' too good. You know what I mean?
Well, now, George, you know
we won't tell your dad about that.
- Isn't that right, Bob?
- That's right.
Well, what do you say
we take a look...
at these super machines
we've been hearing so much about?
Let's get it on.
Thanks a lot, Bob.
See you later.
I'll take care of it later.
Don't worry about it.
Good-bye. All right, Carl.
Thanks a million.
Say hello to the missus for me, will you?
- Yes, sir.
- All right.
Here's the first of the day, fellas.
To old D.H. Lawrence.
[Shouts]
Nik! Nik! Nik!
Phff! Phff! Phff!
[Gasps]
Indians.
[Deep Breath]
[Exhales]
[Murmurs]
You know...
I must've started off to Mardi Gras
six or seven times.
Never got further than the state line.
Governor of Louisiana give me this.
"Madame Tinkertoy's House of Blue Lights.
Corner of Bourbon and Toulouse.
New Orleans, Louisiana."
Now, this is supposed to be
the finest whorehouse in the South.
These ain't no pork chops.
These are U.S. prime.
[Chuckling]
Out of sight, man.
Oh, I'd like to get over there.
[Laughs]
How long, uh...
How long did you boys say it was
gonna take you to get down there?
- Oh, about two or three days.
- Two or three days? That right?
Oh, boy, I sure wish I was going with you.
Yeah?
You got a helmet?
Oh. Oh, I've got a helmet.
[Guffaws]
I got a beauty.
- [Man] ? If you want to be a bird ?
- [No Audible Dialogue]
?? [Vocalizing]
?? [Vocalizing Continues]
? If you want to be a bird ?
? Well, try a little flying ?
? No denying ?
? It gets you high ?
? Why be shackled to your feet ?
? When you got wings
you haven't used yet ?
? Don't wait for heaven ?
? To get out and fly ?
?Just glide there
through the clear air ?
? Making figure eights
through the pearly gates ?
? Where the soul
and the universe meet ?
? If you want to be a bird ?
? It don't take much
to get you up there ?
? But when you come down ?
? Land on your feet ?
?? [Vocalizing]
?Just keep... ?
?Just glide there
through the clear air ?
? Making figure eights
through the pearly gates ?
? Where the soul
and the universe meet ?
? If you want to be a bird ?
? It won't take much
to get you up there ?
- ?? [Fades Out]
- [Motors Revving]
[Dog Barking]
[Dog Barking In Distance]
?? [Billy Clapping, Singing, Indistinct]
Well, old buddy,
I never thought I'd ever see you again.
You know, I threw this thing away
one week ago.
My mother, of all people, retrieved it.
I can't understand that.
She didn't even want me
to play football.
Always afraid I was gonna get hurt.
And here, 12 years later,
lfind it on my pillow...
with a note pinned next to it saying,
"Save this for your son."
[Laughs]
[Gasps]
Nik, nik...
[Exhales]
Nik! Fire.
Do this instead.
Oh, no, thanks. I got some, uh, store-bought
right over here of my own.
No, man, this is grass.
You... You mean marijuana?
Yeah.
Lord, have mercy.
Is that what that is?
Le-Let me see that.
Marijuana. Hmm.
Hmm.
Go ahead, George. Light it up.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
I... l-I couldn't do that.
I mean, I've got enough problems
with the... with the booze and all.
I mean, I can't afford to get hooked.
Oh, no. You won't get hooked.
Yeah, well, I know.
But I mean, it-it... it leads to harder stuff.
Is that, uh... You-You say it's all right?
Well, uh, all right then.
Well, how-how do I do it?
Here.
Mm. Wait a second.
[Exhales]
Well, uh, that-that's got
a real nice, uh, taste to it.
Though I don't suppose
it'll do me much good though.
I mean, I'm so used
to the booze and everything.
You've got to hold it
in your lungs longer, George.
Oh.
[Billy]
Oh, wow.
What... was that, man?
What the hell was that, man?
Huh?
No, man. Like, hey, man. Wow.
I was watching this object, man, like...
like the satellite
that we saw the other night, right?
And, like, it was just going
right across the sky, man, and then...
I mean, it just suddenly, uh...
[Laughing]
It just changed direction
and went, uh, whizzing right off, man.
- It flashed...
- You're stoned out of your mind, man.
Oh, yeah, man.
Hey, like, I'm stoned, you know, man.
But, like, you know,
I saw a satellite, man...
and it was goin' across the sky...
and it flashed three times at me...
and zigzagged and whizzed off, man.
And I saw it.
[Exhales]
That was a U.F.O. beamin' back at you.
Me and Eric Heisman
was down in Mexico two weeks ago.
We seen 40 of'em flyin' in formation.
They-They... They have got bases
all over the world now, you know.
They've been comin'here ever since 1946...
when the scientists first started
bouncin'radar beams off of the moon...
and they have been livin' and workin'
among us in vast quantities ever since.
The government knows all about 'em.
What are you talkin', man?
Mmm. Well, you just
seen one of'em, didn't you?
Hey, man, I saw something, man,
but I didn't see it working here.
You know what I mean?
Well, they are people just like us...
from within our own solar system...
except that their society
is more highly evolved.
I mean, they don't have no wars.
They got no monetary system.
They don't have any leaders because,
I mean, each man is a leader.
I mean, each man...
Because of their technology...
they are able to feed, clothe, house
and transport themselves...
equally and with no effort.
[Exhales]
Wow.
Well, you know something, man?
I think...
You wanna know what I think?
I think this is a crackpot idea.
That's what I think.
[Laughing] How about that?
How about a little of that?
I think it's a crackpot idea.
I mean, if they're so smart, why don't they just
reveal themselves to us and get it over with?
[Laughs]
Why don't they
reveal themselves to us...
is because, if they did,
it would cause a general panic.
Now, I mean, we still have leaders...
upon whom we rely
for the release of this information.
These leaders have decided
to repress this information...
because of the tremendous shock that it
would cause to our antiquated systems.
Now, the result of this
has been that the Venusians...
have contacted people
at all walks of life.
All walks of life.
[Giggling] Yes.
It-It would be a devastatin' blow
to our antiquated systems.
So now Venusians are meeting
with people in all walks of life...
in an advisory capacity.
For once, man will have a godlike control
over his own destiny.
He will have a chance
to transcend and to evolve...
with some equality for all.
How's your joint, George?
Oh, my. I believe... I believe it went out.
I got... I got to talkin' so much,
I clean forgot about, uh...
Went out.
Well, save it. We'll do it tomorrow morning,
first thing, all right?
Gives you a whole new way
of looking at the day.
Well, I sure could use that.
[Laughing]
Yes, I sure could use a little of that.
?? [Country]
[Man]
? Don't bogart that joint, my friend ?
? Pass it over to me ?
? Roll another one ?
?Just like the other one ?
? You've been hanging on to it ?
? And I sure would like a hit ??
?? [Rock]
[Man]
Yeah.
Sing a song, brother.
[Jimi Hendrix]
? If the sun ?
? Refused to shine ?
? I don't mind ?
? If the mountains ?
? Fell in the sea ?
? Let it be ?
? It ain't me ?
All right.
? Got my own world to live through
and l... ?
? And I ain't gonna copy you ?
- ? Yeah ?
- It's all right.
? Now if, uh, six ?
? Turned out to be nine ?
? I don't mind ?
- ? I don't mind ?
- All right.
? If all the hippies ?
? Cut off all their hair ?
? I don't care ?
? Dig ?
? 'Cause I got my own world
to live through and, uh... ??
[Radio: Chorus Singing Pop]
? Gobble-Gobble-diddle-ip ?
- ? Gobble-Gobble-diddle-ip ?
- [Woman] ? Come on and turkey trot ?
What the hell is this? Troublemakers?
- ?? [Continues]
- You name it. I'll throw rocks at it, Sheriff.
[Girl]
Y'all, check what just walked in.
Ooh, I like the one in the red shirt
with the suspenders.
Mm-mmm. The white shirt's for me.
Nah. Look how tight
those black pants are.
Uh, we're in the establishment now,
aren't we, gentlemen?
- What'd you say?
- I said... [Trills Tongue]... tang.
- [Trills Tongue] What?
[Trilling Tongue]... tang?
Oh, I just can't believe.
What are they doin'here?
- Look at the teeth around his neck.
- Did they drive up on motorcycles?
I think they know we're talkin' about 'em.
They're lookin' over here.
[Girls Giggling]
Hot damn. I tell you.
I think I'll order kidneys, 'cause I left mine
out there on the road somewhere.
[Billy Laughing]
- I don't know, but I like
his hair all down his head.
- And I like his eyes.
See that little girl
right over there in the corner?
Well, don't look too close at her,
because the sheriff's right over there.
You know what I mean?
- Check that joker with the long hair.
- I checked him already.
Look like we might have to bring 'em
up to the Hilton before it's all over with.
- Ha! I think she's cute.
- Isn't she though?
I guess we'll put 'em in a woman's cell,
don't you reckon?
Oh, I think we oughta put 'em in a cage
and charge a little admission to see 'em.
[Sighs]
Those are what is known
as, uh, country witticisms.
[Girl] I can't believe they're here.
What are they doin'here?
[Girl #2] I don't know.
Let's ask them to take us for a ride.
- No, we can't ask! Don't be foolish.
- Yeah!
No. They'll think you're...
Oh! They'll laugh in your face.
- That'd be good too.
- I doubt it.
- I might ask 'em.
- You might ask 'em? Go ahead.
Not when I'm around,
you're not gonna ask 'em.
- I don't think you're gonna.
- Go ahead.
- Okay.
[Man] You know, I thought at first
that bunch over there...
their mothers had maybe been
frightened by a bunch of gorillas...
but now I think they were caught.
[Man] Well, one of'em is Alley Oop,
I think, from the beads on him.
[Man #2]
One of'em, darn sure, is not Ooola.
Look like a bunch of refugees
from a gorilla love-in.
[Snickers]
A gorilla couldn't love that.
[Laughing]
Nor could a mother.
Doggone it, I wouldn't even mate him up
with one of those black wenches out there.
Oh, now, I don't know about that.
And that's about as low
as they come, I'll tell you.
- Oh, he's a biggie.
- Man, they're green.
No, they're not green. They white.
- White?
- Uh-huh.
Man, you're color-blind.
I just got to say that.
Sure like to get some food around here.
[Old Man] I don't know.
I thought most jails were built for humanity...
and that won't quite qualify.
[Man #2]
Wonder where they got those wigs from.
[Old Man] They probably grew 'em.
Looks like they're standin'in fertilizer.
Nothin'else would grow on 'em.
No. You know,
I'm not real hungry at the moment.
You know what I mean?
[Young Man] I saw two of'em one time.
They were just kissin'away.
Two males. Just think of it.
What you think
we oughta do with 'em?
I don't never know, but I don't think
they'll make the parish line.
Let's split.
- [Billy] Split?
- Yeah.
Yes, sir. It certainly has been nice.
They got some fancy bikes out there.
That's some Yankee queers.
Check the flag on that bike.
[Sheriff]
It sure is.
I still say they're not gonna
make the parish line.
Here come the poon-poon-poontang.
[Trilling Tongue]
Hey, fellas, can I have a ride?
- You want a ride?
- [Girls] Yeah. Yeah.
- You got a note from your mamas?
- [Girls Chattering]
- My old lady won't mind.
- Please? Please let us have a ride.
- Hey, I like your bike.
- I wouldn't mind giving you a ride.
- [All Chattering]
- [George] Uh-oh.
? The man
the man is at the window ?
? The man is at the window
The man is at the window ?
- [Girl] Oh, come on.
- ? Oh, the man is at the window ??
I love you girls.
I'd love to take you girls for a ride, but...
- [Motorcycles Revving]
- [All Chattering, Shouting]
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Insects Buzzing]
You know, this used to be
a hell of a good country.
I can't understand
what's gone wrong with it.
[Dogs Barking In Distance]
Man, everybody got chicken.
That's what happened to it.
Hey, we can't even get into, like,
a second-rate hotel.
I mean, a second-rate motel, you dig?
They think we're gonna
cut their throat or something, man.
- Like, they're scared, man.
- Oh, they're not scared of you.
They scared of what
you represent to 'em.
Hey, man, all we represent to them, man,
is somebody who needs a haircut.
Oh, no. What you
represent to them is freedom.
What the hell's wrong with freedom, man?
That's what it's all about.
Oh, yeah, that's right.
That's what it's all about, all right.
But talkin'about it and bein'it...
that's two different things.
I mean, it's real hard to be free...
when you are bought and sold
in the marketplace.
Course, don't ever tell anybody
that they're not free...
'cause then they gonna get real busy
killin' and maimin'...
to prove to you that they are.
Oh, yeah, they gonna talk to you
and talk to you and talk to you...
about individual freedom.
But they see a free individual,
it's gonna scare 'em.
Well, man, it don't
make 'em runnin' scared.
No. It makes 'em dangerous.
[Squawks]
Nik, nik! Nik, nik!
Nik! Nik! Swamp.
[Both Chuckle]
Damn, right, man. Damn... Whew.
Swamp.
- Swamp.
- Swamp!
- Swamp?
- Swamp.
You-You... You ever, uh...
You ever talk to bullfrogs
in the middle of the night?
Not generally.
[Chuckles]
- You don't...
- No, man.
You know what I used to do?
What did you used to do, man?
Well, I'll tell you one thing
I didn't used to do...
was talk to bullfrogs
in the middle of the night, fool.
Shit. You're out of your mind.
[George]
That's right.
[Frogs Calling]
[Footsteps Rustling]
- [Blows Landing]
- [Men Grunting]
[Billy Screaming]
Wyattl
- [Groaning]
- [Dogs Barking]
- [Footsteps Running]
- [Vehicle Doors Slamming]
- [Engines Starting]
- [Billy] Come on. Come on.
- [Vehicles Departing]
Hey, man. Oh, man.
- Hey, man, you okay?
- [Groans]
Oh, no. Sh... Sh...
[Sobs]
Sh... Sh...
[Out Of Breath]
Sh...
[Billy]
Oh, God, man. Oh, God.
What are we gonna do
with his stuff, man? Huh?
[Wyatt]
Get it to his folks somehow.
There's not much here, man.
There's some...
There's some money, man.
There's his driver's license, man.
There's a...
Oh, man, here's his card, man.
He ain't gonna be using that.
?? [Rock]
[Man]
? Kyrie Eleison ?
Hey, no, really. We'll go there for one drink, man.
Just one drink.
? Kyrie Eleison ?
No, man. Hey, listen. Now really.
Seriously. He would have wanted us to, man.
? Christe ?
?? [Continues]
[No Audible Dialogue]
? Christe ??
[Wyatt] " If God did not exist,
it would be necessary to invent him."
[Billy Chuckles]
That's a humdinger.
[Chuckling]
I'm getting a little smashed, man.
A little smashed.
Mmml
[Billy Exhales]
I am.
Whew! Wow, it's hot in here, man.
[Sighs]
[Chuckles]
Chicks, man.
[Sighs]
Where are those chicks, man?
Come on, man.
[Chuckles]
Hey! Ta-da!
Look at this.
- It's okay.
- Good-bye, girls.
Later.
- Howdy. Howdy.
- Hello.
My name is Billy...
and this here is Captain America.
Excuse me one minute, ladies.
Man, you mind
if I take the tall one, man?
- No, that's all right.
- Oh, man. Thanks.
Mm-hmm! Over here?
[Billy, Southern Accent] Come on,
you little hustler, you. Get yourself over here.
You ol'thing, you.
[Drops Accent] I'm really from New York, man.
[Chuckles]
This is all just sort of a weird act.
[Woman]
You're a freak, aren't you?
My name is Mary.
- You want a drink, Mary?
- No, thanks.
[Woman]
Uh, what's-what's... What's this?
- I mean, is this really your hair?
- No, it ain't really.
What is this? Is this really your hair?
Are you kidding me?
- What are these things?
- Hey, what are these things?
- What are these, huh?
- You know, I'm kind of a freak myself.
[Billy, Chuckling] I never really
thought of myself as a freak, you know?
But I love to freak.
- What's happening outside?
- What?
You know, on the street.
What's happening? Mardi Gras.
Oh, well, it's, you know...
It's crowded and all that.
Yeah.
Mm-hmm. Hey, want a drink?
- Mm-mmm.
- No?
- [Chuckles] Here's to you.
- Thank you.
[Exhales]
What's the matter?
Don't you like me?
What?
- Well, you paid for me, right?
- Oh.
Well, that was, uh...
That was for my friend.
Oh. I don't, uh...
- Why don't I buy you a drink?
- I don't drink.
I've got an idea.
Let's go outside.
Yep.
We'll all go outside to Mardi Gras.
- Okay.
- Okay?
- ?? [Guitar, Tambourine]
- [Man] The party's back.
- [Man] ? When the saints ?
- [Man #2] ? Oh, when the saints ?
- ? Go marchin'in ?
[Together]
? When the saints go marchin'in ?
? You know I want
to be in that number ?
? When the saints go marchin'in ?
- ? Now, when they march ?
- ? When they march ?
- ? On down the road ?
- [Siren Blaring]
- ? When they march on down the road ?
- [Siren Wailing]
? You know I want
to be in that number ?
? When the saints go marchin'in ?
? Now, when the saints
go marchin'in ?
? Oh, when the saints go marchin'in ?
? You know I want
to be in that number, yeah ?
? When the saints go marchin'in ?
? When they march
on down the road ?
? You know I want
to be in that number, oh, yeah ?
? When they march down the road ?
?? [Continues, Indistinct]
? You know I want
to be in that number, oh, yeah ?
? When the saints come down the road ?
- ? Oh, when the saints ?
- ? When the saints ?
- ? Go marchin'on in ?
? Oh, when the saints
go marchin'in ?
? You know I want
to be in that number, yeah ?
? When the saints go marchin'in ?
[Singer Shouts]
- ? On down the road ?
- ? When the saints come down the road ?
- [Pile Driver Pounding]
? You know I want
to be in that number, child ?
? When the saints come down the road ?
- ? Whoo ?
- [Shouting]
- ?? [Fades]
- [Pounding Continues]
- Hey. [Laughs]
- What's that?
- Hey. [Chuckles]
Never mind.
Just shut up and take it.
[Billy]
Yeah, right.
What do you...
What do you do with it?
- Give it to me.
- Just shut up and take it, man.
Put it under your tongue.
[Girl's Voice]
I believe in God...
the Father Almighty...
Creator ofheaven and earth.
[Man's Voice] I'm going up for the last time,
for the last time, the last time.
[Girl's Voice]
... was crucified, died and was buried.
- He descended into hell.
- [Wyatt's Voice] Oh, Mother.
- One the third day, he arose again from the dead.
- Mother, why didn't you tell me?
He ascended into heaven
and sitteth at the right hand of God...
- the Father Almighty, Creator ofheaven and earth.
- Why didn't anybody tell me anything?
- I believe in God, the Father Almighty,
Creator of heaven and earth...
- What are you doing to me?
- and in Jesus Christ, his only Son, our Lord...
- Why didn't you tell me?
- Shut up.
- who was conceived by the Holy Ghost...
- born of the Virgin Mary,
suffered under Pontius Pilate...
- [Wyatt Murmuring]
was crucified, died and was buried.
He descended into hell.
The third day, he arose again from the dead.
He ascended into heaven and sitteth
at the right hand of God, the Father Almighty.
From thence, he shall come to judge
the living and the dead.
- I believe in the Holy Ghost,
the Holy Catholic Church...
- [Wyatt, Indistinct]
- the Communion of Saints,
the forgiveness of sins...
- Why did you do such a thing to me?
- the resurrection of the body
and life everlasting, amen.
- How could you do it?
- Glory be to the Father
and to the Son and to the Holy Ghost...
- How could you make me hate you so much?
as it was in the beginning,
is now and ever shall be.
- I hate you so much.
- A world without end. Amen.
- Look at me. I always wanted to be pretty.
- I want you to be beautiful.
Shh. Listen to me. Listen to me.
I want you to be beautiful.
- I want you to be beautiful.
- No.
You know me.
- [Crying] I know you.
- [Pile Driver Pounding]
- Baby. Baby, baby.
- [Sobbing]
[Woman]
I did something bad.
- I know you.
- What are you talking about?
- [Girl] Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
- [Wyatt Murmuring]
Blessed art thou amongst women
and blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
[Wyatt, Sobbing]
Make me love you.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners now and at the hour...
I know it. I know you.
I know you. I know you.
- [Siren Wails]
- [Billy, Laughing] Oh, wow, man.
Glory be to the Father...
We're all aglow, manl
Look at thisl We're all aglowl
- [Wyatt] We're glowing. We're glowing.
- Look. Look. Glow. Glow. Glow. Look. Glow.
Who are you? You're a john.
I don't know why I like you.
- I don't even know if I like you.
- Ooh, I like you. [Laughing]
I know, but I like you.
[Gasping, Giggling]
Don't you dare Don't you dare
[Mary]
I can feel the outside.
I can feel the outside, but I can't...
- [Pounding Continues]
- I can't feel the inside. Okay?
Don't stop Don't stop
I'm dying I'm gonna die
I'm gonna die
[Shrieks]
I'm dead. I'm dead.
Do you understand?
[Wyatt]
? Mary loves... da, da ?
? Mary, da, da, da ?
[Mary]
Oh, dear God Please let it be
- Please help me to conceive a child
- [Woman Ranting, Moaning]
I'm right out here.
I'm right out here
- [Moaning]
- I'm right out here. I'm out of my head.
[Overlapping Chatter]
- [Woman] Please, God, let me out of here
- [Pounding]
[Sobbing]
I wanna get out of here!
That's the way you wanted me?
Do you know what I mean?
You wanted me ugly, didn't you?
I know you guys. I know you johns.
- [Wyatt] I hate you so much.
- In the name of the Father and of the Son
and of the Holy Spirit. Amen.
- You never cared about me.
- I believe in God, the Father Almighty...
Why did you leave like that?
- Everybody else, but not you.
- He was crucified, died and was buried.
He descended into hell.
- And not me.
- The third day, He arose again...
Hallowed be thy name...
- I love you.
- thy kingdom come, thy will be done...
- Oh, God, how I loved you.
- on earth as it is in heaven.
- Give us this day our daily bread,
and forgive us our trespasses as we forgive...
- Hold my hand. Hold my hand.
And you're such a cruel mother,
and I hate you so much.
?? [Rock]
[Insects Buzzing]
[Exhales]
[Laughs]
Hey, man. We've done it. We've done it.
We're rich, Wyatt.
[Laughs]
Yeah, man.
[Chuckling]
Yeah. Hey, we did it, man.
We did it. We did it.
We're rich, man.
We're retired in Florida now, mister.
[Sighs, Chuckles]
You know, Billy...
we blew it.
What? [Chuckles]
Wh... Wh...
That's what it's all about, man.
I mean, like, you know.
I mean, you go for the big money, man,
and then you're free.
You dig?
[Laughs]
We blew it.
Good night, man.
?? [Acoustic Guitar, Harmonica: Folk Rock]
? Darkness at the break of noon
shadows even the silver spoon ?
? The handmade blade
the child's balloon ?
? Eclipses both the sun and moon ?
? To understand, you know too soon
there is no sense in tryin'?
? Pointed threats, they bluff with scorn
Suicide remarks are torn ?
? From the fool's gold mouthpiece
the hollow horn plays wasted words ?
? Prove to warn that he not busy bein' born
is busy dyin'?
? Temptation page flies out the door
You follow, find yourself at war ?
? Watch waterfalls of pity roar
You feel to moan, but unlike before ?
? You discover that you'd just be
one more person cryin'?
? So don't fear ?
? When you hear ?
? A foreign sound to your ear ?
? It's all right, Ma ?
? I'm only sighin'??
[Motorcycles Rumbling]
Hey, Roy, look at them two.
Pull alongside.
We'll scare the hell out of'em.
- Want me to blow your brains out?
- [Laughing]
Why don't you get a haircut?
What happened?
- Billy!
- Oh, my God. [Choking]
Oh, my God.
- I'm going for help.
- I got 'em! I'm gonna get 'em, man.
We better go back.
- [Motorcycle Idling]
- Man, I...
[Billy]
I'm gonna get 'em.
We're ready now.
[Man]
? The river flows ?
? It flows to the sea ?
? Wherever that river goes ?
? That's where I want to be ?
? Flow, river, flow ?
? Let your waters wash down ?
? Take me from this road ?
? To some ?
? Other town ?
? All he wanted ?
? Was to be free ?
? And that's the way ?
? It turned out to be ?
? Flow, river, flow ?
? Let your waters wash down ?
? Take me from this road ?
? To some ?
? Other town ?
? Go, river, go ?
? Past the shaded tree ?
? Flow, river, flow ?
? Flow to the sea ?
? Flow ?
? To the sea ??
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.MY-SUBS