Arturo, do we meet tonight?
Tonight at the old hacienda.
- Good-bye.
Rosa!
Get away from that house!
Yes, Mama. I'm coming.
Don't bother those old sisters.
Just leave them alone.
The door was open.
I thought I might see them.
You only see them
when you don't expect it.
Now help me. Your father
and brother will be home soon.
You see,
you're a smart man.
You know that Arturo Xuncax
isn't your friend.
None of them are your friends.
They don't respect old customs.
They'll just ruin you.
It's horrible.
Think of your family.
Now let's stop wasting time.
Tell me where they're meeting.
At the old hacienda — tonight.
It's Don Goyo.
I love his music.
Come, sit down.
Are Pedro and Josefita coming?
Yes, they'll be here soon.
Arturo,
are you really going out tonight?
Yes, probably.
That's it —
the old hacienda.
We'll go on foot from here.
Then we'll spread out.
In the U.S.,
even the poorest people
have toilets...
just like Don Rodrigo's!
You flush it
and everything vanishes instantly!
You can really pee in style there!
It's always "the north" with you!
Can't you talk about anything else?
I love hearing about the north.
Good.
We hear about it enough!
But it's true.
There's a lot of money there.
I've heard from my friends —
all the people that have left.
And you can see on TV
how it is up there.
That's right.
Even the poor people
have their own cars.
So, how do you know so much
about the north?
For ten years, Don Rodrigo's
cook has been giving me
all of her old Good Housekeeping
magazines.
Ten years I've been reading them.
I know plenty.
Excuse me.
Go ahead.
Sweethearts?
Really?
How romantic!
How are you, Rosita?
I'm fine, Luis.
I brought you this cinnamon candy.
Oh, thank you.
I love it.
Well, excuse me,
but I'm going out for a while.
Stay and enjoy yourselves.
Stay here, please.
It's so late.
I have to go.
Lupe.
Don't worry.
He can take care of himself.
Come on.
Sit down with us.
Good night, Rosita.
Good night.
Mama is afraid.
Do you have to go out tonight?
Your mother knows
how things are here.
She doesn't want trouble.
And that's fine, but...
we can't go on
this way anymore.
I'm afraid as well.
So am I.
But sometimes you have to
fight for your land.
There is no choice.
The rich came here.
They're not from here.
They came looking for good land.
No one fights over bad land.
That's why they took our land.
Because this is good land!
I'll tell you something, Enrique,
that my life has taught me.
I've worked in Mexico.
I've worked
on plantations at the coast.
I've worked in many places,
and everywhere it's the same.
For the rich,
the peasant is just a pair of arms.
That's all.
We are just arms to do their work.
They treat their animals
better than us.
For many years we've been trying
to make the rich understand
that the poor have hearts and souls.
That we feel.
That we are people, and we're all equal.
Let me go with you.
The time will come soon,
but not yet.
Go home.
Tell your mother not to worry.
I'll be home soon.
But where can we get guns?
We can run them through Chiapas,
just like other contraband.
The guerrillas
on the coast will help us.
- Yes, he's right!
- No, wait —
Protect him, Virgin Mother.
Arturo's right.
It's impossible to be neutral anymore.
Run!
Let's go.
That Indian bastard killed the Puma.
It is not true
That we come here to live
We come only to sleep, to dream
All things are lent to us
We are only on Earth in passing
Tomorrow or the next day
As you desire, giver of life
We shall go home to you
Mother!
Okay. Take this shit away.
My mother.
Where's my mother?
We'll take care of you.
You'll stay here with us.
We'll protect you.
Forget about your mother.
The army's taken her away.
No! My mother, no!
It's not true!
And Enrique!
- We don't know anything about him.
The soldiers are coming!
They're coming!
Quick! We've got to hide her!
They're leaving! Papa!
They're leaving!
Mama! Papa!
The soldiers are leaving!
I thought they had taken you.
I was hiding in the canyon.
They didn't see me.
I was so afraid.
I kept hearing the guns.
Mother —
They took her.
Yes, I know.
The soldiers will be back, Enrique.
I'm afraid.
People are leaving the village.
I have to leave too.
As long as I'm here,
I put all of you in danger.
You're going?
But where?
To the north.
But I need money.
Ask our godmother.
See if she can help me.
Meet me tomorrow night
in our house.
Be careful.
Don Ramón!
So you're still alive.
I'm amazed.
I hid in the canyon.
Okay, let's talk.
You know a lot about what goes on.
I need help.
Right now your life
isn't worth five cents.
They'll be back for you.
Today, tomorrow,
the next day.
They'll hunt you down and find you.
You can't escape.
It's a fantasy.
Yes, I can.
I'm going to go north.
That's why I came here.
You've been there before.
You can help me!
It's a long journey.
You need money, and a lot more luck
than you've had up to now.
You need big balls...
and the protection of God
and all the saints.
But I guess you have to go.
Because if you stay here,
the only way you can hide from
the army is by turning into a flea.
GOOD HOUSEKEEPING
Rosita, what can we do?
Enrique's life is in danger here.
Enrique is leaving.
He's going north.
And I'm going with him.
To the north?
Is everything arranged?
We don't have money, Godmother.
Help us, please.
Of course I'll help you.
Wait.
I've always wanted to go north,
ever since I was a little girl.
But I'll never go.
I'm too old now.
These are my savings.
Now go to the north for me.
Remember.
You have to pretend to be Mexican.
Otherwise, if you're caught,
they'll send you right back here,
and that's your death.
It's hard to pretend to be Mexican.
Use your head
before they cut it off.
Okay, say something like a Mexican.
Tell me it's a hot day.
It's a — No.
It's a hot day.
Oh, God!
You won't get a mile past the border!
Say it's a "fucking" hot day.
Mexicans are always saying "fuck."
"Fuck" here,
"fuck" there.
If you don't say "fuck"
all the time,
they'll know you're not Mexican!
And if they ask where you're from,
say Oaxaca, Mexico.
Most people can't tell the difference.
They think all Indians look alike.
Do you know a good coyote?
Yes. A good one.
Without him,
you won't get across.
And remember
that the border between
Mexico and the United States
is like a war zone.
Remember.
What are you doing?
I'm going with you.
With things the way they are now?
And you're a woman.
And you're a man.
They kill them both the same here.
But it's so dangerous.
Ramón says it's like a war.
I probably won't make it.
And with you —
My sister's crazy.
Everyone is crazy.
There's no other way, Enrique.
When the soldiers come back,
they'll take me.
I'm afraid.
I'm so afraid.
But the money?
We don't have enough.
And your sweetheart?
The past is gone forever, Enrique.
I've lost my father...
and my mother.
And when I thought you were gone,
I never felt so alone.
I won't let you leave me.
We have to stay together,
whether we live or die.
You're my whole family now.
Yes. You're right, Rosita.
We have to stay together.
But we're not going to die.
We're going to live!
And in the north,
we won't be treated this way.
We'll make a lot of money.
We'll have everything we want.
And we'll return one day.
We'll have good luck now.
I'm sure of it!
Wait.
There's something I must do.
What?
I must do it alone.
Wait for me at the edge of town.
- All right. But hurry.
I will.
For my father.
For my mother.
And for my village.
Where are you going, Rosa?
Rosa, where are you going?
Rosa, are you all right?
What's the matter?
Are you all right?
I'm fine. Let's hurry.
Let's go... to the north.
Motherfucking tire!
Goddamn tire!
Fucking son of a bitch!
Piece of shit.
What the hell?
What the fuck are you doing there?
Cat got your tongue?
Little tramps.
Where are you going?
What direction?
Same way you're going.
Same way?
Where are you from?
- Oaxaca, Mexico.
- Oaxaca?
So you're from Oaxaca, eh?
You're really fucked-up.
You're coming from
where we're going to!
Idiots!
Oaxaca is 300 kilometers ahead!
Guatemalans, aren't you?
Got you!
Just help me fix this damn tire,
and then I'll give you
a mother of a ride.
How did you get across the border?
They've got fuckloads of soldiers
there, so when you try to cross —
Yes, but Enrique knows
the mountain paths.
Done some smuggling, huh?
You like Mexican music?
Yes, I like it.
It's the best!
Hey, motherfucker!
Move your ass!
That's why God gave you one!
I can't stand drafts!
Can't you understand?
Goddamn Indians!
You should die for this!
Old fart.
You can't escape me this time,
you bastard!
We're here — Tijuana.
The shit-hole of the world.
Come on.
I'm a good coyote.
Hey, only $300 to the north!
I'm the one! Come on.
I'm bold. I'll take you there
on the wings of destiny!
Don't be left behind!
Come on, miss.
I'll take you to the north.
Come here! Don't miss out!
Let's cross the border!
Don't be left behind!
I'll take you for $300 each!
It's the ultimate for the poor!
Let's go, "little chicks" — north!
You won't have to sleep on the floor.
Not like here,
where you're dying of hunger.
It's the land of money,
where you'll find beautiful
houses, big cars.
It's the most beautiful thing in life!
Come with me, to the north!
What a pair of dummies.
Don't know their ass
from a hole in the ground.
Dumb as animals.
What's going on here?
Jaime, these donkeys just arrived.
They're looking for their coyote,
but they don't have his address.
They think they're
in their little village, the jerks!
What a couple of turkeys!
Yeah, too bad they're not smart
like all of you geniuses, huh?
If you're so brilliant, what are
you doing here in Tijuana, barefoot?
Come on! Get out of here!
Leave them alone!
Don't mind those idiots.
Just arrived?
Where are you from?
- We're from Oaxaca.
I'm from Zacatecas.
My name is Jaime.
I'm Enrique.
This is my sister, Rosa.
- It's a pleasure.
Who are you looking for?
Raimundo Gutierrez.
A friend of someone in our village.
- Do you have his address?
- Yes —
We had it.
But he doesn't live here anymore.
I see.
Do you have any money?
Well, yes.
A lot?
Yes... I think so.
Let me give you some advice.
Don't give it to anybody.
You'll need it when you
get to the north, understand?
And about finding your friend,
I'd help you, but
I'm crossing tonight.
Maybe you want to stay
and look for your friend.
But if you want to cross,
you can try your luck with me.
Yes, we'd like to!
It's not that hard, believe me.
Do you want a place
to stay until we leave?
If we're going tonight, yes.
Here, stay in here.
What if the owner comes back?
Rosa, look around you.
This is a "lost city" —
people come and go.
No one knows or cares
how many people are here.
And no one owns anything here.
At dusk, I'll come for you,
and we'll cross.
All right?
- All right.
- See you later.
- Until tonight.
I told you we'd be lucky!
Imagine, meeting someone like him
on our first day here.
You're easily impressed.
And you can't appreciate good luck,
even if it comes up and bites you.
It's so hot and dusty.
It's not like San Pedro.
What are you saying?
Are you homesick?
Would you rather be in San Pedro?
I just said it was hot,
that's all.
I'm not homesick.
I don't want to be in San Pedro.
I'm not thinking about that.
If you think about things like that,
you'll go crazy.
Okay, forget it.
We won't talk about it anymore.
Go to sleep,
because tonight you won't be able to.
Do you suppose all these people...
are trying to go north like us?
Yes, I think they are.
That's a lot of people.
Go to sleep.
If you worry about that,
you'll go crazy even faster
than if you think about San Pedro.
You're so practical, Rosa.
Go to sleep.
This is the hole.
Careful. Be as quiet as cats.
I'll be right back.
Wait here.
He's just peeing.
Robbing you is a pain in the ass!
You're a mean motherfucker!
How much dough
do you have anyway?
Dough?
Money, idiot!
Can't you speak Spanish?
Twenty dollars.
What?
I'll be fucked!
You said you had a lot!
- That is a lot.
- Go to hell!
Now I've had my balls busted
for a lousy 20 bucks!
Motherfucker.
Don't move!
Oaxaca, Mexico.
Yes, Oaxaca also.
Do you know how to read and write?
Why does he want to know that?
I don't know,
but I think it's a trick.
We'd better lie.
We can't read or write.
Show me exactly
where you are from.
What the fuck?
What's this fucking thing
you're showing me?
What the fuck
are you talking about?
Come and get your sweet rolls!
Hot tamales!
How many do you want?
Hey! Thief!
Goddamn thief!
Police!
Lazy bastards!
What are you laughing at?
I'm looking for Raimundo Gutierrez.
I'm Raimundo.
- I want to go north.
- You're wasting your time, kid.
I stopped being a coyote a while ago.
It's too dangerous.
I don't take anyone across.
No one!
Wait.
I'm a friend of Ramón Muñoz.
He gave me your name.
Seems like you haven't
eaten in a week.
But you're lucky.
You're alive.
Can you help us?
Ramón is a good friend of mine.
I owe him some favors.
I guess I'll have to help you.
I suppose you don't have
much money.
I won't charge you much.
I'm doing it for Ramón.
But you have to give me something.
There's a lot of expenses.
- How much?
About $100.
There's gas, food, hotel.
Don't worry.
We'll get the money.
Your sister.
Is she strong?
I think she's stronger
than both of us together.
Good.
Because I'm not going to
take you through the mountains.
Too risky.
There's one other way.
The tunnels.
And it's horrible.
The old sewer tunnels that
connect Tijuana with the other side.
They haven't been used for years,
so they're empty.
The safest ones are the smallest.
But you have to crawl
on your hands and knees for miles.
It's safer than the mountains,
but it's really hell.
You can't hear anything.
You can't see.
And the stink —
It's safer.
But most people would rather
go through the mountains...
and risk getting robbed or shot!
Look what I have for you.
Some fruit and a sweet roll.
I brought something for you too.
A steak!
Where did you get that?
I had a big lunch
with Raimundo Gutierrez!
You found him!
Yes!
And he's going to take us north!
There's just one thing.
We have to get $100.
This is pure silver.
This will get us the money.
Mother's necklaces?
No, we can't sell them.
If we want to go north,
there's no other way.
It will seem like you'll never get out.
But I want you to keep going.
And when you get to the other end,
I'll be there waiting.
I promise.
May the Virgin take care of you.
What's that?
I think it's a dead cat.
Come on.
Are you all right?
Yes, Enrique.
Let's go.
We have to keep going.
I can see the end!
It's me.
Raimundo.
Of course.
I said I'd be here,
and here I am.
Just like I promised.
I brought you some sandwiches.
You've got a first-class coyote!
Rosita, come here!
That's San Diego.
Pretty, isn't it?
From here, it's easy.
Tomorrow we'll be in Los Angeles.
Very simple,
but very comfortable
and very safe!
I'll come for you in the morning.
Yes.
Good night.
Josefita was right.
We have a flush toilet.
And we have electric light.
Now all we need to do is
to buy a new car without money.
Josefita and her crazy stories.
- What's your name?
- Rosa.
I'm Nacha.
Look.
When you get a bundle to iron,
find the ticket that says "pressing."
Tear it out and keep it.
They'll pay you 30 cents —
for each piece.
Understand?
And be careful.
This is steam.
Look! Look!
What?
Look at those ladies.
They're like something in a magazine!
And I don't look like a model?
Iron.
Because you look normal.
Run!
What's this?
It's a croissant.
It doesn't fill you up like a tortilla,
but it's good. Eat it.
Where are you from?
From Oaxaca.
I'm from Chihuahua.
It's nice to have
another Mexican here.
He's Mexican too, isn't he?
Him? No, he's a "pocho."
The dummy can't even speak Spanish.
Hey, Carlos.
Is it true you have testicles for eyes?
Suck my sweet potato, asshole.
What's a "pocho"?
A Chicano.
What's a Chicano?
Well, he's an American citizen,
but he comes from
a Mexican family.
That's why he has to do
the same shit work we do.
I always check out a place
before I take a job.
If I can't find a good escape route,
screw the job.
Sit down, my treat.
Hey, sweetie!
Give me two burritos with
green chili and two coffees.
Where are all the gringos?
Look at this street.
It's just like Mexico City.
Oh, Lord. You don't think gringos
want to live with Mexicans, do you?
They live out there
in their own neighborhoods.
Listen. I've been thinking.
I think I'll go back
to cleaning houses.
It's safer, and with my contacts —
Listen. Maybe we'll be lucky
and get some big houses to clean!
What do you say?
You want to team up?
- Yes.
- Okay. It's a deal.
But you have to learn some English.
Yes, I want to learn English.
And I know where you can do it.
In the public schools it's free.
The government?
Isn't it dangerous?
No, it's the safest.
They never ask questions.
Why?
If you try to figure out gringos,
you'll just get a giant headache.
They're cuckoo.
You know, you look like an Indian.
That is... a little change
of clothes wouldn't hurt, eh?
Have you ever heard of Sears?
What happened to you?
Nothing.
Nothing!
What do you mean, nothing?
Everybody's talking about the "migra" raid!
I didn't know what happened to you,
if I would ever see you again.
I'm sorry.
I escaped.
I met a smart woman.
I was lucky.
Rosa, no one escaped but you!
I've been crazy with worry.
And just look at you!
What's wrong with the way I look?
Nothing, but...
you look like a clown.
No, I look like an American.
And I'm going to work with Nacha,
cleaning houses!
What are you talking about?
Who's Nacha?
Enrique, we have to learn English.
Rosa, don't change the subject.
It's a good idea, don't you think?
I guess so.
But what circus
did you escape from?
Do you understand how this works?
Sure. Anyway, we'll figure it out.
The important thing is, whatever they say,
just smile and say yes.
Can you operate the machine?
Yes, a little.
It's very complicated.
Rosita, why did you
wash the clothes like that?
I don't know.
No, I don't know.
What?
What difference does it make
how I do it?
The clothes are clean, right?
It does matter how you do it.
You have to do it in the machine.
That's how it is done in the north.
You always use machines.
Look at me!
What happened?
You look wonderful.
I've been promoted!
See?
I'm becoming somebody important!
I'm very proud of you, Enrique.
Very proud.
I want to tell you something
that Papa told me before —
before he was killed.
He told me that,
for the rich,
all peasants are just a pair of arms
to do their work.
But he wanted something more for me.
He wanted people to know
that I'm a man
with a heart and a soul.
Look at me now!
People will see me
and respect me.
In this country you work hard,
but you can get somewhere.
I told you, Rosa,
things would change for us.
We've had hard times,
but look.
Nothing can stop us now.
Nothing.
Come in.
Big city, far away.
- Far?
- Very far away.
Excuse me.
Let me see it.
Let's go celebrate, okay?
I'd like to, but I have to go home.
Why?
I have to go see my sister.
Oh, fuck!
It's always your sister!
She's a woman.
You're a man.
You can do what you want!
What do you say?
Let's celebrate.
All right.
Here you are with your napkin.
You asshole.
Who's there?
Come in.
What's the matter?
I was better,
but now I'm much worse.
You have the fever of hell!
It's very bad!
Mother!
Good morning.
Hurry up now.
You have to go to work.
But, Mother —
It's so hard to make tortillas on this stove.
If only I had my comal.
But what can we do?
Life here is so hard.
You have to buy food,
pay rent —
It's all so expensive!
They told us that in the north
you could make a lot of money,
but they never told us
you had to spend so much.
It's your father.
Go see what he wants.
Look, Rosita.
I cut these for you.
What's the matter?
What happened?
- Mother.
Jorge! Immigration!
Holy shit, run!
No, no. They'll send me back!
I can't go to the hospital.
They'll send me back,
and I'll be murdered! No!
At least we got away.
Let's drink to that.
Yeah, but we don't have any work.
We're really fucked.
We'll find something else.
It's not so easy.
Being out of work up here
is the worst.
There are so many people now
and not so much work
as there used to be.
It was that "pocho" who turned us in.
The "pocho"?
How do you know?
Easy.
The "migra" doesn't show up
just because their balls itch.
Someone has to call.
He's been pissed off
ever since you got promoted.
That's the way it is here.
You've got to look out for yourself,
or you're fucked.
You do whatever
you have to do to survive.
That's what the "pocho" did.
That's the way it is.
That's the way it is — reality.
None of this would happen if only
we had those damned papers!
Thank God I found you!
You've got to come with me immediately.
- What's going on?
- Rosa is in the hospital!
- What's wrong?
- I don't know.
She got sick this morning.
The doctor said I had to get you.
But I can't go right now.
Why?
I've got to leave.
I'm going to Chicago, tonight.
What are you saying?
Are you crazy?
Rosa is in the hospital!
You take care of her, Nacha.
She'll get better.
I know it.
I'll call when I arrive.
Nacha, I must go!
I don't have a job!
I don't have much time.
I must go now.
Nacha, take care of her, please.
I can't believe it.
The doctor told me to find you.
Rosa could die!
Listen to me!
She could die!
Leave me alone!
Leave me!
All right.
Rosa may be dying,
but you...
are already dead.
Are you feeling better, Rosa?
Yes.
In my dreams, I felt afraid.
I felt like that day in San Pedro
when I thought
you would never come back.
But when I woke up,
you were here...
with me.
Of course.
You're the only family I have.
We have to stay together.
Life here is very hard, Enrique.
We're not free.
Isn't it true that we're not free?
Yes, life is difficult here.
It's true.
You have to work very hard.
In our own land,
we have no home.
They want to kill us.
There's no home for us there.
In Mexico there is only poverty.
We can't make a home there either.
And here in the north,
we aren't accepted.
When will we find a home, Enrique?
Maybe when we die
we'll find a home.
Don't say that, Rosita.
It's hard,
but we're going to have luck.
And we'll get everything we want.
And we'll make a lot of money.
And we'll return to our village.
And when we walk down the streets,
people will look at us with envy.
Things are changing.
Yes, we'll have a lot of luck now.
I'm sure of it.
The only thing is to not lose faith.
That's it.
The important thing
is not to lose faith.
Okay, come on.
I need men with strong arms to work.
- Me! Take me!
- I'm strong! I can work!
Me! Take me!
I have strong arms!