This is the Australian
Broadcasting Commission.
And now the news.
Japanese forces continue
their heavy attack on
the Philippines and Dutch East Indies.
Occupation of Manila is now complete.
With American and Philippine forces,
under the command of General MacArthur,
withdrawing to the Bataan peninsula.
His Majesty's forces are carrying out an
orderly evacuation
of the New Guinea coast, in preparation
for defense of Port
Moresby and the southern...
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Get off.
Boom!
Here, just a minute.
Where do you think you're
going with those, hmm?
Do you know who I am?
Um...
not exactly, no.
Well, we'll let it go this time.
Yes, sir, I understand.
Salamaua will be cleared
by noon, the latest.
Nothing left that the Japanese
will be able to use, sir.
Sir, there's a chap outside who...
- May I respectfully
remind the admiral that
I was harbor master here
for nearly 20 years?
I helped put the docks
together, so I should
certainly be able to blow them apart.
Sir, there's a chap outside, sir,
who's pinching our petrol.
- Yes, sir, all our
coastal watching stations
are assigned, except.
Matalava, sir.
Except Matalava, sir.
I haven't been able to find
a replacement for Anderson.
I don't believe there's a civilian left
on the entire north coast.
We could have transferred George Dickens
from the interior if he hadn't
got himself eaten that way.
- You needn't make him sound
such a shirker, Stebbings.
What's that, sir?
For want of a nail, the war was.
Yes, I'm well aware of that, sir.
Hello, hello, hello.
I think I may have found our nail, sir.
A rusty one, I grant you, sir,
but they don't come any sharper.
Excuse me, sir.
- Sir, that's the chap
I was telling you about.
He was leeching.
- Later, Stebbings.
- Who is he, sir, is he
someone I should know?
His name's Walter Eckland, an American.
He knows these islands
like the back of his hand.
Oh.
Oh well, now that America's in the war
he's probably on his way back to enlist.
- Eckland's not on his
way anywhere, Stebbings.
Hasn't been for years.
Hello, Walter.
Frank!
That you inside there, Frank?
What have you done to yourself?
There's a war on, Walter.
Everybody's saying that.
At the moment, we're losing it.
I guess you must be.
Cheek of the man!
- That's quite a boat
you have there, Walter.
Doesn't it belong to old Van Der Hoeven?
No!
Whose is it, then?
Mine.
How did you get it?
I bought it from old Van Der Hoeven.
What with?
American dollars.
You've never had more than $200
at one time since I've known you, Walter.
You can't tell me that
Van Der Hoeven sold you
an $18,000 launch for $200.
No, it cost me $400.
$400?
- You know, that's exactly
the way he said it.
Only, I pointed out to him
he might as well sell it
to me as let the Japanese
have it for free.
What impresses me, Walter, is the fact
that you even had $400.
- Well, I didn't, I only
had 200, just as you said.
I owe him the rest.
Well, come along, lend a hand.
Come on.
Empty hands make idle minds.
Here, pick those up.
No, no, no.
Two, come on.
Coastwatching Service is, Walter?
I beg your pardon?
The Coastwatching Service.
It's a chance to become a hero.
Why would I want to do that?
- It's a cushy
assignment for anyone
who knows these waters intimately.
- With never a dull
moment, I can tell you!
Working behind the enemy
lines, never knowing from one
moment to the next what...
- Stebbings, please.
Walter, listen to me.
There's nothing to it, really.
Each man is assigned an island,
often uninhabited.
He stays there alone and
he radios to headquarters
any movement of Japanese
planes or ships which...
You're not listening
to me, are you, Walter?
Hold it, hold it.
Hey, hey, hey, come on, beat it, scram!
Come on, get off!
Did you hear what I was saying?
No, what were you saying?
About the Coastwatchers.
Matalava will be in the center of things
when the Japanese start
moving towards New Guinea.
It's important work, Walter.
Damned important, I'd
like you to volunteer.
Oh, I'd love to, Frank.
But I've only just volunteered for
another important watching service,
the Watch Out For Walter Eckland service.
- A great many
lives are at stake, Mr. Eckland.
Now listen to me, both of you.
Several years ago, I made
peace with the world.
Now if the world isn't
bright enough to make peace
with itself, it'll have to
settle things without me.
It isn't anything permanent, Walter.
It's just until I find
a replacement for you.
The other man went down with fever,
and we had to take him off.
Well, now, Frank.
You've known me a long time.
Do you really think you're
gonna talk me into it?
No, I suppose not.
Stebbings, confiscate all
the small craft on this pier.
But this is the only one there is, sir.
Confiscate it.
- Frank, you
won't get away with that!
Proceed with your orders, Stebbings.
Frank, you can't do this to me!
I'll go over your head!
That boat's all I have.
- You said we've been friends
for a long time, Walter.
Do you really think you
could talk me out of it?
If I go to Matalava,
I can keep the boat, right?
Well, no use fighting it.
What time do I shove off?
An hour be all right?
Anything you say, Frank.
You're the skipper.
Hey, buddy, lend me a
hand with those cans.
I'll get on board.
But sir...
you don't really expect him to
go to Matalava, do you, sir?
As soon as he clears harbor,
we'll never see him again.
- Where's your faith in
human nature, Stebbings?
Da-da-da-da,, oh yeah.
Good heavens!
What is it?
He...
He made a gesture, sir.
You set a fine course there, Walter.
My compliments.
Yeah, I shoulda led you up on the reef!
It's a sorry day when a man's
friends don't trust him.
What about all those provisions?
You don't suppose that boat
of yours could carry them?
Frank...
I want you to take all those provisions,
and I want you to...
Hey, be careful with that!
We'll be at Kings Point in Australia.
When you call us, we want you
to use the following code.
Kings Point is Briar Patch.
I'm Big Bad Wolf,
Stebbings here is Bo Beep,
and you're...
Mother Goose, sir.
That's it. You're Mother Goose.
Now try to remember all that, Walter.
It's bloody important.
Yeah, bloody.
All right, then.
Goodbye, Mother Goose.
Mother Goose.
Let's get under way, Stebbings.
- Sir, it has occurred to me
that as soon as we've gone,
Mr. Eckland might...
Proceed, Stebbings, hard to port.
All right, sir, Coxswain, hard...
Excuse me, sir, but did you say.
Hard a port, son.
Aye-aye, sir.
Coxswain, hard a port!
Hey, hold it, hold it!
Are you crazy?
Look out, look out, Frank!
Do you hear me?
Hard a starboard, Frank!
All in all, watch out!
Are you gone nuts, look out!
Frank, can you hear me?
Hard a starboard, you
ignorant, silly son of a...
Oh, great.
Have you lost your mind?
Look at my boat!
Terribly sorry, Walter.
Our steering must have jammed.
I'm sorry.
If you didn't know how to work
one of those things,
why didn't you say so?
I'm sorry!
- Oh, stop saying
that, look at my boat!
What am I gonna do now?
Become a coastwatcher, I expect.
Lucky we put all those supplies ashore.
Oh, Walter.
We'll stand by until you get safely in.
Frank, I'll sue ya!
I'll sue, I'll sue the entire war!
Quite right, Walter.
I'll be your witness.
Oh, and Walter.
Thanks for volunteering.
Oh come on, buzz off.
Mother Goose?
Frank!
I knew you wouldn't leave me here!
- Mother Goose,
this is Big Bad Wolf.
Go away!
- I know you're saying
something, Mother Goose,
but I can't hear you.
You've got to flip the key.
I said go away.
- You're still not
coming through, Mother Goose.
There's a button on the
microphone, you have to
press it down while you're speaking.
Can you hear me now?
That's better.
You'll find some charts there, Walter,
identifying enemy ships and aircraft.
Study them, will you?
Have you seen anything yet?
Any planes or ships?
Yeah, some planes.
Ours or theirs?
- Kind of depends which
side you're on, doesn't it?
- Walter, news has just come
through that the Japanese
took Singapore this morning.
Frank.
What keeps them from
taking Walter Eckland?
- We've 32 spotters
spread over 3,000 islands.
So you see the odds are
in our favor that you'll
never be found.
Our favor?
You're not stuck out here in
the middle of nowhere, I am.
Now when do I get off?
- I've told you
as soon as we can find
a replacement for you.
Meantime, be good enough
to keep in touch, Walter.
Oh, and I am sorry about your boat.
I really am.
Is Big Bad Wolf really sorry?
Because if he is,
Big Bad Wolf and Little Bo Peep
can do something for Mother Goose.
They can go...
I don't really blame him, do you?
- I can't see that we've
accomplished anything, sir.
I don't think he'll report in.
I mean you can lead a horse to water,
but can you make it drink?
When he gets thirsty enough,
he'll drink, Stebbings.
He'll drink.
Frank, can you hear me?
Frank?
- Loud and clear, Mother
Goose, what is it?
- Where'd those men of
yours put the whiskey?
I've been looking all over this dump.
You don't suppose they kept
it for themselves, do you?
Seamen of His Majesty's Navy?
You must be joking.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, where is it?
- Well, I can
imagine how dull it must get
for someone left all
alone on a small island,
so I decided...
- Alright, alright.
Get to the bad news.
- Well, I decided
to liven things up a bit by
making a little fun and
game thing out of it.
What sort of fun and games?
- I had my men
hide all the bottles
around the island.
In very unlikely places, you'd
never find them by yourself.
The ground rules are simple.
You report an enemy
ship or plane movement,
and I tell you where the bottles are.
One report, one bottle.
Hold it a minute, Frank.
I hear a flight going over right now.
Yeah, isn't that odd, now just a minute
while I get the binoculars.
Oh yes, there's
six, seven, eight of them heading south.
They're...
Nakajima 97s.
But just a minute while I
verify that on one of
these little old charts.
Walter, there's,
there is another rule attached to this.
It has to be a confirmed report.
Confirmed how?
- By other
spotters along the line.
Now just tell me what all
those planes were that you saw.
Hmm?
Frank?
Frank, Frank.
Frank, wake up, Frank.
Frank?
Briar Patch here, Mother Goose.
Bo Peep speaking.
- Briar Patch, what's that,
that's a new one, isn't it?
We've moved.
Are you at Kings Point already?
- Listen, Mother Goose, you
must use the code names.
If you don't like it, fire me.
Now, get Houghton.
The regulations...
Frank here, Walter.
Mother Goose, sir.
What's new?
Five Mitsubishi light bombers,
at around 10,000, headed southwest.
Southwest.
Huh.
At 10 thou.
Got it, sport, thanks!
Hold on now, wait a minute, whoa!
Now it's fun and game time.
Now I played the game, how about the fun?
Confirmed, Walter, remember?
But Frank, I swear!
- Well, in that case,
you've nothing to worry about,
have you?
Sit tight, Mother Goose.
Sit tight, sit tight.
Briar Patch here.
Are you there, Mother Goose?
I'm here, Frank!
I'm here, I'm here.
- We've just received
news that your report
has been confirmed.
Congratulations.
Never mind the congratulations.
Where is it?
- Proceed 50 yards east
northeast to a large rock.
Okay.
- Then 20 yards
due east to a coconut palm.
- No, no, not so fast, not
so fast, wait a minute.
Large rock, 20...
- 20 yards due east
to a coconut palm.
Sir?
Sorry to disturb you at this hour, sir,
but we've heard from Humpty Dumpty.
Oh come on, Stebbings, you can tell me.
Who's Humpty Dumpty?
Perry on Bundi Island.
He reports enemy landings
here on this fare,
here and here on Greater
and Lesser Samengo,
and here on Prince Consort.
- They've ringed him in
pretty well, haven't they?
- He says they don't
know that he's there yet,
but he expects somebody
along at any time now,
and requests to be withdrawn.
- Well, Combat can't
spare a thing, Stebbings.
All our planes and ships are committed.
Who's our nearest man?
I'm afraid he is, sir.
Briar Patch calling Mother Goose.
Come in, Mother Goose.
Do you read me, Mother Goose?
This is Briar Patch.
Yes, yes, I read you.
What's even worse, I can hear you.
Now what do you want?
Walter.
I haven't been sleeping
too well because I've
treated you so badly, so
I'm gonna make it up to you.
- Whatever it is,
Frank, the answer is no.
I don't blame you, sport.
I don't blame you at all.
I'm not listening, Frank.
But supposing I got someone
to repair your boat for you?
I'm listening, Frank.
And after it's repaired,
to stay on there as your replacement.
Who is he?
Malcolm Perry, he's one of our regulars.
When can he be here?
Tonight too soon?
No, Frank, tonight's just fine.
There's just one small thing
Uh-oh.
- He's not able
to get to you, so you'll
have to go and fetch him.
From where, Frank?
Bundi Island.
Bundi?
How do you suggest I get there, Frank?
- That launch of yours
has a dinghy, doesn't it?
- All those miles of
open sea and back again
in a seven-foot dink?
You're nuts!
Shall I call him back, sir?
Frank?
Yes, Walter?
Suppose I could make it to Bundi,
where would I put in, the south jetty?
That's right.
Only be careful, there's a
pretty fair moon tonight.
- You got some special reason
for telling me that, Frank?
No, no, no.
Only it'd be better without a moon.
Why, Frank?
Well, Bundi's liable to be occupied.
With what, Frank?
I didn't say it would be.
Frank.
Yes, Walter?
Kiss my foot, Frank.
If he leaves within the hour,
he should make Bundi just after dark.
But sir, you heard what he said.
He won't go to Bundi.
Frank!
Yes, Walter.
- All those miles of open sea,
a man would need something
to keep warm, wouldn't he?
Two bottles.
All of them, Frank.
Three.
Five.
All of them, Frank.
Got a pencil?
Number four,
is ten yards west of
the shack under a mango.
Five is 30 paces from there, due north,
in a stunted palm.
Just a second, slow it down.
Number six is.
Perry?
Who are you?
I...
I asked you first.
Where's Perry?
Who's Perry?
Perry, the man who lives here.
I buried him.
He was dead.
I found him here.
A Japanese plane must
have attacked the house.
How did you get here?
I.
Duck.
They've passed by before.
I think they are landing on
the other side of the island.
What makes you think that?
Well, I saw them.
If you want to look,
there's a place over there.
Why would I do a silly thing like that?
Come on, let's get out of here.
Do you have a boat?
No, I walked.
Come on.
Come on, we're leaving now.
Look out.
Come on, look out.
Just...
What?
What are all those?
As you can see, they're young ladies.
Now listen, miss, whatever your name is.
Oh, Freneau, Catherine Freneau.
Charmed.
Now suppose you tell me.
What is your name?
Eckland.
How do you do.
Now, miss,
I don't what this is all about but...
Please, miss!
I don't believe it.
Miss?
Shh.
Where is your boat?
I can't see it.
Lady, it's right where we're standing.
If you spit, you'd sink it.
Oh dear.
Oh well, I suppose we'll
just have to manage.
Come on, girls, into the boat.
Wait, wait, wait.
Wait a minute, hold it.
Everybody settle down.
You don't think they'll
all gonna fit in that?
All right, Mr. Eckland.
Which ones do you suggest we leave behind?
You decide.
I'll leave it to you.
It's suicide.
- Would you stand a
better chance without me?
Naturally.
Very well.
Well, I suggest you leave immediately.
Well, that's really very decent of you.
You're a very good sport, thank you.
Now, the rest of you, snap it up.
- Jenny, you're the
smallest, sit in the back.
You'll be out of the way.
Do you mind, lady?
This is my boat, such as it is.
If anyone's going to
sink her, it'll be me.
Now I'll seat them.
You sit in the back.
That's right.
Give it to me, let go.
Mr. Eckland!
Well, this is not the Queen Mary,
there's no room for baggage, come on, you.
My glasses!
I don't want to go.
Oh, that's tough, come here.
Please, take your hand off that.
All right, now.
My scent.
Huh?
Scent.
It's called Anticipation.
Two pounds, 10 the ounce.
You don't say.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
Sit there, that's right.
Take your hands off that.
Hey, hey, ooh!
Oh.
What is that thing?
A cricket bat.
Isn't it a smasher?
I only hope you all can swim.
Take your hand off that.
Now you two, get in
the bottom of the boat.
Get in the bottom of the...
They don't understand English.
Sure, they do.
See?
Oh!
Please.
All right.
Now, I guess that's about all.
Don't forget Gretchen.
What?
Oh, that's her friend.
I'll help her in, dear.
Would you mind?
Oh.
- Now, then, Mr. Eckland, I
suggest you leave immediately.
Oh.
Lady, lady, do you mind?
Just get in the boat.
Well, you said it would...
I don't care what I said.
If by some miracle we do make
it, I'd be stuck with them.
Now get in the boat.
All right.
That's right.
No, no, no, no, not that!
We'd have had a use for that.
Come on.
Come on!
All right.
It's all right, now, don't be afraid.
Quiet, quiet.
Oh for goodness...
- Mr. Eckland,
please keep the boat quiet, the girls
are extremely frightened.
Will you shut up, lady?
Now, here, get off of my paddle.
Well, I'm terribly sorry,
but you put it there in
the first place, you know.
Now, that's all right,
children, don't be scared.
There we go.
Mr. Eckland.
Must you?
- What are you, some kind
of religious fanatic?
- I couldn't care less what
you do to yourself, but...
must you do it in front of the children?
No.
Well then.
Well then, tell them to turn around.
- That is not exactly what
I had in mind, Mr. Eckland.
Now, lady.
The name is Freneau,
Catherine Freneau.
I don't know what you had in mind.
I don't even know who you are
or what you were doing on that island.
- Well, if you must know, an
American plane left us there.
from New Britain...
- I wanna go home.
Oh, Anne, it's rude to interrupt.
We were on our way from New
Britain to Port Moresby,
when the pilot was ordered to
pick up eight survivors of an
Australian bomber that
had crashed in the water.
Unfortunately our...
- Hey, you, take that
bat or whatever it is out of the water.
It's acting like a rudder.
Harriet, really?
The name's Harri.
All right, Harri.
He said he'd try and
come and pick us up later
but that was five hours ago and he.
Quiet.
You don't have to be so rude.
Quiet, I think I hear something.
What?
Put your heads down,
do as I tell you, keep your faces covered.
Hey, keep your face down!
Are they Japanese?
I don't know, do you want me to ask?
Hold on, we've gotta ride out the wake.
We're sinking!
- Well, don't just sit
there, damn it, bail!
Mr. Eckland, your language, really!
Just bail!
Do as I say!
Come on, you can move faster than that!
Come on, all of you!
Use your hands, anything!
Come on, keep bailing.
Faster!
Bail, why aren't you?
Ow!
Come on, now get to work!
Go on!
That's better.
Hold on to the boat, Harri!
Hold on!
Bail the boat!
Well, really.
Come on, girls.
Right, come on.
Come on, Anne.
Kings Point?
Get Houghton.
Is that you, Mother Goose?
- Walter, I can't tell
you how delighted I am.
- Oh, you've Mother Goosed
me for the last time.
What are you talking about?
Now don't play stupid with me,
You'd sell out your father
if you know who he was.
Oh no!
Walter?
What happened?
- Run along.
Frank, get them off of here!
Get who off?
You know who, get 'em off.
- No one could have known
we were there, Mr. Eckland.
The radio was destroyed.
Will you please stay out of this, lady?
I'm only trying to...
- I'm quite
capable of handling it
myself, thank you.
- I'm hungry!
I say, so am I!
Walter, what's?
Walter, who's?
Walter!
Thank you.
Now, suppose you tell me who's there.
Well.
I am Miss Catherine Freneau.
Who is this, please?
- Commander Frank Houghton
of His Majesty's Navy.
Who are you, Miss Freneau,
and what are you doing there?
I'd like to hear that myself, go ahead.
I am the daughter
of Charles Freneau, the
French Consul at Rabaul.
I heard children's voices.
Yes.
I am in charge of seven students
from the consulate school.
Four English, two French, one Australian.
All of them daughters
of diplomatic personnel.
When the bombing started, it
was decided to evacuate them
to Australia.
Unfortunately, the plane our group was on
put us down at Bundi.
And now Mr. Eckland
has been kind enough to
bring us here.
- Come on, come on.
What about Malcom Perry?
Well, I'm sorry, Commander.
The house had apparently
been attacked from the air
and when we found him.
Oh, I'm sorry.
- Commander, how soon do you
think you'll be able to...
arrange for our transportation?
I'd like to hear that as well, yeah.
- That's a difficult question
to answer, Miss Freneau.
If you'll just be a little patient.
No.
Never mind their patience, Frank.
My patience.
Get them off of here!
- All right, Walter,
I'll take it to the top.
Stand by.
- If you're waiting for
the big finale, I'm sorry,
this is all I do.
Oh, son of a...
Mr. Eckland.
I'm bleeding.
Oh dear.
Mr. Eckland,
we could all do with some food.
Elizabeth,
you and Harri open some tins.
Anne, Christine and Jenny.
Find the knives, forks and napkins.
That'll be a good trick, napkins.
Angelique, Dominique.
Hey what, be careful.
What are you doing with those?
Mr. Eckland, where are your tea things?
My what?
Your tea things.
- Last time I looked, they
were next to the finger bowls.
Hey, hey, be careful with that!
Didn't I tell you to?
Oh, it's an empty.
Are you standing by, Walter?
All set to go, Frank.
What did you work out?
A parachute drop.
A what?
They've got to be picked
up, Frank, not put down.
- We thought you
could do with more provisions,
what with all those extra mouths.
I want their mouths out of here.
When are you coming for them?
- Well, that's
rather difficult to say.
Well, try saying today.
I don't think it'll be today, Walter.
- Well, what's
making that parachute drop,
a seagull?
We can only manage a night drop.
There's no way to land.
Frank?
You still haven't said when
you're gonna get them off.
No, I haven't, have I?
Two or three weeks.
Two or three?
Four.
Four?
With luck.
We'll have to stay here a month?
I don't want to stay here.
- Well, Frank, you've slipped
it to me again, haven't you?
I'm sorry, Walter, there's a war on.
Oh, stop saying that!
Commander,
would you be so kind as to
contact my father in Rabaul
and have him inform the
parents of the girls
that they're quite safe?
- All civilian personnel
are being evacuated from
New Britain, Miss Freneau.
But I'll see to it that they're informed.
Signing off.
Three or four weeks.
I heard it, I heard that.
Mr. Eckland,
may I speak with you outside for a moment?
Some other time.
I've been up all night.
I'm going to bed.
Girls.
Go outside and play.
But stay close to the house.
Tell 'em to stay off the beach
or out in the open.
Mr. Eckland?
Yes, sir.
- It now appears likely
we'll remain here together
for some time to come.
Mhmm.
- This being the case, I
think it would be wise of us
to arrive at an understanding.
It must be quite clear to
you that the children must be
our first consideration.
Your first consideration.
I'm my first consideration.
- They are young, sensitive
and impressionable.
They've been through a most
- So am I.
trying experience,
and they will need a normal,
orderly routine established,
and I would expect you to do your share.
Oh, sure, sure.
- It was quite one thing
for you to live as you did
when you were alone on this island,
but you are no longer
alone and your behavior
is totally unsuitable.
Your language is common, your
eating habits...
revolting.
Your appearance disgraceful, and...
as for your drinking, that
must stop immediately.
I will not have the
children subjected to it.
You are, after all, the
only man with whom they'll
come in contact, that makes
you the father figure.
Are you finished?
Good, now let me tell you something.
I am not a father figure.
I am not an uncle figure,
or a brother figure or a cousin figure.
In fact, the only figure
I intend being is a
total stranger figure.
So now,
if you'll excuse me, I'm going to bed.
- And now I'm
supposed to cover my eyes
and run screaming from the
room, you'll be disappointed.
Ain't she a pip?
I doubt very much anything
you could do would shock me.
Let me repeat.
My only concern is for the children.
Well then, why don't you go and
concern yourself with them
and let me get some sleep?
- Gladly, as soon as you've
told me where we will stay.
Stay anywhere you like.
- Well, as
this hovel seems to be
the only shelter on the island,
it's obvious we will have to stay here.
You know what fat chance means?
This is my hovel, so why don't you
back out and let me get some sleep.
Very well.
Oh, for.
Huh, what, what, what?
What the?
Lady,
you are making a powerful enemy.
Girls, let's get in.
- You ought to
be ashamed of yourselves.
A gentleman simply does not enter a room
when ladies are not decent.
- Well, you
learn something every day.
I have to use the radio!
All right, Mr. Eckland,
you may come in now.
Oh.
Didn't you want to use the radio?
Yes, radio.
What's it doing over here?
Kings Point, this is Eckland.
Six Mitsu 104s heading east at 10,000.
Message received, Mother Goose.
Message received.
- Are you looking for
something, Mr. Eckland?
I asked you to stop
drinking, but you wouldn't.
Oh, no.
Where is it?
Somewhere where you won't find it.
Gone again.
Of all the meddlesome.
Oh.
Come on, prod, now where is it,
you got it up here?
Whoa-whoa-whoa!
Wait.
Oh you wait, you just wait!
Kings Point, this is Eckland again.
- Hello, Mother Goose,
this is Briar Patch.
Get Houghton on the double.
Big Bad Wolf is engaged.
- I don't care if he's
married, you get him.
You know, lady, you missed your calling.
You ought to carry a tambourine and put
fig leaves on statues.
What is it, Walter?
Frank?
Now this is a military
zone and you're in command.
You tell Miss Goody Two Shoes
here to get off my back.
Goody Two Shoes?
Yes, you tell her.
Tell her she's a pain in the...
Uh.
Please, Walter, be civil.
Civil?
Who pushed who out of whose home?
Who stole whose liquor?
Who bit whose hand?
Twice.
She bit you?
Miss Freneau?
No.
Now you tell her, you tell
her to give me back my booze.
You tell her to butt
out, you tell her to...
All right, Walter, I'll speak to her.
Here.
Yes?
Miss Freneau.
I'm sure you've noticed
that Mr. Eckland is not the
most sociable sportsman in...
Mr. Eckland is a rude, foul-mouthed,
drunken, filthy beast.
- Give me that.
- Well, be that
as it may.
This is the filthy beast speaking.
Now listen, Frank, when
you send those supplies,
send plenty of whiskey.
- I insist you do nothing
of the kind, Commander.
Now be quiet, both of you.
We've arranged for the parachute drop
to take place tomorrow night at 2200.
I suggest therefore if
you want anything at all,
you better give me a list of your needs.
Whiskey!
Yes, we know about you.
What about Miss Freneau and the girls?
Summer clothes.
Girl magazines.
Peppermint drops.
Tennis balls!
Bow and arrow!
Girls, please.
I have prepared a list.
Now hold it.
You've taken over everything else,
but the radio is still my responsibility.
Eight nighties.
Would you repeat that, Walter?
- Mr. Eckland isn't here
any more, Commander.
I'll give you the list.
Eight nighties.
Nighties?
That is correct.
In various sizes, starting
with children's size six.
And would you please make
that one a bunny suit?
A what?
A bunny suit.
I'm sure you've seen them, Commander.
You know, with the hands and feet.
With the hands and feet.
Mother Goose?
Mr. Eckland?
Big Bad Wolf is calling
you on the wireless.
Oh.
Don't touch anything.
In fact, you'd better get off the boat.
Look, his shirt,
and his pants too.
Good morning.
Er, I'm wanted on the radio.
Ah.
Oh.
Hey, Kings Point, this is Eckland.
Come in, Mother Goose.
This is Briar Patch.
Well, you had something to tell me.
- Big Bad
Wolf had a message for you
concerning the parachute drop.
He gave it to Goody Two Shoes.
Oh, er.
Er, Commander Houghton couldn't wait.
He asked me to give you the message.
Well?
Well what?
The message.
What message?
The message message.
Oh, oh, that message.
Oh, I wrote it down for you.
That's in French.
Oh, is it?
Oh, so it is.
Read it, please.
No, no, no, no, no.
You're reading it in French.
Well, it's written in French.
Oh...
Translate it.
Oh, you want it in English?
Commander Houghton says
there's too much enemy activity
in the area to chance a...
How do you say in English "parachute?"
Parachute.
Oh, really?
There's too much enemy activity
in the area to chance a
parachute drop, and he asked us to make do
with the supplies we have.
Oh no.
Mr. Eckland?
Er?
- I don't suppose there's any
use my asking your permission
to share certain of your
personal belongings with us?
- So far, you've shared
me out of my home, my bed,
my food and my shirt.
Now how about sharing
some of my things with me?
Would you like some tea?
Tea?
Lemon or milk?
Milk?
Oh sorry, we're out of milk.
Oh.
But we could use
some additional place
settings, some rope, some
tools, and above all,
a change of clothing.
Above all, I could use some whiskey.
Now how about making a trade?
Sorry.
That I can't do.
Then, madam, I wish you a good day.
Mr. Eckland, wait!
Hello, Mr. Eckland.
The answer is no.
I wouldn't think of it.
Ah!
You stepped on my foot!
You put it under mine!
Look out!
All a bunch of nuts.
Oh, now, hold it.
And what have you got there?
Oh no!
Come back here, you pirate!
Mr. Eckland, stop chasing the girls.
I'm not chasing them.
They're all crooks, and
you're the crookiest.
And a good day to you, Mr. Eckland.
Rumplestiltskin?
Can anyone hear me?
I can hear you, Rumplestiltskin.
I can hear you, too.
Where's Mr. Eckland?
He is not here.
Nobody is here except my friend Gretchen.
We're not well today.
Say hello, Gretchen.
Did you hear Gretchen?
She said hello.
Hello, Gretchen, I'm sorry
you're not well today.
Go and get Mr. Eckland, please?
The Filthy Beast?
Oh, we don't speak to him.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Come on, get away from there.
Come along, Gretchen.
Is that you, Walter?
No, it's Gretchen.
- Keep them away from
that radio, will you?
You keep them away from the radio.
Beat it.
- Miss Freneau told us
to stay in the house.
- After breakfast, may we
go out with the others?
No.
Not until you're feeling better.
It's Gretchen that's not well.
And I'm tired of staying here.
Oh, do stop complaining.
You sound like Anne.
Is anything wrong?
- The whole Japanese
navy's anchored off shore,
they're sending a boat in.
Where are the other children?
Er, there...
Come on, let's round them up.
Let's get them in the shack.
Mr. Eckland, shouldn't we report the
Japanese to Commander Houghton?
- In five minutes, he can
talk to them personally.
You and Gretchen stay in the house.
Come on, hurry it up.
Get in the house.
Quickly, where are the other two?
- They're down on the
beach collecting coconuts.
- I told you to
keep them off the beach.
No, you didn't.
- Yes, I did, but you
weren't listening as usual.
Come on, let's go.
Show me where.
Anne's up in one of those trees.
Uh-huh.
Get down.
Stay here, don't move.
Hey, stay, shh.
If she opens her mouth, we've had it.
Jenny hasn't said a word since she
left her parents seven days ago.
I thought you might have noticed.
She can still scream, can't she?
Here.
There you are.
Shh-shh-shh-shh.
Baby, shh, baby, shh.
Don't cry, shh, shh.
Don't cry, don't cry.
Stay up.
I wish I knew what they were saying.
Shh.
The one with the glasses is the cook.
Their captain adores turtle soup.
He sent them ashore for turtles.
There doesn't seem to be any.
Oh, it's all right,
they're going to leave now.
Oh dear.
What?
- One of them suggested they
bring back coconuts instead.
It's a bad dream.
- The cook says the captain
wants turtle soup or nothing.
He's sick of coconuts.
Good for him.
Oh!
What?
He just called the captain a dirty name,
and they're leaving.
Help!
I'm slipping.
Oh!
Quick, let's go.
Go on, beat it.
Come on, buzz off.
You're not supposed to be on the boat.
Get off the boat.
Thank you.
And what's your name?
You got a name, haven't you?
See this whistle?
Would you like to have it?
Okay.
Now all you have to do is
repeat three simple words
after me.
Is that a deal?
Just repeat three words.
All right.
Elephant.
Rhinoceros.
Wrong.
Why?
No, not why, wrong.
Wrong is the third word, you lose.
No, give me that back!
Oh, I didn't think you'd
be a sore loser, here.
Fine.
- I'm sorry,
we're all out of whistles.
I told Harri she could help us.
Help us do what?
Fix your boat.
Harri knows everything about boats.
How'd you like to swab down the deck?
Smashing, I'd love to!
Good, you'll find a mop down below.
Go ahead.
Oh, hello, hello.
Er, well, you do that.
Do that, mhmm.
But do it quietly.
Mr. Eckland?
Quiet, quiet.
Want me to mess this up?
Mr. Eckland?
- Now, I know you've
saved up a lot to say,
but would you mind
spreading it out a little?
You're doing it wrong.
It's backwards.
No, it isn't.
See, the boat's upside down.
Do it this way so when
you turn it over, you...
How can I get anything done when you're
chattering all the time?
Besides, you should be working.
Go on.
It can't be.
Red light!
So this is where you are.
What are you all doing here?
Look at their clothes!
They're my clothes.
But they're filthy!
No they're dirty, I'm filthy.
All of you get back to the house.
It's nearly time for your lessons.
- Mr. Eckland asked us
to help fix his boat.
Well, I'm sure he will excuse you now.
But we want to stay here.
I don't...
What did you say, Jenny?
We want to stay here.
- Mr.
Eckland got her to speak.
I created a monster.
A talking person.
Well, better do as she said.
Get going.
Thank you, Mr. Eckland.
Next time I want them to talk
or do anything, I'll call you.
Well, it's not my fault that boats are
more fun than lessons.
I did it on purpose.
Nothing is ever your fault, Mr. Eckland.
And if I return seven wild
Indians to their families,
who trusted me with them, that
won't be your fault either.
Shh-shh-shh.
Huh?
- Well, you don't have to be
a schoolteacher all the time.
I am not a schoolteacher.
But some form of discipline
has to be maintained.
Shh.
When did you teach them something useful?
What do you suggest?
Drinking and swearing?
Why are we whispering?
Oh!
I don't know, why were we whispering?
Hmm?
Is it edible?
No, I get lonely.
Now why don't you teach
them something like that?
Something practical, like catching fish.
- Oh well, that doesn't
seem too difficult.
I mean, if you can do
it, I'm sure anyone can.
Try it.
I haven't had my morning laugh yet.
All right.
Oh, that was good.
Good.
Woo!
I didn't quite understand the reason
for that last movement.
Would you mind demonstrating it again?
I have an infuriating lack of talent
for doing simple things.
- You probably don't do
'em right, that's why.
All right, all right, just stay there.
I like fish, but fish don't like me.
- All right, now, be
quiet, just keep still.
Give me your hand.
Cup them, cup them.
That's right.
Oh.
Mhmm.
Now, watch what you're doing.
Hey, here she comes again.
How do you know it's a she?
Her mouth is open, now be quiet.
Okay, now,
now slowly.
Slowly, now.
Slowly.
Mr. Eckland?
Aren't we moving too slowly now?
Hmm, hmm?
Shouldn't we.
Shouldn't we what?
What?
You said shouldn't we.
Shouldn't we what?
Well, you've got the hang of it now.
Oh.
We didn't catch a fish.
That's right, that's right.
We didn't.
But you got the hang of it.
You already said that.
Oh, I did, huh?
Mr. Eckland, are you going to show me
how to catch a fish or aren't you?
I aren't.
I wanna go back now.
- Just as soon as I've
picked some of these berries.
What if they're dangerous?
- Oh, we can
always ask Mr. Eckland.
- Yeah, if he says eat them,
we'll know they're poisonous.
Oh.
Oh!
Something bit me.
A snake, there, next to your leg.
Woo!
It bit you, it bit you!
Oh.
Let's go back, quickly.
I don't know what she's saying.
snake, I saw it.
It bit mademoiselle on the leg.
Okay, everyone out.
- Girls,
do as Mr. Eckland says.
I'll be all right.
I want to watch!
Oh, Harri, please.
Is it painful?
Your hand is wet.
Yeah.
Now this is going
to hurt a little.
You should enjoy that.
Quiet.
Go ahead, you can yell
if you feel like it.
I don't feel like it.
Okay, it's all done.
- Do you really
think it was poisonous?
Well, no sense taking any chances.
Lie back, this isn't going to hurt.
Mr. Eckland,
I want you to know I really
appreciate what you're doing.
Save it.
Come in, Kings Point, this is Eckland.
Briar Patch, Mother Goose.
Bo Peep here.
- Get Houghton, will
you, we got trouble here.
What's wrong, Walter?
- What kind of snakes
they got around here, Frank?
Is that a rhetorical question, I hope?
No, Miss Freneau went and found one.
Good grief, is she?
She seems all right at the moment.
Find out if they're
poisonous, will you, Frank,
and if so what we can do about it.
Right away.
Oh, and Walter.
Until we get a positive
identification, don't try
and be a movie hero
and suck out the venom.
Walter?
Are you there, Walter?
Yeah, I'm here, Frank, shoot.
Plug in the phones, will you?
Yeah.
Go ahead.
It's not good.
I've got Dr. Bigrave here.
He's checked with Tropical
Medicine, I'll put him on.
Mr. Eckland.
There are three varieties of
serpent indigenous to those
islands and I'm afraid all of
them are extremely poisonous.
Well, I opened the wound, Doctor.
I think I got all the venom out.
- Taken orally, it can't
hurt you, Mr. Eckland,
but if she were bitten and
it's entered her bloodstream,
there's nothing we can do.
I'm afraid she's bought it.
Well, there must be some...
- The venom is neurological,
it attacks the nervous system.
The end will come suddenly
preceded by a general
numbing sensation and dizziness.
Oh, oh, I see, Doctor.
- I suggest you do
everything to make her as
comfortable as possible.
Including the liberal use of any strong,
analgesic sedative you happen to have.
- I don't have
anything like that.
- Nonsense, Walter, you've
been using one for years.
No, I haven't.
Oh yes, I have, yeah.
Call me, Walter, when it's over.
Goodbye.
Yeah.
It's bad, isn't it?
Where's the whiskey?
Oh, I knew it.
I'm going to die and
you're afraid I'll take
the secret to my grave.
- Whiskey is still the
best thing for snake bite.
Where is it, lady?
Stop calling me lady.
It sounds so awful.
It's in the oven.
It can't be in the oven.
I looked there.
I know you did.
Gretchen told me.
I put it there after you looked.
- Hey, I
thought that was for me?
- Just want to make
sure it hasn't gone bad.
Come on, drink that.
It won't hurt you, go on.
Hey, hey, be careful.
You'll ruin your amateur standing.
I'm French, Mr. Eckland.
My parents started me
on wine mixed with water
when I was six.
But I don't believe in excessive drinking.
Especially in front of children.
Oh.
No, the truth is,
when my mother died,
I became the mistress of...
the consulate.
Oh, oh.
- I presided over all
the diplomatic dinners.
We had martinis before dinner,
white wine with the fish.
Red wine with the main course,
champagne with the dessert.
Cognac with the coffee,
and port after dinner.
Sounds great.
- Isn't it
getting hot in here?
Woo, isn't it getting hot in here?
Isn't it getting hot in here?
No, no, you mustn't move around now.
Come on, just...
That's right, just lie quietly.
I bet you think I'm an iceberg.
Do you know how old I am?
No.
The truth is,
we've lived in 11 countries
I can speak seven languages.
I'm excellent at bridge.
I play the cello very well.
I'm double-jointed,
and I know how to ride a camel.
I was engaged once.
Huh, uh-huh.
His name was Cesare and he worked
in the Italian consulate at Fiume.
Do you know where Fiume is?
Yugoslavia, isn't it?
No, it's in Yugoslavia.
He called me Carissima and gave me
handkerchiefs with my initials on them.
Every time he wanted to kiss me, he'd say,
And then afterwards, he'd say,
You've had enough.
- Oh, Cesare would never
have done to my leg
what you did.
Oh, probably couldn't reach it.
- I liked what you did to my
leg, the last part, I mean.
Oh, that.
Tell me, I'd like to know.
What did my blood taste like, hmm?
Delicious, now come on.
No, no, no, no, I'm being serious.
What did it taste like?
How would I know?
I'm not a vampire.
Oh.
Was it salty?
A little salty, yes.
Too salty?
No, it was just right.
Oh no.
You thought it was too salty,
I can tell you didn't like it.
No, no, I liked it.
Oh, really?
I liked it.
You're not just saying that?
No, great blood.
Please, now, buzz off, will you?
Miss Freneau isn't feeling very well.
Now come on.
I'm gonna kill that rotten snake.
Anne!
Your opinion of me is correct, you know.
I'm a...
a picture straightener.
You're a what?
A picture straightener.
Oh.
- When I see a picture
on a wall that doesn't
hang straightly...
I straighten it.
Oh, you do that.
- And I brush my teeth every
morning and every night.
And if I don't have a toothbrush...
I use my finger.
Mm.
Oh.
I feel so numb.
Numb?
Where?
Everywhere!
What does it mean?
Oh, you'd better lie down.
And I'm so cold.
Oh, why am I so cold?
Oh, I'm dizzy.
I'm very dizzy.
You lie down, just rest.
Oh.
That's right.
- Oh, come closer so I
can tell you something.
My coconut is empty.
Oh.
Have a belt yourself.
Oh...
no, no thanks.
There'll be plenty of time later.
I mean, you go ahead.
What was she like?
She, who?
The lady who drove you to this.
Drove me to what?
Drink.
Oh, there was no lady.
That was your wife.
No, there was no wife.
- Then from what are
you running away from?
Mmm?
Oh, I'm not running away.
Oh, there must have been some, some.
Well, there was.
A necktie.
A what?
I was late for class one morning.
I forgot my tie, they wouldn't let me in.
How long ago was that?
About eight years ago.
- Weren't you a little
old to be going to school?
Oh, I wasn't going, well...
I was teaching.
Oh!
I was a professor of history.
And what about the necktie?
- Well now this is no
time to talk about me now.
Why not?
Why not.
Well...
See, I thought they'd be more
interested in what was inside
a man's head, not around his neck.
Mmm.
Then I noticed they all wore ties.
They all looked alike,
they all behaved alike,
and they all talked alike.
But they were all going the same way,
no matter which way they
said they were going.
So, what was the use of
teaching them history,
or anything?
They weren't learning by it.
Still creating the same old problems.
So I packed, got on a boat,
and got away from them.
Mmm.
Now look what they've got me doing.
Ah-ha.
What's so funny?
You're the schoolteacher.
Oh dear.
What's that?
The snake.
But that's not a snake.
It looks like a snake.
You ninny.
You better tell Mr. Eckland.
I wanna go home.
He'll be furious.
Why?
Because Miss Freneau's not dead.
This is Eckland, is Houghton there?
I'm here, Walter.
Frank.
It's all over, Frank, she's.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
What do I do about the kids, Frank?
They don't know yet.
They'll have to be told, Walter.
Yeah.
Stick around, will you?
I may need you later.
Sure, sure.
I'll stand by.
Mr. Eckland?
Oh, oh, oh.
Just a minute, I...
Er, will you all come over here, please?
Mr. Eckland?
Please.
There's something I want to tell you.
There's something we want to tell you.
Just a minute, now.
This isn't going to be easy.
Now, er...
Those of you who are old
enough to understand what I'm
going to say will be able to
help the ones who...
well.
Mr. Eckland?
Please, there's a good girl.
Now, Miss Freneau...
who I guess we all gave
a very difficult time to
when she...
well.
Miss Freneau has...
has gone away.
No she hasn't.
You tell him, Anne.
Why me?
Because it was all your fault.
Er, just a minute.
Tell me what?
It wasn't a snake, it was this.
But that's not a snake.
It looks like a snake.
Here.
Watch out for the thorns.
Uh!
Thank you.
Not a snake.
It looks like a snake.
No, that doesn't.
This looks like a snake!
Is it morning already?
Walter?
Are you there, Walter?
I have the chaplain.
I thought it might be a
comfort if he said a few words.
Never mind the chaplain, Frank.
She's alive.
The snake's dead.
Walter,
explain yourself.
Walter?
Walter!
Were you really a schoolteacher?
All of you, raise your right hands.
Come on, raise your right hands.
All right.
Now none of you heard
anything I said in there,
you got that?
Okay.
Now spit.
Go ahead, spit.
The first one who breaks
the pledge will get warts.
warts?
Er, Mr. Eckland?
May I speak with you, please?
Oh.
You don't have to shout.
I don't even have to talk.
Mr. Eckland, do I
owe you an apology or a...
an explanation or anything like that?
Probably, some other time.
I seem to remember someone saying that a
drop or two helps.
Ooh!
- Not today!
I went through enough nonsense with you
just to get this much.
Mr. Eckland.
What exactly did I do yesterday?
Nothing.
You just put a flower
between your teeth and
danced around the room naked.
But I couldn't have!
I did?
You mean you don't remember?
No.
Oh.
Oh, well then, you don't
remember anything I said, do you?
Why, what did you say?
Nothing.
- Well, there doesn't seem
to be much to remember then,
does there?
No, no, no, no.
- Unless you mean what you
said about running away from
civilization because of a necktie.
- I thought you said
you didn't remember anything!
Oh, nothing after that.
There wasn't anything after that.
- Then when did I dance
around naked with a
flower between my teeth?
I only told you those things about me in
strictest confidence.
Why, I haven't told anyone!
You just told me, didn't you?
You are the one who told me.
Well, I don't care.
I only told you because
I thought you were dying.
Sorry I disappointed you.
Ugh.
- I don't mind that you
were a schoolteacher.
There you go again!
Now it's none of your business.
- I thought you were
running away from something
much worse than that.
I wasn't running away, I was escaping,
from hypocrites like you,
who have to get drunk
before they can let go.
There.
Why then, you're a happy man.
That's right.
- And that's why you drink so
much, because you're so happy.
Yes.
Is this boat tilted?
No!
Now you listen to me.
Before you mess around
with other people's lives,
you better take a look at your own.
And what's wrong with it?
- Well, maybe if you stopped
straightening pictures and let
men wear their own pants,
maybe they'd be able to
touch you without asking
Dear Lord.
- Oh Harriet,
it's Dominique's turn
to say grace.
Amen.
Oh, Mr. Eckland.
Oh.
I thought if you had enough food, I.
Well, certainly.
Look, he's combed his hair.
And he's actually wearing socks.
Well, you see, my feet were chilly.
Oh...
we're delighted you could come.
Anne, move over next to
Elizabeth so Mr. Eckland
can sit down.
I don't want to sit there.
She never wants to do anything.
That's not true.
I wanna go home.
All right, Anne.
Change places with Harriet.
The name's Harri.
Oh, sorry. Harri.
On the other side of Mr. Eckland.
Thank you, Harri.
We fellows should stick together.
Pass to Monsieur Eckland.
That's my dinner.
Well, then, take it.
I'm sick and tired of tinned beef.
Then give it back.
I wanna go home.
Why can't we have fish once in a while?
Professor Eckland was giving me lessons,
but he never finishes what he starts.
Raise your arms.
Lower your head.
- Drink something, give
him something to drink.
Quick.
Drink!
Yeah, hold it.
Jenny!
Well, how strange.
Why?
That you should bring me this.
I've done it before.
Yes, I have.
Shut up.
Well, since it's here, I'll.
- There's already a beverage
on the table, Mr. Eckland.
Yes, what?
Coconut milk.
You're kidding.
- Well, it happens to be very
tasty and quite healthful.
Oh, I'm sure it is.
Ah-ah-ah, Mr. Eckland?
Delicious.
Coconut milk.
Young coconuts must love it.
Get back, get back!
Come on, let's get back in the shack.
I hurt my ankle when you...
when I fell.
Now get up.
Let's see.
Put your weight on it.
That's not too bad.
All right.
That's fine.
This is Eckland, get Houghton.
Standy by, Mother Goose.
Yes, Walter, what is it?
A plane, Frank. He dove at us.
Go on.
Go on where? He spotted us.
- And now you'd like me to
take you off the island.
Is that it?
Naturally.
Really, Walter.
You never give up, do you?
All right, tell me what happened.
- I've already told you, a
Japanese plane flew over.
What kind?
I don't know what kind.
- Well, that's what you're
there for, isn't it?
Really, Walter.
Planes are supposed to fly over.
We wouldn't need you where
planes didn't fly over, would we?
Now, just because one gets a little close.
A little close?
Now you listen to me, Frank,
you get us out of here by tonight.
- I really don't think
it'll be tonight, Walter.
Well, thanks a lot.
I won't need you when
I get the launch ready.
- Walter, I'd forget about
the launch if I were you.
You're completely ringed in
there, which means you can only
travel by night,
in a boat which you can't be too sure of.
And even if you could break
through, which I doubt,
Port Moresby's the only
place open and that's over
200 miles away.
Then do something.
Walter...
I have 32 men in precisely
the same position you're in.
How is it that I spend most
of my time listening to you?
Now be a good chap and relax, signing off.
The fathead.
I'll be down at the launch.
Mr. Eckland?
Hmm?
Oh, I thought your
ankle was bothering you.
Well, it's feeling much
better now, thank you.
Fine.
I wanted to thank you.
For saving my life, I mean.
I behaved quite stupidly.
Can you forgive me?
Sure.
- I wouldn't want you
to think badly of me.
Do you think badly of me?
No.
I don't think badly of you either.
Well, good for you.
Mr. Eckland?
You can kiss me if you want.
I may?
Oh, my darling.
I have thought of nothing
else since that moment we met.
This first burning kiss
is but the beginning.
Tonight you will leave those children
and come live with me on my boat.
What are you doing?
But of course, how thoughtless of me.
We must be careful.
What time can I expect you tonight?
- But mademoiselle doesn't
let us out at night.
Oh well.
- Mr. Eckland,
have you been listening to me?
- How can I help it with
you screaming in my ear?
- Because you've
been talking total nonsense,
as usual.
It's quite clear you know nothing
whatsoever about children.
Uh-huh.
And you're an expert, of course.
Well, I know one thing.
Elizabeth is at that...
Wait, wait, wait.
Hand me those pliers, will you?
The small ones.
Those?
Thank you.
Now what were you saying?
- Elizabeth is at that difficult
age and you frightened her.
Yeah.
Well, I'm at a difficult age myself.
She nearly scared me to death.
How about teaching those
kids the facts of life,
or don't you feel you're
up on the subject?
I wouldn't exactly call them backward,
not the way they were
watching during lunch.
Watching what?
It works!
Course it works!
Now what were they watching during lunch?
They were watching us.
Watching us what?
Watching us watch each other.
So we watched each other, so what?
Well, they're not blind, you know?
- What do they think watching
is, a proposal of marriage?
Whoever said anything about...
- Just because a man puts
on socks and comes to lunch?
- If you think I'd want
to get involved with an
undisciplined, self-indulgent
escapist like you.
- Well, that's better than
being a frustrated spinster
who can't find a husband.
It's Matalava, sir.
Mother Goose is requesting a chaplain.
A chaplain?
Good heavens, he's killed her.
No, sir.
They want to get married.
Married?
Goody Two Shoes and the Filthy Beast?
What's taking him so long?
He's had enough time to get
the Archbishop of Canterbury.
Oh, Mr. Eckland, really.
- Oh, stop calling me Mr.
Eckland, it sounds ridiculous.
Walter?
Are you ready, Walter?
Just a minute, Frank.
Here, use my tie.
Oh.
Thank you, Harri, but ties
don't suit Mr. Eckland.
Oh.
Well, have you got the chaplain, Frank?
Yes, he's here.
There's a little paperwork, Walter.
Bride's full name.
Catherine,
Louise,
Marie,
Ernestine Freneau.
Groom's full name.
Walter Christopher Eckland.
Witnesses.
Who's the maid of honor?
Elizabeth Anderson.
And the best man?
Harri McGregor.
Harri?
Just believe me.
Proceed, padre.
Thank you.
Now.
Is everyone ready?
Yes, padre.
Dearly beloved.
We are gathered here...
and there,
in the presence of these
witnesses to join together
this man and this woman
in the bonds of holy matrimony
which is an honorable estate,
instituted of God.
Into this holy estate,
these two persons come now
to be joined.
Duck, down, quickly!
If there be any present...
Who know any
just cause...
- Hurry up, quickly!
- Why they may not
lawfully
be joined in marriage,
I require him now to make it known,
or ever after to hold his peace.
Anything there?
Good.
Now, then.
Do you, Walter Christopher
Eckland, take this woman
to be your lawful wedded wife?
To love and to cherish,
to have and to hold,
so long as you both
shall live?
Mr. Eckland?
Do you, -
Walter Christopher Eckland...
Walter!
- To be your
lawful wedded wife?
Hold it, padre, hold it.
Mr Eckland, do you...
I do, I do.
Get Houghton, quick.
What is it, Walter?
They came back, Frank.
I told you they would.
Who came back?
You know who, now listen.
Did you hear that?
Yes, I'll get onto it right away.
Stand by.
I want the name and exact
position of every Allied submarine
within 12 hours running distance
between here and Matalava.
And get onto it right away.
Aye-aye, sir.
Walter?
I told you to stay where you were.
The plane's gone.
I was afraid I was a widow
before we were even married.
Mr. Eckland?
What should we do now?
Well,
all right, we'll take another whack at it
if you will, padre.
So take your time, but hurry it up.
Oh, yes, yes, of course, I understand.
Let me see now.
Do you, Walter Christopher
Eckland, take this woman?
We did that part, padre.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm a little rattled.
Let me see here.
All right, then.
Do you, Catherine Louise
Marie Ernestine Freneau,
take this man to be your
lawful wedded husband,
to love and to cherish,
to have and to hold,
for as long as you both shall live?
I do.
- For as much as you
have consented together
in holy wedlock, and have
given and received a ring
in token of your troth.
Wait a minute, what ring?
Didn't we do the ring?
No, we didn't do the ring.
- Oh, I'm afraid
we'll have to do the ring.
Hold it, padre.
All right, padre, we did the ring.
Oh good.
For as much as you have consented
together in holy wedlock,
and have given and received a
ring in token of your troth,
I now declare you husband and wife.
You may kiss the bride, Mr. Eckland.
Mr. and Mrs. Eckland,
if you're finished now, I
suggest you get the hell
out of there.
- Yeah, that's a good
suggestion, padre, thank you.
Hold on, Walter, hold on.
What, Frank?
- One of your American
submarines, the Sail Fin,
is in your area.
She's running submerged, so
we will not be able to make
radio contact with her
until she surfaces tonight.
But she ought to be able
to get through to you
by dawn tomorrow.
She'll have to lie off the
reef and await your signal,
so I suggest you stay on the beach.
Have you got that?
I've got it.
- Oh and incidentally,
Walter, congratulations to you
and Mrs. Eckland.
And the best of luck to all of you.
And they're going to need it.
Walter, are you awake?
Uh-huh.
I was thinking about yesterday.
Somehow the word "wedding"
has always called to mind
a different picture.
- Somehow, the words
"wedding night" have always
called to mind a different picture, too.
- Well, we couldn't very
well have left the girls
by themselves.
They're our responsibility.
They're not our children.
- If they were our children,
they'd have never gotten
to be our children,
would they?
You won't be coming with us, will you?
How did you know?
- Oh, when a woman has been
married as long as I have,
she knows what her husband's thinking.
Oh well.
I'll shove off right after the rest of you
and get to Port Moresby in no time.
- You know what
Commander Houghton said.
I can't leave my boat.
Must be a good one.
- Good and bad is all the
dowry you're going to get.
I'm thinking of starting
a charter service,
right after the war.
Somewhere around the
Solomons and New Hebrides.
Good money there for anyone
who knows the islands.
All right.
I'm not leaving without you.
Oh, yes you are.
Someone's got to get those
children back to their parents.
Lord, you're stubborn.
That's right, now come on.
There, come on.
That's it, go to sleep.
They're here.
Girls?
Hold it.
That's a Japanese patrol boat.
Oh my God.
They picked a fine time to check us out.
What about the submarine?
- She won't surface
while that thing's there.
Get off the beach!
Come on, girls, wake up.
- Quickly as you
can, wake up, come on!
Take your gear!
Now this.
They're sending two boats ashore.
Now these fellas aren't
looking for turtles,
they're looking for us.
- Oh, what if the submarine
leaves without us,
can't you radio them?
- No, I can't make contact
while they're submerged.
Now, take the kids to the launch,
and for God's sakes, keep them quiet.
Oh.
Walter?
Hmm?
I look awful in black.
Over here.
The house is on fire.
I know, I started it.
When did you do that?
Last night when you were asleep.
What else was there to do?
Hey, hide all that stuff.
We're getting off this island.
Is the submarine there?
It had better be.
Are we going home now?
That's right.
I don't wanna go home.
Oh come on.
Get in the dinghy and hurry it up.
- Commander
Houghton said there'd be
a signal, he wasn't joking.
- They're coming out
to meet us on a launch.
Dead slow.
Dead slow, sir.
Answer's dead slow.
Holy Cow!
An enemy patrol boat giving chase.
Ready the bow torpedo tubes.
- Tubes forward, con,
make ready forward tubes.
Submerged reef 300 yards from shore.
No torpedo clearance.
The launch is heading out
beyond the reef.
They're following.
That's what he's up to, he's
bringing them out to us.
They're plastering him.
He's cleared the reef.
They're right behind him.
Bearing?
Mark.
Zero-two-five.
Range?
Mark.
Six-five-oh.
Tubes one and two open outer doors.
Check fire, check fire.
The launch is veering into target path.
Get going, get going.
Final bearing.
Mark.
Fire one.
Fire two.
On the nose!
Not that it'll do those
poor devils any good.
Let's take her up and look for survivors.
Walter?
Mr. Eckland!
Oh, zit!
What's the matter with this thing?
Mr. Eckland?
There's his hat!
Jenny, move over, I want to catch it.
Mrs. Eckland, I presume?
Mr. Eckland!
Took me forever to tie the wheel off.
I thought I'd have to stay with her.
Our boat, The Catherine, I'm sorry.
- Yeah, well, in a war,
everybody loses something.
I'm just glad it was that Catherine.
Hey, wait a minute, hold it.
Wanna invite me in first?
Oh, oh!
Walter, no, you'll tip us in!
Not if you do it right, now.
Just shift your weight, get over there.
Walter, I really don't think it's such a
good idea.
- Now please, please.
Just this once, will you do it my way?
All right.
Shut up.
I didn't say anything.
Looks like we'll be taking on passengers
after all, Mr. Cartwright.
Break out a raft.
Aye-aye, sir.
Ah.
I wonder if they serve
coconut milk on submarines.