THE ORGANIZER
TURIN - THE LATE 1800s
Omero.
Wake up. It's 5:30.
Wash well, you hear?
Your neck and ears too.
Come on, lazybones.
The milk needs heating.
You haven't got
the coal burning yet.
The coal's wet.
It's so damp in here.
The coalman's dog
pisses on the coal!
Watch your mouth!
Hey, wake up!
Leave him alone.
His stomach hurt last night.
- He just hates schoolwork.
- That's not true!
Oh, yeah? Maybe I can't read,
but I know my numbers,
and this is a big fat zero.
Omero, leave money
for groceries.
Again? The week
isn't even half over.
This is the last of it,
so go easy.
"Go easy."
Easy for you to say.
Your lunch.
Did you wash?
Morning.
Wake up, dummy!
Take it easy!
- Same spot today?
- I'm coming. Hold your horses.
Don't ever call me "dummy" again,
you hear?
I'll call you anything I want
as long as I'm bigger than you.
So much for talking things over.
Rice and turnips again.
It's good for you.
Nusetta, here I am!
Some idea,
bringing the baby here in this cold!
He's asleep when I leave
and when I get home.
I've got a right to see him.
Hey, small-fry!
Look at Papa.
See that?
He doesn't even know me.
That'll teach you, you pig!
Nice manners.
They don't even give you time to eat.
Here, take this.
Come on, Pautasso.
You're always the last.
Did you have enough time to eat?
These cannibals wolf it down
without even chewing.
Come on, get moving!
The bastards treat us
like animals!
It's worse than prison.
To hell with all of 'em.
My arm!
Stop the machines!
Stop the wheel!
Stand back!
Let me through!
How is he?
How do you think?
Hands don't grow back.
We're taking up
a collection for Mondino.
Another collection.
Ls that all we can do?
Raoul's right.
Can't you even do that for the poor man?
What kind of animals are you?
I'll tell you!
We work a 14-hour shift
with half an hour to eat.
Then something like this happens.
Do we ask for more reasonable shifts?
No, we can't take any risks!
We take up a collection!
Right, Pautasso?
Cenerone?
Sheep - that's what we are!
What do you mean, asking me?
I'm always ready.
Don't believe it? Maybe
a knuckle sandwich will convince you.
Papa, calm down.
Words don't put food on the table.
Will Mondino get by on our collection?
What a laugh!
We don't even have
accident insurance.
And I'm the one
talking nonsense?
Martinetti, you didn't answer.
I said I'm ready.
- To do what?
- To give the boss an earful.
About what?
I don't know.
Anything you want.
I'll raise a stink!
To tell him 14 hours a day
is too much.
Right! They have to cut
the hours, or -
We'll form a committee
to decide who'll speak to them.
Good. I'll be the leader.
- No, we're all equal. You, him -
- And me!
Women too now?
Look, this is serious.
Oh, so we can work
and contribute to collections,
but not stand up for our rights?
Quiet!
Go home now. It's late.
Forgive us, Sister.
Home to bed now,
or tomorrow you won't even get
your drawers on straight.
Your father's quite a guy, eh?
He produced
a juicy tidbit like you.
Animal!
Dinner's ready for Ward 3.
Soup with meat and potatoes.
Hey, the umbrella!
Wait for me!
- We should turn back for you?
- What cavaliers!
To hell with your cavaliers.
- Who's gonna do the talking?
- All of us.
- Like an opera chorus?
- I'm no talker. Martinetti.
Scram!
All right, I'll do it.
- Where are you going?
- We wanted to speak to the manager.
Good-bye, Mr. Baudet.
The manager?
What do you want with him?
- We want to tell him something.
- Tell me.
It's just that -
- ls it a secret?
- On the contrary.
We speak for everyone.
It's about the accident yesterday.
Fourteen hours a day is too much.
You're really lucky, you know?
If you'd said that to the boss,
you'd all be finished.
Everybody in Turin
works the same hours.
That's why
these accidents happen.
My good man,
accidents are accidental.
You have to be careful
and hope they don't happen.
You're not going to blame
the manager, are you?
See you later, Baudet.
Enjoy your lunch, sir.
Listen.
I'm on salary, just like you.
I'm on your side.
I mean this sincerely:
Come back down to earth
and forget this nonsense.
Where did you ever get
such crazy ideas?
Go on. Speak up.
They're not crazy ideas.
What's crazy is exploiting people.
- Right.
- That's it.
Am I wrong?
Here.
Write your name
and fold it up tight.
Hold your horses.
I'll be back.
He's in there.
Another collection?
- You putting your name in?
- For what?
We're quitting early tonight.
- The manager agreed?
- Yeah, and pigs fly too.
No, we're taking matters
into our own hands.
We're demonstrating,
like the British.
Bend over.
What are the names for?
Just stay there.
To decide who'll blow
the whistle an hour early
so we all stop
at the same time.
Are you in?
Yeah, but the whistle-blower's
taking a big chance.
As soon as you hear the whistle,
shut off the steam.
The machines will stop,
and everyone will have to quit.
- Don't worry.
- Let's have the names.
I can't read.
Just great.
Here, you read it.
This guy can't write.
Who put an X?
Me too.
Forget all this. I'll do it.
Watch out!
What's going on here?
Back to work, all of you!
We stop at 7:30.
Spread the word.
When the machines stop,
we all leave.
Foreman!
I gotta go.
Go away! Beat it, mutt!
- Hey!
- Ready!
Hey, you!
Yeah, I'm ready!
Hey, you lucky devils!
You're nice and warm in here
when it's freezing outside!
And you'd still rather
go home earlier?
What's going on?
You sure that's our whistle?
Don't shut the steam off!
Don't stop the machines!
- Come on.
- No one's moving!
Didn't you hear the whistle?
Let's go!
Keep working!
There's still an hour to go.
- Something went wrong.
Hey!
Why have you got your coat on?
I'm cold.
We really came through
for Pautasso.
Who sounded the whistle?
What kind of joke is this?
What are you doing here?
Playing with the dog.
He's been in there
an hour and a half.
Here he comes!
Did they give him
the third degree?
Let me shake your hand
for being the only one -
Stop it!
Stop the brute!
Damned fool!
Stop it!
That's enough!
Pautasso, listen!
You're right, but let us talk!
No, I'll do the talking now!
Some friends you are!
You left me high and dry.
I had to pretend I was drunk.
"Pautasso,
have you been drinking?"
"Afraid so, sir. For my rheumatism."
You make me sick!
We'll get better organized.
We'll form a committee,
and you'll be on it.
Tomorrow we'll decide.
They've already done
the deciding!
Two weeks' suspension for me,
and a fine for everybody.
The crooks!
Now let me go!
Let him go on three.
One, two, three!
Listen carefully, all of you.
Forget Domenico Pautasso exists.
Cross my name off your list!
We'll make up your lost pay.
But we must remain united!
Sure, like my balls!
Foul-mouthed pig!
Learn some manners!
Papa, stop it!
You old walrus, let's go!
Take that, bastard!
Let me go!
Bastards! Murderers!
You animal!
Hit me and I'll kill you!
Excuse me.
What town is this?
A shithole of a town!
That's how you answer a stranger?
This is the Porta Susa district of Turin.
- Porta Susa? Thank you.
In "The rose smells sweet,"
the subject is "the rose."
In "The butterfly is graceful,"
the subject is -
The butterfly!
"The nightingale -"
The others have been here
half an hour!
Sorry, sir. We're late.
I hadn't noticed!
I could have been home
snug in bed by now!
I'm here for your good,
not mine!
Let's get this straight right now.
To vote
you must be able to write.
That's the law laid down
by our beloved government.
On these crude benches
is where you earn the right
to make your voice
heard in parliament.
This classroom
is where your brains will find
new power and strength
to nourish the flame of a faith
that will shine ever brighter
and with which we must -
Anyway...
forget I said anything.
Mr. Di Meo, sir,
we demonstrated
to leave work an hour early.
- But you're an hour late.
- Lt didn't go so well.
Barbero...
go to the blackboard.
What am I supposed to do?
Write anything,
whatever comes to mind.
Go ahead.
I'll be right back.
Copy down what Barbero writes.
I came along
with my father, sir.
Fine, go in.
We never close.
We live so far away.
How's he doing?
What can I say?
Not very well.
He won't apply himself.
But he's no trouble.
He just sleeps.
Don't get me wrong.
He's very smart.
- Yes?
- Good evening.
I'm Professor Giuseppe Sinigaglia.
Attorney Pancani
in Genoa sent me.
- Attorney Pancani?
- Yes, sir.
This letter's for you.
- So there's trouble there too.
- At least for me.
- You'll be staying here a few days.
- Exactly.
After class
I'll see about putting you up.
Nothing deluxe.
- Very kind of you.
DEATH TO THE KING
Barbero, what's that you wrote?
This is what you came up with?
Look, boys,
I share your sentiments,
but you must realize
that becoming educated
is also about acquiring
discipline and self-control!
Let's keep the racket down.
Quiet!
Bardella Carlini here is taking
Pautasso's place on the committee.
Pautasso didn't show up.
Go ahead.
Anyone want to say something?
Shit, I didn't get
a damned word of that.
Such language!
It's Bergamo dialect.
My poor father was from there too.
He suggests that
instead of quitting an hour early,
we all agree to start
an hour later tomorrow morning.
Hey, easy!
Hurray for Pautasso!
All right, that's enough.
Raoul Bertone has the floor.
I wonder if you learned
from yesterday's fiasco.
Think carefully before you try
anything stupid again.
That's enough!
I've got the floor now.
- Why?
Because I'm on the committee,
and you're a dope. End of discussion.
Excuse me.
There's some truth
to what the young man said.
- Who's this guy?
- I don't know.
I am Professor Sinigaglia,
a guest of Mr. Di Meo.
May I speak?
Let's hear what you have to say.
Thank you,
and please forgive the intrusion.
What I wanted to say
is just this:
One should indeed think twice
before inciting any action.
The young man was right
on this point.
Wait, you big ape!
Go on.
There's no doubt
you've accomplished
the most important thing:
Near total unanimity of intention.
And I know how difficult it is
to gather so many workers
outside the workplace.
That's why I thought
it would be a pity to let
such an occasion be wasted
in discussing
a mere hour of work.
Think about it.
I say not just an hour,
but a whole day,
a whole week,
until your bosses realize
they're dealing with men,
not pack animals!
But that would be a strike.
Would it? Perhaps.
That's a strike, all right.
Friends, let's go on strike!
Whoever doesn't join us
is a bastard!
Just a moment, please.
There must be freedom of choice.
If the young man is afraid,
he needn't join.
No one's afraid here, see?
Afraid you'll all shit your pants
when it comes down to it, maybe!
Who is this guy anyway?
I have years of experience in these matters.
It was just a suggestion.
Show of hands for a full strike!
Approved "humanimously,"
except for Raoul Bertone.
I'm with you.
Speak up!
- He said he's with us.
- That's more like it.
Just a moment, please!
May I further suggest
you act with discretion
and not let word get out
until you've laid in
groceries, coal,
as many provisions as possible -
on credit!
Don't pay for any of it!
Just a moment.
Because you must be able
to hold out as long as possible.
Tomorrow, when people
find out you're on strike,
all credit will stop.
They'll slam the door in your face.
You should know that right now.
Today's Sunday,
and the stores close at noon!
Don't breathe a word of this
Or you'll weaken, my blond beauty
I'll take you for a holiday
By the lake or by the sea
Tighten your belt
and don't give an inch
and wave our banner high
Tighten your belt
We'll march by the hundreds
Whoever backs down now
is a traitor
Excuse me, Professor.
I forgot my -
Please.
Adele, how about coming to my place
and cooking us a big dinner?
Take a hike!
You've got me wrong, as usual.
I live alone.
Really? You can always find
that type of girl.
Ask Maria over there.
I see. You're jealous.
I'll tell Maria what you said.
You do that!
Hey, baby doll,
give me a hand.
- What a haul!
- I racked up five lire in credit!
Coming through!
I'll pay you tomorrow.
My hands are full.
Hey, is it true that tomorrow
you're all going on -
Watch it!
Is it true that tomorrow -
Right in my face!
- Outside!
Excuse me.
Evening.
She didn't see me, did she?
I don't want anyone thinking
I'm a streetwalker.
Quick, then.
Come inside and you'll be safe.
To help Italy get better
Italy is ailing
And full of woes
To help Italy get better
Give her all you've got
Scoundrel! Let me out!
- Are you crazy?
- Go to hell!
Who do you think I am?
You and the bearded man are pigs!
- What bearded man?
- Pig!
Damn it all!
Good evening.
- What are you doing here?
- Drying my feet.
Ls this your place? The committee
assigned me to this apartment.
They've kindly
appointed me their adviser,
so I'll have to stay
in town a few days.
You think this is a hotel?
Get your shoes on and scram!
Easy, fruitcake.
It's been decided
and that's that, see?
Not unless
you're paying the rent!
Nice way to talk!
We have to stick together, don't we?
You're the only single person
with a double bed.
- Cesarina here is single too.
- Some gentleman!
- A man like him would do you good!
- Selfish bastard!
Stop this nonsense,
for God's sake!
Professor, I've put your things
here in this hat,
because your basket
fell out in the street.
My toiletry kit!
Everything fell out,
but I picked it all up.
A darning egg, soap -
ls this your soap?
- Yes, thanks.
A sock.
A brush.
Ls this yours too?
- These little tubes.
- That's my piccolo.
What's a piccolo?
A musical instrument
of the early 18th century.
Really?
Imagine that.
And here's your horseshoe,
Professor.
Ls this yours?
- No, not that.
I told you to leave it on the ground.
I carried it all this way!
Wait, we have
to ward off bad luck.
And make sure we get our rights!
And make sure
the manager drops dead!
Now toss it out the window!
You hit someone.
Right on my head,
you shitheads!
Who's this Mustafa!
With all due respect,
I'm reporting for work tomorrow.
Who are you?
A desperate man.
I'm new in town.
I can't get credit,
and I've got a family.
We've all got families.
You northerners don't think much
of us Sicilians, I know.
- You would defy the committee?
- No, sir.
I came for your authorization.
That way
I won't be defying anyone.
What's he ranting about?
If you work,
you'll undermine our solidarity!
Idiot, we all voted!
Then vote again.
But think it over,
because I'm going to work
in any case.
My respects, Professor.
Stop!
Didn't you hear?
This is crazy!
Some people!
If that Ethiopian
goes to work tomorrow,
one by one they'll all go back,
with yours truly first in line!
Stop yammering.
We need concrete suggestions.
If you're serious, you'll give
that Sicilian a good thrashing.
Teach him a lesson.
If you're serious.
Heaven help us.
What a sad world this is.
A poor devil leaves his native village
with his starving family
in search of work.
He finds it.
And what do we do?
We snatch it from him
and leave him
in the darkest despair.
Does that seem right to you?
Let's give him his lesson.
How?
Friends,
unfortunately Raoul is right.
If we indulge in false sentiment now,
it's all over.
You want that, Pautasso?
- I'm Cesarina!
I'm Pautasso, and any scabs
will have to fight me first!
No mercy!
We can't afford mercy.
This is where you live?
Did you expect a royal palace?
Salvatore, what do they want?
Have you come to give me
what I asked for?
Swear you won't work
if we don't authorize it.
Are you gonna authorize it?
Swear first.
I swear, Mr. Pautasso.
All right. Go ahead.
If 13 hours
Don't seem much to you
You try working them
They seem serious, eh?
This is the end of the world.
I've been here 12 years,
and I never expected this
from them.
I'll reduce their hours all right!
What do you plan to do?
- If they don't block entry, nothing.
Some protection you are!
One of them's coming this way.
Hey, you!
Don't you know there's a strike on?
I've got the committee's permission.
Hey, Bedouin!
Stop him!
They're quarreling
amongst themselves.
Good. if one comes to work,
it's a good sign.
- Why's he get special treatment?
- Are we dumber than that Arab?
Let's all go in.
We'll call the others.
Salvatore Arrò
reporting for work, sir.
They can start the machines.
I'm ready.
To work all alone?
What do the others plan to do?
That's secret information
that I don't have.
You're defending those carrion?
They can't be that bad
if they gave me permission
to come to work.
Ah, so they gave you permission?
Yes, sir.
Then you can leave too.
I'm reporting for work,
and I'm not leaving.
Beat it!
Didn't you hear the gentleman?
Don't you dare touch me!
I told you why I'm here, didn't I?
Filthy procurer!
Damned be the blood of Judas
and your kind!
Help! He's got a knife!
He's gonna kill us!
Have you lost your mind?
You'll be sorry for this!
Get him!
- Careful, now!
- Stop him!
- Does the Arrò family live here?
- Yes. Why?
- What's making all that smoke?
- Wet paper.
What is it?
- I'm from the factory.
We took up a collection.
It's not much,
'cause we're on strike.
- Mama!
- What is it?
- They brought money!
- Who?
A boy from the factory.
May the blessed Mother of God
protect your father, the poor sinner!
Greetings, everyone.
Hello.
Carry on, gentlemen.
Be seated.
- I was saying, Uncle -
- Speak up!
We can assume the workers
won't be able
to hold out much longer -
Meanwhile our losses
from unfilled orders are piling up.
Did I say you could smoke?
Everyone helps them: the troops,
social service societies.
But that's charity.
You've been living off
my charity for 20 years!
Wake up, all of you!
If they have friends, so do we -
and ours are more powerful.
We'll cut off their supplies,
block the streets,
until they know
who's calling the tune.
Then they'll be ready to talk.
Now go learn your business,
blockheads!
Enough. Today's a holiday,
and we've talked shop long enough.
Let's join the young people
and enjoy ourselves.
Would you like to come along?
- Very kind of you.
Stop.
No, you're not properly dressed.
Giovanni will see you out.
Good-bye now.
Where's this free coal
you mentioned?
It's my little secret.
Don't worry.
- Is it far?
- Just follow me.
What was your name again?
- Gesummina.
- What kind of name is that?
- It's Jesus's name.
- Jesus was a man.
He wasn't a man or a woman, dummy.
He was above everyone.
You're from those dark lands.
Talk about dark.
The sun never shines here.
There everything is
green, white, and red.
Out of the way, Omero!
Why'd you come up here?
All our troubles here in Piedmont
started when you Sicilians came.
My father says they started in Sicily
when you Piedmontese arrived.
Coal coming over!
Some secret.
Look at all these people.
Ls my old man on the other side?
I don't know.
- Watch out over there!
- Make way!
That's my pop!
That's our stuff, you hear?
I'll give him a hand.
Help me up.
Push!
- You're heavy!
Come on!
Good girl!
Give us a hand!
Want some help?
That wall's high.
You might land on something hard.
Stupid idiot!
Raoul!
Let go.
You're nuts!
You insult me, then call me over,
and then slap me!
You can get lost!
What are you doing over there?
Give me a hand.
Come on, baby doll.
Step lively!
Isn't there a watchman around?
Don't worry.
The professor's chatting with him.
Railway tie coming over!
Watch your noggins!
Why don't you do the same?
You railway employees
are a strong group.
Show your solidarity
with the strikers
and go out on strike yourselves!
You never let
that tongue of yours cool down.
Railway employees can't budge.
If we strike, they send in troops,
and we're jailed as deserters.
So you just sit back and watch.
No one's watching anything.
Your friends are stealing coal,
but I don't see a thing.
Some of you
are getting in line twice.
You better watch out.
I know all your faces.
Next.
What is this, a restaurant?
That's enough, Corporal!
Captain's orders!
The sergeant's a bastard!
Go fuck yourselves!
To hell with soldiers!
I hope you choke
on your god-damned soup!
Miss!
The corporal sent me.
This soup is for you.
Your bowl's inside.
Thank God.
And some bread too.
No, that one's mine.
I already took a bite, see?
How come you're all so skinny?
This strike will be
the death of us.
Typhus killed five people
in my hometown last summer.
A strike isn't a disease!
There's even some left for tomorrow.
Thanks again.
Careful. It's hot.
Good soup!
Thank God for our soldiers.
The professor
would let us all starve.
The professor's a great man.
He gives us advice.
I think he's a swindler -
and a stupid one.
You're the stupid one.
The soup tastes better here
than at the barracks.
Maybe it's the dishes...
or this house.
My house is just like this.
- Imagine that.
The window's open.
The smell will bring them
around like flies.
Too late.
So much for leftovers.
Oh, you're eating.
Pardon me.
Must be hot where you come from.
You're from Naples, right?
No, Abruzzo.
We get snow six feet high.
And wolves too.
- "Wolves" - what's that?
- Plural of "wolf."
That's mine!
Always in other people's pockets!
Who paid for it, and everything else
since you went on strike?
To think we farmers always say
that you factory workers
are the lucky ones.
Got a match?
- Never use 'em.
Like my grandfather.
He chews his cigars.
If you spit, you'll clean it up.
- Got anything to drink?
- Water and vinegar.
Better than nothing.
Nice soft doublets
they give you now.
In my time they felt like nettles.
Very nice.
- You like it?
I'll see if the quartermaster
can get you one.
He's a friend of mine.
I wear a size 12 shoe.
That fellow from Bergamo!
Pautasso!
What the hell are you saying?
Who wants to talk?
The bosses called the committee!
They're giving in!
My regards!
"First: A 13-hour shift,
with an hour for lunch."
Write that down.
"Second:
Repeal the disciplinary action
against Pautasso.
Third: Repeal the fines imposed
on the workers at large, etc.
Fourth, fifth and sixth:
Five minutes' grace time
in the morning, strike pay,
and accident insurance.
Seventh -"
ls something wrong?
How about
coffee and pastries too?
Aren't we going a bit far?
What do you mean?
You think it's too much?
It's not small change.
For God's sake!
Are the bosses
surrendering or not?
It's absolutely unprecedented
in this stronghold of conservatism!
Woe to the vanquished!
Like Brenno, whom history
has deemed an oppressor and yet -
Fine.
You talk and I'll write.
Workers injured on the job -
What?
I should come here in secret
to avoid upsetting
my blockhead of a father?
Don't shout!
I'm shouting so he'll hear me!
For the last time, don't ever
set foot in my house again!
Who do you think you are?
You can croak for all I care.
I came to see Mama, you hear?
Since you're so ashamed of me
in front of these imbeciles.
Yes, I take any man who pays,
and anyone
who's interested can find me
at the Caffè Corsini
on the piazza.
Get out of here!
- Giulio!
- Forget about him!
The bosses are probably waiting.
Excuse my saying this -
No, Cesarina,
family matters are private.
It's just good manners.
- Good manners say ladies go first.
Easy, friends. Don't hurry.
Let the bosses wait.
Come in.
About time.
It's been an hour.
Who's going in first?
Excuse us.
Well?
Come in!
Don't be shy.
Sorry for the short delay.
I was busy.
So...
these are our agitators.
You don't have bombs
in your pockets, do you?
Let's introduce
this distinguished delegation.
This is Martinetti,
and the others are
Porro, Camerone, and -
No need to introduce her!
This is the lovely Cesarina!
Remember when you first came
to the factory in '71?
I'd have liked
to give you a good pinch.
We saw to that ourselves, sir.
And aren't you
the one who likes
the bottle?
Now I see
why they call you people "Reds."
Mind you:
I like that kind of red too.
We're not Reds, sir.
I know.
You're all hard workers.
Doing work that has its compensations,
even if it's a bit hard.
"Man is the only animal
that has to work,"
said that philosopher,
what's-his-name.
Well, I'm one
of those animals too.
But you feel
things would be better
if we were a bit more indulgent.
Gentlemen, shall we rescind
the fines on these rascals?
- If you think so.
- Let's rescind them.
As for our whistle-blower,
we abolish his suspension
and end the whole matter.
Satisfied?
Sir, allow me to speak to you
man-to-man.
We can't go back
to our colleagues
with a mere consolation prize.
Look here.
If you call my offer
a consolation prize,
this becomes
a whole other matter.
I know what's happened.
You've let that vagrant
get you stirred up.
He's a rabble-rouser
and a fugitive from justice!
That's not true, sir.
Look, you whiners,
you know how many
are unemployed around here?
Skilled workers like you,
willing to work this minute,
under worse conditions.
In Saluzzo, 200 factory workers
are out on the street.
I'm willing to let
bygones be bygones,
but I need an answer
by tomorrow.
Otherwise, I too have
interests to look out for.
And the unemployed from Saluzzo
will be on the next train here.
Pautasso!
Come on out here!
The bosses have called in the scabs!
- Scabs?
Where are they?
- They're coming from Saluzzo!
Goddamn it!
Where are you going
in your drawers, you lunkhead?
Fine results you got, you dopes!
He calls himself a leader!
Uncle, did you hear what Pop did?
You should be ashamed!
No!
Where are you going?
Leave that here, you idiot!
Pautasso, we'll stop 'em
at the freight yard!
Go get the professor!
Adele, my jacket!
Cesarina, climb up out of the way.
This could get dangerous.
Dangerous? Why?
We've got to talk to them
and convince them.
They're just like us.
What have you got here?
What's this?
For self-defense.
That hurt, damn it!
"Talk to them"!
We'll see if yakking
changes their minds.
We didn't ask you to come,
Mr. Doomsayer.
Fine. Pretend I'm not here.
Here they come.
Off the tracks!
Out of the way, you bums!
Are you crazy?
Out of the way!
Friends!
Fellow workers from Saluzzo!
We have nothing against you.
Listen to us.
We're the striking workers.
- Who's this lunatic?
Just a moment, please!
Hear me out!
We've been forced
to strike for our rights.
That's why these people
are sacrificing, starving -
We're starving too.
We haven't worked in a month.
I understand.
That's just what the bosses
seek to exploit.
Don't play their game!
So we all starve together?
Who gains from that?
Wait!
Start the train!
They're trying to keep us out!
Where are you going?
Beat it, preacher!
Friends!
Why are you doing this?
Gang up on one guy, will you?
Unhook it, quick!
Get down here, you bastard!
Come down off that train!
Get out of here, you bum!
Take that!
You rat!
Let's discuss this rationally!
Let's talk it over!
No, stop!
Where's the switch?
I'll divert it to the sidetrack.
The express is coming!
Come back, Pautasso!
Pautasso!
Just then,
the express was arriving -
We're from the gas works.
Who do we give this to?
Cesarina's handling the collection.
It's all we could manage.
Thanks all the same.
A drop in the ocean.
After all this, we at the munitions
works better tread cautiously.
I agree.
We probably should never have -
- He's right.
- Who?
Martinetti.
There's been nothing but trouble
since that professor showed up.
And now the workers from Saluzzo
have taken your jobs.
Idiot. You don't
understand anything.
We can hardly get by,
even with the soup from the barracks.
I'm thinking of cutting my hair
for a little money.
- Your hair?
- They pay well for it.
For those fake things
for women's heads.
The word's
on the tip of my tongue.
- And then what?
- What do you mean?
You'll be cute
with your head shaved.
What do you care?
Antonio didn't say anything.
What's he got to do with it?
It's just that...
we're engaged.
- He's not much to look at.
- You don't have to think so.
They're pinning it all on the strikers,
but it's not true.
Are you having a mass
said for him?
There's something
I've tried so often to tell you,
but I always chose
the wrong words...
and now I've chosen
the wrong moment.
Say it anyway.
Gentlemen!
Why all the long faces?
Haven't you seen the paper?
The bosses are taking
a beating over this. Listen.
"Factory manager being held."
- What's that mean?
The scabs are being sent back
to Saluzzo to prevent further incidents.
I told you something
would happen if we held out.
Sure, a man lost his life.
Happy now?
How many more do you want?
What are you doing?
Shove your paper in my face again
and I'll smash your snout in!
Sure, you've got
the muscle for it,
but you got any ideas
in that brain of yours?
That's all you care about -
your stupid ideas.
You're not here to help us.
We're dumb animals with no ideas, eh?
Why should you care about us?
You're being foolish and unfair.
Then tell me the truth.
Can we really pull this off?
Look at me, damn it!
There's only a handful of us.
We're divided and discouraged.
They're powerful, well-connected,
sure of themselves.
So I don't know.
It might even be impossible.
Then you're a lunatic and a scoundrel!
You want to destroy us all?
You expect to win the first time?
That doesn't happen!
That would be too easy.
And you're not the first, you know.
This fight began with Spartacus!
- Who's Spartacus?
I'll tell you some other time.
But you have to hold out
and make them pay
so they know that next time
it'll be even worse.
That in itself would be a victory!
And don't hog the covers!
But we take all the risks, right?
What do you care?
You're not one of us.
You'll vanish one day
just as suddenly as you appeared.
You're right.
I'm not like you.
I have no home, no family,
no friends.
No one's interested in me
except the police.
Then why are you doing this?
Why?
Because I'm full of foolish ideas.
Good boy, Quinterio.
Fagiolini, my regards to your father.
No, Pierino, not you.
This is from grades 1, 2 and 3.
Miss Spirinbergo refused,
of course.
Thank you.
- Di Meo.
- Good morning, sir.
I spoke to you yesterday about
a complaint from the school board,
and I was very civil,
you must admit.
One can be decent
without being a socialist.
Yet despite my explicit order
to the contrary,
you organized
yet another collection.
I'm the assistant principal!
You're a spy!
What are you doing?
- Returning this to the children.
Hands off!
I said hands off!
Teach your pupils
good citizenship - period!
You weren't hired
to engage in subversive activity!
Subversive activity!
It's a simple act of compassion
for a deceased worker.
It's a wonderful lesson
for the children!
Don't shout at me!
We should just keep teaching them
about tyranny and servitude!
Enough!
I'm going to report you!
Fine!
I'll write the report myself,
so it's not full of stupid mistakes!
Pompous ass!
Good morning, sir.
Tell your friends there'll be
no more collections at school.
I'm sorry.
Sir, how's my little brother
here doing?
He's not stupid.
But he doesn't study,
so he's not doing well.
Tell your mother
to keep after him.
You have to study, you hear?
I don't like school!
I want to work
in the factory like you!
You're gonna graduate,
you hear me?
I'll kill you
before I let you do like I did!
Blow.
Lazy bums!
Good-for-nothings!
- What's your excuse?
- Mr. Luigi!
Must I notify you when I'm coming
so you'll be on the job?
- But the strike -
- Am I paying you or not?
Then you have a duty here,
strike or no strike!
That goes for you too!
Go to hell!
Look at these figures.
I did more in half a day
than you do in a month!
In four weeks
we haven't billed a cent.
Our clients are ordering
their goods elsewhere.
Here, read!
The time's come for action!
No more excuses!
We've taken steps
in several directions.
Even the textile union voted to -
I don't care!
These people will stick it out
as long as that meddler's here.
You there - earn your salary.
Notify the police that
the public safety is threatened.
That bum of a professor has a record.
Why don't they arrest him?
Maybe you're right.
No maybes.
Otherwise we'll have to give them
everything they want!
Carlo.
Either we get rid of that professor
or we throw in the towel.
It's just the right temperature.
- Some chicken?
- No, I hate chicken.
But you like me, eh?
Come on. Just a bit.
- Who's that?
- I know that man.
That's not allowed here.
Give me something
for that man.
Two lire!
Who is he - Verdi?
Please leave.
Hey, wait!
Here.
Do you work at the factory?
- No, I'm a professor.
- Professor of -
- No, a high-school professor.
- Then excuse me for giving you -
- Charity?
That's what I was playing for.
Then you're not like
that starving crusader.
Who? I know so many.
He's ashamed of my money.
Says he earns his by honest work.
- Who?
My father.
He says I should work in the spinning mill,
my hands in water 16 hours a day,
and end up in the hospital
like all those other idiots.
So I changed jobs.
Did I harm anyone? Did I?
You did just fine.
You mean it?
Of course.
As you see,
I changed jobs too.
How'd you get messed up
in all this?
- Out of selfishness.
- I don't understand.
Because I like it,
and when you like something,
it's not a sacrifice.
And to ensure that someday
a girl like you...
won't have to make
the choice you had to.
Transferred to Cassino?
I guess I was too much
for the principal.
On the anniversary
of Garibaldi's death, for instance -
Are any of our men there?
I can leave you his address.
Please do.
There's pen and paper there.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
Food for your journey.
No, I'd be taking it
right out of your mouth.
No, not out of mine.
Why do we do all this?
Maybe we're
out of our minds after all.
Professor Sinigaglia?
He's not in.
And who might you be?
Who are you?
Raoul Bertone.
The professor's my guest. Why?
- When's he due back?
- I don't know.
Fine. We'll wait.
- Police?
- Headquarters.
Good Lord!
What's the professor done?
Don't worry.
It's just my darning egg.
Nippy, isn't it?
- There's nothing on it.
- Why'd you throw it away?
- I've got too many papers.
- Don't move!
You there.
Are you Professor Sinigaglia?
- What?
I don't understand.
Who are you?
We're from police headquarters.
Your papers.
Stop!
Good evening.
Why are you dressed
like that in this cold?
I left in a bit of a hurry.
You'll catch bronchitis
in a hurry too.
Please sit down.
- Sit down?
Thank you.
I'm so sorry.
Please, another for the lady.
- Don't bother.
No, please.
I'll have this one.
You're very kind.
Anyway,
bronchitis is better than jail.
I'm innocent, mind you,
but we drive them crazy,
so they hound us.
- Where were you headed?
- Nowhere special.
I didn't want to put
my friends at risk.
Don't you have family?
A wife and two children.
But my wife and I didn't get along -
my fault, to be sure.
I lead a rather chaotic life.
They're better-off
with my father-in-law.
The old owl's rich,
but he's a good type.
And teaching
was a bore anyway.
I should have a picture
of the little devils somewhere.
Of course, they must be
young men by now.
- And this?
- You like it? It's yours.
Ah, here it is.
I'm coming.
I'm afraid...
it's a bit tattered.
- Handsome, aren't they?
- They're good boys.
I'm coming!
My glove.
- Sorry.
Listen, Professor,
go sleep at my place tonight.
Portici Cavour No. 4,
second floor.
No, I couldn't take advantage
of your kindness.
Don't worry about that.
I'll see you later.
Since you're so kind,
would you deliver
a message for me?
Certainly. To whom?
Raoul Bertone.
Via Caval di Ferro No. 18.
Tell him they must hold out,
that we're going to win.
Thank you so much.
Bruna, put it all on my bill.
Very well.
- Who's that?
- A most exceptional character.
Really?
With an exceptional appetite.
Who's there?
Excuse me.
No, excuse me.
Ah, you brought my things.
- I hope it's all there.
I'm sure it is.
A lovely girl named Adele
gave them to me.
Ah, Raoul's girlfriend.
- He's at her house.
- Her house? Why?
They questioned him for hours.
They did, huh? And then?
When they released him,
he decided to relocate too.
Damn! I'm sorry.
The poor fellow.
Did they rough him up?
Not at all.
As for you being hounded,
Professor,
you're also wanted for wounding
a policeman in Genoa.
I know.
But they can't touch me.
It was self-defense.
Just what were you up to?
You asleep in there?
I asked
what you were up to in Genoa.
Sorry.
Genoa, you say?
Nothing really.
I was crossing the piazza
when the police stopped us.
Stopped "us"?
So you weren't alone.
No, there were 300 of us.
There were 300 of you?
Why not just come out
and say it was a demonstration!
Ls that against the law?
All right, all right.
Looks like you'll be
hiding out here a while.
Are you kidding?
I have to set an example.
If I show I'm afraid,
the strike will falter.
It's the factory owners
who are faltering.
Seriously?
I've been told
they'll cave in before you do.
How do you know?
Mr. Baudet is
my girlfriend's client.
Really? Please thank her
for this welcome news
that confirms all my theories,
as I've tried to -
We'll discuss all that tomorrow.
It's late. Good night.
Would you please close the window?
Good night.
If you'll clean up a bit first,
there's room for you here.
I'm coming!
Don't bother, Rosa.
I'll get it.
Good old Martinetti.
How are you?
I thought of having
the shop fix my old stove,
but then I remembered
that you fixed it for me once.
And you'll do
a better job anyway.
Come on in.
There's the old piece of junk.
I'd appreciate it if the others
didn't hear about this, sir.
Why should they care?
The strike is the bosses' affair.
I'm on salary like you.
Go on.
Rosa, two cups of coffee.
So...
how are things going, Martinetti?
You know,
after this long strike...
maybe it's time
to take stock, eh?
Let's not discuss that, please.
I only came for the money,
for my wife's sake.
- What's wrong with her?
- She's pregnant.
She has kidney trouble,
a high fever, and other stuff.
She should be in the hospital.
- Really?
Much more of this
and we'll all end up there.
Your stove is fine.
Look, I know Professor Spaziani
at the gynecological clinic.
I could talk to him.
- Thank you.
I'm your friend.
You know that.
Then couldn't you help us
with the bosses?
Convince them
to give in just a little.
Maybe I shouldn't say this,
but we can't hold out much longer.
Set that here.
No, no, run along.
Make yourself comfortable.
It's too bad,
but the bosses
can hold out for years.
Just last night the old man
told me he'll never give in.
It's a matter of principle with him.
Besides, you've shown
your strength now.
So take a tip from me
and play it smart.
Give in first to show you're coming
from a position of strength.
They'll show their appreciation.
Striking for 31 days
is already something.
We've shown the bosses
we have the upper hand.
Now that they know that,
we should play it smart
and make the first move,
because it's a matter
of principle with them.
They can hold out for years.
So you're saying
we should back down?
Back down?
I'm just saying that,
for better or worse...
since we're still united,
we can go back
with heads held high and -
ls it true
there's a general meeting later?
That's what we decided.
To decide whether
to go back to work.
You didn't consult
with the professor?
The professor!
We're not married to the man.
We've listened to him for weeks.
Friends, you know me.
I was the first to act
while you were all still asleep,
and now I say
let's go back to work.
They're not monsters.
They have families too.
They have wives and children.
Tell me: Did they pay you
to spout this crap?
Raoul, no insults here.
You can speak your piece
at the meeting.
Omero!
Professor!
It's Omero!
What is it?
Raoul says to come quickly!
They want to go back to work!
Goddamn it!
What's going on?
What are you doing?
- I have to go.
- They'll arrest you!
They'll arrest you!
- Probably. In fact, almost certainly.
I have to go.
Just like that?
Without a word?
Don't ever come back!
Look at that oaf!
I don't ever want to see him again,
dead or alive!
Scoundrel!
You'll end up
in the hospital, not jail!
At least put this on,
you stubborn fool!
Looks to me like the majority
want to go back to work.
Let's take a count.
- Can't you see?
- A count?
What's to count?
Isn't it obvious?
It's an important decision.
I want a count.
All right.
We'll do it the other way.
Hands down.
Those in favor of continuing
the strike, hands up.
Satisfied?
Count them.
Forgive me.
In my rush I forgot my glasses.
But even if
I can't see you clearly,
I know all the same who voted
to keep up the fight.
Barbero?
Yes, Professor.
Now and forever!
Good. I knew it.
Gallesio!
I won't back down!
Bardella.
Isn't Bardella here?
I'm right here.
So you've joined the others too.
Bunch of lily-livers!
Please, friends.
No, they're not
a bunch of lily-livers.
They're the majority,
and the majority
is the voice of wisdom.
You're the crazy ones -
you, Barbero, and you!
You who think 13 hours a day
on the job is enough.
You who'd like
a few extra pennies.
You who'd like to avoid
the hospital or the poorhouse.
The majority are the wise ones.
They feel their salary is enough.
The proof: No one has actually
died of starvation yet.
And statistics show
that only 20%% of you
are maimed in accidents.
How many are here?
Five hundred?
Then only 100 of you
will end up crippled.
You, Baietto, or you, Occhipinti,
or your daughter Gasperina.
Mondino, where are you?
- Right here.
Show them!
That's what the majority wants!
No! We've starved for 30 days now.
We've lost! Can't you see?
- Who says so?
- Everyone!
Friends, it's not true.
We haven't lost.
This is the crucial moment.
The side holding out
just one hour longer wins!
The bosses are even worse-off!
- How do you know?
- I know! You must believe me!
- No more blind faith!
- Our cupboards are empty!
- And our stomachs too!
Your stomachs will stay empty,
and your children's too,
if you give up this fight now!
The bosses will always win,
and your misery
will continue to enrich them!
It's not our factory!
Not yours?
Who works there
14 hours a day their whole life?
Whose sweat keeps
the machines going?
Ours!
Then take it!
The factory is yours!
Show them it means more to you
than your own homes!
Make the bosses, the city,
and the government see
that it's your life and death!
Go, my friends!
Got it bad, eh?
Seeing her again?
They're good people.
Attention! Present arms!
All officers are to report immediately.
Sound the call.
That's us!
All leaves are canceled!
Fall in, quickly!
Dress quickly! Look lively!
All leaves are canceled!
WE'RE NOT ANIMALS!
WE WANT A 13-HOUR DAY!
Company halt!
Captain, what should we do?
Clear the square.
Line up
in front of the factory, men!
Company forward!
Halt!
Dismount!
In rank, forward march!
Give me a piece.
What are we doing here?
I don't really know...
but I smell trouble.
Here they come!
Ready.
Company, ready!
Cowards!
Criminals!
- Bastards!
- Exploiters of the people!
You're on the bosses' side!
Let us through!
We want to enter the factory!
The factory is ours!
Come here, you!
Raoul!
Get ready, and stay calm.
They've got you
in their sights! Beat it!
Disperse!
Stop!
Murderers!
Captain, what do we do?
Get back or we open fire!
Take aim and prepare to fire!
Fire!
Omero!
Where are you going?
Are you crazy?
- Where are you going?
- Let me go!
It's your fault! Goddamn you!
You killed him!
I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
Let me go!
Hello, Adele.
I couldn't go to your place.
The police are still standing guard.
I collected a few things
from our friends.
- And the professor?
- Still in jail.
But we're making him
a candidate in upcoming elections.
If he's elected,
they'll have to let him go.
Cenerone and Cesarina
are going door-to-door for him.
Good idea.
He sent you this.
A friend's address in Lugano.
Amazing.
He doesn't give up.
Even in jail
he's thinking of others.
The train.
Write to me!
What?
But you can't read!
Write anyway!