Our town's boardwalk.
Our last summer party:
The election of Miss Mermaid 1953.
Nice crowd, no?
Visitors, tourists,
and a Roman actress as judge.
Everybody's here.
And, of course, we're here too...
the guys...
This is Alberto.
This is Leopoldo, the intellectual.
And here's Moraldo,
the youngest in our crowd.
Look at the lightning.
It's beautiful.
The tenor's Riccardo. As always,
this is pretty much his night.
And here's Fausto,
our leader and spiritual guide.
Do you believe me now?
Do you think I'm that stupid?
Give me my shoe.
I will, but give me a kiss.
- Let go.
- Give me a kiss.
I said let go.
- Don't be so coy.
- Let me go, you jerk!
The nerve!
Listen, you goose,
you promised me...
- Promised you what?
- That before you left...
You're so gullible.
People promise a lot of things.
Think what you promised Sandra.
- Sandra who? You're hallucinating.
So now you don't even know her?
That's rich.
With four of five votes,
Miss Mermaid 1953 is
Miss Sandra Rubini.
My little girl! Just think,
you didn't even want to enter.
Your little sister won!
Go, dear, go.
Miss Mermaid 1953!
She's really excited.
Ladies and gentlemen,
here from Rome is film star Lilia Landi.
She will now place the sash
of Miss Mermaid 1953
on our very own beauty queen.
Party's over.
A few words for the fans.
- I...
- Wonderful! She said "I"!
Look! It's lightning!
- I didn't want to compete...
- It's just a passing shower.
The party'll continue.
It's just a little...
The check, Mr. Alberto.
- Everyone's leaving.
- At least pay your share.
- Introduce me to Lilia Landi.
- Not right now!
There she is. Please.
Miss Landi, meet one of
our most esteemed citizens,
playwright Leopoldo Vannucci.
- Delighted.
Most honored.
I've followed your career closely.
He's also our resident poet.
It's beautiful outside,
like the end of the world.
Congratulations, Sandra,
Mrs. Rubini.
Now you'll be in the movies.
I want you to meet my little girl.
My God! Moraldo!
- What's wrong, Mama?
- Come here! Your sister's sick!
- Excuse me, please.
- Get a doctor, quickly!
Mama, calm down. It's nothing.
Is there a doctor around?
Yeah... Mancinelli!
Here I am. What's happened?
Step aside! Let me by!
Doctor, my little girl...
Here I am. What's happened?
Get out of the way!
Let me through!
It's nothing!
She just needs some air.
- Look at poor Sandra!
- It's nothing, Mama. Calm down.
- Fausto! Leopoldo, call Fausto!
- Fausto!
Come here!
- Calm down, Mama. It's nothing,
- Nothing? Look at her!
Let me through.
- What happened?
- Sandra fainted.
Is she better?
- Mama.
- Darling!
What's wrong?
I want to die!
What? You want to die,
now that you're Miss Mermaid?
Don't say that, even as a joke!
Doctor, what's wrong with her?
Answer me.
All right, everyone out!
Back already?
That's why it's raining.
What are you up to?
Papa, I gotta leave now,
on business.
Remember that job offer
from Milan?
Well, I've thought about it,
and I'm going to take it.
At this hour?
What have you done now?
Nothing. I'm taking a job.
Aren't you satisfied?
What sort of job?
With a company.
They're reliable people.
By the way, can you lend me
5,000 lire for the train?
I'll pay you back
when I get there.
You punk. What did you do?
What did you do?
Nothing. I just got a job.
Don't you believe me?
I'm catching the 1:00 train.
I'll see who it is.
Hello, Mr. Francesco.
How are you?
Hi, Moraldo. Come in.
Come on in.
Sit down.
Excuse us, Papa. Okay?
Some downpour, no?
Summer's over - too bad.
Cigarette?
- You only have one left.
- Never mind. I don't want it.
It'll rain for days.
Depressing, huh?
- So you're going?
- Yeah, I'm splitting.
- Will you be gone long?
- I don't know... depends.
And Sandra?
She's Miss Mermaid now.
She must be happy.
Sandra's expecting.
Yeah, I know.
That's why I'm splitting.
I'd like to do the right thing,
but how can I?
I'm broke, like you.
That's why I'm going to Milan.
I wanna do something with my life.
Just till I get on my feet.
Don't you believe me?
I didn't say a word.
Look, we understand each other.
I really love Sandra.
I'll swear by whatever you want,
by my own mother. I really love her.
It was fate.
Be honest. In my shoes, wouldn't you
first try to make it on your own?
- I don't know.
- You're hopeless.
Why not go with me?
We'll go together.
This town's dead in winter.
If not Milan, we'll go somewhere else.
We've always wanted to leave.
- Right now?
- This is our big chance!
And Sandra will be thrilled,
you'll see.
Let's go and talk outside.
Be quiet. Don't make any noise.
- But I...
- Come on!
Turn off the light.
Papa! Excuse me, Moraldo.
Can I have that 5,000 lire?
What do you want it for?
To run out?
- No, Papa.
You get in trouble and you run.
I'll wring your neck.
- Papa, please...
- Shut up! Come here!
What are you gonna do, Papa?
I swear I'll...
Get out of my way!
You little weasel!
I swear by your poor mother
that your foul escapades are over!
That girl's father is a decent guy.
Worked all his life, like me,
idiot that I am,
to support his family honestly.
You'll marry her, if I have to kick
your ass all the way to the church.
You bastard!
What's going on, Papa?
Nothing.
Go back to bed.
You will marry her.
I'll make sure of that.
Hey, Fausto.
Go ahead, laugh, idiots.
My father's crying.
So they got married.
It was a lovely wedding,
even if a bit hastily arranged.
Riccardo sang Ave Maria
and made us all cry.
And the parish priest,
who'd known us forever,
gave a very moving speech.
My children...
you can't imagine
what a joy it is for me
to join you in holy matrimony.
You, dear Fausto...
and you, dear Sandra.
See? Quick and painless.
Good for you.
See, Papa?
I'm a married man now.
My little girl.
Hold it. Stand together.
Alberto, you're standing
in front of the bride.
Don't quarrel!
Be careful crossing
the streets in Rome!
What are you crying for?
- Riccardo.
- I'm coming.
- Where to now?
- Let's go to Marina.
Good-bye, Francesco.
Thanks, Mr. Rubini.
You'll see.
Fausto's not really a bad kid.
I know.
This must be your little girl.
Your youngest?
Yes, she's an angel.
Of course,
Fausto will live with us
until he can support himself
and his wife.
Good day.
Why does she treat him like that?
Take us home.
Can we buy you a drink,
Mr. Francesco?
No, thank you, Riccardo.
I'm going home.
- Nine and two... that's 11.
- 11 to 20.
You think you won?
Leopoldo, mark two points
for me, please.
Leopoldo, why the long face?
I'm depressed.
What's the big deal?
Just 'cause those two left...
- I wonder if they're in Rome yet.
- What a drag!
You gotta know your way
around Rome to have any real fun.
If he'd gone with me,
it'd be a different story.
A couple of phone calls
and we could have had a ball.
And what about Sandra?
I meant if we were single.
If I went on a honeymoon,
I'd go to Africa, like Hemingway.
Free, in the wild, in a Jeep.
Sounds fabulous.
Africa would be a real escape.
I'd go there with Esther Williams.
- What about Franca Marzi?
Franca Marzi, Ginger Rogers.
Oh, I know!
Remember the surveyor's girlfriend?
The one who burned her shoulder.
- The Ciuffini girl.
- Yeah, Africa with her!
I'd prefer India.
Antonio.
Come on, I called you.
You're always in the way.
What do you want?
You can talk all you like,
but he's in Rome and we're stuck
in this dirty little rat hole.
They make a nice couple, though.
Nice couple?
She's a pretty girl,
but not Fausto, with that face!
He's tall and well built.
- And he has a decent voice.
- Big deal.
We all have voices.
Didn't you have any inkling
about Fausto and your sister?
To be straight about it,
Fausto was a real cad.
He's a scoundrel.
- I wouldn't go that far.
He's a passionate creature,
driven by animal instincts.
What are you talking about?
You think you're writing a play?
Fausto's just a horny...
It's as if one of you went with my sister.
Now there's an idea!
Alberto, leave her alone.
Bastards, you oughta be in bed!
What's left for us to do?
Another day has come to an end.
Nothing to do but go home, as usual.
Alberto lives
with his mama and sister,
and he knows that
Mama waits up until he gets in.
Alberto's home.
Riccardo, as usual,
stares at his growing gut.
Helluva time to walk in,
you little punk!
'Night, Papa. 'Night, Mama.
After eating the meal
his aunts have left for him,
Leopoldo prepares to work
on his new play.
He puts on his favorite
record, Fly the Night
and sits at his table.
Removing the cap of his pen,
he draws a triangle
and watches his characters
parade across the ceiling.
Caterina.
She's the neighbors' maid.
Hi, Caterina. How's it going?
Not so good.
It's too cold out.
How are you doing?
- Okay. I'm working.
Really?
What a lovely moon!
- As lovely as you.
- Liar!
Why do you always play that song?
It inspires me.
Just like every other night,
only Moraldo walks the empty streets.
What if I left too?
Where are you off to?
It's 3:00 a.m.
Aren't you gonna sleep?
Sleep? I just got up.
I always get up at 3:00.
- Why?
- I go to work.
Work?
At the station.
Sit down a minute.
What do you do?
What kinda work?
I just told you: I work.
- Is this a railroad cap?
- Yeah.
Tell me, are you happy?
It's okay.
- Want a smoke?
- Sure.
I had one here...
Sorry, I'm out.
- Never mind. I gotta go.
Listen...
- How's the helmet?
- Okay, it fits fine.
- Will it fly?
- Sooner than my enemies think.
So it does fly! Invite me,
and I'll bring a spoon to celebrate.
Olga.
Come out here for a moment.
Do me a favor. I'll pay you back
on Sunday. I'm closing a deal.
Lend me 1,000 lire.
- So you'll pay me back?
- Yeah.
You worked all night?
They should give you a raise.
I'll have a word with the boss.
- I only have 500.
- That's okay.
Thanks, Olga. See you.
Massimo and Leopoldo are off
to Bologna for the trotters.
I've got an inside tip.
Let's get a bet down.
A thousand would cover it.
I've got 300 - how about you?
Now, even on Sundays,
the beach is deserted,
Still, we'd stare out to sea.
If you were offered 10,000 lire,
would you go in?
I would.
Let's go.
Let's go and watch Giudizio fish.
Come on, Riccardo.
You know who Leopoldo looks like?
The priest!
Please don't tell Mama you saw me.
You said it was over with him.
Listen.
Let me go!
Quit staring, guys.
Come on,
let's go watch Giudizio fish.
Hi, Alberto.
- Look...
- We keep bumping into each other.
You're making me look like a jerk
in front of my friends.
Your friends mocking other people?
That's rich.
Ya gotta break up with that jerk!
What can you expect from him?
Nothing.
I don't expect anything.
- He's got a wife!
- Stop yelling! Mama's sleeping.
- He's married!
I know, but they're separated.
So what?
Is he gonna marry you?
- Butt out, Alberto!
I can take care of myself.
I know what I should do.
- You work so you can do as you please?
- Yes.
No, you can't!
You're my sister!
Get your hands off me!
If you make Mama cry...
Get outta here, Alberto!
If you make Mama cry, I'll...
Then, one day, when we'd just
about forgotten about him...
Hey, guys!
It's Massimo.
- Guys! Fausto's back in town.
- He's really back?
- Yeah, and he's got a mustache!
- Where is he?
There he is!
- Hey, boys!
- Fausto, how's it going?
- How are you?
- Just great, thanks.
Hi, Alberto! We've been looking
for you for an hour.
Come over here, guys.
I've got something amazing to show you.
- What's that?
- It's a gramophone.
We saw Wanda Osiris.
- She was wonderful.
Sure, it was a nice show,
but let's not go overboard.
She came down this long staircase...
Quiet, quiet.
Just listen to this mambo.
There was a guy who danced like this.
- Teach me. Is it hard?
- Just follow me.
- Nice, isn't it?
- Are you happy?
Yes, very happy.
Things would've gone on as usual
if Fausto's father-in-law
hadn't come up with a crazy idea.
- Praise our Lord Jesus Christ.
- Forever and ever.
My good friend,
you get younger by the day.
How are you?
This must be your son-in-law.
Pleased to meet you.
Belated congratulations!
You're a lucky man.
Very lucky.
What's your name?
- Fausto Moretti.
Let me be absolutely candid.
This here is my establishment.
Somewhat small, perhaps...
You call this small?
Built through hard work.
Frankly, what I really need
is someone with experience:
A delivery man, handyman, stock boy.
Someone who can open
in the morning and close at night.
But I'd really prefer
to take you on instead.
- Thank the gentleman, Fausto.
- Thank you.
Don't mention it.
I'm pleased to give
a young man a start in life.
Feel right at home.
When can you start?
- Right now!
- Now?
Sure, you can start
learning the ropes.
Giulia, this is Sandra's husband.
He'll be working here now.
- Hello. The truck is here.
- I'll be right there.
Shouldn't he get one of these?
A work coat? I have an extra
he can use right over here.
- Just to keep the dust off.
- Here we are.
Wait, Giulia.
Try it on.
Mama'll make one just for you.
Something wrong?
It's just been cleaned.
Button up and tie the belt.
Looks like it was tailor-made for him.
Very nice.
Now, young man, you start work.
There are crates to unload.
Get the shipping log from my wife.
And keep an eye on the men
or they'll break everything.
It's fragile stuff. Get going.
- There he is.
- What's he doing?
Come on, leave him alone.
He'll lose his job.
How are you? Welcome back.
- You look great.
- What a pretty hat.
- You just got back?
- Yesterday.
- How's married life?
- Where's Fausto?
- He's got a job.
- He's working?
Yes, I'm on my way to meet him.
You're wise to keep an eye on him.
Why? Fausto's a good boy.
He's just a little fickle.
Do you like your new place?
We're staying with Mama for now.
Of course, you had so little time.
Everything was so rushed.
You're hardly showing at all.
It's still a long way off, isn't it?
- Sorry, I've got to run. Bye.
- Bye, dear.
Let's get together,
and bring Fausto too.
- I came to get you.
- Terrific!
Watch this.
How's that?
- Bravo!
Fausto, not in public!
What's the big deal?
We're married.
Guess what.
Today I sold a statue this tall.
- Really?
- Yes.
I'm so proud of you.
And now let's go to the movies.
- Great!
- We have enough to get in?
Yes, I've got it right here.
That's my baby.
There's a couple of seats over there.
Is this okay?
Can you see?
- What a nice refrigerator.
- Soon we'll get one too.
How adorable.
Looking for your cigarettes?
Thanks. I've got matches.
Know what?
Papa really likes you.
This morning Mama told me
Papa is planning
an addition to the house.
But it's to be a surprise.
- Got it.
A light, please.
Thanks.
My pleasure.
- So we can live together.
- What?
So we can live together.
Sure.
- Don't believe him, my dear.
- You mean I should trust you?
I knew he found me irritating.
- Terrific, aren't they?
- Yeah, really good.
Excuse me for a minute.
Be right back. Hold my seat.
- You feeling okay?
- I'm fine. I'll be right back.
Ma'am.
Pardon me.
Good evening, ma'am.
When will I see you again?
- What do you want?
- Your phone number.
- My number? Get lost.
Wait, don't shut the door.
I must talk to you.
- Are you out of your mind?
- I recognize you from the boardwalk.
This summer you wore
that white bathing suit.
So what?
I recognize you too.
You were with a young lady
at the movie theater.
Not me! When can I see you again?
Get out of here.
I'm a married woman.
My maid is upstairs.
Let me see you.
Tomorrow night?
No. Never.
Day after tomorrow?
Then when?
- Whenever we meet again.
Let's leave it to fate.
Good-bye.
Please, don't go yet.
I must speak with you.
Come back. Listen.
I've got to speak with you.
- Go away!
- Sandra, what are you doing here?
- Where were you?
I had promised to see a guy off
at the train station.
Am I late? Is the movie over?
Too bad.
How'd it end? Did she die?
- No, she didn't.
- So what happened?
- They got married.
What a fine actress. We saw her
in that movie when we were in Rome.
What was the name of that picture?
Sandra, are you crying?
Yes, you are. What's wrong?
I'm scared.
Scared? Of what?
I don't know.
I'm just scared, Fausto.
I'm sorry.
Don't, Sandrina.
Don't worry. I'm being silly.
I just feel very sad.
Sandra, there's no reason.
I love you very much.
Let me hold your little hand.
I feel better now, darling.
I can't stand to see you cry.
I won't cry anymore.
Just be near me.
I'll always be near you.
- Let's go home.
- Yes, let's.
In the months that followed,
the most important events were
Riccardo's mustache - just like Fausto's -
and Alberto's sideburns.
Fausto had, by now,
shaved his mustache.
Occasionally his father and sister
would pass by the shop
to see him at work.
Leopoldo worked as usual.
He, in turn, cultivated a goatee.
It's scary.
I thought you'd like it.
And, at last, the eagerly awaited
carnival season.
It'll be better this year.
People seem anxious to celebrate.
Add a beauty mark on the other side.
- Nah, one's enough.
Is my dress ready?
- Yes.
Now leave me alone or your mother
will kill me. I have to do the sheets.
- I need bigger breasts.
- I padded it in front.
Look what he's done to himself,
such a good-looking boy.
- So, you're sweet on Alberto?
- What a mouth.
- Alberto, she's in love with you.
- Yeah, even Mama's noticed.
- Is she really loaded?
- Why, do you want to marry her?
Elvira, my hat.
I don't have your hat.
So who's got it?
Hold this. Mama.
You're still here?
I'm ready to go now.
I'm not going.
Then let me have your hat.
Come on.
- You know I don't wear hats.
What am I gonna do?
It's just not fair. When you wanna
have a good time, no one helps.
Look in the trunk. You'll find something,
but don't make a mess.
What's up? Why's she crying?
What's wrong?
- Nothing. Just a slight headache.
You and I are gonna have it out.
Alberto, come and look.
This chest is full of stuff.
Don't mess things up.
Your mother will have a fit.
Riccardo, I'm sure these are
the right moves. Watch me.
Who's this bearded guy?
That's my poor old man.
Leopoldo, look at these pictures.
Here's the hat.
Look what I found.
- They're hilarious.
- Who is that?
- I don't have a clue.
What a kook!
Look at me.
Look at Alberto!
Wanna dance?
- Yes, dear.
- Mama, we're gonna dance.
- Don't exert yourself.
Ever been up to the rafters
in this theater?
No, and I have no desire to.
Leopoldo, wait for me!
What a coincidence -
we're both Chinese.
I love you so much.
And I love you too.
- Why're you squeezing me?
- That's the Chinese way.
- I'm going to get a drink.
- The bar's that way.
I'll bet that one day you'll come here
to see one of my plays.
I like variety shows.
- What'll you have to drink?
- An orangeade.
- Antonio, an orangeade.
- An orangeade, right away!
Ever been up to the rafters
in this theater?
- Recognize me?
- Of course I do!
Here alone?
- No, with some girlfriends.
Your costume is cute.
- Excuse me.
- Of course.
I made a last-minute decision
to come.
We'll have a dance later.
- Sure.
Gisella, wait!
Who's he?
A great writer.
He's my neighbor, you know.
Whiskey, darling?
Whiskey? I want a sandwich.
A large one.
Antonio, a sandwich.
Here, ma'am, just made.
Isn't this fun?
A glass of milk.
- Right away, sir.
Why the ham sandwich?
- Because it's good.
- You're always eating.
- I'm hungry.
- It doesn't look good!
What a nice nose!
May I dance with my sister?
Go right ahead.
Lose the sandwich!
Come on.
I'm going to show her the rafters.
I'm starving.
- Cognac, Giulia?
- No, no. I'm feeling dizzy already.
Good evening.
Having fun?
- Lots. Aren't you?
Yeah.
Listen, they're playing
the Sioux Mambo.
- Yes, it's a beautiful song.
- May I?
Actually, I'm not alone.
- Giulia, listen.
- Good evening, sir.
Why don't we go over
to the other spread?
Excuse me.
Two orangeades, Antonio.
Why that face?
- Did you see Michele's wife?
- No, who?
My boss's wife. She's really classy.
Put it on my tab, Antonio.
I don't think you've got it right.
A master like me?
- What are you staring at?
- Nothing.
Where are you taking me?
- Look, it's breathtaking.
- I'm getting dizzy.
- Then don't look down.
- Now what?
Nothing.
Tomorrow we'll go for a drive.
- I'm not going.
- Of course you are.
One more kiss on that lovely neck.
Please.
You're so annoying.
Stop, stop now.
Get out of here
with that damn trumpet!
Come with me, sweet little head.
Anita, come on.
Let's go to Mass.
Why won't you believe me?
Alberto, what's wrong?
Feeling sick?
I'm okay.
- Come on, I'll take you home.
- I'm okay.
Get out of here.
- Moraldo.
I'm taking you home.
Go to Peking, why don't you.
- Moraldo, leave him alone.
- I can't. He's a friend.
Come on.
- Let go, I'm okay.
- Hey, let's go swimming.
- Yeah, but home first.
- Okay, home first.
- And then we go swimming.
- Then we go swimming.
- We'll all go together.
- Who the hell are you? Who?
- It's me, Moraldo.
No, you're nobody.
You're all nobodies.
What do you think you're doing?
- Nothing, nothing.
- You make me puke. Let me go.
But Alberto, if I let you go...
Let me go.
I wanna go by myself.
- Alberto, you'll get hurt.
- I want to go alone. I'll be okay.
You're nothing.
- Alberto, look out, you'll fall.
- You make me puke.
- Moraldo, please, let's go.
- I can't just leave him.
May I come along now?
- Yeah, sure.
Come on, come on.
What do you want with me?
- Nothing. Just keep walking.
Moraldo, know what?
We gotta get married.
- Yes.
You see Fausto?
He settled down.
He's happy.
He has a house.
We just gotta get ourselves wives.
Hey, Alberto!
You gotta get married, Riccardo.
You just gotta.
Okay, bye.
See, I told him too.
You know what we'll do instead?
We'll go to Brazil.
We'll take her along.
Yeah, right.
Brazil... by boat.
Yeah, but first we go home.
You gonna leave me here?
I can't just leave him.
You come too.
Alberto, you're home.
Do you want me to take you in?
I don't wanna go home.
What's there for me?
I've been waiting for you.
I wanted to say good-bye.
I'm leaving, Alberto. Forgive me.
I just couldn't take it anymore.
Take care of Mama.
I'll always think of you.
Good-bye.
Bye, Alberto.
Try to be sensible, Alberto.
Olga, where are you going?
Where's she going?
Mama, what's going on?
You can see. She's gone.
How can my own daughter
do this to me?
After all I've sacrificed for her.
Don't cry, Mama.
I'll stay. I'll always be here.
You'll see, she'll change her mind
and come home. If not, better yet.
For the few pennies she gave us.
Good riddance!
I'll get a job.
- Really, Alberto? You will?
- Of course.
Have you found something?
- Good morning.
- See what that lady wants.
- What lady?
- That lady. Over there.
Hello. May I help you?
Two candles,
the kind I bought last year.
I wasn't here last year.
She wants the same candles
she bought last year.
So get them for her.
They're in the stockroom.
Sir.
Excuse me.
Did you enjoy yourself last night?
Try to get here earlier.
It's 11:00. We open at 9:00.
My friend's sister ran away.
Someone runs away every night.
You always have an excuse.
- And I have a toothache.
- Get to work.
Giulia, see what's happened
back there.
I apologize.
Look at the craftsmanship.
- What happened?
- They fell.
Please, I'll take care of it.
I'm sorry.
- Well?
- Just paying you back.
Carnival is over.
You should always wear
what you did last night.
Hand me the receipts in that drawer.
Which drawer?
That drawer under the counter.
- The receipts you requested.
- Thank you.
What are you doing?
I got no sleep last night.
I waltzed with you
in my dreams, all night long.
- Put away these books, please.
- Give me a hand.
Never mind. I'll do it myself.
How passionate! Last night
I realized you're a real woman.
You must be drunk!
Yes, drunk with you,
your flesh, your scent.
Enough! Stop this right now!
You trying to tell me
you don't like it?
Please keep quiet about this.
It's sunny, but quite chilly.
Hello. Do you have
some angel ornaments?
- Good night, sir. I'll go out this way.
- Wait a minute.
Why not come up
and have a drink with us?
Today's our anniversary.
Fifteen years.
Congratulations,
but I wouldn't want to intrude.
On the contrary.
We'd love it.
If I'd known, I would've brought
flowers or something.
Nonsense.
We live upstairs.
It's very convenient.
After you.
- Thank you.
Allow me.
Come right in.
Giulia, please bring
some vermouth.
Giulia, the vermouth.
- Yes, Michele.
Have a seat.
- It's lovely.
- You like it?
- Really lovely.
- Modest, but we like it.
I'm about to get our place set up.
- Is that so?
- Is that a real antique?
Yes. Here's the vermouth.
Evening, ma'am. Congratulations.
I hear it's your...
Thank you. I've got to finish.
Go ahead, dear.
Go ahead.
My wife's a good woman, no?
Yes, very good, and...
And what?
A good woman.
Ah, yes.
We're not so young,
but we still get along well.
Since we have few friends,
we spend most evenings
in this room.
Sometimes we play cards.
That probably sounds dull
to you, no?
You'll find it amusing
that we play cards.
Sometimes I read
while my wife knits.
But we're not bored,
and do you know why?
Because we really
love each other.
But you wouldn't understand.
Of course I understand.
No, you don't.
- But I really do.
- No, you don't.
I really pity you.
And I pity your poor wife even more.
- What do you mean?
- What do I mean?
This.
Here's your month salary.
Make up an excuse for your family.
Say you didn't like it. Too much work.
Give them any excuse.
You're really good at that.
But why are you firing me?
So you'll learn to live right.
I treated you like a brother
and you acted like a cad!
Now get out of here,
before I wring your neck.
I never expected this from you.
No, leave her out of this.
Giulia, Fausto's going.
He won't be working for us any longer.
He just quit.
So I shouldn't come in tomorrow?
Good evening.
I was only kidding around, ma'am.
I lost my job
because of that silly woman,
my boss's wife.
Who's that?
She came on to me, but out of respect
for Michele, I turned her down.
She's an old lady. How could I go
for her? So she bad-mouthed me.
And today he made up
some excuse to fire me.
- What excuse?
- Huh?
He just can't do that.
It's way too easy.
Oh, he can and did. He said,
"Tell your family anything you like.
Find any excuse at all."
That's unfair. You shouldn't have left.
And no severance at all, nothing?
He should have given you notice -
a month at least.
No, no notice.
A month at least. He can't just
cheat you out of 30,000 lire.
One can't just do that today.
You work. You've got a job.
That was refreshing.
Not drinking?
Aren't you thirsty?
Moraldo, can you keep a secret?
I don't know. Why?
My boss should've
given me notice, right?
So I'm gonna get what's mine,
and we'll split it.
I don't understand.
Would you be up
to pulling off a job?
- A job?
- You know.
- No. What do I have to do?
- Are you chicken?
- No.
- Then let's go.
Follow me.
- Quiet.
- No, out of the way.
Where the hell are we?
- Quiet.
In the courtyard.
Be careful. We don't want
to burn down the house.
- Where are you?
- Over here.
What's that?
Beautiful, isn't it?
- What is it?
- An angel.
Now we've gotta get it out.
You know how much it's worth?
40,000 lire. I saw the bill.
And you're stealing it?
Let's split, Fausto.
It's not theft. It was unpacked
and got left here. It's been two months.
No one's noticed.
And you said I should've gotten notice.
So we'll take this instead.
But it's wrong.
Listen, Moraldo,
I have a family now. I need this.
I've got a lot of things
to take care of.
If you're scared, I'll go it alone.
At least give me some light here.
Look how beautiful.
Beautiful.
- Tell him to be quiet.
- Giudizio, cut it out!
Good morning, Sister.
Is Mother Superior in?
Why?
I'd like to discuss some business
I think she'd find in her interest.
What is it?
Mother Superior's in chapel now.
Let's go.
No, Moraldo, wait.
Let's show her.
Show her.
An angel, solid wood. It's been
in our house, but we're forced to sell.
The Ursuline Convent
could have it for a reasonable price.
Just look at that expression.
Beautiful angel, beautiful angel!
Don't be afraid.
He's harmless.
We already have
enough angels. Sorry.
Sister, listen.
A brother, way up!
What do you want?
How are you today?
Would you like a cigarette?
Wait a moment. Here, catch.
Terrific.
It's lovely here. This is the life.
What's your name?
- Father Felice.
- Is the Father Superior in?
No.
- So who's in charge in his absence?
- I am.
Wonderful. We have
a real bargain for you.
A magnificent statue.
Colorful, perfect for the altar.
- Is that it?
- Yes.
Show it to him.
Beautiful angel, beautiful angel!
Isn't it beautiful?
Look how expressive.
Where did you get it?
It's from our house,
but we've got no place for it.
We thought it would look
better in your church.
We have no need for it here.
They were unable to sell
the statue that day.
So that evening, Fausto and
Moraldo entrusted it to Giudizio
with a thousand instructions.
Here's Papa.
Good evening, Papa.
Moraldo, come here.
Don't make me come after you!
- Papa, what did I do?
- You really have to ask?
Hoodlum! Cheat!
Wait till I get hold of you!
I haven't done anything.
What's the matter?
What's the poor boy done?
Poor boy! He's a monster!
We're all disgraced! Thieves!
Get out! Both of you!
What did they do?
They stole a statue!
- No, Papa.
- Liars!
These two... I had to beg the police
not to arrest you in my home.
Yes, the police, in my own home!
And this pig tried to force himself
on the wife of my dearest friend.
A pack of lies! I'm shocked
you believed them! Very shocked!
And you dare raise your voice?
Yes, I will! You treat me like
a five-year old! I'm 30!
Keep your crummy food!
You'll never see me again! Never!
It wasn't his fault.
Giulia came on to him,
then lied to her husband.
Sandra, are you listening to me?
Really?
Yeah. Fausto never encouraged her.
Wouldn't give her a second glance.
And then they wouldn't pay him.
So we took the statue.
He really didn't make a pass at her?
I swear.
Now stop crying.
Where is he now?
Out in the garden.
I'm waiting for Moraldo.
Tell Papa I'm leaving.
I don't want to be a burden.
What are you saying?
Moraldo told me everything.
- What do you mean?
- Don't worry, I'll tell Papa
that that woman flirted with you.
- Let's forget about it.
- No, they have to know the truth.
Here, your cutlet.
You haven't eaten a thing.
Damn it!
Why did you take the statue?
Did you need money?
You should have told me, Fausto.
Why didn't you? There should be
no secrets between us.
We have to cling to each other.
All we have is each other.
Mama is very kind,
but she treats me like a baby.
And Papa is always so busy.
He doesn't even know me.
You're all I have, Fausto.
If you leave too...
Sandra, don't.
- Do you still love me, Fausto?
- Yes.
- Do you love our baby?
- Sandra, my Sandrina, our baby.
So will you stay with me?
Yes.
Then come on home.
Let's go talk to Papa.
So Fausto was forgiven and started
leisurely looking for another job.
They didn't pay him much attention
at home once the baby was born.
A veritable Adonis,
he looked just like Mama, Papa,
Uncle, Grandfather, Grandmother
and even Moraldo.
He looks like my math teacher.
He's so ugly!
Sandra was happy, and one day
she quietly took the baby
to meet her father-in-law.
- The coffee is almost ready.
- Good girl.
Moraldino, why are you so fat?
Yesterday he said "blue."
I wonder what he meant.
Has Fausto found a job?
I guess so.
He should start in a matter of days.
Excuse me, Papa.
I'll see about the coffee.
- No, I'll go.
- Please, let me go.
- Sandra, can I hold him?
- Be careful with him, Mirella.
Come on, Moraldino,
give your auntie a kiss.
No, Papa, you don't know
how to hold him.
That's no way to hold a baby.
I don't know that one.
- Is that the farthest?
- Yes, it's called Sirius.
- Are there people living there?
- I don't think so.
- Would you live there?
- Yes.
- I don't believe you.
- Sure I would.
- Will you walk me home?
- Sure.
The evenings were getting warmer.
Spring was in the air.
And now, a man whose heart
is as great as his name.
That's him. He's brilliant.
Listen.
Mr. Sergio Natali.
I shall recite Reminiscence of Youth.
- Is that Natali?
- Yes.
He's uglier than sin.
Grandpa, when is Papa coming home?
Little one,
your papa has already returned.
He's here, lost in the crowd.
He's watching you, smiling at you.
He just brushed by you.
And you, little one,
didn't feel a thing.
Why not, Grandpa?
Because you're innocent.
Your papa left in the spring,
just like your grandpa.
As a lieutenant, amid flowers,
songs and a flag.
Leopoldo has long awaited
this evening.
The great actor has read his play
and will see him in his dressing
room after the performance.
His big moment has come.
Even we grasped
the importance of this meeting,
and we were as excited
as Leopoldo.
Ah, I see you've brought company.
Please, come in.
Bring some chairs.
- That's all right, sir. We'll stand.
Forgive the candle.
In these second-rate theaters,
they always steal the light bulbs.
- Of course, sir. It's nothing.
- May I offer you a cigarette?
They're domestic, you know.
American cigarettes
are very bad for you.
- Sir, I'm a great admirer.
- I saw you in I due Foscari.
Yes, well, the best parts
were left on the cutting room floor.
Please, have a seat
while I finish removing my makeup.
Sir, I've admired you for years.
I saw you for the first time
in Bologna, in 1943.
It was an unforgettable evening.
You revealed Ibsen to me.
- Ibsen. Those were the days.
Feels like yesterday.
Being principal actor
is hard work, my friend.
And you're seeing me during a break,
a vacation, I'd like to call it.
It's temporary, of course.
Fausto, look who's here.
Let me tell you,
I have great ideas for next season.
I want to put together
an amazing cast.
A cast that will make history.
I might be able to get Ferrati,
and perhaps even Gassman.
Did you hear that?
He's gonna get Ferrati and Gassman.
I want young playwrights, both
for the grants and for the challenge.
By the way,
I read your piece.
Skimmed it, really.
You understand, I'm always so busy.
The theater is a tyrant.
But you've got it.
You really liked it?
You've got it here... and here.
Sir.
"I'm a product of my time.
I am, alas, powerless.
Do you understand, Frida,
the writhing agony of my soul?"
Frida laughs.
"I understand, Roberto,
that you are consumed by pride..."
Salt.
"...by your being. Roberto laughs.
What more damage can pride do
to a soul already ruined?
Blind man!
Only fear could save you."
Only fear could save you.
Brilliant! But that was Frida's line.
She goes on.
"In the silence of your desert,
don't you hear a voice calling you?"
Robert, ironic: "Your voice, Frida?"
"No... God's."
So ends Act II.
Beautiful.
Don't you think it's good?
- I like it.
- May I start Act III?
- Go on.
- Act III, Scene I.
The door!
I'll close it.
Waiter, what have you got?
- Have you eaten, sir?
- May I go on, sir?
Very well, thank you.
- Of course, read on.
- Act III, Scene I.
What's the omelet Romagnola?
The one with all that grease?
- It's our specialty, with bchamel.
- All right, I'll have that.
Ask Mr. Natali to introduce us.
Why not?
They'll be represented
by two figures clad in white.
Black light will give the scene
a nightmarish quality.
The wind from time to time
will carry in the cry of the gulls.
As if shaken by a sudden shiver,
Frida turns.
She looks tired, aged. She approaches
him. "There will be no moon tonight."
I like you, baby.
And if you're not drinking with me,
damn you to hell!
- Can you do Gary Cooper?
- Alberto, do the saw.
I do a good saw.
But you've got to close your eyes.
Be quiet and listen!
My turn to do an impression.
My grandmother.
- Granny, I'll never leave you.
Can't you do impressions?
Why are you so serious?
I like this dark-haired boy.
He's got class.
That's true.
"No, not even crime horrifies me now.
Yet I can remember..."
Hey, there's a radio here.
I'm gonna turn it on.
That's a naughty thing to say.
Leopoldo, where are you going?
I'll tell you later.
I feel poetically inspired.
An idea worthy of a genius!
An ocean breeze, a night wind.
- Sir, my friends...
- Your friends disappoint me.
He who cares not for art
cares not for life.
Is the beach that way?
- Yes, sir.
Excellent!
Let's use first names -
we're both artists, after all!
Your Frida is wonderful.
She's marvelous.
What a well-sculpted character.
Perfect for Ferrati!
Excellent! I'll write to her tonight.
She'll be thrilled.
If Act IV is anything like
the first two you read me,
I can tell you we have
a guaranteed success on our hands.
What's your name?
- Poldo, sir.
Leopoldo, in two months
you must come with me to Milan.
- Really, sir? Are you serious?
- Call me Sergio.
- Sir, are you serious?
- Come, Leopoldo. Let's read Act IV.
Sir, you have no idea
what this means to me.
I was ready to give up
on all my dreams.
- Is the beach this way?
- This way, sir.
Sergio, I can hardly express...
This town is blind to art.
It's so hard,
being perpetually misunderstood.
My friends don't even understand me.
They only care about material things.
They live their sordid lives,
thinking of women and money.
I feel so alone.
And the winter is awful.
It's endless in this town.
I'm so full of sadness and anguish.
At midnight the town goes dark.
How can an artist feed his demons?
How can he live in this silence?
The years go by,
then one morning you wake up.
Just yesterday you were a boy,
and now you're no longer young.
My hat!
But that's all over now. In two months
I'll go to Milan, Genoa, anywhere.
I knew I shouldn't give up.
I knew I'd find my way,
that one day you'd come along.
Where are you?
The wind has died down.
Is that the pier?
Come and read me Act IV.
Sir - Sergio, where are you going?
We'll find a spot down there.
But it's dark down there.
Come.
You aren't afraid of me, are you?
Poldo, where are you going?
I was joking.
What did you think I meant?
Come back here, Poldo.
Bye.
Bye, baby.
Don't catch cold.
I'll come to the station
in the morning to see you off.
What are you doing here?
- I was waiting for you.
- Good for you. Thanks.
I think it's better
if we go home together.
Of course.
Man, what a woman!
You know what she told me?
If I could sing, she'd hire me.
Honest. She was going
to take me on tour.
It's not a bad life.
You travel, you're free,
you have fun, no worries.
Always surrounded by women.
What about you?
What about me? Nothing.
Why not?
She really wasn't bad-looking.
What's wrong with you?
Nothing. I was just thinking.
About what?
Sandra.
What's she got to do with this?
You gonna preach to me now?
Is that why you waited for me?
Answer me.
Good night.
You've still got lipstick
on your face.
Other side.
Sandra, aren't you asleep yet?
Look at that little face.
- Don't touch him!
Why not?
Are you crying?
- Go away. Get out.
- What did I do?
- Go away.
Sandrina.
- Don't touch me.
- You'll wake the baby.
Tell me what I did, at least.
That morning, Sandra left the house
at dawn without a word to anyone...
and at noon
she still hadn't come back.
Here comes Riccardo
with Papa's car.
Hi, Riccardo. Hi, Alberto.
Get in, Fausto.
Hi, Fausto.
Moraldo went to see Miss Rossi,
Sandra's old teacher.
She might have gone to see her.
That's right, Fausto.
I think she might be there.
Let's go to the school
and then to her nanny's.
How far to the nanny's?
What about the gas?
What happened?
Did you have a fight?
Well?
She hasn't seen her.
Get in.
Let's go to the nanny's.
You go ahead.
I'll look for her on my own.
What's happened to her?
Nothing, miss.
Forget about him. Let's go.
Leopoldo, how about before
we leave town we grab a bite to eat?
We could grab a bite to eat
before we leave town.
Shut up!
I think we'll find her at the nanny's.
I'm sure of it.
She went to show her
the baby. You'll see.
That's what I think.
She went to show her the baby.
Did you have anything to eat
before you left the house?
Nothing at all?
- I'm not hungry.
- A sandwich, maybe...
- Where are we supposed to turn?
- Let's get out.
- Let's ask for directions.
- Ask who? There's nobody here.
There's a house down there.
There's no one there.
This is a wasteland.
Fausto, where are you going?
- Watch Leopoldo.
- Go ahead, do it.
- Hey, you could have hit me.
- Don't look at me. It was him.
Quiet.
Did you hear the pipit?
- What?
- The pipit.
That's no pipit.
That's a robin.
That's no robin.
Robins sound like this...
How do robins sound?
But Sandra wasn't at the nanny's either.
Fausto was getting scared.
- What happened?
- Riccardo.
We have to go back right away.
- The car won't start.
We'll have to take
the carburetor apart.
- May I borrow that bicycle?
- Of course, dear boy.
It belongs to Cesare,
but he won't need it today. Be careful.
Would you like something to eat?
An omelet with bacon, maybe.
- Wait. Where are you going?
- Get out of my way.
Listen, Fausto.
Sandra is at home. I'm sure of it.
I'll bet you anything
that she's at home.
- Cut it out. Out of my way.
- Now you feel guilty?
It took you long enough.
- Out of my way, idiot!
Worry about that sister of yours
who never came back!
Dirty rotten coward!
Lecher!
- You mentioned an omelet?
- Yes.
- With bacon. Albertone.
- Leave me alone.
- With bacon.
- With bacon?
- Isn't anybody home?
- They're at the police station.
They're looking for her
at the beach.
At the beach?
Why would they do that?
I don't know.
What should I do?
Should I start making lunch?
It's you.
See? We meet again.
It's fate.
What's the matter?
Why haven't you shaved?
Where are you going
in such a hurry? The movies?
I'm going home.
Would you be a gentleman
and carry this for me?
I'm sorry. Forgive me.
I really can't.
Is she back?
If she doesn't come back,
I'll kill myself!
You'll never kill yourself.
You're a coward.
Moraldo, listen.
Mr. Michele.
What's the matter?
Sandrina has disappeared.
Hey, workers.
Stupid workers!
- What's up with this car?
- Hey, why are you stopping?
- Get out. Open the hood.
- What do you want me to do?
Let me out.
Look at him. He's asleep.
- Hurry up.
They're coming.
Hey, we were only joking!
What's going on?
What did I do? I was asleep.
I'm a socialist.
- Socialist?
You're not even a man!
- Are you looking for Sandra?
- Yes.
She's been here with us all day.
Hold it right there.
Sandra, take the baby
in the other room.
- Papa, it's all right.
- Please, go in the other room.
You too, Mirella.
- Please, Papa, let me stay.
What a day, Papa.
Papa, what are you doing?
- You hear that?
- No, I can't hear a thing.
He's beating him!
Let me go in there!
They're just arguing.
A little loudly, but they're men.
He's hurting him.
Please, Papa!
Leave them alone.
They're just playing.
No, Papa, no!
Let me go in there.
Can't you hear them yelling?
- Don't worry, it's nothing.
- Mirellina, he'll kill him.
- He's beating him to a pulp.
- I don't think he's hurting him.
On the contrary...
Please hold the baby.
I have to go in there.
Papa, enough!
Allow me to shake your hand.
Michele Corti's the name.
It's an honor.
- You really gave me a scare.
- Did he hurt you, darling?
No. How are you?
Good night, Papa.
You scared me so, Sandra.
Never do that again, you hear?
And if you make me mad again,
I'll beat you like your father.
But even harder.
I'll beat you senseless.
That's how I like you!
Let me hold the baby.
- Don't let him catch cold.
- Look, Mirellina is at the window.
Bye, Mirella.
Fausto and Sandra's story
ends here for now.
As for Leopoldo,
Alberto, Riccardo
and the rest of us,
you can imagine what happened.
We all talked about leaving,
but only one of us, one morning,
without a word to a soul,
actually left.
- Are you leaving?
- Guido.
- Yes, I'm leaving.
- Where are you going?
I don't know. I'm leaving.
All aboard.
All clear.
- Why are you leaving then?
- I don't know.
I have to go away. I'm leaving.
Didn't you like it here?
Good-bye, Moraldo.
Good-bye, Guido.