THE FILM THAT TRIUMPHED
AT THE 20TH VENICE FILM FESTIVAL
AND WON THE GOLDEN LION
and THE PRIX DE L'OFFICE CATHOLIQUE
INTERNATIONAL DU CINEMATOGRAPHE
Our women love us no more
Because we wear black shirts
DESERTERS AND THOSE EVADING
CONSCRIPTION WILL BE EXECUTED
THERE AREN'T ENOUGH RUINS
TO BURY ALL THE BRAVE
ANYONE CAUGHT CARRYING
UNAUTHORIZED FIREARMS...
WILL BE EXECUTED
ON THE SPOT
- Is the curfew over?
- Yes, it's 6:10.
We're lucky
it's cloudy again today.
They can't bomb us so easily
when it's cloudy.
It's our turn.
WE WILL WIN
Come here!
Didn't you hear us?
There's no point shouting.
If he doesn't speak German,
he can't understand.
Excuse me, sir.
Is there a phone nearby?
All the bars are closed now.
Do you have a flat?
For the fourth time.
We have no more spares.
There's a tire shop
just around the corner.
Really? Thank you.
He says there's a tire shop
just around the corner.
Another nail planted
by the partisans?
Get the spare tire.
Cigarette?
- Thanks.
Thanks.
Turn right
at the first corner. Recht.
Thanks.
- From Genoa?
- Naples.
Ah, Naples.
This time last year I was in Naples,
at the Hotel Vesuvio.
I'd open my windows
and have the sea before me,
with Mergellina and Posillipo on one side,
Capri and Sorrento on the other.
- And Auntie Teresa down below.
- Right.
We were sorry to leave Naples.
We'd come to really love it.
Your fellow townspeople,
on the other hand,
were pleased to see us leave.
They started shooting at us
out of sheer joy.
Actually, I'm from Sora,
between Naples and Rome.
So in actual fact,
I feel more Roman than Neapolitan.
The Romans
don't care for us much either.
- Are you based in Rome?
- Not anymore. I'm in Milan now.
- Do you like it?
- Not at all.
The weather's awful, and the people
are hostile and rebellious.
You Italians
don't like this war much.
We don't like wars in general.
This is a just and therefore
necessary war. Don't you agree?
Yes, but not everyone
shares my view.
Exactly. And that creates
some very awkward situations.
- May I be of help?
- No, thanks.
I should be getting to work now.
Thank you, Mr...
Grimaldi. I’m an engineer.
Colonel Müller.
I hope we meet again.
I hope so too.
- What time is it?
- It's only 6:00. Go back to sleep.
Were you out gambling again?
Don't worry.
We'll talk later.
Did anyone call?
- Did you lose again?
- I asked you a question.
How would I know?
Ask Maria.
- Maria.
- Who is it?
It's me.
Did anyone call?
Yes. That lawyer, Mr. Borghesio,
called twice.
- No one else?
- No.
- Oh, yes - Mrs. Camelli.
- Cantelli. What did she want?
She said, "Tell the colonel
that my brother's been released."
She sends her regards and thanks.
- Released? Are you sure?
Yes, she said he's back home.
Released!
I don't understand these Germans.
- Shall I make some coffee?
- No, go back to sleep.
Oh, and a package arrived.
I put it in the dining room.
THIS PACKAGE IS FOR MY FATHER.
I HOPE YOU'LL GET IT TO HIM.
Salami again.
They already cut off
the electricity.
Valeria, I’m in trouble.
You have to help me.
What do you want?
Give me something I can pawn.
Just for a few days.
You had a wad of big bills
Iast night.
I’m an unlucky bastard.
Borghesio gave me
100,000 lira for his son,
and I gambled it all.
I wanted to round up
the 50,000 I was owed,
and it was supposed
to be my night.
I'd lost the night before,
so last night I should've won.
That damn bastard jinxed me
and won the whole thing.
It was an awful night.
Only God knows
what I've been through!
I'm taking these risks
for you too.
You think I don't feel responsible
having a woman Iike you?
That I don't feel bad
not giving you the life you deserve?
You've said that for three months.
I know it by heart.
You can't charm me anymore.
Hello?
My dear Mr. Borghesio.
No, you're not disturbing me.
I’m an early bird.
News?
Things are Iooking up.
What was that?
Did the order come through?
No, not yet.
But everything will be
sorted out this morning.
I know.
I understand your concern.
But don't despair.
Go ahead and tell your wife.
Tell the poor woman
everything will be all right.
You have to trust me.
I've taken this matter to heart.
I don't even sleep nights.
I've spoken to him.
It will be resolved today,
come what may.
Don't worry.
Valeria, this is
a matter of Iife and death.
I must give that stingy German
the 50,000 I owe him before noon
or he'll send Mr. Borghesio's son
to Germany.
What's that to me?
Give me something I can pawn
just for two days -
You already made off
with my emerald earrings.
I’ll get them back, I swear.
Don't you believe me?
- No.
- Don't be so cruel.
I swear I won't gamble anymore.
- Do what you Iike.
I’m leaving anyway.
- Where are you going?
Turin. I got a job
at a radio station.
- Doing what?
- Singing, you fool!
Dancing and acting.
I'll start living at last!
You don't realize
that these are wretched times,
full of danger.
But I'll do anything.
I've got some irons in the fire.
I'm organizing some shows
for the armed forces.
When the war ends,
I’ll put you on stage in revues.
All your friends will envy you.
You've made lots of promises.
Can I help it
if all my assets are down south?
"Down south" again! I’m not sure
the south even exists anymore.
Well?
Well, what?
If you'd just lend me
your necklace and bracelet -
And my ring and brooch too?
I said no!
It's no use insisting.
Why don't you pawn
this ring you gave me?
The one
with the oriental sapphire.
Take it.
Try pawning that.
Think I didn't know it was fake?
Idiot!
The man who can trick Valeria
hasn't been born yet.
I never said a word
because I'm a lady.
Doria? You can go in.
- Is Sergeant Major Hageman in?
- He's busy, but you can go in.
- May I?
- Come in.
But give me just a moment.
He was arrested three weeks ago
outside San Giorgio.
The prison in Marassi
sent me here.
- His name?
- Canevari, Alberto.
- Check on that, please.
- Right away.
Canevari, Alberto.
He's the communist
who was executed last week.
No, he's not a communist.
My husband's not involved in politics.
I swear on my little girl's life.
She said he was arrested
with communists.
But if he's honest and not involved
in politics, he'll be released.
- But when?
- That's not my decision.
May I visit him and take him
some clean clothes?
You'll have to ask the warden.
Thank you.
- Excuse me, please.
- Wait. I’m busy.
- Ladies first.
- Well?
We're looking
for Lieutenant Michele Fassio.
He was arrested in Savona
last Thursday.
- Are you family?
- I’m his wife.
I’m his mother.
My son's never been
involved in politics.
He fought in Africa and Albania
and received a silver medal.
You said Michele Fassio?
Please, Miss Sieglinde.
Lieutenant Michele Fassio,
son of Angelo and Matilde Masuero,
born in Varigotti
on the June 8, 1916?
Yes.
Lieutenant Fassio was arrested
for being a member of the armed
brigades that attack our troops
and oppose the legitimate government
of the Italian Social Republic.
That's not true!
He stayed at his father's villa
after the 8th of September.
When he was supposed
to report for military service.
An Italian officer doesn't need
to be told his duty.
Calm down, Carla.
The gentleman was simply saying
that Michele should have reported.
You must understand :
They're just boys.
So much has happened.
He was upset by it all.
These are difficult times
for everyone.
It calls for understanding
on both sides.
The propaganda of hate
maddens the soul.
But don't lose hope.
Our German friends are nearly
always very understanding.
Let's go, Mother.
I told you we could hope
for nothing from these people.
She's a fiery one!
- Coffee, Colonel?
- Real coffee, yes.
But if it's like last time -
- It is.
All right. Thanks.
You're always very kind, miss.
I saw Mr. Borghesio.
- Well?
He couldn't raise the money,
but he gave me something
much more valuable.
An oriental sapphire
set in platinum.
That's of no use to me.
I said 50,000, and that's that.
- But this is worth much more.
- I want the money.
- Precious stones are a good investment.
- But money can't be traced.
- A sapphire is a sapphire.
- I want the money.
Don't be stubborn.
Where would I get it?
It's simple.
If that ring is worth
more than 50,000 lira,
sell it and keep the rest.
But it's a shame.
I wanted you to have it.
You'll marry one day,
won't you?
"One day..."
So much could happen before then.
Here's your coffee.
So we're agreed then.
AIways at your service.
Thanks for everything,
Sergeant Major. Good-bye.
Shall we help Mrs. Fassio?
No, it's a lost cause,
and I don't Iike that woman.
I do.
Remember: I’ll be waiting
tomorrow morning.
I’ll be here.
Ladies, I’ll be waiting
in that bar.
I have good news.
Please sit down.
Have a seat.
I am Colonel Grimaldi.
The Gospel says,
"Judge not, lest ye be judged."
Don't be fooled
by appearances, ma'am.
I told you my name,
but don't ask why I’m friends
with the Germans.
These blue stripes show
I served my country
with loyalty and honor.
Our country that's so scorned
and downtrodden.
Three coffees - real ones.
- Neapolitan style?
- Yes.
Forgive me for approaching you
so abruptly,
but these are dangerous times.
I’ll get to the point.
I must be discreet
about certain matters,
just as you must be
about others.
I trust
I've made myself clear.
I mean that,
given the circumstances,
we must exercise
a certain discretion.
Listen, Colonel,
Iet's be very clear.
If you can help my husband,
just tell me how.
- Carla!
- Let's get to the crux of it.
You asked me
if I can help your husband.
I'm saying, "Within the limits
of my capacity."
But whether true or false,
the accusations are very serious.
Someone's waiting for me -
a case very related to yours.
I hope I've been
of some small help to him.
We Italians
must help each other,
despite the hatred.
Excuse me.
I’ll be right back.
He seems
Iike a good person.
You can relax.
Your son won't be sent away.
Thank you for all you've done,
and all you will do.
But do you think
he'll be released?
We can't expect too much.
Let's just be glad he's not Ieaving.
Then we'll see about the rest.
I have a little business proposal.
- Go ahead.
Two ladies
are in financial trouble
and need to sell
a family heirloom.
An oriental sapphire.
Very nice.
A marvelous stone.
Only 50,000 lira.
50,000?
Where would I get that?
To raise the 100,000 lira
I gave you,
I had to mortgage my house
on very unfavorable terms.
I can imagine.
But I can show it
to someone else.
No, don't bother.
Good-bye, sir.
- Thank you so much.
- Don't worry.
Forgive me.
You haven't drunk your coffee?
It's the real stuff.
We always drink
real coffee at home.
We have tons of it.
Don't mind her.
She's beside herself.
Don't abandon us.
Don't worry.
Colonel, if there's
anything you need -
You think Michele will be freed
because his father's rich,
but what about all the others
they've arrested?
Will you pay for them all?
- Leave it to me.
Where can I find you?
Call us.
The name is Fassio.
86386.
Fassio... 86386.
Very good.
I hope to have news
about your son soon.
Thank you.
Good-bye.
No news
from the front at Anzio.
An enemy bomber
was destroyed by our fighters.
Two Italian planes are missing.
This has been the news...
Hello, Mrs. Pina.
I have a bargain for you,
an oriental sapphire.
It was my mother's.
One of a kind. Just 100,000 lira.
It's lovely, but I can't.
You can give me part now
and the rest later.
I'd love to, but I can't.
These are hard times.
Let's say 50,000 now,
and you cancel my tab.
You mustn't tempt me.
I really can't.
I managed
to find some meat.
Hello.
What's going on?
Just a little business matter.
Bye, Michele.
Good-bye.
It's a real bargain.
An oriental sapphire.
Just look at it.
I thought of you.
- It's beautiful.
- 80,000 lira.
It's lovely,
but I'm not interested.
I’m sorry, but no.
- You're sure?
- I’m sorry.
It is very beautiful though.
It's a bargain.
An oriental sapphire.
It belongs to a Jewish woman.
She has to sell.
She'll take 70,000 lira.
- No, thanks. I’m not interested.
We're closed until 2:00.
I'm a friend of Miss Olga's.
Open up, please.
- She's eating.
- Tell her it's an old friend.
Who is it?
Olga, it's me.
Emanuele!
How did you find me?
I ran into a friend of yours
the other day - Evelina.
The other day?
She left three weeks ago.
I wanted to come earlier,
but I've been so busy.
I can imagine.
So why have you come now?
I’m so happy to see you.
I thought you'd feel the same.
Really?
- I see I was wrong.
- That's right. You were wrong.
- Good-bye, then.
- Olga, it's getting cold.
- Madam Vera!
- Emanuele!
What a surprise!
How are you?
What brings you to Genoa?
The house in Livorno was bombed,
so I was sent here.
Why didn't you tell me
Emanuele was here?
Have you eaten?
- Not really.
- Join us for lunch.
- I don't want to impose.
Don't be silly.
Come on.
We have to catch up.
I haven't seen you in years!
Do you mind?
Me? She's the boss.
All right, then.
Come with me.
Let him sit down.
Olga!
- Hello, ladies.
- Serve the food, please.
What have you been up to?
Where have you been?
Here and there.
Sometimes up,
sometimes down.
Right. Sometimes up,
But you're looking good,
Madam Vera.
- Oh, I get by.
- How's business?
Not good. With the curfew at 9:00
and everyone so worried -
I know.
What about you?
Apart from gambling.
I've given that up... more or less.
I’m an honest man now.
You don't say!
- I buy and sell jewels.
- Like you used to.
No, not Iike that.
I sell these now.
How beautiful!
Let me see.
It's lovely.
It's magnificent.
It's an oriental sapphire.
It's a good time to buy.
People need to sell things.
The lira's losing value,
but not precious stones.
It's beautiful,
but what does it cost?
Not much. 50,000 lira.
It belongs to the wife
of a big shot.
Her husband
stayed down in Sicily.
- But 50,000 lira -
- I’ll buy it.
- You?
- Won't you sell it to me?
But Madam Vera
and this lady here Iiked it.
- If Olga likes it -
- I’ll give you a check.
Don't you trust me?
- It's not that.
What then?
Has it been long
since you saw her?
- Yes.
- Since Livorno?
Yes. Then we went on
to La Spezia...
She's changed so much.
She's always moody and argumentative.
If I didn't love her
Iike a sister -
You want Madam Vera
to sign it too?
Excuse me.
Emanuele!
Come in here.
If Madame Vera
or one of the girls had bought it,
you'd have taken the money.
So why not from me?
Why did you give me a check
when you knew it was fake?
Here's 30,000 lira.
It's all I have. Will it do?
Why are you doing this for me?
I don't know.
Or maybe I do.
You hurt me so bad,
but we had happy days
together too.
The only happy days
of my Iife.
I live in the memory
of those days.
No! Go away!
Go away...
and never come back.
Ladies, come to the salon.
10,000 in the bank.
Place your bets.
Once again...
- Bank.
- No bets.
Card.
The bank has nine.
Good for the bank.
It's baccarat.
19,500.
Place your bets.
- Bank.
- No bets.
The bank has eight.
There's still a bank.
Here's your money.
Take it.
Don't worry. It's nothing.
Send this message:
"The piano tuner has arrived."
Stop or I’ll shoot!
I thought I could trust you,
but I was wrong.
You know how important it was
to get Della Rovere alive.
What good
is a dead body to us?
I gave you precise orders.
- I passed them on.
- That's not good enough!
You should have checked
they were carried out correctly.
We didn't know where he'd make land.
I couldn't be everywhere.
You're great at excuses,
but you haven't learned to obey me.
A brave soldier was killed
Iike a small-time criminal.
If he hadn't died like that,
he'd have died some similar way.
What do you mean?
We could have exchanged him for one
of our generals held by the partisans.
We could have held him hostage.
What you did is unforgivable.
I want no more mistakes.
Bury the bodies of Della Rovere
and his accomplice far from Genoa.
They must be unidentifiable.
And the troops responsible
are to be sent to the Eastern front.
Yes, sir!
Spread the word
that we've arrested Della Rovere.
Yes, sir.
Something has to happen.
Someone will try
to come to his aid.
You can go.
May I?
Hello?
I'd Iike to speak to Mrs. Fassio.
Speaking.
This is Colonel Grimaldi.
Don't cry.
I have good news.
I’ve taken your case to heart.
Really?
You must be strong.
This isn't
an orthodox procedure.
What are you saying?
I know a fellow
who's unfortunately -
but also luckily for us -
very greedy.
Really?
All right.
I’ll meet you in the same café.
See you soon.
Sorry I’m Iate.
My call must have surprised you.
- Not at all.
I mean, you probably didn't
expect me to call so soon.
But ever since I Ieft you
and your mother-in-law yesterday,
I’ve thought of nothing
but how I could help you.
I got to work
and called all my contacts.
I’m not boasting,
but I know a Iot of people.
And so?
Well, it's not simple.
It'll take time.
And lots of money.
You have no idea
how greedy these Germans are.
I can imagine.
Here's 100,000 lira.
Will that do for now?
Of course.
I’ll deliver it right away.
You wait here.
I hope to bring you good news.
Don't despair, ma'am.
Have faith.
Have faith in my friendship.
- Where's the phone?
- On the right.
ROOM NO. 25
One moment, Colonel,
and I’m all yours.
Good morning.
Colonel, what a surprise!
What brings you to these unpleasant
surroundings? Anything wrong?
Yes, unfortunately.
Yesterday you said this war
was just and therefore necessary,
and I said I agreed but that not everyone
shared my view. Remember?
Yes.
Well, a young relative -
distant, on my mother's side -
is a scoundrel
who doesn't share my view.
His father's a famous jurist.
His mother was born a noblewoman.
He's descended from Garibaldi's men,
but he didn't hear the call of duty.
He didn't respond
to his country's call,
and he let himself get nabbed -
I mean, he was arrested.
He's to be deported to Germany.
Quite rightly, of course.
Why didn't he choose
to fight with us?
He'd have been freed
immediately.
- Why?
- Yes, why?
- You want to know?
- I’m curious.
Out of pride!
That boy has a monstrous
sense of pride!
He took after his great-grandfather.
And he said,
" If I fight alongside
our German colleagues,
it may look like I’m doing it
to avoid the concentration camps.
I don't want our brave German
colleagues to think
I’m a coward. "
- I’ll see what I can do.
- Can you speak to Captain Schrantz?
I don't need to speak to anyone,
my dear man.
Come with me.
This way.
- What's the man's name?
- Vittorio Borghesio.
Get me Vittorio Borghesio's
information.
This says that in addition
to being a deserter,
he was involved
in illegal activities.
If we believed everything
the police said -
My dear man,
I am the police.
Well, if all policemen
were like you -
I don't care for flattery.
This Borghesio
is to remain in Genoa.
He's on the transfer list.
- Take him off the list.
- Yes, sir.
The problem's resolved.
He stays here. Happy?
You're lucky you're able
to do some good!
It doesn't happen often,
unfortunately.
I’ll give
his poor parents the news.
Let me thank you
and bless you on their behalf.
I don't Iike thanks
or blessings.
I hope you'll come by again.
- I will.
And thank you, Colonel.
I’ve got good news!
I just need to make a call.
I’ll be right back.
Mr. Borghesio, please.
It's the colonel.
Mr. Borghesio?
Victory!
No, not Vittorio.
Or rather, yes -
victory for Vittorio.
He won't be leaving,
and he may be released.
I’ll tell you when I see you.
Let your wife
know the good news.
No, I don't Iike thanks
or blessings.
See you soon, my friend.
Madam, your husband's fine.
The path is long
and complicated,
but it leads to freedom.
My husband is already free,
my dear colonel.
He was shot yesterday
behind the Staglieno cemetery.
Shot?
- Then why are we -
- Yes, why indeed?
- Come with us.
- There must be some horrible mistake!
How long
have you known this man?
I met him
three or four months ago.
I was performing in revues
in Mondovì.
I’m a serious actress,
but times are hard
and you have to make do.
And if you're talented, even revues -
- Try to be brief.
How did you meet this man?
I told you, in Mondovì.
I was going home
with some friends after a show.
We'd been out late to dinner,
and that damn curfew
had started.
A patrol car
wanted to arrest us,
and the colonel intervened.
- What colonel?
- Him.
Why, are you a colonel too?
Later...
I’ll explain later.
- Right.
Go on.
- He took us to our hotel.
- Then?
Well, one thing led to another.
He made me leave my job.
- Go on.
- He brought me to Genoa.
He promised me the world.
"Once the south is freed..."
What's his Iine of business?
Tell me the truth,
for your own good.
I only know
he got lots of phone calls,
and he had a lot of visitors
with packages.
Containing what?
Clothes, food...
a lot of salami.
I ate so much salami
that I broke out in a rash. Look!
The lady can go.
That way.
Bring them in.
Do you know this man?
Why don't you answer him?
Why don't you tell him you know me?
I have nothing to hide.
Colonel, let me explain.
Maybe I was wrong - I was wrong -
but for a good reason.
It started with
Mrs. De Dominicis.
Step forward, ma'am.
She lives upstairs from me.
She was distraught one day on the stairs.
Her son had been arrested.
Faced with a mother's anguish,
what else could I do?
I said, "I’ll try and help."
Isn't that right, ma'am?
- Yes.
Then the others came to me.
I was overwhelmed
with their requests,
their problems and suffering.
What else could I do?
I tried to help,
but it was never enough!
First they wanted
to find their loved ones,
then to send letters,
and then the packages started.
Then they wanted me to keep them
from being sent to Germany,
and then even
get them released.
What should I have done?
Tell me.
Put yourself in my shoes.
I tried to help.
Then I Iearned the terrible truth.
That they slept ten to a cell,
standing up Iike horses,
that they were beaten
and tortured
and packed into sealed trains
headed for Mauthausen.
And I kept quiet.
I didn't have
the heart to tell them.
Would you have rather
I told you?
No!
Better to let them hope.
Only I knew the truth.
- Let them go.
- Yes, sir.
You're all free to go.
Come with me.
Now tell me what you prefer.
You can be tried
as a colonel
for sabotaging
German war regulations
and corrupting German officers.
Or you can simply be
Emanuele Bardone,
son of the late Luigi
and Teresa Camarano,
born in Sorrento
on May 3, 1894,
and be charged with fraud
and impersonating an officer.
Is that a choice?
In the first case, I'd be shot.
In the second,
I'd get three years at most.
"Impersonating an officer"
is a joke.
Article 498 provides for a fine
of 1,000 to 10,000 lira.
It's Article 310
that's a bit troublesome
regarding crimes
committed during wartime.
But this blessed war
has to end one day,
and there'll be an amnesty
like last time.
You were an officer
in the cavalry.
You were expelled from the army
for debt and embezzlement.
Then you were convicted
four times
for fraud, swindling the disabled,
possession and dealing of drugs,
and even bigamy!
If you'd stayed in the army,
you could be wearing
a real colonel's uniform today.
Maybe even a general's.
Hageman, Bardone's accomplice,
has confessed.
What?
Sergeant Major Walter Hageman
has confessed.
Then punish him accordingly.
Here.
Listen, I want to help you.
Despite everything,
I like you.
- May I say something?
- Go ahead.
I like you too,
despite everything.
Bardone,
I have a proposal for you.
Of course Della Rovere
had a marvelous career!
He married
a general's daughter.
His aunt, Marquise Barrino,
died in 1928, leaving him sole heir.
He's suspected of being a Mason,
and his uncle is a monsignor.
These types make me Iaugh.
I’m a self-made man.
Listen, these notes mention
that he speaks fluent English,
French and German.
I know
a few words of French.
"Place your bets, gentlemen."
"AII bets have been placed."
AII bets have been placed, eh?
You know the cause of all
my troubles? Gambling.
I always lose.
What's worse, I pay.
And I’ve never cheated.
I hope I won't be the first
to find otherwise.
This is no game we're playing,
Colonel.
Heil Hitler, Lieutenant Colonel.
Come on.
Get me the senior squad leader.
What if someone here
in San Vittore recognizes me?
I doubt it. Common criminals
aren't mixed in with political prisoners.
I didn't mean them.
I was talking about the guards
and chaplains.
They often get transferred
from one prison to another.
Chaplains aren't allowed
in the political sector.
I don't trust priests.
They're all spies.
What about the others?
Right.
If anything should happen,
call me right away.
May God help us.
Hold this prisoner,
but don't register him.
No fingerprints
and no photographs.
Keep him under surveillance
and in isolation.
Make sure you treat him
with the utmost respect.
- Yes, sir.
- All right, then.
Come with me.
Follow me.
I may not see you again,
so I’ll thank you now
for all the kindness
you've shown me
in this embarrassing situation.
Any German officer
would have done the same.
I should Iike to believe you.
Give my regards to Field Marshal
Kesselring when you see him.
Tell him that just because
we're now on different sides
doesn't mean I admire
or respect him less.
I will, Mr...
Follow me, please.
Who's come in,
the Shah of Persia?
- Where?
- Basso Piave.
- When?
- July, 1918.
The Battle of the Solstice.
What unit?
- 131st Avellino Brigade.
Great soldiers.
Well done.
Will you set up my bed?
- I’ll call the attendant.
- Take good care of him.
- All right.
Water, sir!
Banchelli, come out here.
- Set up his bed.
- Help me.
Don't bother, sir.
I’ll get someone else.
Cold, huh?
If you're staying here a while,
ask for a different cell.
The ground floor
is really damp.
Thanks for the tip.
May I?
My name's Aristide Banchelli.
- Of the cotton family?
- I wish!
I’m just a poor typesetter.
- Have you been here long?
- Eight months.
Are you involved in politics?
We're all involved
in politics here.
- General Della Rovere.
- I’ll be damned!
Sorry.
You've come from outside.
How are things going?
- Help him set up the bed.
- AII right.
- Where are my things?
- In the storeroom, sir.
- But I need them.
- Tell me what you need.
My slippers, my pajamas,
some shirts and my wool scarf.
And my toiletries.
- I’ll bring them, sir.
General Della Rovere's here!
He's with Badoglio,
from the south!
General Della Rovere's here!
D-E-L-L-A...
R-O... V-E... R-E.
- Della Rovere!
- Wait.
P-U...
Ah, one of Badoglio's men!
IT'S ALL OVER
FOR YOUR SON MARIO.
LIFE IS A JOKE.
THE CURSED ENEMY
IS GOING TO EXECUTE ME.
HOLD YOUR HEAD UP HIGH.
YOUR SON NEVER TREMBLED.
MY NAME IS
RUTILIO CASTELLINI.
TO WHOMEVER READS THIS:
PLEASE INFORM MY FAMILY
THAT I HAVE BEEN EXECUTED.
GIVE MY LOVE TO EVERYONE.
GOOD-BYE, MY DARLING!
I'D NEVER HAVE THOUGHT
DYING WOULD BE SO EASY.
The things you asked for, sir.
Please have a look
and then sign, please.
Who were
these condemned men?
Young men working
with the partisans in the hills.
- Were they all shot?
- All four of them.
- Were the families informed?
- Yes, by the chaplain.
- Who's the chaplain?
- Don Luigi Gavino.
But the Germans
won't allow him into this wing.
- Savona, I didn't say a word.
- Neither did I.
This is Calandrino, seventh company.
Anyone there?
Calandrino, Vendetta's brother.
See you outside.
General Della Rovere!
Can you hear me?
Good evening, general.
My brother was a radio telegraph
operator with you in Africa.
Micheluzzi, Fausto.
You remember him?
General!
General Della Rovere,
do you remember my brother?
Yes, I remember him.
General, talk facing the door,
or your voice gets garbled.
Yes, I remember him.
General,
when are they coming?
The Americans
are taking their time!
Antonio!
I didn't see you outside.
- I fell down the stairs.
- Did you hurt yourself?
- Yes.
Sir, I'm Lieutenant
Carlo Maria Mida.
And I'm Deputy Chief
Carlo Frassinetti.
We were arrested in La Spezia
by the Germans and convicted.
At your service, sir.
I'm General Della Rovere.
Be strong, boys!
- Good evening.
- Where's Fabrizio?
He's coming on the 5:10 train.
Come with me.
- Any news?
- He was taken to San Vittore today,
accompanied by Colonel Müller.
He didn't go through registration.
He's in block 5
on the ground floor, cell 39.
- We're sure it's him?
- Of course. And so are the Germans.
- How did they recognize him?
- They were expecting him.
- They have spies everywhere.
- That doesn't surprise me.
They were our allies 10 months ago.
- Mussolini's allies!
That doesn't change anything.
We should have freed him
on the trip from Genoa to Milan.
- He might have gotten killed.
- We have to contact him.
It won't be easy.
The guards we know
have been transferred.
Still, we have
to contact him at all costs.
What's taking Fabrizio?
The station's
just 10 minutes away.
- Maybe he had to walk.
- Annamaria's meeting him on her bike.
- Maybe he never Ieft Cernobbio.
- He'd have let us know.
- It's late.
- Here's Annamaria now.
Here's Annamaria.
- Where's Fabrizio?
- He was arrested.
- Where?
- Near Piazza Castello.
We were caught in a raid.
He tried to escape,
but his bike got stuck
in the streetcar tracks and he fell.
The fascists locked him up in a truck
with some other poor souls.
Were there many prisoners?
About 80,
three trucks full.
- You know where they took them?
- No. I followed the trucks.
I saw a bag fall from the one
Fabrizio was in. No one else noticed.
I grabbed it and came here.
- Good work.
They probably took them
to the Cantore barracks, Iike usual.
We'll know soon.
Two in a row:
first the general, then Fabrizio.
But they were out to get the general.
They got Fabrizio by accident.
They don't know it yet.
No one knows him.
At worst he'll go to a work camp.
We can easily free him.
He could be set free tonight.
His papers are in order.
Let's hope so,
but we should expect the worst.
First of all,
we have to find him.
Then we must track
every movement in those barracks.
Who's in charge of that sector?
- Virgilio.
He's a smart boy,
but tell him to be careful.
Let's go.
You go on ahead.
- What is it?
- Six new prisoners for you.
Send them up.
Why'd they bring you here
at this hour?
My name's Pietro Valeri.
We were caught in a raid.
They brought nine of us here.
I don't know why.
What are they doing this Iate?
- Wait. I’ll help you.
- Thanks.
Don't worry.
They'll bring everything.
What's going on?
Nine new prisoners,
caught in a raid.
Who are they?
Watch out!
Here you are.
My dear Bardone,
you have the chance
to earn what I promised you :
freedom and a reward.
Nine men were brought
to San Vittore Iast night.
I know. So I heard,
and so I was told.
One of them is called Fabrizio.
That's the code name
for the leader of the resistance.
We're sure
Fabrizio is one of them.
You must identify him.
- Me?
General Della Rovere's first task
when he arrived
must have been
to meet Fabrizio
to coordinate
the partisans' war plans.
Fate destined you
to meet here.
Yes, but...
how will I recognize him?
Don't worry.
He'll identify himself.
And when he does,
you want me to denounce him?
You only have to tell me
who he is.
In Genoa you told me
I was to be a decoy
for the ducks.
Now you want me
to be the rifle too.
For this duty,
you'll receive one million lira
and a safe-conduct to Switzerland.
Your task will be even easier.
Two of the nine men
will be freed immediately.
They really are who they claim to be:
government officials.
So you'II have
just seven men to choose from.
Take him back to his cell.
Soup.
I'm the barber too.
If you need me,
my name's Banchelli.
Thanks. I hope it won't be necessary.
I'm here by mistake.
Soup.
Requests!
What do you need?
- Two packs of cigarettes.
- What about you?
- Some soap.
Good morning, sir.
Good morning, my friend.
Coffee for you.
- Real coffee?
- Yes, from the warden.
He wanted to come in person,
but he's not allowed
in the political sector.
The Germans
don't trust even him.
- Do they trust you?
- No.
But they need us.
There's not many of them,
so if you need anything -
I could use a barber.
Is that possible?
Of course.
I’ll call Banchelli.
- Good morning, General.
- Good morning.
You're the barber too?
- If you trust me.
I do.
I hope you won't be sorry.
I don't do this often.
May I?
I’ll take that.
Did you sleep well, sir?
Yes.
- Is your bed soft?
- Not bad.
Our beds are like planks.
But I don't care.
I sleep less,
but I live more.
The German military court
has sentenced me to death.
They say I blew up
a munitions train.
But it seems
they've forgotten about me.
I’ve been waiting to be executed
for three months.
Sorry.
Maybe they can't find
another barber.
Sorry.
"The wind blows
from the west."
When did you get this?
This morning.
From whom?
The barber,
a certain Banchelli.
Damn it! I know the one.
He'd rather die than talk.
What should I do?
Calm down.
Reply with another note.
Tell him you don't trust him.
Force Fabrizio to reveal himself.
Write back, "Let's wait
for the wind to die down."
Give the note to Banchelli
and wait.
Open up! Open up!
Go ahead!
Drop your bombs!
I’m not scared!
Open up!
We have
to quiet them down!
We have to calm the men down!
Open up!
Friends...
this is General Della Rovere.
Show some dignity
and self-control!
Act like men!
Show these swine
that you're not scared of dying.
They should be scared!
Every bomb that falls
brings them closer to the end
and brings us closer to freedom.
My wife visited me,
the poor woman.
She brought our son along.
He's grown so much.
A handsome boy,
and not just because he's mine.
What'll happen to them?
I won't see them again.
Don't throw it so high!
Let the others in!
- There are six of them.
- Good.
Stop!
Get going!
Go on!
How can a man who's spent
so many years in prison
not even send a note
without getting caught?
Now our plan's ruined.
I’ll have to make Banchelli talk.
I hate doing these things.
Put him in solitary.
- Yes, sir.
Come in.
Have a seat.
- Cigarette?
- No, thanks.
My dear Banchelli,
you've been sentenced to death.
Your days are numbered.
I’m offering you a chance
to save yourself.
General Della Rovere
admitted that he gave you a note.
This one here.
Tell me who it was for,
and you'II have my word :
I’ll have your death sentence
reduced to 30 years in prison.
And we both know
that the war won't Iast that Iong.
But I know nothing, sir.
Someone gave me the note
when I came in from the yard.
Yes, and you hid it
in your shoe.
I was going to give it back
to the general.
Banchelli, you're no idiot,
and neither am I!
I know the note
wasn't for you.
The general was using you
to get it to someone else.
Who?
Who knows?
He didn't tell me.
Why don't you ask him?
Why are you all so stubborn?
You know we have ways
of making you talk!
You know that!
- I know.
But even you can't force a man
to tell you what he doesn't know.
Colonel, I have a wife and son.
I saw them today.
I’m all they've got.
Don't you think
I'd tell you if I knew?
I’m asking you
for the Iast time.
Don't force me to use methods
that go against my principles.
I wish I could, believe me.
Let's go, Banchelli.
Come in.
Countess Della Rovere is here.
- Where?
- She's waiting outside.
Show her in.
Colonel Müller?
That's me.
Have a seat, Countess.
You must be surprised
to see me.
In a certain sense.
His Eminence advised me
to come to you.
He said you would understand
and help me.
Within the limits of my duty,
of course.
But let me ask you something.
Our sources assured us that you
and your children were in Switzerland.
I must deduce
that you have returned to Italy.
Don't worry.
I won't charge you
with illegal reentry.
I was just asking
to pay tribute to your courage
and devotion.
I’m just doing
what I have to.
I haven't come to plead
on my husband's behalf.
That would be useless,
and my husband wouldn't approve.
I’ve only come out of my hope
and desire to see him,
if only for a few moments.
Believe me,
I’m very sorry
that I cannot fulfill your request.
But prisoners aren't allowed visitors
during the inquiry period.
I didn't ask for a visit,
but just to see him
for a few moments.
Countess,
I understand how you feel,
and I’ll prove it.
You may see your husband,
and even talk to him.
But think about it first.
General Della Rovere has been
arrested on serious charges.
He's calm and serene,
behaving like the soldier he is,
I can assure you.
You know what gives him
strength and courage?
Knowing not only that
he's done his duty as a soldier,
but also that his loved ones
are safe and far away.
So I ask you,
do you think seeing you
for a few moments behind a screen,
seeing you worried
and in risk of danger,
will be of comfort to him?
Or rather would it have
a negative effect on his morale?
I speak to you as a friend.
I have the deepest admiration
and regard for the general,
and I regret that this war
has placed us on opposite sides.
Follow my advice
and don't visit him.
It would upset him greatly,
I’m sure.
Let him think you're safe
with his children.
Write him a letter
if you'd Iike.
I’ll tell him that His Eminence
gave it to me.
His Eminence will forgive
this small Iie.
I give you my word
that it won't be opened.
Perhaps you're right.
If you'd Iike,
you could send him
some clothes
and something to eat.
The food here is unfortunately...
just what it is.
Thank you.
Banchelli!
Damn them!
General, I didn't say a word,
but I don't know
if I can hold out again.
It was terrible.
Why didn't you talk?
Why should you pay
for someone else?
General...
God! I don't know
what I’m saying anymore!
General...
do you know who Fabrizio is?
Drink some of this.
Banchelli, have some soup.
You'll feel better.
Banchelli killed himself!
Banchelli's dead! Open up!
I want to speak
to Colonel Müller!
Banchelli's dead!
It's all your fault!
If you hadn't been so stupid,
they wouldn't have
found the note,
and we'd know
who Fabrizio is now!
Instead we have
another dead man on our hands!
Now go!
I’m not going back out there.
By now everyone knows
that Banchelli was tortured,
that he killed himself.
They won't believe
I’m General Della Rovere.
They'll kill me!
The guards themselves might kill me!
They're on their side!
No such thing will happen.
You'll be welcomed back
as a victim...
and a hero.
Take him away.
They tortured
General Della Rovere!
Murderers! Murderers!
There's a letter
and a package for you, sir.
A letter for me?
Open it.
There's a picture -
must be your wife and children.
What does it say?
I can't make it out.
You read it.
It's from Geneva.
"Dear Gianni, I hope
these few words reach you.
Our consul
told me of your arrest.
I’ve told the boys.
They were very good.
They didn't cry.
I didn't cry either.
We read the letter you wrote
after the 8th of September,
and we remember your words:
'When you don't know
which path to take,
choose the hardest one.'
The boys are fine.
They're doing well at school.
I’m proud of them.
At all times, in every situation,
whatever may happen,
we'll be worthy of you,
my darling.
We pray for you and hold you
in our thoughts and hearts.
God cannot permit
that we never see each other again.
The boys and I send you
all our Iove.
Bianca Maria."
Show me the picture.
They're handsome boys, sir.
They killed the fascist
party secretary in Milan.
Oh, God!
What'll happen to us?
They killed the party secretary
in Milan.
- Camerata Gaetano D'Accosta.
- Present among us!
We must carry out
a massive house-by-house search.
Milan is a working city.
Dragnets and deportations
would disturb its productive rhythm.
We can't allow our best men
to be ambushed in the heart of Milan.
The partisan war is a reality.
Reprisals only make
the situation worse.
So you want us to do nothing
and wait to be killed?
If it were German soldiers,
you'd think differently.
Perhaps it's not thinking
that's called for.
I’ve informed the high command
on the southwest front,
the Wehrmacht high command,
and the Führer's headquarters.
I’m awaiting orders.
Colonel Müller's office,
Senior Lieutenant Haftig
speaking.
Yes, right away.
Colonel,
it's the Wehrmacht
high command.
Colonel Müller speaking.
Thank you.
Good morning, Field Marshal.
Yes, I understand.
He doesn't agree.
He says reprisals
have the opposite effect.
He'll carry out orders.
Draw up a list of 20 men.
Next to each man's name
write his race, occupation,
offense, and sentence.
Yes, sir.
The execution will be
tomorrow at dawn
in the prison courtyard.
Good-bye, Colonel.
Good-bye.
The list is ready, sir.
Would you Iike to see it?
- Why are there only five Jews?
- The others were deported yesterday.
There are only
women and children Ieft.
Add General Della Rovere
to the list,
and the nine men
we arrested yesterday.
But they're in pretrial custody.
Just do as I say.
Here's the list.
But there are ten names here.
Remove Oliviero Scotti.
He was released yesterday.
Colonel Müller's office.
The archbishop's office, sir.
I’m afraid the colonel's not here.
If they're really taking us
to Germany,
why didn't they say
to bring our things?
But you're not
being investigated.
This is just a routine check.
- They're verifying our identity.
- That's what I said.
Damn it,
we've been here another night!
Admit it: You were starting
to get worried,
but no one wanted to say it.
They're sending us to work.
I say they're sending us
to Germany.
Then they'd have said
to bring our things, but they didn't.
That means
we'll be coming back soon.
- Even the general's here.
- So we're not going to Germany.
Why? Can't he work too?
The Germans don't give a damn
about Italian generals.
Right?
Maybe it's to work on some railway
or road around here.
They must need laborers
after all the bombings.
And you're not
under investigation.
General,
you have to do something.
What can I do?
I told you, but you wouldn't believe me.
We're being sent to work.
We thought they were killing 10 of us
for the one fascist killed.
But now there's 20 of us.
The general couldn't
care less about us.
Don't you get it?
He's a hero.
We're here because of him
and the other would-be heroes
among you.
You could have been spared,
but not you!
You thought you'd win the war
by dropping a few bombs
and killing eight Germans?
Well, I’m not to blame.
I didn't do anything!
It's a general's duty to be a hero.
That's what you're paid for.
In fact, I paid you.
I happen to be a taxpayer.
You needn't take it so hard.
We'll work a few days and -
No, I didn't do anything!
Open up! I want out!
You should be ashamed.
Why? Because I don't
want to die?
I didn't do anything!
- Neither did we.
- But you're Jews.
- That's right.
Don't get worked up.
You say you did nothing -
It's true.
I did nothing.
That's the problem.
You did nothing.
Why not? The world's been
at war for five years.
Millions have died. Hundreds
of cities have been leveled.
And you did nothing.
You should
have done something,
taken one side or the other.
You wanted to be in the midst
of it all and do nothing
but worry about your business.
In fact, you told me
you made handsome profits
while others were dying.
Very convenient!
Now I see why you don't
want to be executed
without having done anything.
- What did you do?
- Not much.
But I did my duty,
because that's what matters:
doing your duty
no matter what happens.
If everyone had done that,
maybe we wouldn't be here.
My Jewish brothers...
there's no hope for us now.
Let us pray to God.
Our Father who art in heaven...
Who'd have thought
we'd meet in here?
I waited a long time
for the piano tuner to arrive.
I wouldn't say
I'm a bank clerk,
but I'm not much better.
I was never a soldier,
but I found myself in charge
of thousands of men.
I was able to bear
such an enormous responsibility
because I believed
I was fighting for a better world.
Will we live to see it?
Will others?
I think so.
Excuse me, General.
I want to send my wife a message,
but there's no pen or paper.
I want to ask her to forgive me
for having abandoned her,
for Ieaving her
and my children alone.
I want to ask forgiveness
for making her suffer
and tell her to be strong.
I want to tell her I’ve always
loved her and the children,
even if I couldn't show it...
and to get my money back
from the mechanic,
and that I gave the bike
to Giulia's brother.
She should get it back
and sell it for a good price.
And when better times come,
she should take the children
to see my parents.
They've never met
their grandparents.
Piperno, Samuele.
Ontani, Mario.
Albertini, Luciano.
Sinigallia, Leone.
Pasquali, Antonio.
Cohen, Davide.
Marconi, Paolo.
Leggi, Abele.
Funaro, Davide.
Di Castro, Giuseppe.
Giovanni Braccioforte
Della Rovere.
Go ahead.
Well? Did he talk?
Do you know who he is?
- Who?
- What do you mean? Fabrizio.
Is he one of them?
He must have talked to you.
During a night like this,
a man confides in his companions.
How would you know?
Have you ever spent
a night like this?
Did he talk or didn't he?
Do you know who he is?
Do you have a pencil, Colonel?
PIease deliver these few words
to Countess Della Rovere.
Open up.
Open up!
MY LAST THOUGHTS ARE WITH YOU.
LONG LIVE ITALY.
Bardone!
Open up.
Look!
What are you doing?
They're going to die!
Gentlemen,
in these final moments,
we remember our families,
our country,
and His Majesty the King.
Long live Italy!
We made a mistake, sir.
Ten men were supposed
to be executed.
The mistake was mine,
Lieutenant.
All mine.
Grant them eternal rest,
O Lord,
and may everlasting light
shine upon them.
May they rest in peace, amen.
Out of the depths
have I cried unto thee, O Lord.
Lord, hear my voice.
Let thine ears be attentive
to the voice of my supplications.