You didn't go to Boston.
No.
I tell that prick
I'm gonna have 1000 bucks,
I'm gonna have a thou.
I'm still 50 bucks short.
What's that got to do with anything?
Everything.
Business is business.
You gotta keep your word.
Your word is your reputation.
You lose your reputation,
and you're out of business.
Well, you're not talking about business,
you're talking about your own ego.
Ego, reputation, what's the difference?
Well, that's what I just said.
So, anyway,
looks like my customers are just gonna
have to wait till I get me 50 bucks.
Good.
Good? Shit.
Rich broads.
You never had to make
a buck in your life.
I have to go out and hustle every day.
What are you doing?
Just sitting there in the
bathtub on your fat ass.
We ain't got nothing here.
We can't move.
And we ain't got much left in
the old cookie jar either.
But, Frank, you promised...
Maybe we could stay off of the hard
stuff for a while and just smoke.
Yeah, yeah, but when I make this deal,
we ain't even gonna
have to leave the house.
We can just groove and groove.
You can go down and get yourself a
year's supply of peanut butter.
I can get the hi-fi out of hock.
I can go down to Netty's
and get me some brushes
and some paints and an easel
and a mile of canvas.
Who paints?
I paint.
You know I love you.
You got love, you don't need this stuff.
Is that the message?
Well, I love you, too.
So there.
You know, I was only kidding.
About your painting.
I really like your paintings.
You're not gonna take that
much yourself, are you?
You want a poke?
No.
You didn't ask me where I was today.
Where do you think I was?
Did you think I was with some other guy?
I went to my parents'.
What the hell did you go there for?
Well, it was near, my mother's
birthday was coming up, and
I don't like to be here all
by myself when you're away.
And anyhow... Well, why should
that freak you out so much?
It freaks me out.
You know it freaks me out.
How about some music?
Here.
It's okay.
You don't have to do it for me.
I understand about your parents.
That's got nothing to do with my parents.
Come on, Frank, let's make love.
Ouch!
That fucking radiator.
When are you gonna move the bed?
Where are you going?
I'm gonna get me that 50 bucks.
That's crummy.
You promised you weren't
gonna do that anymore.
You want me to sell them
our stuff, do you?
No!
So, instead of a trip, the teeny
boppers get vitamin pills.
I'm doing them a favor.
Shit. With a line like that,
I could run for mayor.
Frank, please don't go. I...
I don't feel very good.
Frank!
You'll be okay. I'll be right back.
It can't take too long.
Pop one up if you have to.
You'll feel great. See you.
How do I know it's any good, man?
It's so good, you'll
wish it wasn't so good.
I got beat last week.
That was last week.
Now is now.
How about a taste up front?
Sorry, man.
No samples.
It's too good.
Well, let me see it, man, okay?
Sure.
Here's a satisfied customer.
I don't need that, man.
Sit down.
Look, she's
a bum tripper.-
If your head's on straight,
like yours is, it's a groove.
It's dynamite.
It's you.
I'm hip.
You're a big help.
Frank, I don't feel so good.
Shit.
Take it.
No.
I said, take it.
Take it.
Now, go home.
Fifteen minutes, you'll be floating.
I just have one more pass to make,
and then I can
get the stuff. Okay?
And stop being such a drag,
for Christ's sakes!
Hey, honey, what are you doing?
Hey, wait a minute. Hey!
Hey! Take it easy.
Let me...
You'll be all right. You'll be...
Nobody's gonna hurt you.
Easy, easy, easy.
Let go.
Easy.
Nobody's going to hurt you.
That's it.
Hello, Sergeant O'Connor? Mr. Miller
from the 2nd Avenue bargain store.
Fine, sir.
Well, we have a young girl
here who's flipped out.
Looks like she's OD'd on speed.
Hippie.
You better send an ambulance.
2nd and 7th.
Right.
Boy, you've got a weird
sense of humor, Sergeant.
Yes, sir.
Thank you. Goodbye.
She's coming down now
from the amphetamine.
One hundred milligrams of Thorazine
in the butt does wonders.
If you want her effects, you can
pick them up from the property room.
Would you like to see her now?
Yes. Yes, please, very much.
You won't have to stay here.
No, no, darling, you're
going to River Crest.
It's a beautiful place, not like here.
No locked doors.
And Dr. Bergman said you
could be out within a week.
And when you come home, darling,
we'll all go someplace.
Maybe the islands.
Frank would understand.
Now, look, Melissa, honey...
When you come out, we'll try again.
You know what I mean, talk it over and...
Maybe we haven't been
as open as we could.
We'll work it out, honey.
It'll be okay.
I don't think this is such a good idea.
You wanna go back?
I'll do it myself.
No, she'll be furious.
Well, now that she's out
of this environment,
maybe she'll come to her senses.
Good luck.
The smell, Bill, I'm getting
sick to my stomach.
I don't want to go up there. I don't...
I don't want to see it.
Christ! Will you
stop bitching?
This is your own daughter.
Couldn't you just once in your
life do something for her
without looking for some
convenient excuse not to do it?
Why, you bastard!
I'll say this for you, you're
consistent, you don't change.
Go to hell. And you
can do it yourself.
All right, I will.
It's no novelty.
Keep going, and make a right.
Okay.
Who's got 10 bucks?
No, wait a minute, let's see it first.
Sure.
Is it any good?
Yeah, yeah, it's dynamite. Dynamite.
You sure?
Yeah, yeah, would I kid you?
Look here.
Yeah.
Okay.
Ten bucks.
How long will it last?
As long as you want.
Depends on your head.
If we take it now, will
we be okay on the street?
Sure, sure, anywhere you want.
Have fun.
Yeah, thanks.
Hey, what's your name, man?
The Lone Ranger.
Okay, well, you go first.
No, that's okay, you can go first.
All right, scaredy-cat, here.
Who are you?
Melissa's in the hospital.
I'm picking up her clothes.
You're Daddy.
I should've recognized the nose.
How's she doing?
Why?
You want to bring her some more pills?
Don't sweat the small
stuff, she'll be okay.
And Melissa told us you were handsome.
Rugged, she said.
Strong.
Intense.
With great talent.
Yeah?
Yes.
But as far as I can see,
you're a weak little bastard
who couldn't paint
his way out of a toilet.
How's things in the advertising world?
We can't all be geniuses.
How are your toasters doing?
You know, Melissa's got a
real hang-up about you.
You done a real groovy job on her.
That's pretty good, from what
Melissa says about her old lady.
I see you still got some balls.
You shut up!
She's got a real thing about you.
When I met her, she was balling her
way up the aisle at the film...
Shut up!
And every now and then, she used
to like to try an old codger.
Shut up, you bastard!
You bastard!
You...
Get up! Get up, you filthy fucker!
Get up!
My God.
Jesus!
The niggers.
The niggers are getting all the money.
Why work? You tell me,
why the fuck work
when you can screw, have
babies, and get paid for it?
Welfare. They got all
that welfare money.
They even get free rubbers.
Think they use them?
Hell, no. The only way they
make money is making babies.
They sell the rubbers
and then they use the money to buy booze.
Nobody has a right to booze
unless he earns the money.
It ought to be a law. You
don't work, you don't drink.
Yeah, the social workers,
the ones in welfare,
how come they're all nigger-lovers?
You ever notice that?
All those social workers
are nigger-lovers.
You find me a social worker who ain't a
nigger-lover and I'll massage your asshole.
I ain't queer.
Scotch and water.
Double for 90 cents, you save a dime.
I sweat my balls off 40 hours a
week in front of a fucking furnace,
and they get as much money
as I do, for nothing.
They got them living in
hotels at $50 a day,
$1,000 a month.
Now they want charge accounts.
Charge accounts.
I ain't even been inside Macy's,
and they want charge accounts.
All you gotta do is act black,
and the money rolls in.
Set fire to the cities, burn a few
buildings, you get paid for it.
Throw a few bombs,
you get money and jobs.
If you can't read, you got a
better chance of getting hired.
A lot of good my education did me.
And the kids, the white kids,
they're worse than the niggers.
Money don't mean nothing to them.
Motorcycles, marijuana, $5 records.
The dollar ain't worth shit.
I get a 30-cent-an-hour increase.
My wife bought better
hamburger last year.
I got a kid.
Screw him.
I got another kid.
Couldn't get into a regular college.
You want to know why?
My kid ain't dumb.
Couldn't get into college 'cause
they let the niggers in first.
That's how they're saving the cities.
They keep the smart niggers
busy wrecking the colleges.
Yeah, my kid's grades. Not
like those kids in Chicago.
Chicago!
They got no respect for the
President of the United States.
A few heads get bashed in,
they act like they got it in the ass.
Liberals.
Forty two percent of all
liberals are queer.
That's a fact.
The Wallace people took a poll.
And don't tell me about communists.
How can a kid be a communist?
Kids are idealistic.
Yes, PQ3 please.
They used to be idealistic.
Now they're going to those peace marches.
This is William Compton. Could you
tell me how my daughter is, please?
Melissa Compton. They're
so whacked out on drugs,
they gotta have candles to
see where they're going.
Well...
When will he be back?
The white kids.
Would you ask him to call me, please?
The rich white kids.
Yes, the number here is 7-2-4...
The worst, hippies.
Sugar tit all the way.
The cars, the best colleges,
vacations, orgies...
Yes, William Compton.
Christmas, Easter.
Thank you.
They go to someplace, like a
fancy resort, and have orgies.
Easter orgies.
The day Christ rose, they're
all screwing one another.
And the poor kids and
the middle-class kids,
they're all copying the rich kids.
They're all going the same
goddamn "screw America" way.
Hippies.
Joe. Joe, do me a favor.
Give us all a break.
Can it a while?
Here's a quarter.
Go play the juke box, okay?
Want to do it again?
What's the matter, Joe?
You got all those opinions,
and you can't pick a record?
Look at this shit music.
Those goddamn nigger-loving hippies,
they even fucked up the music.
I'd like to get my hands on
one of those little bastards.
I'd kill them. I'd like
to kill one of them.
They're getting away with murder.
Sex, drugs,
pissing on America, fucking up the music.
I'd like to kill one of them.
I would.
I just did.
Glad to hear it.
Hey, you're serious!
You're really serious!
For Christ's sake, you...
You had me going for it,
you had me believing you.
Jesus, you're a great kidder, mac.
You had me going for it. I went for it.
You're putting me on. Terrific.
What are you drinking?
Hey, Pete, give this guy a drink.
No kidding, you're all right, mac.
My name is Joe, Joe Curran.
What's yours?
Anyone here called William Compton?
He's all right, you know what I mean?
Anybody who can set me in like that...
Hello?
Anybody who can make me laugh...
Yes.
They're all right, you know?
Doctor?
She is?
Good. Good.
Yes, yes.
Tell her.
This world needs a lot of laughs.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
You know? You gotta be able
to laugh, to roll with it.
You know?
Hey, Compton, I bought you a drink.
What is this?
Where have you been?
Bill?
What in the world happened?
Where are Melissa's things?
What's wrong?
Look at yourself, darling. What happened?
Honey, you about ready to go to bed?
Yeah, I'm gonna watch
the 11:00 news.
Well, I'm gonna go on now.
Okay.
Okay, come on,
whore. Do it.
Come on, come on in there, get
it in there, come on, bitch.
Bastard. Get in there, you bastard.
Hi, honey.
What's for supper?
Guess.
Come on.
No, guess.
For Christ's sake, tell me.
It's on the stove, look.
You got covers on, come on.
We're having mashed potatoes,
the way you like them, lumpy,
and a nice piece of chuck
steak, the way you like it,
with onions and ketchup.
Heinz?
Yes, I'll never do that again,
buy the supermarket kind.
You're right about ketchup.
That's my girl.
And a nice piece of Jane
Parker chocolate fudge cake.
You know, I tell the guys
what a good cook you are.
You know, my sandwiches
are better than theirs.
How was Samantha Cartwright today?
Well, she wasn't on so very much,
but a lot happened to her.
She's in the hospital
having her kidneys removed.
And while she's in the
hospital, her daughter, Kim,
is being seduced by a lawyer,
and her son, Biff, is getting a little
crushed in an elevator accident.
And it looks like her husband, Derek.
Her husband is interested
in her best friend, Phoebe.
While she's having her...
While she's having her kidneys taken out,
you see the knife going in,
Derek gives Phoebe such a look.
That woman, she has such courage.
That's my favorite program,
The Searching Light.
How was Mabel Archer?
Well, looks like things
are looking up for her.
Looks like she's gonna have
a father for her baby.
Yeah, the guy who knocked her
up, he's gonna marry her?
No!
The guy she's in love with?
No. The gentleman she
met at the drugstore.
It looks like something's
happening between them.
What happened down the block?
The boys are out.
I see the boys are out.
What happened?
Well... Brian has a date with Patty,
the girl who wears the Indian headband?
She wears an Indian headband. Mary
Lou, are you gonna answer me?
Well...
They moved in.
They don't look so bad for colored, Joe.
Joe, what are you gonna do?
Shit, where's Phil?
He's out riding. He picked up
the Harley-Davidson today.
He got it? Shit.
I'm going to go downstairs. Call me.
Well, Joe, it's... It's not gonna
be very long. It's just gonna...
black militants abroad.
Overseas agents of the Federal
Bureau of Investigation
and the Bureau of Narcotics
and Dangerous Drugs
originally scheduled for reduction...
The van came
about 11:00.
They got nice furniture for colored.
They have a real nice Castro
and a fancy bedroom suite.
The kids are cute.
They're clean, too.
New York's Greenwich Village.
Police today discovered the body...
I think they're real high-class colored.
Of a 23-year-old youth
brutally beaten to death...
They're different.
In an apartment on East 4th.
Hold on, hold it.
The young man, Frank Russo,
had been dead for 3 days
according to the medical examiner.
I think he's not going to be... Shut up!
Russo, sometime painter, had been selling
drugs recently, the police said.
Investigation revealed that he
had picked up a large shipment
the day that he was killed.
Police believe Russo
was killed by a junkie,
who then fled with the drugs.
Detectives say there are no leads
to the killer at the present time.
Albany. Federal State
crime investigators
are expected to serve a number of
subpoenas on state government figures
possibly involved with illegal
activities of the mafia.
The subpoenaed witnesses will be ordered
to appear before two grand juries
probing malfeasance and bribery.
Mr. Compton's office.
Hello, Mr. Compton,
please.
Joe Curran.
Yeah, you do that.
Yes?
There's a Mr. Curran
on the line.
Who?
Joe Curran.
I don't know him.
Tell him I'm busy.
Mr. Compton is
in conference.
Look, you just tell him that Joe Curran,
the guy he met in the bar the other
night and bought him a drink...
Tell him I wanna talk to him now.
Very well.
What?
He says he met you in a bar the
other night and bought you a drink.
Okay, I'll talk to him.
Hello?
Hello, Compton.
Listen, I wanna see you.
How did you get my number?
You're the only one in the book.
The maid gave me your office.
Look, Compton, we got to get together.
Look, you meet me at the
Bowladrome around 6:00.
That's Camwood and Grant
Street in Astoria.
Around 6:00, okay?
Okay?
Yes, yes, yes, okay.
I'll see you then.
Okay.
Compton!
Hey! Over here.
Hey, you look okay, pal.
Hey, everybody, listen.
I want you to meet a great guy.
This guy's got real balls,
not no bowling balls.
This is Jack, Sam, Michael, he don't
like to be called Mike, and Art.
Hey, you like to bowl a frame?
Come on. Come on.
I bet you ain't had much
exercise for a couple of days?
Here we go.
Hey, you creeps, this guy's
gonna bowl a frame for me.
Come on, come on, show these bums.
My shoes, street shoes.
Fuck the shoes.
Come on.
Hey, Joe...
Maybe your buddy ought to stick to golf.
Golf?
Screw it, forget it.
This game's for morons, anyway.
Come on, you guys
got chalk in your brains.
Hey, Jack, finish the
string for me, will you?
Come on, I wanna talk to you.
Couple of beers, please, Sylvia.
Catch you later.
You know when it hit me?
When I saw the paper.
The TV started me thinking.
The paper, I knew.
Couldn't get over it.
I couldn't get over it.
Why?
Why did you call me?
I wanted to meet you.
Hey, I know what you've been thinking.
You been thinking I was going to put
the old squeeze on you, didn't you?
That's what you been thinking, right?
Yes.
Well, the...
The thought had occurred to me.
Yeah, well...
I could blackmail you.
Hey! Hey, don't
worry about it.
I just wanted to shake your hand.
I mean, look.
There I am, sitting in a bar.
You know, drunk, and shooting off.
Just words.
You know, and you come in.
And you did it!
You did it.
I just talk about it, but you did it!
I mean... Look.
When I get drunk, you know,
I let off a lot of steam.
Drink up.
I know a better place.
Thank you.
Listen, nobody's gonna blame you.
A guy like that, your daughter.
Look, to plenty of people,
people with kids,
I'm telling you, you'd be a hero.
The guy was selling dope, right?
So now he can't make dope fiends
out of anybody anymore, can he?
Yeah, that's right.
God knows how many kids he hooked.
Maybe...
Maybe that's why I get this...
I had it a couple
of times lately. A...
A feeling of...
Pleasure?
Satisfaction.
Yeah, yeah, like in the war.
You remember how you felt
in the war sometimes,
after you killed a few of 'em?
You feel bad and you feel
good at the same time?
Yes, well, something like that.
But not exactly.
You make a lot of money.
How much?
What do you... What do you make an hour?
Well, they... They pay
us by the year, Joe.
I get...
I get four an hour,
plus some that I don't count because,
you know, the union keeps it.
That's 160 a week.
That ain't so bad.
It's not so bad.
I mean, shit, you can't live on it.
What do you make?
Sixty thousand.
Sixty thousand dollars a year!
You gotta be kidding.
Only movie stars make that kind of money.
The fucking president of my union
pays himself that kind of money.
Sixty thousand a year.
You gotta kiss a lot of ass, I bet.
Well, after a while,
you don't notice it anymore.
You think I don't have to kiss ass?
Four dollars an hour?
The foreman, the shop steward,
the guy on the night shift so he
don't leave my furnace a mess.
Bet you got a pile saved up.
No, not really a pile, Joe, only about...
Eighteen thousand.
Eighteen thousand, the
kind of money you make?
Hey, I got 10,000.
My wife don't know it.
Yeah, and two lots in Florida.
Hey.
Hey, look at that.
Look at that.
Nice?
I like to look at 'em once in a while.
You like to look at 'em once in a while?
Yes, I like to look at
it once in a while.
A little on the side once in a while?
Once in a while.
It helps, you know, so you don't
resent the old lady so much.
Right?
You know, guys like us,
we don't often get a chance
to talk to each other.
Find it hard talking to me?
No.
Yes, you do.
I'm just a working stiff,
and you're way up there.
Educated.
Well, look.
Just talk to me the way you would,
somebody at the office,
a friend, like that.
Joe,
would you like to see where
my kind of animal hangs out?
Sure.
Good. Then let's get
the hell out of here.
They look like a bunch of fags.
Not really fags,
but close, getting there.
What would you like, sir?
Johnnie Walker on the rocks and...
The same.
Yeah, but they're smart. They're smart.
They gotta be smart, right?
Joe, you wanna see how smart
they really are? Watch.
Bill, Bill, baby, how are you?
Gil! It's good
to see you.
Gil, I'd like you to meet Joe Curran.
This is, Gil Richards, Joe.
Happy to meet you.
Same here.
By the way, Gil, Joe here is...
Shall I tell him, Joe?
Yeah. Yeah.
Well, it...
It hasn't been officially announced yet,
but, Joe here is moving
over to your shop.
Yeah?
What...
What spot?
Guess.
Hell, I don't know.
Which...
Come on, Gil.
What have they been looking for
over there for three months?
Exec VP?
That's it.
Yeah, I know he looks a little rough,
but that's just part of his act.
He'll, be looking things over
pretty closely over there.
Getting rid of a lot of dead wood.
You'll be shaking things up
over there, won't you, Joe?
Yeah, I'll be shaking things up.
That place is gonna shake like
a hurricane and a tree hit it.
Well, when you come in,
drop by my office.
Nah, why don't you drop by my office?
Yeah, yeah, sure.
Well, I'll see you.
Joe, look, no hands.
Doctor's orders.
Can't lift anything
heavier than 10 pounds.
Hey, they got ice down there.
Yes.
Hey, I never pissed on ice before.
Well, don't catch cold.
I'll try not to.
Feels good!
This is one of nature's
simple enjoyments.
God.
I needed that, you know?
After you, my...
My dear Alphonse.
All right.
Now, you see those buildings, Joe?
Yeah.
Those beautiful monuments.
Concrete, glass.
I work in one of them.
And do you know what they
do in those buildings, Joe?
They move paper.
That's right. They pick
it up in one place,
and they move it to another place.
They pass it all around their offices.
And the more paper you move,
the more important you are,
the more they pay you.
And if you want to really
show how important you are,
what you can get away with,
you make little paper airplanes,
and you sail them right
up somebody else's ass.
Do you ever get the feeling that
everything you do,
your whole life,
just one big crock of shit?
Yeah.
Hey, I got a great idea.
Wanna go hunting?
Hunting?
Yeah.
I haven't gone hunting in years.
Hey, I got a great place, you know. Yeah?
You should've seen the buck
I got last year, big one.
Hey, you know what else
you gotta do? What?
You gotta come out to the house,
you gotta meet the little woman.
You gotta have a little dinner with us,
see how the other half lives, okay?
Okay, Joe.
Okay, Compton?
It's a deal.
Take care, Compton, and...
Just remember, you don't have
anything to worry about, okay?
Now you won't believe this, darling,
but I have just been
with a guy who knows.
What?
It's all right.
He likes me.
Rest up. The doctor said
only a few more days.
I'll see you tomorrow, okay?
Okay.
Goodbye, darling.
Bye, Mother.
Say goodbye to Daddy for me.
Excuse me.
Yes, surely.
Hi.
Phyllis! Well,
how'd you ever find me?
Spies.
Hey, you don't look so bad.
Well, I could look a lot worse.
My mother was just here.
She's been here every day, twice a day.
Twice a day?
Well, she can't be that bad.
You ought to meet my mother.
Well, so how's Frank?
Stop it, for Christ's sake! You'd
think the Pope was coming!
Joe, what am I gonna talk to her about?
For God's sake!
You never had any trouble
talking with the girls.
Shutting you up was the problem.
Joe, I didn't dust.
Look, look, look, you buy
curtains, she buys curtains.
I give you a few bucks
in Gimbels, you go crazy,
you give her a few bucks
in Gimbels, she goes crazy.
She doesn't shop at Gimbels, Joe.
Okay, she goes to Macy's.
Women got a lot to talk
about, they think.
Relax.
It won't be any worse than the
time your rich aunt came over.
The one who didn't leave us any money.
- Hi.
- Joe.
Hi, come in. Mary Lou's
been dying to meet you.
Mary Lou, this is Bill Compton.
It's a pleasure.
Hello.
My wife, Joan.
How do you do?
Hello.
Nice knowing you.
Here, let me take your coats.
Take their coats, honey.
Let me help.
Sure.
My best friend in high
school was named Mary Lou.
I loved her name. I
always wished I had it.
I hated mine.
Well, you've got a nice name, Joan.
Thank you.
Well, I'll just be a minute.
Well, I can see we're gonna
get along real good.
What'll you have, a Bud or a 7 and 7?
Bud or 7 and 7?
We got ginger ale, too.
Yes, how will you have your
Seagram's Seven Crown, dear?
Ginger ale or 7UP?
Ginger ale's fine, thank you.
Ginger ale, beautiful.
And for the gentleman?
Bud.
Bud, the king of beers.
Where's the ginger ale?
Under the sink.
I thought you keep it on the shelf.
Well, I do keep it on the
shelf, but I just...
Did you have any trouble
finding the place?
No, no, Joe. Your
instructions were perfect.
Terrific.
Joe?
Yeah.
Pretty nice place you got here.
Yeah, it's not much.
You never told me you had a girlfriend
named Mary Lou in high school.
I made it up.
God.
You can be charming when you wanna be.
I hope you don't mind the can.
No. it helps
to keep them fresh.
Nice nuts.
No thanks.
I mustn't spoil my appetite.
Do you mind if I shut the window?
No, go right ahead.
I love your curtains.
Thank you.
See, what'd I tell you?
They was... They were 49 cents a yard,
reduced from 79.
I made 'em myself.
And the saleslady told me that
Debbie Reynolds had been in,
and she bought the
same kind of material...
That's enough.
Well, the...
She was wondering what you
was gonna talk about.
I told her you was both women.
That's right.
We're all alike.
What'd you mean by that?
That's the restaurant.
We're gonna have something
real special for dinner.
Chinese.
Lou Wong's is the best Chinese...
The best Chinese restaurant in Astoria.
I hope you like Chinese food.
I love it.
Yes, yes.
Love it.
Joe, give me the box.
They look better when they're
all lined up here together.
The boys just hate Chinese
food, that's why they're out.
Hell, that's not why they're not home.
They're never home,
not even the good one.
Joe's real funny about the boys.
He likes 'em right here when he comes in.
What he'd like is to
have 'em all lined up,
military fashion, in the
doorway when he comes home,
saying, "Hi, Pop."
Yeah.
I was really sorry to
hear about your daughter.
Is she okay?
She's fine, thank you.
Kids.
Everything today is kids.
They make you feel so
old-fashioned, you know?
We made... We made our parents
feel old-fashioned, but...
We didn't make 'em feel old-fashioned
like the kids make us feel old-fashioned.
Everything today is kids.
They are taking over the culture.
The what?
The culture. The movies,
books, clothes, music.
Yeah, yeah.
They're all screwed up, so they got
control of the culture, right?
They're all screwed up, so
they're screwing up the culture.
Yeah, it ain't what the kids
say, that we screwed them up.
It's the other way around,
with all that culture crap.
It's the kids who are screwing us up.
Am I right?
Yes, of course.
Fucking A.
You mean, she knows you killed a junkie?
Yes, she knows.
What'd you do, go and tell her?
No.
She figured it out, just as you did.
Christ. Here, here.
Hey, no, no.
What are you doing?
Don't worry, don't worry, relax.
Hey, Joan, I got something
I wanna show you.
Joe, she don't wanna see your guns.
Sure she does, it'll just take a minute.
What the hell did you go and do that for?
Don't worry, you'll see.
Look, it's not the gun.
I just wanted... Wanted to
get you away from Mary Lou.
See, look, look.
I want to tell you not
to worry about a thing,
see, 'cause nothing's
gonna happen to you.
Nothing.
Your husband's a great guy,
and nothing's gonna happen to him.
See, now, the police in this town
ain't gonna bust their ass
over one junkie murder.
See, a guy who kills one junkie
might kill another junkie.
So why bust him? He's doing such
good work for the cops, see?
That make you feel better?
Yes, thank you.
Okay, now I want you to go
upstairs, and I want you to relax,
and I want you to enjoy
yourself with Mary Lou, okay?
I got here what you might call
a well-balanced gun collection, see?
I wrote a letter to an ammo magazine
and they wrote back, saying,
"You got a well-balanced
collection." See?
Now, this I got off a Jap,
a dead Jap on Okinawa.
Then I got...
Here, hold this.
Here is my old M1.
Now, there's a lot of stories
behind that, believe me.
Right on the park?
Yes, it is lovely.
We have a beautiful view.
I never been in an apartment
like that before, never.
I always wondered what it'd be like,
what it'd look like on the inside.
I always wanted to see.
We'll have you and Joe up one day.
You will?
Yes, of course.
That'd be nice.
What about next week?
Tuesday, Saturday...
Saturday'd be good for us.
I got a lot of other
stuff over here, too.
Got some handguns, some shotguns.
I got a couple of trophies
there for marksmanship.
I'm a real good shot.
But this...
This is my beauty.
It's a submachine gun.
You're not supposed to have
'em, but I got one anyway.
You can do a lot of damage with this.
It's got a lot of stopping power.
Thanks for
letting me in, Mr. Hancock.
Before we were finished,
we practically worked out
a full year's social calendar.
I think we have a free weekend
sometime in April or May.
Are you ready to put him
up for the Athletic Club?
Well...
I wouldn't mind letting him sit in
on one of our creative sessions.
And let him tell everybody what
a bunch of windbags they are.
He wouldn't put it quite like that.
Hell, you know, after years
of nothing but ad types,
Mary Lou, Joe, they're
a refreshing change.
Refreshing?
Well...
Different?
That's for sure.
Lord, I've been in grisly
situations before, but this...
Sitting in that room,
him knowing about Frank,
and you and me knowing about Frank,
and big-eyed Mary Lou yammering away.
Does he know all the
gory details, darling?
No.
When I think...
I just get the shudders.
When you think that man holds
our lives in his hand,
it's like sitting on a powder keg.
A couple of times tonight,
I said something,
and he was just about to explode.
If he gets mad at you, darling,
do you know he can go
straight to the police?
No, no, you see...
The crazy thing about Joe is that
it's as if he shared in it.
As if he killed that boy, too.
You have to keep on the good side of him.
Isn't that what we were
really doing there tonight?
Well, there's
something else about Joe.
Sometimes, with him,
I almost feel as if
what I did was a humanitarian act.
I saved the world from
another lousy junkie.
Funny, isn't it?
What?
How you can learn to live with anything.
Even murder.
I'll drink to that.
Melissa.
How did you get out of the hospital?
Why didn't you tell me about Frank?
Why didn't you tell me Frank was dead?
Because we didn't want to upset you.
Not while you were in the hospital.
Is that the reason?
Certainly, you were
just coming down from the drugs.
Or was the subject too painful?
I heard you, Daddy.
You killed Frank.
And I loved him.
I loved him.
Melissa!
You stay here.
I'll get her.
Melissa!
I wanted to tell you.
I wanted to tell you how it happened.
It doesn't matter. It
happened, that's all.
You might understand.
No!
Melissa.
Leave me alone!
You've got to listen to me.
Are you gonna kill me, too?
"There is some consternation
in these quarters"
"about the allocation
of spots to stations."
"I'd like you to reexamine them from
the point of view of demographics"
"and market proceedings."
Paragraph.
"I know this puts you under pressure,
but we'd like it within a week."
"I'll commiserate with you
over drinks." Signature.
And, Janine,
I know my behavior has been a
little erratic the last few days.
Well, it's,
likely to continue so
for a little while longer.
You know, running in
and out of the office.
So, just keep covering for me, will you?
I always do.
Thank you.
- Yes.
- Mr. Curran for you.
Put him on.
Hiya, Compton.
Joe, hold it a minute, will you?
That'll be all,
Janine. Thank you.
Joe, I've been meaning to call you.
About tomorrow night, it's...
Well, it...
It looks as if we're just not
gonna be able to make it.
Yeah?
Melissa ran away from the hospital.
She found out what happened.
Found out?
How could she find out?
Well, I'll tell you when I see you.
I've been down in the Village
every night trying to find her.
Look, I'll go with you.
I'm falling off my feet.
I was thinking about getting
to bed early tonight.
No, no, no. You can't stop looking.
You gotta keep looking.
Compton, it'll be easier for you if
you got company. I'll go with you.
Okay, I'll meet you down in
the Village around 8:00.
There's a parking lot at
Bowery and East 5th Street.
Okay. Okay,
I'll see you.
Bye, Joe.
This could be a long night.
That's all right, that's all right.
I been wanting to see these
animals, where they live.
Okay.
Let's go.
It's colder than a witch's tit out.
Say, mister, you got any spare change?
No, but I know where there's a spare job.
Dumb honky.
Hey, I like that. That guy,
he never got that before.
Used to be, you had to
be 40 or 50 years old
before you could become
a bum on the streets.
Look at that shit.
Cowboys and Indians.
Well, they grew up on television.
Hopalong Cassidy at the age of three.
Hopalong Cassidy.
Real revolutionaries.
Let's go in here.
The Caldron?
Yeah, she used to mention this place.
Maybe she'll come in.
How's that for a half-assed idea?
All I know is, I need a drink.
There's some room in the back,
but you have to take your shoes off.
Take off your shoes?
What is that bullshit?
Well, when in Rome...
What? What do
you mean?
You do as the Romans do.
Yeah.
Hey, look at these creeps.
He looks like a truck driver.
What's that word they got?
"Grooving"? "Groovy"?
If they're not screwing,
they're grooving.
Screwing and grooving.
Good evening, gentlemen.
Would you like to order?
You got Imperial?
Sorry, we don't serve alcohol here.
You don't serve alcohol here?
Well, what do you serve?
We serve shrimp tempura,
kakiage, miso soup.
That's Jap food.
Not really.
It's macrobiotic.
It's food in accordance with
the order of the universe.
Looks a little bit like Susie.
No, her eyes are different.
She doesn't look a thing like Susie.
At least they still got booze.
Come on, kids.
Melissa Compton, she's about
5'8", about 20 years old,
auburn hair.
Melissa Compton.
No, mister.
Hey, why don't you get a haircut?
Joe...
Joe, take it easy.
No, can't say that I see this one.
Why don't you put it up on bulletin
board behind you with note?
Here is paper.
You have pencil?
Yes, thank you.
Maybe she come in and see.
Yes, maybe she will.
You know that stuff they got at Niagara
Falls, the Empire State Building?
Pennants, pens, gimmicks?
I tell Mary Lou not to buy that stuff.
It's junk.
She buys it anyway.
This stuff, what's the difference?
Junk is junk, right?
All I know is these fucking kids
are getting more than we ever did.
Look at that. The President
of the United States.
If you can't buy a used car from him,
who can you buy a used car from?
Hey, guys, I'm gonna split.
See you up there later?
Yeah, sure, we'll see you there.
Great, peace.
Well, let's get something
to eat, for Christ's sake.
At least it's warm here.
It's pretty hopeless, isn't it?
What?
I said, it's hopeless.
Yeah.
Yeah, you gotta hang in
there, you know what I mean?
You can't give up.
Hey, the truck driver digs you.
Obviously, he's got good taste.
Hey, you wanna turn a trick?
That's lovely.
A hippie pimp?
I'm gonna put those guys on.
Hi.
You guys looking for some, grass, maybe?
I got all I need, sonny.
You kidding?
You really have some?
From the junkie. Still have
it in the trunk of my car.
You know what that guy said?
I said, "You guys looking
for some grass?"
You yo-yo, they could
be narcs or something.
Nah, they ain't narcs.
I know narcs.
Narcs have long hair.
I thought we could lay some
oregano on them or something.
They wouldn't know the difference.
So the old guy says, "I've
got all I need, sonny."
Suppose he's serious?
Guys like that?
They wouldn't have grass.
Nobody's got grass.
Sure.
Hey, man, you putting me on?
You really got some grass?
Yeah, that's what I said.
Well, we're having a little party.
We could all smoke some, at
one of the chicks' pads.
No, thanks.
It'd be pretty groovy,
if you know what I mean.
I know what you mean.
Hey, that's not such a bad idea.
What?
Well, we're not getting
no place this way.
This way, we get to know the kids.
You know, we get friendly,
we infiltrate them.
You know what I mean?
Then maybe they'll tell us
something about your daughter.
Just see.
You don't have to smoke the stuff.
Well, maybe you're right.
What have I got to lose?
What?
Well, then, let's go to the party.
Far fucking out! The grass
famine is finally over!
Hang on, you haven't seen anything.
This is fantastic.
You got that record on
pretty fucking loud.
I'm sorry, do you want
me to turn it down?
Yeah.
All right.
You know I read in Mechanix Illustrated
that sound can hurt your ears.
Yeah, I wouldn't wanna do that.
Acid, grass, look at this chunk of hash.
Coke, speed, psilocybin. Shit.
Am I gonna trip!
You're in the business?
No, no.
His mother is a junkie.
Solid.
Mary Lou ought to see this place.
She'd get some great decorating ideas.
Far out.
See if you can't
fit it into all your openings.
Your mouth, your nose,
your eyes, your ears...
It's the greatest fucking drug in the
whole world. You can fuck for hours.
Yeah. Definitely.
It's like a dream, you know?
It's like a... It's like
a drug-head's dream.
Come on, dance.
I can't.
Yes, you can, you just do anything,
anything at all.
Come on.
Think of this part as the
center of your body.
And just move it from the hips out.
You mean, that's where I
feel the music, down there?
Right, that's it, you're getting it.
From the balls out.
From the balls out, right?
Groovy, that's where it's at.
Here.
No, no.
No, thanks.
What's the matter? It won't kill you.
Chicken?
What you do is suck in deep,
and then hold it until it hurts.
You don't need to tell me. I
seen it on TV all the time.
I better sit down here, you know,
in case I get drunk or it
hits me all of a sudden.
Yeah, right.
I gotta sit down.
Man, it's no good, it's panda piss.
Come on. Get with
the Pepsi Generation.
You're kidding.
No. Chicken?
What do you mean, chicken?
Chickie, chickie.
Get...
You think I'm chicken?
All right.
You think I don't know how?
You watch this.
You think I'm chicken?
Yeah. Yeah.
All right, my friend.
I don't feel any different.
Free yourself.
I lived all my life, I ain't
never been to an orgy.
This is an orgy, isn't it?
Yes, it seems to fit the definition.
Fucking A.
They're touching.
The new sex.
Like eating.
Screwing like that,
you can't be very important.
Well, what you lose in importance,
you make up in frequency.
How do they fall in love?
It was better for you than for me.
Thanks a lot.
Can I have the dope?
Why don't you give the old guys a break?
Yeah, it's not a bad idea.
Hey!
I hope I'm not out of line.
If you want it that bad,
man, you can have it.
Well, take off your clothes.
I don't have to take my clothes off.
I can make it without
taking off my clothes.
If you want to make it with
me, take off your clothes.
Well...
Where we gonna do it?
Here?
I mean, you got another
bed, in another room?
You do have another bed in another room?
Your friend's pretty uptight, isn't he?
Mirrors.
Watching ourselves was as far
as my generation ever got.
You mean you never got
into whips or anything?
Socks, too.
Socks, too?
She's anti-fetish.
You...
You want me?
Why not?
You mean...
"What the world needs now,"
and all that sort of thing?
Something like that.
You just beat the world speed record.
Whose?
Making love, you know,
isn't the same thing as a 50-yard dash.
Well, what do you mean by that?
How you doing?
Never screwed on grass before?
That was...
Outrageous?
Outrageous.
Out. Way out.
Can I join you two?
He's all yours.
Fair enough.
Well, I'll buy that.
No preliminaries?
I don't need no preliminaries.
Get your clothes on.
I'm not going anywhere.
We're cutting out with
this bag of goodies.
That's a dirty trick.
Why should those pricks have it?
I mean Ronnie and Gail, leaving
them here with those guys.
They're big girls, they can
take care of themselves.
I want to...
I want to see you again.
I wanna get together again.
No.
No?
But you liked it.
I could tell you liked it.
Didn't you like it?
It was okay.
So I'll see you again.
No.
Listen, when something happens once,
it doesn't mean that
it has to happen again.
Well, then that's just a one-night stand.
Come on, you've had
one-night stands before.
Yeah... Yeah,
but I decided.
Wait a minute.
No, man, no.
That's too much.
Just the credit cards, man.
You're asking for the pigs.
Sell 'em.
What about a weekend?
Maybe, but I don't really think so.
Is that your way of saying no?
I guess so.
Compton!
Compton! Christ!
Hey, Compton!
Compton! Compton!
Compton! Hey, Compton!
Little pricks stole our wallets.
Our wallets?
Yeah, the drugs, too.
I'm gonna get 'em.
Get your pants on.
Where are they? Where'd they go?
Where'd your friends go?
Come on, bitch! I said, where are they?
Come on, come on, where did they go?
Where'd they go, bitch? Come on,
tell me, where did they go?
You gonna tell me, or am I gonna
beat the shit out of you?
Come on! Come on!
Look, we don't know.
The hell you don't.
Come on!
Come on, bitch, come on.
Come on, whore.
Come on, talk!
Talk!
Will you stop him?
Well, what are you protecting them for?
They didn't give a damn about you.
Come on, bitch, you want
me to hurt you now?
Look, they've got a
commune, in the country.
Where is it?
I don't know.
Tell me! Tell me!
Up Route 9, take it to the 18...
About five miles on Edgewood Road.
You know, if you're lying,
I can come back here.
I'm not lying.
Yeah, and I can finish what I started.
Got that?
Man, you just balled me,
and you don't believe me?
Wait a minute, Compton.
Joe, put them back.
No, no, just give 'em a little scare.
No.
Shake 'em up.
Hi.
Maybe you wanna give us back our stuff?
Yeah, yeah, sure.
Yeah, sure.
You got it all?
Where's the money?
My God.
What the hell you doing, Compton?
God, no, don't shoot me. I won't tell.
Don't shoot me.
Please, don't shoot me.
Please. Just...
I won't tell!
What are you gonna do?
You gonna shoot me?
I won't tell anybody, I promise.
Well, where's that gonna get you?
You wanna shoot somebody, shoot them.
Please, don't.
- Please.
- Look, Compton...
There's only one way out now. Clean.
That means everybody.
At this point it can get to be fun.
No more!
I don't get you, Compton.
You hate those kids.
You hate the way
those girls put you down.
You hate the way those kids,
those little shitheads,
they made a shithead out of you.
Guys like Frank.
What Frank did to your daughter.
No!
Look, Compton, you told me you
got a kick out of killing Frank.
These kids, they shit on you.
They shit on your life.
They shit on everything you believe in.
They shit on everything!
You hate 'em as much as I do.
No! No!
It's your ass now, Compton!
These kids, they shit on you.
They shit on your life.
They shit on everything you believe in.
They shit on everything.
You wanna shoot somebody, shoot them.
Are you gonna kill me, too?
Melissa!