Praesens Film Cinémathèque Suisse
and Swiss Radio and Television present
Book and screenplay
Directed by
Chief Operator, Assistant
Editor, Assistant
Music, Sound, Production Manager
Choir, Manager
Buildings, script, make-up artists, costumes, props, sea shots
Additional cast (including some French children)
12 June 1940
German armies approach the Seine. Rouen becomes a war zone.
The civilian population flees in panic.
You're taking too much, Mme. Fleury.
Why, you'll be back in a few days!
That's easy for you to say. They are alone.
You do not have to worry about anyone.
In 1914, everybody ran away, too.
But our brave soldiers held
at the battle of the Marne
- and they will hold again. - Indeed.
Your husband at the front believes...
Anyway, with General Weygand, we can't lose.
I believe we'll win.
- Absolutely. - Yes, yes.
The car still isn't there.
Don't worry. He'll come.
He should have arrived at 10pm. It's midnight.
It's detouring around the jammed streets.
You can't get through.
The streets are completely blocked.
Look at that.
Everyone's panicky.
- Excuse me. - What is it?
Excuse me, I can no longer
wait alone over there.
Where's the cart?
Come, madame. Sit down.
This has been going on for hours now,
getting closer, getting louder.
Surely they are already very close.
Do you hear the cannons?
Now you are not so scared.
The shots are coming from our artillery.
- Not so loud. - Because of the children?
Are Pierre and Marie-Louise ready?
Pierre is already in the country
and Marie-Louise is dressed in bed.
When it's time to drive, I will wake her.
Poor child.
Don't drive. That's nonsense.
I'm telling you, we'll get there.
We should have gone yesterday.
I saw a truck full of refugees,
their village completely burned.
You could still do it,
be free from the rubble.
The Germans will invade, certainly.
They're coming. I can't stay any longer.
Where do you want to go?
It doesn't matter. Somewhere.
Away from here.
Let's at least get our luggage down.
I'll help you.
How silly women are!
Thinking about escaping. That's madness.
Just like 1914. There's nowhere to go.
You have to hold them back.
[bombing continues]
[whistle of incoming bomb]
[bombs continue to fall]
Two years of war!
Two years of worries, misery, fear, and hunger.
ROUEN. JUNE 4, 1942
The residents of neighborhoods near the
port, industrial centers, and factories
must leave their homes
as fast as possible
due to the risk of bombing.
EVACUATION INSTRUCTIONS
At Rue de la Rampe?
There are still some free apartments
across from the cemetery.
In the new block? That's safe.
And who pays for the move? The Reich?
I'll stay where I am.
Friends of ours have moved away.
Four days later, it happened:
a single bomb, and 38 people die.
Catch up, little one.
The line's long today.
Oh yes. I hope we can go home to Mama.
Where is she?
She works in the factory.
Where they make bombs?
Like the ones that fall from the sky.
And you look after your brother
while Mama works?
Yes. He is very happy.
Here, Madame.
You're still here, little one.
You probably like it in Rouen.
My Mama signed me up,
but the waiting list is very long.
So I have to wait, you understand.
Of course. Here.
[air raid sirens]
[aircraft engine noise]
Pierre! Marie-Louise! Come!
Marie-Louise! Pierre!
[aircraft engine noise]
[aircraft engines coming closer]
Marie-Louise! Pierre!
[bombs whistling]
[explosions]
Don't be afraid. I'm with you.
Marie-Louise, my God. Come, fast!
[explosions]
I'm choking! I'm choking!
[explosions as bombs continue to fall]
That wasn't far. 300 meters at most.
300 meters? Then we'd all be dead.
[explosions continue]
No! Did you turn off the gas?
Yes, I turned it off.
I'd even take the tax return, if it was on fire.
Go away.
Marie-Louise, don't cry. Look here.
This letter came today.
- You can go. - I want to go, too.
I want to visit Papa.
She can't go to Germany.
She has to go to Switzerland.
Come on, don't cry.
You'll see. There is peace in Switzerland.
Soon, you'll leave here.
♫
Don't be sad, my child.
I'm always with you.
I'm always with you...
Help The Children
Get some rest.
The children have been on a long journey.
Like hundreds of others,
they arrived yesterday in Geneva.
Today they traveled through half of Switzerland.
They're tired, so let's get things done
as quickly as possible.
- Is everything ready? - Yes.
Sister, the children should come here.
Come, children, one by one.
What's your name?
Hello, little one. Hello, Claude.
Hello, Madame.
This is Madame Meyerhans.
But that's too much for today.
Hello, my child. Did you travel well?
We are very happy about your visit.
Are you hungry?
That's Robert.
My husband wanted a girl.
Maybe we can swap.
Men are always proud when they have a boy.
Is anyone here?
Unfortunately, Dorli Gugolz
has the measles as of this morning.
Thanks.
You'll have to wait.
Bring it back.
See if we can call someone else to come.
Hello, Marguerite.
It will not take long.
The child of your host family
got sick this morning.
Yes, ma'am.
Don't be sad, dear. Everything will be all right.
Are you tired, Marie-Louise?
Hello, Jacques.
Good day, sir.
Did you find someone?
Mr. Bänninger, I feel bad for her.
She is so sad.
I would like to take her to my house.
Come, Marie-Louise.
- And your father? - I'll handle it.
Good, that's alright.
Well, my child, that's Miss Rüegg.
She'll take you.
You will feel very comfortable with her.
Thank you, sir.
If you have trouble at home,
we'll find someone else. Just go.
- You don't need me any more? - No.
Come, Marie-Louise. Give me the suitcase.
We're nearly home.
Give me the note.
You don't need that any more.
Here we are.
Come in.
That's Barry. Don't worry, he doesn't bite.
Anna? Anna?
Päuli, is my sister there?
She's on the veranda.
- Please come. - Yes.
This is Marie-Louise Fleury from Rouen.
My sister, Mademoiselle Anna.
- Well? - Hello, Mademoiselle.
- Who is she staying with? - With us.
- Is this...? - Yes, a French child.
Coming to us? In our house?
And we didn't know about it.
Where are you from?
What's your name? How old are you?
Listen, she needs rest.
The journey took her two days, and
she is dead tired.
Bring her to the guest room.
Has she eaten anything?
I can make something right now.
No, she ate in Zürich.
At most, a glass of watered-down milk
so it doesn't make her sick.
Come, my dear. We'll plump you up.
Omelette with applesauce and honey for breakfast.
We still have enough of it.
She doesn't understand German.
She understands me, right? Come here.
This is your room. You stammer, huh?
You certainly don't have that at home.
Tomorrow we'll go shopping
and on Sunday we'll take a walk in the woods.
Barry will come, too. That's him.
You will definitely like it here.
Yes, ma'am.
I'm not "ma'am," I'm Päuli!
Come, sit down.
I'll help you undress.
Papa didn't say a word about this.
True. He may not realize it yet.
How so?
She was left behind,
so I brought her with me.
- Papa doesn't know about her? - Not yet.
Hedi, it doesn't work that way.
You should have asked him. You know how he is.
He'll see it my way.
I'll tell him when dinner is ready.
We'll see.
It won't hurt us to do
something for this little girl.
Here, this will do you good.
Thank you, ma'am, but I'm not hungry.
As you wish.
She's so skinny. You should see her arms.
- Move, Barry. - Come on, let's go.
Are these your parents?
What are they doing now?
Mama works in the factory, since the war started.
- And Papa... - And Papa?
Papa's in Germany.
He's a prisoner of war.
This is my little brother, Pierre.
You love him.
Oh yes, ma'am. He is sweet.
- You're Catholic? - Yes.
We are Protestants,
but that doesn't change anything.
Päuli will pray with you.
She will pray with her.
Sure. I am Catholic, too.
We go to church together.
We have to stick together.
And now, sleep well.
Sleep as long as you like.
To turn on the light,
just press the button.
But the shutters must remain closed
because of the blackout.
- Will there be airplanes? - No, no.
Don't be afraid,
there are no bombings here.
Good night!
Sleep well, Marie-Louise.
Of course the children are completely scared
- because of the planes. - Right.
She's from Rouen.
- Was it attacked? - Certainly.
If you can imagine that - these kids.
Such a dear child, a little angel.
What is Mr. Rüegg saying?
He doesn't know about her yet.
Mr. Rüegg knows nothing?
[soft crying sounds]
- Should we...? - No, leave her.
of course she's homesick.
We'll come back later.
She'll calm down.
♫
Hello.
Miss Anna, Mr. Rüegg is here.
Then please set up the soup course.
Well, Marie-Louise, my father is here.
We'll introduce you to him now.
Yes, ma'am.
Greet him in a friendly way,
and don't worry, even if he's a bit grumpy.
- You will like him. - Yes, ma'am.
- Where are you going? - Down. Father is here.
No, it's too early.
I couldn't say anything.
He still doesn't know?
There's always so much going on, on Saturday.
I have to write twenty letters
since we had the salad.
What can I do?
I'll tell him at lunch.
Go back to your room and play.
We'll call you.
Don't come down, and be very quiet, ok?
Tell Päuli, so she won't blab.
I have to set the table.
Barry, come.
Come, Barry. Be quiet.
Shake, Barry!
Shake, Barry. Good dog.
Go get the ball!
Look!
Yes?
What are you doing here?
Where are you going?
Have you forgotten how to talk?
Excuse me, sir, I would like...
What?
- You speak French? - Yes, sir.
I was told not to come down.
Where do you live?
14 Rue de Lessard, 2nd floor.
Where? In Lausanne?
- No, sir, in Rouen. - What the...?
Are you one of the French children
who arrived yesterday?
Yes, sir.
And where do you live now?
With Miss Anna
and Miss Hedi and Päuli.
- Here? - No sir, upstairs.
- Since when? - Since last night.
No?
Come in!
Come!
What's your name?
Marie-Louise.
- Dinner's ready! - Yes!
Marie-Louise, sit down
and stay here until I call you
- Do you understand? - Yes, sir.
- Hello, Father. - Good day.
Noodle soup.
- Do you need something? - No.
- What is it? Did you have trouble? - Yes.
- In the factory? - Yes.
Ugh. bad?
They tried a new lubricant on our looms today.
We're in short supply.
Without informing me, behind my back.
I can't stand that.
Afterward, when things went wrong,
they came and wanted to apologize.
But for me, afterward is too late.
- You rang? - Yes.
Set another place, please.
I think it's time the French child
who has been in my house since yesterday
should come to the table.
She's waiting in there.
Here!
Listen to me, Father. It was stupid.
It was an impulse, and
I wanted to tell you last night.
I don't need an explanation.
Discussing it is unnecessary.
That's enough.
Eat your soup.
Come see how lovely it is up here!
Oh, that's high up!
You can hang your things there,
but don't go near the edge.
We have to take care of our clothes,
because of the rationing.
Mr. Rüegg says, in the pretty dress,
I look like a Swiss girl.
Yes! Stay up here and
I'll get your other clothes.
♫
[airplanes approach]
Päuli, Päuli! Open the door!
Päuli, they're coming!
[airplane engines overhead]
[airplane engine noise recedes]
For God's sake, what's wrong with you?
What's wrong, my dear?
What's wrong?
Look!
I don't understand what you mean.
Those are just planes, silly girl
Come.
- Hello. - Is this necessary?
The doctor says yes.
- Hello. - Good day.
Can she have a private room?
We don't decide that.
The children are sent to the general ward.
That's what I want to avoid.
I'll call the doctor in charge.
What are they doing with you?
What about your things?
What's going on with you, Marie-Louise?
Will you say something?
She's been like this for an hour.
Stay here. There are lots of people out there.
I'll go with you.
Come back soon!
Miss Rüegg, what about the French child?
She was so frightened this morning
by the planes.
She thought we were being bombed?
A nervous shock?
Yes, and the malnutrition.
Nervous shock? A child?
Because of a few planes?
The marvels of science.
Imagine how the children are doing there
if a few propellers
can send a girl like her to the hospital.
We don't do enough for these children.
Leave me alone with your charity.
They bring the children here, feed them,
make them feel warm and safe,
and three months later
you send them back to hell.
We can't change that.
I know.
- In a thousand years we'll say - No.
we are just as guilty
because we couldn't prevent it.
That's why we have to help,
not just the rich people with big houses.
The working people are enough.
You, maybe? Or me?
Should I or my tenants
bring a child home?
No, you'd have to find another way.
For example, we could...
We can't do anything.
I know.
Bye, Schibli!
Seriously, listen!
Marie-Louise, a visitor for you.
Hello, my child.
How are you?
Say hello to the director.
Have a seat.
Thanks, I won't stay long.
So, I was told you go home in a few days?
Yes, we're happy with how Marie-Louise is doing.
- She's pale. - It will pass.
On the other hand, I find it sad
that she never laughs.
A child. Imagine that.
I brought you something.
Thank you, sir.
She's probably homesick.
She draws her house all day long.
Show him what you drew today.
This is where I live.
This is the kitchen.
The living room.
The bedroom.
That must be a really great apartment.
So? She doesn't laugh.
It's a good drawing.
- I can't draw that well. - But.
This is a little masterpiece.
My art teacher always tweaked my ears, like this,
because I didn't pay enough attention.
So!
- Thanks. - You can keep it.
Oh, thank you.
A gift?
I have to go, unfortunately.
I hope you can come back to us soon.
We'll throw you a party.
Goodbye, Sister Martha.
It's only an idea right now,
but I think it's a good idea.
Right. Put it in my office.
But I hope we could do something.
I don't want to put obstacles in your path,
but in my opinion you should
deal with the problem at the source.
You can't keep putting Band-Aids on it.
We have to do what we can.
That's how you wanted it.
It has to get much worse
before people will understand.
The first thing you have to do
is hunt down those who are guilty.
Nobody speaks against them.
It would be 30 extra minutes of work a day.
Schibli says it can be spread over two shifts
of fifteen minutes each.
That would work.
Two months?
How many children could come?
About 30, they say.
I thought about a hundred.
A hundred! Thirty is better than none.
Where would they stay?
In a chalet.
And our children?
We toil and struggle
to buy them shoes and clothes.
The French children are starving.
It would mean every shift we work
would be 15 minutes longer every day.
With the extra money, we could bring
30 French children to Switzerland
and care for them here.
Even Baumann realized it would work.
Here's what I don't understand:
Each child costs 111 francs per month.
With 30 children, that's a total of 10,000 francs.
We can't do that.
Half that cost would be too much.
If you think Mr. Rüegg agrees, you're naive.
You know he won't agree.
Come on.
It's impossible. I guarantee it.
Here's my problem.
Once the factory starts getting the overtime,
they'll want to keep it forever.
They'll have to talk to us first.
- You? - Why not?
You're against it?
Yes, though it's not the kids' fault.
Thanks.
Thank them, if you agree.
You probably want to know what's going on here.
Is there a referendum?
No more than the adjustment for inflation.
This is something special, Mr. Rüegg.
May I explain?
We have an idea. We thought...
Now I'm curious.
Get it out of your head.
Let me explain.
I understand. Discussion is superfluous.
I can't submit that to the board of directors.
- Post? - Another letter.
It's well meant, but not well thought out.
Take up a collection. I'll participate.
Most of the workers have already signed.
Then tell them...
- Someone's waiting for you. - How so?
I want my time off.
See who it is first.
Ah.
Anna brought her two hours ago.
She wanted to pick you up.
So? Entirely of your own choice?
Ah, Marie-Louise, that's nice of you.
You're well again!
Sorry, Miss Rüegg.
He just doesn't listen.
The matter is dismissed.
You're being naive.
Did you think that would work right away?
Even I had to think twice.
How do I explain it to him?
You can't explain anything to Father.
Just try to make sure he understands your idea.
One moment.
We'll go in and I'll show him your idea could work
- And then? - Then, it'll work.
To celebrate your return home
I have a present for you.
But you have to look for it.
Go on. Look.
That is "cold." Do you know what that means?
"Cold" means there is nothing near you.
When you're near, I'll say "warm."
"Warm" means chaud in French. Got it?
- Yes. - Then look.
Cold.
Freezing cold.
It's snowing!
Even colder!
I'm shivering with cold!
You're at the North Pole!
The ice is slowly melting.
Cold.
Cold?
A bit warmer.
Warmer, warmer.
Lukewarm. Warm.
The sun burns!
Cold.
You're in the heart of Africa!
Watch out, or you'll burn yourself!
Excuse me. Hedi, imagine.
She laughed!
Well, Marie-Louise. Do you like it?
Oh, yes sir. Thank you.
- Did you see? - Yes.
- What? - Mr. Schibli is very unhappy.
You should at least hear him out.
I know. It's impossible.
Nothing is impossible!
Just badly thought out.
Until everything was organized...
Do you have any ideas?
The very idea of something...
Do you have beds for the kids?
Laundry? Dishes?
I thought you could rent those.
Of course. It takes time, though.
Rent?
Hedi is right. It needs organization.
The Town Council could take over.
They could act as sponsor.
Someone would have to manage it,
up in the chalet.
Mr. Bänninger would be willing.
A retired teacher would be good. He has time.
And me.
That'd leave me without a secretary!
Miss Schäfer would like to help.
But when I was in the Women's Help Service,
the board was a problem.
Don't worry about that.
I'll send them a memo.
- Do you like it? - Oh, yes sir.
Do you think we could talk about it?
Of course.
First, it needs a name.
You're right. Maybe -
Wait, I've got it.
Yes. That sounds good.
"Fifteen Minutes Overtime"
- Great! - First...
"The board of the linen weavers has decided,
in agreement with the workers
and employees of the factory,"
… colon …
"Beginning with Monday,
July 20, at 6:45…
♫
[children singing]
WELCOME
It has to be up there.
You won't see it just yet.
Only when we approach Vitznau.
- When will we get there? - Don't be impatient.
Hedi is already with the children.
She's doing it right.
Thanks for the invitation,
even though it was a detour.
We must show her Switzerland.
Otherwise she'll tell everyone
there's nothing here but factories.
Look, Marie-Louise.
That's the Tell Chapel.
William Tell is the Swiss national hero.
You know William Tell, yes?
Yes. I know.
- Did he kill the bad guy there? - No.
That was in Hollow Alley.
There, he jumped from the boat and escaped.
Ah, got it.
Slow down - stop!
[ship's horn blows]
Look, a school trip!
I've done this very trip so often with my students.
The story of William Tell is true, right?
Of course. He lived like .. who ...
- Like Joan of Arc. - I agree.
You're right.
Let the kids believe in William Tell.
Even if it's just a story.
Don't say that.
The latest research says
it happened pretty much that way.
No, really? That's interesting.
- So, then everything is true? - Yes.
That makes me very happy.
♫
Oh, look!
- Look how high that is! - Oh yes.
She's already become well-acclimated.
Do you see that meadow in the middle of the forest?
- Where the sun shines? - Yes.
What's that?
That's the Rütli.
There, the bravest men of three cantons
swore to drive out the tyrant.
Feel the heat?
Yeah, the sun's shining a bit.
For me, it feels like that
when we approach the Rütli.
How nice!
Our homeland is beautiful, isn't it?
Very.
She's probably never seen anything like it.
It's time for the kids to eat!
Look what I've found!
- Is that silver? - I don't know.
Andre bothers me all the time!
That's not true!
My sweater is ruined.
We'll fix it later. Go eat!
The kids are lovely. Really nice.
Watch out!
Sorry. I didn't do it on purpose.
That may be a villain.
That's just Andre.
He's naughty, you understand?
It looks that way.
Big Snake is looking for her victim!
Not so fast.
It tastes better if you eat slowly.
- Water, please! - Later.
Andre, take this off while you eat.
- No! - You'll get it back later.
George, sit down.
Come, Marie-Louise, sit with the others.
No, thanks. We'll eat downstairs in the hotel.
You aren't staying for dinner? Too bad.
you'd rather eat with me, right?
The hotel has ice cream for dessert.
Mr. Bänninger?
Be careful. Don't spoil her.
Remember, she has to go back to France soon.
- And? - I don't want to get involved,
but the more you spoil her,
the harder the change will be for her.
We know.
As long as she's here, she should be happy,
these three months, anyway.
No, beat that idea out of your head.
There are no exceptions.
We can't take her from her parents.
Thousands of others also would want to come.
We want to see
if we could appeal. If she could stay.
- A longer stay. - Thanks.
Goodbye, sir.
Goodbye.
Mr. Bänninger was angry, right?
He's just an old teacher, you know.
We still eat our ice cream for dessert.
Happy birthday.
We are not so bad.
We eat potatoes every day.
They are wonderful.
Pierre wishes you well, too.
Hugs and kisses from your mama.
Your mother would have sent a gift
- But that isn't allowed. - Yes.
Look here.
That brooch works well with this dress.
It's beautiful.
That's for me. Come along, Päuli.
You're disappointed, right?
The last birthday with Mama was nice.
She gave me roller skates.
You know, you can't send anything
from the occupied zone.
Not even letters.
Your mama is thinking of you today.
She and Pierre are only talking about you.
You think so, Anna?
I'm sure, sweetie.
I painted this brooch for you.
A little memento.
To my little Swiss mama.
Put it on the piano stool.
On the desk.
No, on the piano stool, I said!
That way, you can turn it.
- What is it? - Hands off!
- Is it nice? - Look at it!
No, leave that to her.
- Good, then. - No, stay, Mr. Schibli!
You created this lovely work. - Hands off!
Come.
Take the cover off.
- Me? -Yes, you.
Ah, our house!
- A dollhouse! - Great, father.
You stammer, huh?
It's okay, sweetie.
It's done with love.
Good day, Miss Rüegg.
I don't know who you make more happy,
Father, or her.
- It's really great. - Look here.
You can turn it around
and open that. See?
and if you push here, the light goes on.
Incredible!
This is our apartment in Rouen.
Wonderful!
It brings tears to my eyes.
Look, the living room!
Look, Päuli, the kitchen.
I've never seen anything like it, even in museums
Here's the bedroom.
Mama, Pierre, and I sleep there.
I built it from your drawings.
Mr. Rüegg gave me the blueprints.
Very nice, Mr. Schibli. Perfect.
You will let me know how much I owe you for it?
It's out of the question. - Why?
It was an official assignment.
I did it for her sake.
Think of it as thanks in turn
for participating in our action.
We'll talk about it over coffee.
Will you stay for dinner?
- Sure.
Discussion is superfluous.
Päuli, set a place for Mr. Schibli.
- Do we still have any vermouth? - Yes.
Anna! Through the window, you
can see the ships on the Seine.
Even the piano is there.
Oh, Miss Anna, this is amazing!
Too bad she can't take it back to France with her.
We hope she can come back next year.
I am glad to see you again.
You used to come more often.
- I always liked it. - Nice...
Now you're a stranger?
I wasn't in the factory before...
but I don't have to explain that to you.
I understand.
Although, lately...
Father has become more sociable.
That's because of her.
This is great.
- Come for an aperitif! - Yes, Father, come.
Come eat, sweetheart.
Päuli, the house is fantastic.
Come wash your hands.
- We'll play the entire afternoon!
This is the Swiss Telegraphic Agency.
First, the war news. After heavy airstrikes yesterday,
Reuters reports that scouts crisscrossing Rouen
found Rouen still in flames hours after the bombing.
All targeted military targets have been reached...
♫
Elise Masson, born in Valence on July 23, 1870,
died on 22 August 1942.
I wanted to live,
to experience peace.
Henri Laine, cabinetmaker, born in St. Malo
on March 17, 1904, died on August 22, 1942.
I leave a wife and three children.
Jeanne Thomas, seamstress, born in Rouen on
December 3, 1918, died on August 22, 1942.
I was to be married a month from now.
Goodbye, Marcel!
Pierre Fleury, born in Rouen
on May 12, 1937, died on August 22, 1942.
Now it is completely dry.
We can bring it to Monsieur Rüegg.
Not today.
You have a visitor. Mr. Schibli is here.
- You're in for the night. - But.
It's late. Get in bed.
- Will he like it? - Why, surely.
You painted the flowers and everything so beautifully.
The beautiful flower is from Miss Anna.
But the others are from you.
Come to bed.
We'll put them on his desk,
so he'll see them before breakfast
as a surprise. - Right now.
It's too late now. Come, we pray.
God in heaven, above all things,
thank you for all the good things you give us,
the goodness that you are,
deliver us from evil.
Dear God, protect Mama and Papa
and my little brother Pierre.
Lord, bless them
and protect them from evil. Amen.
What do you have?
Nothing. Nothing, sweetie.
Sleep well.
Miss Anna, she's in bed.
Thanks, Päuli. I'm going upstairs.
I'm surprised a telegram got out of the occupied zone.
It went to the Swiss legation.
I inquired there.
It's terrible.
She doesn't know yet?
I don't know if we should tell her.
We can't let her go home,
not without knowing.
- When must she go? - In two weeks.
Let's ask Mr. Bänninger what it means.
I'd better go home.
The billing can wait.
I don't feel like it now.
Hedi will not believe it.
We don't know what to do.
Exactly.
Her mother now lives with a sister.
How can we know that?
That's the question.
Do we tell Marie-Louise? And when?
It's so easy to say "tell her gently"
That's what my daughter means.
I don't know. I have to think about it.
It's a terrible blow for her.
In any case, you have to tell her
before she returns to France.
You'll come down on the day she returns?
Maybe a day early?
It's not clear from the telegram.
It just says the house in Rouen
is completely destroyed
and her little brother Pierre is dead.
Mr. Bänninger, I'll call you right back.
For God's sake, Marie-Louise.
What is it? What is it about Pierre?
- What does destroyed mean? - Listen.
What does destroyed mean?
- Is she with you? - No, why?
Where can she be? She's not in her room.
For God's sake, has she heard anything?
MARIE-LOUISE DEPARTS
Drink your milk, Marie-Louise.
Does she have everything, Päuli?
There are only a few details left.
Don't cry.
Look at how she controls herself.
Are we sure she has to go?
I don't know anything else.
Mr. Bänninger has been sitting with her for 15 minutes.
She was nice to you.
It's so nice here. It will be difficult
to get settled at home.
I don't blame you.
Such a child is like an animal.
It gets used to the house,
gets used to the people,
but eventually has to go to work.
Do you think I haven't thought about her staying?
Rouen's a danger zone. If she had to go back there
I'd say to keep her here.
But her mother's out in the country now,
and she should be safer there.
A tiny bit of luck, that.
Take another child,
one that's in extreme danger,
and then three months later
send him or her back into hell?
Like Marie-Louise?
And this is what we call humanity.
If we can only do half measures,
maybe it's better to do nothing.
Be quiet. She can hear you.
Hundreds and thousands of children
die in Europe.
They starve. Suffocate in air-raid shelters.
Torn apart by bombs.
And we who have been spared, barely manage
to rescue a few thousand
for three months at a time.
Why don't we rescue more,
as many as we can accommodate,
and let them stay until the war is over?
I understand that it's difficult.
But if it's this important
there has to be a way.
Switzerland could do more.
Much more.
That'd be great.
Don't just invite the kids to visit, but
offer them asylum.
There's more to do.
Humans are slow to act.
Even your eyes weren't opened
until you saw it for yourself.
Now, many more families have told us
they, too, can take in French children.
It was said there weren't enough trains.
The trains have to do other things, too:
transport troops, weapons, supplies.
Do you know how hard it was to bring
hundreds of kids from Serbia?
People fear angering their neighbors.
A doctor opened his chalet in Mürren
to 16 kids.
And your workers?
No one guided them. They found a way.
We can learn from that.
Mr. Schibli received several requests
from large farms.
You want to do something more,
more than fifteen minutes of overtime.
But Father, what happens now?
We have to go.
It's time.
The committee let me decide
because I was familiar with the case.
But I won't do anything against Mr. Rüegg.
- She could stay? - Yes.
Yes, but ... what are we still discussing?
Mr. Bänninger is against it.
What do you mean, Anna?
Have we heard about Marie-Louise's mother?
The Red Cross has inquired.
She can take Marie-Louise.
She expects to take Marie-Louise back.
In that case, we have
nothing left to decide.
If we think it's so hard to let Marie-Louise go,
how do you think her mother feels?
Well, then, Marie-Louise...
Goodbye, Marie-Louise.
Be well. Be safe.
Goodbye, my dear.
Mr. Rüegg, I don't want to go.
I cannot go!
Why can't I stay, Mr. Rüegg?
Listen, Marie-Louise.
Don't you want to see your mother again?
Of course. But why not bring her here, too?
We'd be happy here.
In Rouen we'll die, like Pierre.
Calm down.
Sister, take her in.
Come on, we have to get in.
You can wave from the window.
- Goodbye, Marie-Louise. - I don't want to go!
♫
[train crossing signal]
Sit down, kids!
We'll come to the nearest train station soon.
You too, yes.
- This is reserved.
I'll move, then.
Are these French children?
- Yes. They're going home. - Poor things.
Have an apple.
Thank you, sir.
Slowly, slowly!
Yes, you get one too.
One at a time.
This one's good, too.
♫
Now they should be in Langenthal.
5:20pm, Burgdorf.
5:43pm, Bern.
At half past eight they arrive in Geneva.
- Are you going into the office today? - No.
They can work without me.
Could we have given her more?
More food? More things to help?
We gave as much as we were allowed.
I can still hear her
running down the stairs, laughing.
You have to accept she's gone.
That's easy for you to say.
I know I shouldn't
have gotten so involved with her.
You're better off
because you're letting it hurt you less.
Yes, Father.
What are you doing?
Leave the track immediately!
There are trains here!
Don't let me catch you here again!
Hey, little one!
- Mr. Rüegg. - Yes -
Mr. Bänninger wants to speak to you.
Yes, Mr. Bänninger.
I just want to tell you something.
Don't be scared.
I just got a call,
from the train ... so ...
- Your Marie-Louise. - What about her?
Everything is alright.
She probably didn't know what to do
and got out.
- Of the train? - No, the station.
She ran away?
Yes, in a way,
but we found her.
I came ahead, to tell you.
- They'll bring her to you. - Who?
- The person who found her. - Oh, my God.
So, Herr Rüegg,
Your little runaway is back.
An unexpected reunion, right?
Don't cry. You're home now.
- What have you done? - Forgive me!
I won't do it again.
I won't do it again. Forgive me.
I will never do it again.
I'll never do it again.
Calm down now.
I would put her to bed now.
I agree. Come, Päuli.
She just followed the train back.
Yes. Home.
I said yes, such a child is like an animal.
Yes, and now?
Thinking about it, the only solution I see:
tonight, she should sleep here
and tomorrow she can come to the chalet with me.
She can recover there.
Fine.
Make way for your new comrade.
Andre, listen!
What honor!
- Aren't you hungry? - No, thanks.
Being around other kids will be good for her.
I wouldn't have come along.
That was very nice of you.
It will make her transition easier.
- She's not eating. - She probably isn't hungry.
Maybe she's scared.
Tell me: are you going to eat that?
- No? Then give it to me. - No!
You don't seem to understand
that my word is law here. Give it to me!
Andre!
Come down immediately! This is dangerous.
- Who owns the plate? - Marie-Louise!
Take him!
That's enough!
In with you! No dessert for you!
Oh, you don't want to? I'll take that.
Sit down. Not a peep from you. Understand?
You make my life difficult.
- What's going on? - You should spank him.
He took Marie-Louise's plate.
Say, kid, why are you acting like such a girl?
Why did you not beat her?
She's weak.
She wouldn't have put up a fight.
Me, beat up a girl?
Where do you think?
Oh, you don't want to be a kid any more.
You think you're a man already?
If you are, then you have to think carefully
about what you do.
Finally, someone who understands me.
You'd be fine with him.
Take the kid home with you.
- Which? - That's a great idea.
That would do us a huge favor.
I like that.
Seriously: he's not malicious,
but we don't have enough time for him.
He needs individual attention.
- You're crazy. - Yes, Father!
Anna would be happy
and it would bring life to our house.
I agree. Listen to Andre.
Do you want to go with this gentleman
and live with his family for a while?
With him? Why not, if I can help.
Stop. Nothing will come of it.
I've already heard about your house,
and all its comforts.
It would be a great honor.
Do you have a ping-pong table?
Andre, you should be very happy.
That goes without saying.
You know me.
Discussion is superfluous. I have to go.
The train leaves in ten minutes.
- Where's my hat? - Below.
Goodbye.
Don't go. There will be tears if you do.
That's better. Goodbye, Hedi.
- Goodbye. - Thanks.
Eat something.
The others are eating well.
I'm ready, sir.
What?
Courage! I hope your experiences with me
won't be too bad.
That's nice. Take him with you.
You'll enjoy it.
In God's name.
I take it as a kind of punishment.
Come!
♫
We made this album together.
Last week, in the evening, with the kids.
A good memory for later.
Also for the kids.
It was a good start
but they didn't finish it.
If no more children can come,
you should keep the ones that are here.
They don't want to stay.
Look.
"When everything is reborn with hope"
That's what Marie-Louise wrote.
"I'd like to see Normandy again."
Do the kids know the Nazis have occupied France?
You know what they can expect:
hunger and misery.
But they still want to go home.
They want to go back where they came from.
They'll have a very hard time.
But I think... or better, I hope,
that the children who survive this war
will rebuild their countries,
not just houses and cities.
Something bigger. Something more important.
You understand me.
- Do you want to go? - Yes.
See you at the station tomorrow.
- Mr. Rüegg is coming too. - With Andre.
The good Andre.
- He destroyed half the house? - Nearly.
Luckily, Hedi is traveling to Geneva.
Otherwise he'd pull the emergency brake
or dismantle the engine.
- Mr. Bänninger. - Until tomorrow.
- Mr. Bänninger. - Yes.
Marie-Louise.
You can't sleep?
I can sleep a long time on the train.
The ride isn't that bad.
You'll have company.
Tomorrow evening, you'll be in Geneva
and the day after tomorrow, at home.
Yes, my mama will pick me up.
She writes that she will come to the station.
When she says it,
you can count on it.
I know.
Do you look forward to the journey this time?
Yes, like all the other kids.
Now you really need to sleep.
Mr. Bänninger.
This time I won't run away.
Promise.
- Everything ready? - Yes, sir.
- Are they all here? - Yes.
- Nothing forgotten? - No, sir.
Good. Let's go.
Mr. Bänninger, thank you for everything,
and for the holiday
we were able to spend here.
Very good, kids, very good.
Listen, kids.
We still have time.
You don't have to say thank you,
but I have something to tell you.
You're going home now.
What will you do when you are home?
What will you do then?
We have to obey our parents.
Good. That's right.
Above all, love your siblings and parents.
You've experienced hard times.
Help them with their suffering and grief.
Tell your parents we wish the war would end soon
and that peace would reign again.
Let's finish with a little song.
What should we sing? Any ideas?
- No one? Marie-Louise? - "Ma Normandie."
Good. We'll sing that.
When everything is born again
in the hope that winter flees
and France's sky shines magnificently
When the sun returns more gently
When nature becomes green again
The swallows find their hoard
I like to see my Normandy
The country of my birth
I saw the green of Helvetia
and its chalets and glaciers
I know Italy's sky
Venice, and its gondoliers
At every home I greeted
I said to myself: it is not a place
As beautiful as my Normandy
the land of my birth."
- Pity. - It's a shame.
Everything worked perfectly.
Our workers were enthusiastic.
We bought the house
and no children are allowed to come.
It's still good, Mr. Bänninger.
The war won't last forever.
How happy will the people be
in those ruined cities
if they can send us their children.
True. You're right.
Then we're ready.
For those who will come in the future.
Come on!
- Let's get the kids to Geneva. - Yes.
- Hello, Hedi. - Good day, Father.
Hello, Anna. Hello, Andre.
Look, Andre, and Mr. Rüegg?
Actually, we got along quite well.
I'm happy. Forgive me again
for breaking your central heating.
Let's not talk about it any more. It's fixed.
Thank you, sir.
Go!
Mama writes that she's fine
and can hardly wait to see me.
It will be good to see your mama again.
Oh, yes.
Thank you for everything, Mr. Rüegg.
Thank you, Miss Anna.
Goodbye, Mr. Schibli.
Many thanks, Mr. Schibli.
Wait, there's something else.
Did you notice that your bicycle valve
was wide open every morning?
The Velo valve? Yes.
- That was me. - Why?
Jealousy. I like Miss Anna, too.
Don't worry. You can have her.
Listen, friend. You're totally crazy.
Me and Anna?
Do you think I don't have eyes in my head?
Discussion is superfluous.
A girl once told me
that love overcomes every obstacle.
Andre, in with you!
- At least in France! - Salut, Andre!
Again, thanks for everything!
I don't say goodbye, I say "until we meet again."
- Until we meet again!
Long live Switzerland!
♫