The 4k digital restoration of Paisan was done
from a fine-grain nitrate source from the period
kept at the CSC-Cineteca Nazionale.
The restoration was carried out
by the Cineteca di Bologna
and the CSC-Cineteca Nazionale
at the L'Immagine Ritrovata laboratory in 2013.
PAISAN
On the night of July 10, 1943,
the Allied fleet opened fire
on the southern coast of Sicily.
Twelve hours later,
the first large-scale Allied landing
on the European continent had begun.
Under cover of the first shadows of night,
Allied patrols advance into Italian territory.
Ricuzzo! Ricuzzo!
Heavens! Who are you? What do you want?
What do they want?
Maybe they're looking for their buddies.
Your friends left this morning. They're not here.
Willkommen, my friends.
They didn't land, did they?
- These are Americans!
- What Americans!
If they set foot here, they'll stay here
for good - horizontally!
Are you Americans?
Americans!
My son was in Licata until ten days ago.
He was a soldier. Did you hurt him?
My blessed son, with these
horrible things happening -
Don't be afraid, ma'am. No one will hurt you.
But what happened here?
Good Lord, he speaks Italian!
Are you Italian like us?
Yes, my father's Sicilian, born in Gela.
Gela? I'm from Gela too. Luca!
This American's from Gela!
- Is that what he says?
- The past few days have been awful.
- They've bombed all day.
The Germans all left this morning.
We didn't leave the village.
We're holding a wake.
Everyone left, even the gravedigger.
We can't leave, we can't go anywhere else.
We can't even lay my daughter-in-law to rest.
- How many Germans left?
- The American's from Gela!
- What's your name?
- Tony Mascali.
He's not from Gela.
My father really is from Gela.
Then he left for America.
There are no Mascalis in Gela.
We're supposed to believe a pack of lies.
So much for freedom!
- When did the Germans leave?
- They laid mines everywhere this morning.
- How many Germans were there?
- Lots - 3,000 or more.
- Thirty thousand.
- Thirty million!
Which direction did they go?
Maybe toward Scopina. North for sure.
- Where are the mines?
- Along the coast heading north.
The lava canal's the only way,
but it's dangerous at night.
You need a guide like Carmela.
She's gone that way twice looking for her folks.
Come with me.
Come on.
Who'll give me a cigarette?
Carmela, these Americans want to talk to you.
You know the way over the lava?
I go that way every day with lunch for my father.
- Is it a path or a road?
- It's lava.
Can someone in your family lead us?
No, my father and brother
have been gone for four days.
I tried to leave the church twice
to look for them,
but the others are afraid to let me go alone.
I'll take you. I know the way.
You can't go off alone with these strangers!
Where are you going?
- You really coming with us?
- Yes.
- Where are you taking the girl?
- Let's go, baby.
Carmela, don't go!
Why'd you try to run off?
I didn't come along to look at your pretty faces.
I haven't seen my father and brother
in four days. I'm going to look for them.
Good work, Carmela.
Don't worry about your family.
If we find them, we'll bring them back with us.
You stay here. Joe will keep you company.
Look how cute he is.
Can I go back to the church?
We'll all go back together later.
No light!
What's he saying?
Ah! I'm Carmela.
The ocean...
My father and brother
went out to sea. Understand?
It's a good boat, and the sea is calm.
Maybe they didn't come back due to the war.
I'm going to look for them. You stay here.
You're all alike -
you, the Germans, the Fascists!
You people with guns are all the same!
Ah, stella cadente.
- Comma?
- What?
You said comme.
Paisan...
spaghetti...
bambina...
mangiare...
fusillini...
c'est la guerre...
Ah, biondo.
"Comme"? It's the same word in America?
Latte.
Uncle Luca had cows.
He sat seven bambini on a cow once.
Sister?
- Why did you shoot?
- I saw a light.
Get a grip on your nerves.
Everyone's hallucinating lately.
Let's go.
I saw it, I tell you.
Naumann, you see that?
The light could have come from there.
- It's possible. Let's have a look.
- A pirate's castle.
- What's that?
Make sure no one comes in.
Stay here. No, don't come along.
War is like children's games.
Except that the bullets are real.
I could get romantic here.
And the Americans?
I was right. A real pirate's den.
You can turn on your flashlight now.
Look, there's even straw for us.
Come on, let's redecorate
and set up headquarters.
Shit, it's dark as a cave.
Just the place to break your neck.
- Wait!
- Thank God. Got past that one.
Watch your things and quit grumbling.
- And the Americans?
- They can take a flying leap.
It's like a glimpse of the afterlife in here.
Look. There's somebody over there.
What are you doing here?
- Why you leave village?
- I was scared.
What's going on?
- We got something here.
- Send her up.
- You scared?
- Of the Americans.
No be afraid.
- There's everything here - even people.
- What did you find?
We no hurt you. Us friends.
You shine light?
Looks like she forgot how to talk.
Bad sign for a broad.
But what's she doing here?
This could be dangerous.
If the light wasn't hers, someone else is here.
Nonsense.
Get a load of that pair, boys.
Enough for the three of us and then some.
Damn all this climbing.
Show me what you rustled up.
What you do here?
You no here because scared.
You meet boyfriend, right?
Hands off.
Your boyfriend very stupid not show up.
Me guess right?
I think you have dishonorable intentions.
I'm completely incapable of that right now,
what with the bad food
and all this running around.
You'd have rather found a barrel of wine.
Both. A barrel of wine and the girl on top.
I'd settle for water. I'm thirsty.
You got a complex? Wouldn't you prefer milk?
We thirsty. You find water?
Good. Very far?
I'll go.
We're in for some surprises tonight, boys.
Of course. Always the gentleman.
- What if she doesn't come back?
- We're too good-looking.
Fritz, you think they'll keep advancing?
Will we keep retreating all the way to Palermo?
Retreat? We don't retreat.
Tomorrow we'll counterattack.
They'll run like rabbits.
All the way to Egypt - no, all the way to hell.
Bachelors first.
Let's roll for her.
- Three.
- Eight.
Twelve.
- Watch out!
- The little bitch!
Let's go.
The war advanced quickly through southern Italy.
On September 8th, Allied cannons
were trained on Naples.
After crushing German resistance at Salerno,
the Allies landed on the Amalfi Coast,
and a few weeks later, Naples was liberated.
Its port became
the most important logistics center
of the war in Italy.
Egyptian fakir defies death! The man of steel!
Step up, folks! Watch him leap and spin!
He could break his neck, but he never does!
Watch his stunts!
Joe, gimme something.
- Wow!
- He's amazing!
- Pasquale, you leaving?
- We're not making nothin' here.
We gotta get this stuff out of here.
I'm going down to the port to pick up some dough.
- And leavin' us here?
- You should learn to eat fire.
Look at that dirty Arab!
Fire-eaters make a lot of dough!
Get your taralli here!
Gimme a light, will ya?
Hey, wanna make 50 lira?
- Two hundred.
- One hundred.
- No, 200.
- 150.
Okay. What do I do?
Stay here and look out for the police.
They're buying a Negro over there.
Look at these shoes.
I got a hundred lire off him.
Look at his jacket!
- Why don't you take his shoes?
- And you take his jacket!
Wait a minute! 3,000 lire!
I'll give you 3,000 and two packs of cigarettes.
Get out of here!
Here's 3,000.
I already outbid you!
- Get lost! 3,000's enough!
- It's 'cause I'm just a kid.
The MPs! Run for it!
The MPs!
Long live Orlando!
Go on in, Joe.
The Roman senator, great leader of the knights!
Take up arms, Christians,
and fight the black Saracen!
God calls us.
- We seek not riches!
- Justice and civilization!
Death to the Moors!
Hey, sit down!
I, fair Orlando,
shall fight you, the black Moor.
Come on, move your feet!
Come and get it!
You got it backwards. Give it to me.
This is a house key,
but the doors are wide open,
so the key's useless.
You sang good, but I didn't like your song.
What are you doing?
What's with you?
He's gone nuts!
An airplane!
What are you saying?
If you sleep, I'll steal your shoes.
Take it, you ugly mug!
I told you not to go to sleep!
- Where's your home?
- I ain't got one.
Joe, here are your shoes.
These are good soles.
I don't understand.
Where are your mama and papa?
My mama and papa are dead. The bombs.
Understand?
A long and tragic delay at Cassino.
On February 22, 1944,
the Allies landed at Anzio.
Rome waited anxiously.
After a series of long, bloody battles,
the Germans were crushed.
Kesserling's troops retreat
through the streets of Rome.
Miraculously intact,
the city welcomed its liberators
on June 4, 1944.
SIX MONTHS LATER
American cigarettes. Come on, you smokers.
Singles or packs.
American cigarettes, singles or packs.
What do you want?
That ugly witch has been staring all night!
You're not much to look at yourself!
What's wrong with you?
That hillbilly!
Me?
You slob! You'll starve when these guys leave.
No more little hats.
You'll be in rags, like before.
The cops!
She's a little tramp!
My papers are in order.
They're in there. Just hold on!
Stop her!
- Your ticket?
- Just for a minute.
Where are you going?
Did you see a blonde woman in a fur?
No.
- Thanks.
- It was nothing.
No, thanks. You keep it.
It's just one flight up.
- Ah, it's you.
- Evening. May I?
He's drunk.
Don't worry. He'll fall right asleep.
Let's hope he doesn't cause a ruckus.
Damn it! They tore my dress.
Your MPs are real louts.
Why'd you bring them along?
Is it cold like this in America?
Did you come from the front?
Aren't you gonna get undressed, sweetheart?
Your clothes.
What lovely manners! Still, you're awful sweet.
Warm me up a bit.
What's wrong?
You should be ashamed, a young man like you.
If you don't like me, you should have said so.
You probably stood around in bars all day.
Isn't it better having a real girl?
Yes, Rome is full of girls like me.
Water, please.
To wash up.
Come in.
I'm afraid all the pipes are broken.
Ah, finally!
I'm afraid it's not terribly fresh.
We've had no water for two weeks.
Not a glass. Lots of water to wash my face.
I'm sorry. I misunderstood.
This way, please.
This is the only soap we have.
It's not very good.
Here's a towel.
Take your time.
I like Italian girls...
their language, their eyes,
their hair, their figures.
“When the thief saw the policeman,
he turned the corner and ran.”
I have nothing to offer you.
Happy?
We waited so long for you.
What took you so long getting here?
I don't understand.
Why so long to get to Rome?
Very hard.
Yes, you're here.
- Afraid?
- Not afraid.
Happy.-- very happy-
It hardly seems true.
It's been so awful.
So awful.
Not awful. Lovely.
It's lovely here.
Rome's lovely. Everything's lovely.
You're lovely.
Chocolate!
You're leaving?
Come back.
Why didn't you look for her?
Don't you remember the fountain in the square?
Francesca's house was red,
with a big doorway, bigger than all the others.
She's become just like you.
No, not her.
There are lots of good, decent girls
who work, who've worked all along,
who've managed to fend off hunger and poverty.
She's one of them.
It's still there.
But it's not in blossom like it was that day.
I know where Francesca's house is.
Piazza dei Quiriti, No. 8.
Go to her tomorrow.
You'll find her waiting for you there.
Tomorrow... you and Francesca...
Signora Amelia.
Coming. Just a moment.
- Leaving already?
- Yes.
When he wakes up tomorrow, give him this address.
- Please don't forget.
- Don't worry.
- Remind him to go there.
- Here you are.
- Thanks.
- Antonio, what time is it?
- 10:30.
- No one came looking for me?
- No, no one.
Pursued by the Allies,
German troops flee through
Lazio, Umbria, and Tuscany.
Fighting flares up again for a while
in the hills around Florence.
But in early August, Eighth Army troops liberated
the city south of the Arno River.
North of the river, Italian partisans
fought German troops and Fascist snipers.
We're injured, Doctor.
Tonino, what beautiful girls!
If I'd have known,
I'd have gotten injured earlier.
Miss, my eye hurts.
Does that hurt?
Let's have a look.
Don't worry. Everything will be fine.
- You speak Italian?
- I lived in Florence a few years.
I was an idiot to get wounded.
Me and nine other men were up in the woods.
We were feeling great. We'd had a good rest
after that fighting on the Arno.
- The Arno. Where?
- In Florence.
We waited a good while
for the English to show up.
- So the English are in the city?
- Yes. Didn't you know?
Yes.
But since they stopped on this side of the Arno,
and there was nothing more we could do,
we went and joined them.
- When did you leave Florence?
- Two days ago.
By now they've occupied
the other side of the city.
No, the Germans blew up
every bridge but the Ponte Vecchio,
and they blew up the buildings
on both ends of that one.
- Where do you live in Florence?
- I don't. I live near Lucca,
but I joined the Arno Valley brigade
because they needed men badly.
But don't you have friends
or acquaintances in Florence?
Why? Do you know somebody?
Yes. I had lots of good friends.
Tell me, did you ever meet
a Guido Lombardi, a painter?
Everyone knows him!
I'd love to see him.
Would it be hard to find him?
Hard? Impossible!
He's our leader, but he's a phantom right now.
Everyone talks about him, but no one
knows where the famous Lupo is.
Lupo?
Boys, we're here.
They got you too?
They got him good!
Just one shot and he fell
like a sack of potatoes.
Did you get a look at these American girls?
Don't look so glum.
You'll see your little wife again.
Any word about Lupo?
Some say he's wounded, others say he's not.
Some say he's in town, others say he's not.
But he did a first-rate job in Florence.
- I'll say.
With my help, of course.
I'd organized everything to a T.
Especially before the Germans moved in.
We could operate in broad daylight.
- Any word about Lupo?
- Nothing specific.
He's fighting in Mugnone with other partisans.
I heard he was wounded,
but who can be sure what's going on over there?
Papa's the only one left at home.
- British trucks have arrived.
- Really?
Ma'am, do you recognize me?
I live across the street from you.
It's the end of the world, my boy.
We've sinned so badly.
Have you seen my wife and son?
Can't you see the state the poor woman's in?
- You're her son, right?
- What of it?
You must have word from across the river.
How could we? We have
other things to worry about.
Massimo!
What are you doing?
Why are you dressed like that?
I just had to come to Florence.
Surely you don't expect to find him here.
If he's a partisan,
he's on the other side of the Arno.
Help me, please.
How can I help you? He's not here.
I haven't the slightest idea where to find him.
The first newspaper printed in Florence!
Lupo wounded in Mugnone!
Give me a paper!
Look, Papa. Lupo's really been wounded.
Those rats! The greatest young man in the world.
- You knew him?
- We were friends!
When I was little, he did a portrait of me.
He was a fine painter too. Really good.
Keep down!
- Where's it coming from?
- Via de' Bardi.
Careful. A grenade just exploded over there.
Look. My house is just beyond that boulevard.
The National Liberation Committee
might know something,
but they're across the river.
What's the news?
Believe me, I'd like to cross too
and chase out those rats
shooting from rooftops and bell towers.
Shooting at whom?
Are there lots of partisans in town?
In some areas, but they're shooting out of rage.
They even shoot women going for water.
They killed two like that last night,
while these guys gaze at Giotto's bell towers.
How do you get this news?
By telephone.
There's a telephone cable linking us to the city.
You have to help me. Don't you have family?
I could take you there,
but they're letting no one across.
Take me where?
Don't make me spell it out.
Others have gotten across. You can try too.
But how? Where?
Use a little imagination. It's not hard.
- The Uffizi passageway?
- I know nothing.
You never said a word. Don't worry, and thanks.
Don't start from the Palazzo Pitti.
The passageway's collapsed there.
Hey, what's a guy like you doing here?
Gigi! I'm in luck.
Where'd you pop out of?
- Listen, I have to get across.
- Be my guest.
Stop kidding around.
I know you can cross via the Uffizi passageway.
Others have done it. I have to too.
No one's gotten across. That's just a tall tale.
The passageway's been there
for centuries. That's no tall tale.
Whether others got across or not, I'm going.
- You're not going anywhere.
- Calm down.
I'm free to go where I want.
But not to be a jerk and endanger the rest of us.
You're not the only one who knows.
But imagine if the Germans find out.
It's a miracle they haven't yet.
And at the end of the passageway - what then?
The Germans occupy the Palazzo della Signoria,
and Florence is in a state of emergency.
No one's allowed in the streets.
They'd nab you the second you got there.
Even authorized medical personnel
have trouble getting around.
It all depends on the Germans' mood.
Harriet, don't be foolish!
- You don't even know where it is.
- I'll find it!
The whole city is in German hands.
Try to get a Red Cross armband.
The partisans only control San Jacopino.
All right.
Keep down!
Look, that's the way we came.
Come on.
Those swine!
They've blown up all the bridges.
Come on, quick.
Look!
The Germans!
- Open up! Hurry!
- The window.
- Please open up.
- Who's there?
The Germans are coming! Open up!
Hurry!
Uncle, some people
want to cross over the rooftop.
Run along now. Keep your heads down.
Hear that 20-caliber machine gun?
They've been pounding that area for three days.
A big mistake, in my opinion.
Excuse me, which way to San Jacopino?
See Borgo Ognissanti there? Continue along there.
Are there still Germans in the streets?
No.
The partisans have been fighting
for that area for two days.
Maybe they'll have word of Lupo.
How long have they been fighting?
Two days. Since the night before last.
Listen, that's the 88!
Major, your wife's worried and says to come down.
I'm fine up here!
I can't budge now. And send up my helmet.
All right.
Just for the sun, not the bullets.
Those I can dodge to the inch.
I fought in the real war, back in 1918!
Renato, another map.
Good! Let's have a look.
They're in Galluzzo.
Send word of their latest position.
You live here? How should we proceed?
Try the rooftops, but be careful.
Lots of tiles are broken, and it's dangerous.
There's the 20-caliber again.
- Good-bye. Thanks, Major.
- Good luck.
These two came from the Palazzo Pitti.
The English have brought white flour.
Really? White flour?
Enough for all of us?
Yes, lots of sacks, and they'll bring more.
Why don't they keep coming?
Easier said than done!
The Germans blew up all the bridges.
Heavens! My aunt lives close to Santa Trinita.
Were the old buildings destroyed too?
- No, just on the Ponte Vecchio.
What are they waiting for?
The partisans control San Jacopino.
Why are the English dragging their feet?
That woman says the whole area's been liberated.
You can go out on the streets.
- How do we get there?
Out our courtyard to the Rucellai Gardens.
It's just minutes from there.
But the Fascists are shooting from the rooftops.
I'm not afraid of them. So long, and thanks.
Red Cross.
Careful. Don't bump it against the curb.
Don't worry.
Keep back. Where'd you come from?
Downtown. I have to get
to my family on the Mosse bridge.
I have relatives there too,
but no one can get through.
Not with the Fascists and Germans there.
- Have they blown up buildings?
- Keep back.
- Do you know?
- No, nothing.
There was lots of smoke over there this morning.
Stop! You can't go here!
Carlo, don't you recognize me? I live over there.
Yes, but I can't let you through!
- My family's there.
- It's too dangerous.
There are Fascist snipers.
You want to get killed?
- It's just over there.
- All right, come on. I'll ask the boss.
Marco, these folks want to get across.
All right. Send 'em through.
All right! On your toes, boys.
They're moving out.
Come on.
I know this guy.
Hold it there! Where are you headed?
- Down the street.
- Are you crazy?
My wife and child are just across the street.
Let me through, please.
Massimo, no! Stop!
Get back, idiot!
Marco!
Move it!
Filthy coward!
Look what you did, you swine! Move it!
No, I don't want to die!
Dear God.
Marco...
find my family
and tell them what's happened
so they don't worry.
Mama, I feel cold inside.
Everything's gone badly today since Lupo died.
You won't get on my back anymore now, Lupo.
The “Gothic line”
is an impregnable natural barrier.
Every village there
must be wrested in bitter struggle
from a ruthless and desperate enemy.
Brothers, let us thank the Lord,
who has delivered us from all danger.
If my wife had listened,
we'd have brought the pigs too,
and the Germans wouldn't have gotten them.
Well, take your chickens anyway.
These are mine.
“Very Reverend Provincial Father...
with the help of divine providence,
we are safe and sound.
Our monastery did not suffer much...”
- What is it?
- The Americans, in tiny little cars!
Come inside.
Fra' Pacifico is coming.
Praised be Jesus Christ.
Good evening. May he be praised forever.
Father Superior's waiting for you.
Run along now, boys.
Peace be with you, brothers.
May Saint Francis bless you.
We are American chaplains.
May we spend the night here?
Our doors are open to all.
Fra' Pacifico, prepare rooms for these gentlemen.
These are our other brothers:
the vicar, the substitute, and the organist.
Please come with me.
Please step inside.
Please have a seat.
A chair, Father Claudio.
Take their helmets.
I'd like to ask about my town, San Leo.
I'll ask them in a moment.
Father, if I may -
Very kind, but no, thank you.
Father, would you have any news about San Leo?
Is it badly damaged?
Not badly.
My deepest thanks.
I'll say a special prayer to our Holy Mother
for your spiritual and temporal aid -
That's fine, Fra' Raffaele. We understand.
We make this liqueur from own apples, Fathers.
Would you like to try it?
- Hail Mary...
- Full of grace.
The rooms are ready, Father.
Fathers, if you'd be so kind.
Such men, those three chaplains!
Father Superior, they forgot this.
Don't get excited.
They're down the other corridor.
- Are they spending the night?
- They'll be our guests at dinner.
Of course. We'll share all we have with them.
- Praised be Jesus Christ.
- Forever and ever.
What are you preparing for this evening?
Broccoli.
Is there enough for three honored guests
- who'll be joining us?
- No, there's very little.
We could mix in some potatoes.
There aren't many potatoes either.
I've noticed that the pear tree
is starting to bear fruit.
They won't be ripe for a month,
and they're barely edible anyway.
Do your best. I know I can count on you.
Divine providence will help us.
Praised be Jesus Christ.
Forever and ever.
Go see who it is.
- What is it?
- An offering for the monastery.
- You saved our animals.
- May Saint Francis bless you.
Help me carry all this.
Come here, please.
Meat and vegetables - good.
Cocoa, butter, milk...
more meat.
All very good food.
Go now. The rest later.
Look what they gave me.
There are eggs, butter, and chocolate inside.
Eggs in cans? In here?
- Well, I'll be!
- Let me see the chocolate.
These Americans think of everything.
Give me that gadget.
Careful, Father Salvatore.
You'll hurt your fingers.
This isn't your line of work.
It's milk!
Smells good.
Well, I'll be!
Nothing would grow here before.
Now it's the most fertile part of our garden.
One of Fra' Raffaele's miracles.
Smells good.
Mint.
Good evening. Lovely garden!
He's very bad.
No, he's good.
Excuse me. I must go now.
Good evening.
Why aren't they praying?
These two are very bad.
He's a Protestant,
and he's a Jew.
Father Salvatore, one of the chaplains is a Jew!
- What is it?
- Come back here!
One of the chaplains is a Jew!
Merciful Saint Francis!
Father Claudio, one of the chaplains is a Jew!
One of the chaplains is a Jew!
Jesus...
protect us and help us.
- What is it?
- One of the chaplains is a Jew.
Don't worry. Get up now.
A Jew in our monastery!
The short one's a Protestant.
The heresy of Luther,
the worst of all Protestants.
What is it, my sons?
One of the chaplains is a Jew,
and another's a Protestant.
Two lost souls, Father Superior.
No soul is lost while it still has life
and a will to be saved.
There are always opportunities for redemption.
We can do something for them, brothers.
Would you mind if I asked a question, Father?
Of course not.
Have you lived with the other
two priests a long time?
We've been together
for the entire Italian campaign.
Twenty months. No, 21.
Sicily, Salerno,
Rome, Florence.
They're good and dear friends.
I admire them very much.
Have you never tried
to lead them to the true faith?
Have you never tried?
But Father, the Protestant and the Jew
are just as convinced
that they're on the true path.
- But we know that they err.
- Yes, we do.
Certainly.
We must try by every means possible
to save those two souls that could be lost.
I am a Catholic, Father, and a priest,
and I humbly believe I'm a good Catholic.
Forgive me. I didn't mean
to remind you of your duties.
I just meant that you're military chaplains.
Your mission exposes you
to the same risks and dangers as soldiers.
Have you never thought that your two companions
might perish any day?
Saint Paul says...
"Omnes quidem resurgemus,
sed non omnes mutabimus in gloria."
But for those of good faith...
"in novissima tuba surget in gloria."
That's true, but have you
examined their conscience?
Are you sure they're of good faith?
Have you ever discussed these things with them?
No. I've never examined their consciences.
I've never discussed this with them.
I've never asked them anything,
because I've never felt I could judge them.
I know them too well. They're good friends.
Perhaps you...
here amid this peace,
this atmosphere of serene meditation,
consider me guilty.
I don't feel guilty.
My conscience is clear.
“My soul is sad unto death.”
Our rule asks that we remain silent during meals.
I'm sorry I can't make an exception for you.
On this day the following brothers
passed on to a better life:
Father Salvatore of San Leo in 1722,
Father Giambattista of Rimini in 1743,
and Father Teodoro of San Marino in 1744.
Please start.
We'll wait for all of you.
We're fasting.
Why?
Because divine providence sent to our refuge here
two souls on which
the Gospel's light must descend.
Our human presumption leads us to hope
that for this humble sacrifice
we might receive a great reward from heaven.
Forgive me...
if I do not heed your rule...
but I wish to speak.
I must tell you that you've given me
such a great gift
that I feel I will be forever in your debt.
Here I've found that peace of mind...
that I'd lost
amid the horrors and misfortunes of war.
A beautiful and moving lesson
in humility, simplicity...
and pure faith.
Pax hominibus bonae voluntatis.
Behind the lines,
Italian partisans and American
OSS officers join as brothers
in a battle missing from war reports
but perhaps even fiercer and more desperate.
PARTISAN
Partisans! Bandits!
Another partisan killed. I'll go get him.
I don't care. I'll go anyway.
All right, but make sure you do it right.
Look!
Look! Shoot!
Filthy swine!
- What happened?
- Another partisan in the Po.
Another partisan in the Po, boys.
Go get the guns.
San Marco!
Where is it? Where's the radio set?
Take the boats into the canals right away.
Keep down.
You and you, come with me.
That's Casal Madalena.
The guns.
We'll find something to eat there.
Here comes Cigolani.
- Come in.
- Evening, boys. Any news?
The Germans were here yesterday.
Let 'em look. I'm not afraid of 'em.
You know I'm hiding some Americans?
Yes.
I haven't lit a fire in days
so there won't be smoke.
They have lookouts everywhere.
They're hunting us hard out there.
Can you spare anything to eat?
- Whatever we have. A little polenta.
- We could cook up some eels.
- Fine.
There's an American outside. May I ask him in?
Yes, call him.
Let's go in and eat.
On his face.
Keep it hidden.
How many?
Eight, ten - however many you want.
Here they come.
Here they are.
I got confirmation for the drop.
Good.
Cigolani, the flares!
Light the flares, boys.
The flares!
Put 'em out!
He says to put out the flares!
- You find anything?
- Not a thing.
Look harder!
Damn it! They're firing on Casal Madalena.
Think they figured out we were there?
Cigolani!
Take all your men to Pancirli and wait there.
To Pancirli, boys!
Back to the sheds, and keep your eyes open!
Look, boys! British planes
are strafing Scardovari.
Let's go, quick!
Come with us, quick!
- Cigolani, was it just those two?
- Yes.
But they're English, not American.
Better than nothing.
- They're all wet.
- We have to warm them up.
Gimme your hand.
Come on. There's one more.
- Did the plane sink?
- Yes.
- Anything salvaged?
- Nothing.
- Nothing at all?
- Not a thing.
Go get them some oilskins.
- Did you send it?
- Yes.
Hurry or the Germans will get us.
- Who's there?
- Popsky.
Come out.
Boys, the Germans are coming up the Po.
We've got to scatter and get to the sea quickly.
Hurry, boys.
Keep down!
Hands up!
Good. Let's go.
Glasses.
A glass.
Now get out.
Cheers.
What are they gonna do to us?
They'll kill us.
Why'd they kill Cigolani and not us?
They'll kill us too.
Poor Giulia
You're dead and gone now
Damn it.
My folks will never know what happened to me.
He pissed on me like a whore.
Stop, you filthy pigs!
This happened in the winter of 1944.
By early spring the war was over.