[short breaths]
[Woman on TV]
It'Ős all so strange.
All I remember
is that I wasn'Őt happy.
Was I?
[Second woman, on TV]
Scarlet--
You keep calling me that.
Sounds like some other person.
Isn'Őt there anything
that you can remember?
There is something.
It'Ős more like a dream
than anything
that really happened.
I'Őm walking down a hallway.
It'Ős dark.
And it'Ős so quiet I can hear
my footsteps echoing.
The hallway is very long.
It seems never to end.
All the time I'Őm walking,
I have this feeling
that when I reach
the end of the hall,
I'Őll find something.
It'Ős very frightening
at first,
but if I can stand up to it
and face it,
it could be something
wonderful.
[Scarlet, on TV]
But I can'Őt remember
my dreams.
That'Ős my close-up.
[Scarlet, on TV]
Maybe I just don'Őt want to.
He gave her
my fucking close-up.
[nurse]
Is something wrong?
I thought that was
the call button.
[nurse]
Do you know where you are?
Yeah.
I'Őm in the fucking hospital.
I was here yesterday,
wasn'Őt I?
[nurse]
You'Őve been here for a while.
My legs... fell asleep.
I wanted to get up.
-Do you know who you are?
-[laughs]
She'Ős the one with the amnesia,
not me.
Just help me sit up,
all right?
-[inhales sharply]
-You had surgery yesterday.
We put the rods on your spine.
Do you remember?
I'Őm going to call Dr. Miles.
He'Őll give you something
to calm you down.
No, I don'Őt need
to be calmed down.
I need to be helped up.
You did something to me,
didn'Őt you?
You gave me a shot
and my legs went to sleep.
-I'Őm going to call Dr. Miles.
-No!
Just give me a straight
fucking answer!
-What did you do to me?
-I think he'Ős on the floor.
[gasping]
I'Őll get Dr. Miles.
He'Őll give you something
to calm you down.
No.
What happened to my legs?
[nurse] Sometimes the medication
makes it hard to remember.
[woman, sobbing]
What am I doing here?
[heavy breathing]
What is wrong with me?
[Max, on TV] It'Ős good to see
you out of the hospital.
-How are you feeling?
-Fine, Dr. Buckner.
[therapist]
Try to hold your position
without using your arms
too much.
[woman gasping
and breathing heavily]
Okay. Now turn your head
to the left, very slowly.
[gasping]
I'Őm right here.
I'Őm not going to let you drown.
I knew there was a catch.
[therapist 1]
Look at Carlos.
He'Ős doing ten reps already
with weights on his shoulders.
Carlos is a fucking monster.
Carlos belongs in a circus.
[therapist 1]
You'Őre just as good a candidate
for rehab as he is.
Right. Can you take me
back to my room now?
-No.
-My shoulders hurt.
Are you gonna make me
stay here?
[therapist 1] Go back
to your room if you want.
-You know the way.
-[therapist 2] All right.
Let'Ős try a little
weight on it.
[therapist counting]
[therapist 1] If you had
some upper body strength,
you wouldn'Őt have
any trouble with that.
Fuck you!
Fuck you too, Carlos!
Who are you?
[man]
I'Őm Dr. Kline.
A shrink.
[Kline]
I'Őm a psychologist.
You got the voice.
[Kline]
Do I?
I was under analysis
for seven years.
[Kline]
I see.
I'Őm going to ask you
some questions about yourself.
You going to make me walk?
[Kline]
No, May-Alice.
You going to make it
so I can pee
without sticking plastic
inside me?
[Kline]
I'Őm not a urologist.
Then go peddle it
somewhere else.
[therapist]
Okay, I want you to raise
yourselves up on your elbows.
That'Ős it. Not too much
side to side with the head.
Okay.
Now push your body back
to where your elbows are
underneath your shoulders.
That'Őll give you
the leverage.
Hey, that'Ős really good,
Chuck.
Okay, I want you
to roll to the left.
Really slowly now,
under control.
Go right to the supine
elbows position.
Use your momentum.
Don'Őt lie back.
Okay, from the elbows,
we extend the arms,
keeping balance.
Walk it up
to a sitting position.
Wonderful.
Okay, leaning forward,
those of you with your legs
still crossed...
[sobbing]
[May-Alice, into phone]
I just want out of this
fucking boot camp.
It'Ős like a fraternity here.
All these gang members
shot in holdups,
motorcycle casualties,
hang gliders.
I want to go home.
No. "Home" home, down there.
You'Őre my business manager.
You'Őre supposed to know
about this stuff.
Square it with
the insurance company
and get me out of here.
[woman 1]
Scarlet.
[woman 2]
We read all about your tragedy
in the Digest.
[woman 1]
We were so shocked.
[woman 2]
You'Őre one of our favorites.
[woman 1]
Could you sign this?
Thank you so much.
You'Őre going to make
a wonderful comeback.
I just know it.
Thank you very much.
[therapist] Hold it there
as long as you can.
Is that as much
as you can do?
[May-Alice] I don'Őt have any
upper body strength.
We'Őre going to get you some.
Car accident.
Fucking taxicab.
I was getting out of one,
another one comes along
and sideswipes it.
Hit me,
took the door right off.
Fucking kamikazes.
Don'Őt let me push this down.
I was going to have
my legs waxed.
New York City.
It says you'Őre some kind
of actress.
Some kind.
I was on daytime.
-"Daytime"?
-Soap opera.
Some of my patients
watch those.
Yeah, we always got
lots of letters from shut-ins.
What brings you down
to Louisiana?
I heard what a brilliant
therapist you were.
Might not be New York City,
but we do alright.
Can even get your legs
waxed here, if you want.
I have a house here.
Vacation house?
No. I grew up here.
Jeff Davis Parish.
Could'Őve fooled me.
I spent a fortune
losing my accent.
Okay, there'Ős two kinds
of therapy
I'Őm going to work on with you.
One is to strengthen
the muscles
you still have control over.
Keep your back lined up right,
increase your range of motion.
The other is to promote
circulation and tone
in the areas
you'Őve lost the use of.
I'Őm not the wheelchair
Olympics type.
May-Alice, you'Őre a T-10
complete spinal lesion.
Whatever movement
and sensation you'Őve lost
because of that
isn'Őt ever coming back.
But the rest of your body,
the rest of your life,
it'Ős whatever
you want to make it.
Right, Coach.
I don'Őt know what you were like
before the accident.
You mean my premorbid
personality?
Oh, you'Őve been reading
the literature.
You got a standing frame
at this house?
My business manager said
he bought everything
in the catalog.
Well, you have to use it.
I want you to stand
one hour a day.
[May-Alice snorts]
Sure.
If you'Őre going to be
my patient--
Look, I know the whole routine,
and I'Őm not buying into it.
I don'Őt want you
coming to my house.
I don'Őt want your pep talks.
This visit is just something
that my business manager
cooked up
with the insurance company.
Am I going to meet this guy,
this business manager?
I'Őm out of business.
Mm-hm. No ramp.
No.
The house
has not been prepared.
I figured we'Őll sort of
work our way into it.
An old house.
Not that old.
Old houses are dirty.
I had my business manager call
to get it cleaned.
[grunts]
There should be a ramp.
That hurts.
You must be clean.
I'Őm clean enough.
It hurts.
You think this is pain?
At home I do 100 abortions.
Illegal. No drugs.
That is pain.
[laughter on TV]
[indistinct chatter on TV]
[nurse]
You eat now.
What exactly is this?
Kasha. Big fiber.
Is good for stool.
Yeah.
It looks like it might
have something to do with that.
[Rhonda, on TV]
That'Ős what it'Ős all about.
[Jessica, over TV]
Look, it was a computer error.
[Rhonda]
Computer error?
Well, isn'Őt somebody
supposed to check dosages
before the prescriptions
are filled?
[Jessica] Do you know how many
patients a day we treat here?
[Rhonda]
I don'Őt care how many.
The only one I care about
is Scarlet.
A little cleaning?
It'Ős important
that we have clean walls.
I'Őll be climbing them soon.
[snorts]
[announcer chattering
indistinctly over TV]
Can you hear this?
It is 3:00 in morning.
I'Őll turn the volume down.
Is night.
You must sleep.
I got the rest of my life
to sleep.
[sighs]
Eat.
I'Őm not hungry.
Is good breakfast.
Eat.
I'Őm not hungry.
I'Őm not even awake.
No eat, no TV.
Weren'Őt you in
"Ilsa: She-Beast of the Gulag"?
Eat.
I call agency.
They send new person
tomorrow.
Before I found him,
I used to get, like,
really depressed and all.
You know?
Like, I'Őd try to go on a diet.
And I'Őd starve myself and, like,
throw up a lot and everything,
you know?
But then the minute
I went off the diet,
I, like, gained back
all the weight I'Őd lost,
and then some.
And I'Őd feel
so weak and worthless
and, you know, like...
Pudgy.
Pudgy. Yes.
But then I found him,
and it, like,
clicked in my head
that he loves you
whether you'Őre, like,
pudgy or skinny,
or short or tall,
or really smart
or kind of stupid,
or all healthy and athletic or,
like...
Crippled.
Physically challenged,
you know?
And then it, like...
[crying]
I'Őm sorry!
You hate this job.
No, it'Ős not that.
I mean, I do hate this job,
but that'Ős not
what'Ős so terrible.
You got problems
with your boyfriend.
Yes.
Well, you shouldn'Őt
let some big dope
get you all hysterical.
But he'Ős not a dope.
He'Ős not even American.
What'Ős his name?
Derek?
No.
-Jean-Claude?
-No.
Paulo?
Yes.
[woman on TV]
It just seems a little
convenient, that'Ős all.
I mean, Rhonda is...
Do you know that Blake?
Different show.
I hate her.
How'Ős about Lucinda?
Lucinda?
Lucinda on the stories.
Do you know her?
A different show.
Raven? Dominique?
Different show.
It'Ős on the same network,
though.
She comes on
right after you.
There'Ős not like a room
where they store us all
in between shows.
What about that Erica?
[new nurse]
Morgan City, which is, like...
-[indistinct audio from TV]]
-...the lowest pit of hell,
you know?
I was stuck there for about
two or three weeks
until I met this guy,
Blackout, this biker.
You like bikes?
Hm.
Well, Blackout got these
disability checks
from the government,
you know?
Because he was in this
psychological drug
experiment thing
when he was in the Army,
and something went wrong.
I mean, you know what it'Ős like
to sleep with somebody
that'Ős got, like,
a ten-inch hunting knife
strapped to his thigh?
Hm.
But you know,
he was an okay guy, really.
As long as he stayed
on medication.
Boy, if he skipped a dose
or two, that was like...
[pops lips]
And besides, he had to go back
in the hospital to get a refit
on this steel plate that he--
You know, he had in his head.
And that'Ős when I met
this guitar player.
Okay, you know, heavy metal?
-Mm-hm.
-Okay, well, like,
this is way beyond that.
I know this guy
that got electrocuted once
when he was working out
on the rigs.
And he told me
that he sees, like,
exactly the same
kind of blue flashes
when Dwaine plays.
You ever been electrocuted?
Mm-mm.
[static crackling on TV]
I'Őm Chantelle.
Didn'Őt think they'Őd send
another one.
How long have you been
without somebody?
I dropped the remote.
I think it'Ős behind
the couch.
You really ought
to have a ramp out there.
Breakfast.
Oh, shit.
I haven'Őt been taking
my Ditropan.
I had an accident here.
I'Őll help you wash up.
Listen, Sharelle...
Chantelle.
[sighs]
You got any problems...
personal problems...
I don'Őt want to hear them.
You been doing this long?
No.
You?
You are a nurse,
aren'Őt you?
Yeah.
I just haven'Őt done
this caretaker thing before.
I mean, staying over
at somebody'Ős house.
Well, I'Őll tell you,
Shondelle, it'Ős a snap.
Chantelle.
All the things I can'Őt do,
you do them for me.
These days,
that'Ős just about everything.
Can'Őt go anywhere by myself.
I can'Őt cook anymore.
I can'Őt work anymore.
I can'Őt shit
without a suppository.
I can'Őt have sex I can feel,
unless I really
get into blowjobs.
Sorry.
You'Őre probably
some big Christian, right?
And I just put my foot
in my mouth.
It'Ős none of my business
what you put in your mouth,
Miss Culhane.
Chantelle, huh?
Chantelle.
What'Őd they tell you about me
at the agency?
You'Őre a T-10.
What else?
You have your own money,
so the pay was better
than the state cases.
Did they tell you
I was a bitch?
On wheels.
[May-Alice chuckling]
[gasps]
Hey.
You found my umbilical cord.
[laughter and indistinct chatter
over TV]
Do you have any way to call me
if you need anything?
I just turn the volume
way up.
Look, I got no idea
what the last one left you
up there.
I'Őll be fine.
Good night, Miss Culhane.
Chantelle?
I don'Őt usually wet myself.
Don'Őt worry about it.
[cries softly]
[Chantelle]
You need me to cut that up
for you more?
I can'Őt deal with grapefruit
in the morning.
[Chantelle]
We don'Őt have any eggs.
I'Őve got them on the list.
I can'Őt deal with breakfast
at all.
There'Ős still a car out back,
isn'Őt there?
Big brown thing?
Good.
Last one took it into Lafayette
a couple times.
Afraid she might have
sold it.
Is there anything you need
before I go?
I can change
the channels myself.
Should I...
Should I help you
in the bathroom before I go?
[scoffs]
I was the best voider
in my rehab group.
Thought they would give me
a fucking medal or something.
Your bathroom'Ős
not set up too well.
Keys should be in the car.
Try to get back
as soon as I can.
Don'Őt kill yourself.
You neither.
[sighs]
[groans]
Ooh.
Oh, God.
All right.
I can do this.
[grunts]
[panting]
You ain'Őt from around here.
I can tell.
Yeah.
And you are. I can tell.
Somebody'Ős in a bad mood.
Must'Őve walked, what?
Three, four miles?
What do you do for this lady
you work for?
I take care of her,
I guess.
White lady?
-Mm-hm.
-Old?
Are you a detective?
You a nurse?
I was. Almost.
The pay must be real good
to get a fine-looking
young lady
to live out with some sickly
old white woman.
Pay'Ős all right.
Well, I hope you stay
working around here.
If you'Őre trying
to be charming,
don'Őt be wasting it on me.
What is that smell?
[laughs]
That'Ős horse, darling.
You put a horse back there?
I take care of them.
Put shoes on their hooves.
Train them for their owners.
You'Őre giving me grief
about working for a white woman.
Is this the town?
Most of it.
Where you want me
to leave you?
Right here is good.
Right.
Want me to find gas
when you'Őre back out?
I can manage, thanks.
-Sugar.
-What?
[turns engine off]
Sugar LeDoux. That'Ős me.
You have got to be kidding.
[chuckles]
Well,
my real name is Ulysse.
Like Ulysses in the ballad.
My man, beaucoup le classique.
What'Ős your name?
-Chantelle.
-Chantelle what?
Chantelle who'Ős got no time
for French-talking
Louisiana cowboys.
You dance, Chantelle?
No. Not anymore.
Excuse me.
Could I buy
one of those cans?
Them are mine.
Oh, you don'Őt work here?
Well, nobody work here.
Old Abe there
owns the pumps,
but he mostly drinks
and sleeps.
Leave the box out for people
to put the money in.
He'Ős sleeping now.
So they just leave the money
for what they take?
-You'Őre not from here, are you?
-No.
And your car'Ős broke down
somewhere without no gas?
Wait one minute,
I'Őll take you, put some in.
Well, I have a lot of stuff
over at the liquor store.
Oh, we can go by there,
pick them up.
[gasping and panting]
[grunts]
[grunting]
Shit! Shit!
Shit.
[panting]
Propane guns keep the birds
off the rice seed.
It'Ős that time of year.
Well.
This used to belong
to Mr. Culhane.
Lived out by the lake.
It'Ős his daughter'Ős now.
-Word is she'Ős stuck in a bed.
-She'Ős paraplegic.
Well, how'Ős she doing?
I just started out there.
The place could use some work.
It wasn'Őt set up
for somebody in a chair.
[car door closes]
I'Őll do the carpentry.
A little plumbing,
fix your roof.
I'Őll talk to her.
You maybe wanna have this car
looked at.
I'Őll tell her you said hi.
Nah. She won'Őt remember me.
Bon chance.
[engine starts]
[sighs]
[breathing heavily]
[turns TV on]
[Chantelle]
I'Őm really sorry I'Őm so late.
I need a glass of wine.
The car broke down.
Didn'Őt have any gas in it.
With ice.
I had a really terrible day.
Mine was a scream.
If you'Őd just bring
the bottle over,
I can pour my own.
-I'Őm not your waitress.
-What are you then?
I'Őm going to get
the rest of the groceries.
If you want a drink,
I'Őll be in the kitchen.
I can'Őt make it out there.
Where'Ős your chair?
You'Őre all sweaty.
I couldn'Őt get back into it
in the bathroom.
It was easier
to come out here.
You fell?
-What are you doing?
-I need to look at your legs.
-I didn'Őt hit hard.
No!
Please. You might be hurt.
You got a big bruise
under your hip.
Nothing'Ős broken, but we
need to take you for x-rays.
No.
There'Ős no way for me
to be sure.
No! It'Ős my fucking body!
I said no!
[May-Alice sobbing softly]
I'Őm not very good at this,
am I?
[sighs]
Yeah, I know.
I'Őve been thinking
about a career change myself.
I thought that you drove back
into the agency
and told them
you were quitting.
I need this job.
Okay.
I'Őll get you some dinner.
Could you help me
pull up my pants first?
[man]
Hello there!
Anybody home?
Can I help you?
I was wondering
if May-Alice might be in.
No one seems to answer
your telephone.
I was something of
an afterthought in the family.
May-Alice'Ős father was already
in high school when I was born.
What time does May-Alice
usually rise?
About noon or so.
Oh.
Sensible girl.
Noon'Őd suit me just fine.
But as long
as there'Ős real estate
to be bought and sold
in Crescent City,
I have no rest.
Real estate.
That'Ős what our dreams come to.
Can I help you find
something?
Oh, I'Őm poking around, aren'Őt I?
I lived here for a spell,
after May-Alice'Ős parents
passed on.
Bachelor days.
If you'Őre looking for the
bottles, I threw all that away.
I see.
There wasn'Őt so much left.
We got some white wine
cold here.
That might be pleasant.
My brother, May-Alice'Ős father,
was an amateur flyer.
He was quite a sportsman,
actually.
His house was once filled
with his trophies on every wall.
Until I was compelled
to donate them
to the local museum
of natural history.
Their eyes seemed to follow me
from room to room.
They were flying
down at the Keys
for the bonefishing, I believe,
not the marlin.
May-Alice'Ős father
was a great admirer
of Mr. Hemingway.
He flew everywhere hunting,
fishing.
-Her mother went along?
-Whither thou goest,
I shall go.
[inhales and sighs]
At the service,
three people rose
to comment on what an excellent
pilot my brother was.
Not my drink, I'Őm afraid.
[pours drink into sink]
I built this myself.
When I was younger,
photography was quite
an obsession of mine.
Huh!
[camera clicks]
[chuckles]
You ever seen the work
of Mr. E.J. Bellocq?
I don'Őt think so.
Well, it'Ős very striking.
Anyhow...
photography remained
an avocation...
not a way of life.
[chuckles]
Mm-mm.
Improves with age.
My friend Jason got his first
taste of financial independence,
and it was gone
with the proverbial wind.
[Reeves and May-Alice laugh]
[May-Alice]
Oh!
He inherited money?
The only thing Jason'Ős
in line to inherit
is a Naugahyde dinette set.
[both laugh]
You remember he was something
of a potter?
Well, he came up
with a scheme
to manufacture
homoerotic delftware.
Go on!
Dinner plates
with little Dutch boys
painted in compromising
positions.
[laughs]
Oh!
Perversion is rampant
in our society.
[chuckles]
You'Őre better off
without him.
I keep telling myself that.
I was so sorry to hear about
your affliction, May-Alice.
I always wanted you
to be the one who went away
and became famous
and was always happy.
Now this.
Reeves, if you start to cry,
I'Őm going to throw
my drink at you.
[gasps]
That'Ős my Uncle Reeves.
Inn'Őt he great?
He'Ős real... literary.
[chuckles]
Reeves has been, uh...
"literary" ever since
he was a boy.
Didn'Őt go down real big
in my family.
Takes all kinds.
He gave me his camera.
Isn'Őt that sweet?
Mm.
[woman, on TV] But you were
insane toward the end,
making up all kinds
of crazy stories,
sleeping with every man in sight
and then accusing...
Hey!
-This.
-What--
What is this?
I'Őm taking them out with us.
-Us?
-Us. You and me.
-Out?
-Outside.
Uh-uh. I don'Őt like
the sound of this.
You need strength
in your upper body.
Oh, really?
And why is that?
Because I'Őm not taking you
to the potty every four hours,
wiping your butt, and pretty
soon you'Őre going to be too weak
to do it for yourself,
how'Ős that?
When was the last time
you were outside?
They used to park us on the roof
at the rehab hospital.
You need sun.
Raisins need sun.
Alfalfa needs sun.
Do you swim?
Not willingly.
Can you swim
in this lake?
[chuckles]
You mean,
with the snakes?
Maybe I can find you a pool.
Okay.
Let'Ős see what you can do.
Here.
That'Ős what I can do.
Now push me back inside.
Push yourself back inside.
Don'Őt pull that motivational
crap on me.
I want to go back in!
I'Őll have lunch ready
when you get there.
Chantelle, get back here.
You get back here!
I want to go back inside!
Chantelle!
It'Ős uphill!
So'Ős life!
Chantelle!
Damn it!
Here'Ős some hot tea.
Water gets lively
this time of year.
Saw some fish.
Couple of herons too.
Are there really
snakes out there?
There were when I was little.
We kind of ignored them.
Kids aren'Őt scared
of anything.
I was scared of stuff.
Are you going to do something
to get stronger?
And why do you think
I need to be stronger?
Because the next one
may not be so nice as me.
Right.
And you'Őre
Florence fucking Nightingale.
You got a telephone anytime
you want to get rid of my ass.
But if I'Őm going to stay,
I have to be able to do my job.
Are you going to try it?
Don'Őt leave me places.
[exhales]
[gasps]
[woman]
Hello.
May-Alice.
Oh, shit.
[laughs]
[forced laughter]
We'Őre so glad
to find you at home.
We'Őve been so naughty
about not visiting.
And we weren'Őt sure if--
We weren'Őt positive
you'Őd remember us.
That'Ős the character
she played, Precious,
not May-Alice.
You do remember us,
don'Őt you, darling?
Hello?
Chantelle,
these are my old friends,
Ti-Marie
and Precious Robicheaux.
Chantelle is my assistant.
-Pleased to meet you.
-Hello.
[mouths]
Don'Őt.
Would you like to stay
for lunch?
We'Őd love to.
[chuckles]
We'Őve been following
your program.
Everybody is so proud
of you.
There are so few people
from here to be recognized
on a national level.
Unless, of course,
you read the sports pages.
Edward reads them
out loud to me.
Edward is her husband.
Twenty years next May.
Precious has inertia
confused with romance.
And Ti-Marie
changes husbands
like Edward changes
automobiles.
A new one
every four years.
Anthony lasted five.
It took you a year to find him
to serve the papers.
Of course,
we'Őre very provincial
compared to the goings-on
on your television program.
What was it called?
"The Young and the Stupid."
Was that it?
It'Ős a joke, Precious.
What do these people eat
for lunch?
And you never married,
did you?
-Once.
-Oh!
And were you blessed?
-Pardon?
-Children?
She wants to know
if you had children.
I don'Őt need an interpreter,
Ti-Marie.
I do speak English.
I never had children.
What a shame.
And now you can'Őt.
Precious, slow down,
darling.
I thought about having them,
but I never really did
anything about it.
You were always
so eccentric at school.
She means different.
I just knew you'Őd do something
original with your life.
Didn'Őt we always used to say,
"I wonder how May-Alice
is gonna end up"?
Now you know.
[door closes]
Chantelle.
Well, what have we here?
We haven'Őt unpacked
the china yet.
Moving is such a bother.
You haven'Őt moved
in 20 years, Precious.
Well, I can empathize,
can'Őt I?
Chantelle, could you bring
some wine?
She is such a jewel.
Wherever did you find her?
Did her people
work for your parents?
She works for an agency.
Ah. You don'Őt see as much
colored help these days.
It was the 'Ő60s,
those riots up north.
Right. How you'Őre going
to keep them down on the farm
after they'Őve burned Chicago?
Did they burn Chicago too?
It'Ős a joke, Precious.
[chuckling]
Well, ours down here have
certainly caught the attitude.
[Ti-Marie] Precious and Edward
have a Guatemalan woman.
-[Precious] Spanish.
-[Ti-Marie] She speaks Spanish.
She'Ős from Guatemala.
[sighs]
Oh, it'Ős warm.
I thought it was gazpacho.
I wasn'Őt expecting--
Campbell'Ős?
[laughs]
Just a little surprised.
Excuse me.
My husband, Edward,
can'Őt tolerate truly hot soup.
He'Ős very sensitive.
Edward? Sensitive?
You are so critical of him
just because he'Ős faithful
and steady.
Steady?
He'Ős practically comatose.
Edward is in perfect health.
-It'Ős a joke, Precious.
-[door slams]
[both chuckle]
Chantelle, I just thought
of something else
we need at the market.
[Precious] I remember
when we were here last.
Your parents, God bless them,
were still with us.
Some sort of soiree.
A slumber party.
Oh, yes, I remember now.
Laurel Pettibone was there,
and Stacy Lee Ellis.
[gasps]
And who was that girl?
That one with the hair?
We all had hair, Precious.
No, the one with the hair
who we were so awful to.
She wore it in that enormous
braid down her back
like some sort
of peasant woman.
That was me.
[cork pops]
Oh, May-Alice.
[chuckles]
It couldn'Őt have been you.
It was a picture I had
of Joan Baez.
Took me hours
to get the same effect.
Perhaps I misremember.
I'Őm thinking of someone
we just tortured.
That was me.
[Chantelle]
Miss Culhane?
It'Ős 2:15.
It'Ős time for your injections.
[gasps]
Right.
My injections.
Oh, dear.
Have we overstayed
our welcome?
If I don'Őt have the spasms,
they only take about an hour.
Well, we were just
passing through anyway.
And now we know
where you are.
Yes.
You think I'Őll need
the restraints today?
They'Őve been set up.
Excuse us, please.
That was her
with the strange hair,
wasn'Őt it?
[sighs]
I feel like I'Őve been
picked clean by buzzards.
You hadn'Őt seen them
in a while?
Not since I boarded with them
at Grand Coteau.
I thought that soup bit
was brilliant.
You just open the can
and heat it up.
What'Ős so brilliant
about that?
Well, I thought, you know,
you were trying to help me
get rid of them.
I can'Őt cook.
Sure you can.
Is there some rule all black
people got to know how to cook?
[in Creole accent]
Darlin'Ő, down here
there'Ős a rule
that everybody got
to know how to cook.
[music playing over TV]
You want to watch with me?
What is it?
Bette Davis
and Joan Crawford
pretending they'Őre
the Robicheaux sisters.
[chuckles]
Oh!
You thought I looked bad.
[chuckles]
Chantelle, do you have to wear
that uniform all the time?
I thought you wanted it on.
It'Ős so nursy.
I am a nurse.
Not an assistant.
Well, I don'Őt know
what else to call you.
You'Őre not my servant.
Thank you.
You'Őre not my babysitter
or my housekeeper.
I'Őm not your friend.
You know, you can go out
at night if you want.
Oh, no, I'Őm fine
right here.
Must be so boring for you.
It'Ős a job.
It'Ős supposed to be boring.
"Oh, no, Miss Culhane.
It'Ős never boring
working for you."
[chuckles]
If you want me to be that way,
I'Őll try.
No.
You have to be totally
straight with me, okay?
Whatever you got on your mind,
I want to hear it.
Yeah?
Yeah.
You drink too much.
No, I don'Őt.
Is this the one where
she feeds her sister the rat?
[hammering]
[sighs]
Chantelle?
Somebody is pounding
on my house
with a large,
blunt object.
He'Ős been doing that
for a long time now.
Who'Ős "he?"
He'Ős the guy that I hired
to build a ramp
and to fix up the bathroom.
You told me you wanted to,
and I think he'Ős given
a good price.
Why'Őd he have to start
so early?
It'Ős past noon,
Miss Culhane.
Hm.
Could you call me May-Alice?
What, you mean when your friends
aren'Őt here?
I mean all the time.
Whatever you want.
How long have I been
wearing these?
Since Monday.
I kind of gross you out,
don'Őt I?
Is this a trick question?
Rennie.
Hi.
It'Ős Rennie, right?
Yeah, yeah, it'Ős--
Yeah, it'Ős me.
[laughs]
Wow.
How are you?
I'Őm fine.
I'Őm older.
[laughs]
How are you?
Um... uh...
So you'Őre a carpenter?
Yeah, some of this,
some of that.
Oh, Chantelle wondered
if you wanted to come inside,
have something to drink.
Lemonade, iced tea.
Sure.
Great.
[laughs]
Rennie.
May-Alice.
You have a family,
I guess.
Mm-hm. Oh, yeah.
-How many kids?
-Five.
Wow.
I didn'Őt realize
people had that many anymore.
Us coon-asses do.
You still go out
on your daddy'Ős boat?
Oh, I suppose
you got your own now.
No, that'Ős mostly what I do.
Take tourists out
on the swamp
and point out the alligators
and snakes.
Beats chasing around
an oil patch, like my daddy.
Five kids.
Mm-hm.
I know your wife?
I don'Őt see
how you'Őd have met.
Well...
thanks.
Later you might want to show me
what you need in the bedroom.
[snickers]
We got all these rails
and things
from the gimp catalog,
but I never got around
to having them installed.
Well, I'Őll take a look at it.
And, you know,
that'Ős a real nice boat you got
sitting out front.
Hasn'Őt been run
in 20 years.
Well, ought to somebody
check it out someday.
[door opens and closes]
Why didn'Őt you tell me
it was him?
Was he somebody special?
[sighs]
At least he'Ős not in jail.
[chuckles]
Did you go to school
with him?
He'Ős from before
I went off to Grand Coteau.
He was real wild.
We all had crushes on him.
But he was--
You know, his daddy wore
alligator teeth around his neck
and had all these tattoos.
Rennie'Őd come over
and sell fish bait to my daddy.
White trash?
It was more complicated
than that.
They was the real
swamp Cajuns, darling.
[speaks French]
Rennie Boudreau.
Five kids.
Jesus.
[sighs]
I look like shit,
don'Őt I?
[indistinct chatter on TV]
[man, on TV]
Rolling at first,
trickling ever downward,
gathering force,
winter snows go into a torrent.
Scouring their ancient pathways
to the valley floor.
And above it all,
an eagle soaring
on the moon-settled mountains.
The river and valleys
all sprang forth.
From this celestial vantage...
[continues indistinct]
[sobs]
[answering machine beeps]
Hi, May-Alice
isn'Őt here right now.
If you want to leave a message,
wait till after the beep
and leave your phone number.
[answering machine beeps]
May-Alice is always here.
They know that.
And what if it'Ős for you?
I won'Őt be getting
any messages.
Listen, what if the car
takes longer than a day to fix?
Stay over, I guess.
Be a nice break for me.
I should tell them to leave
the time they call, huh?
Hi. May-Alice has crawled
into a hole to die.
If you'Őd like to leave
a message, forget about it.
[answering machine beeps]
-[May-Alice humming]
-[water splashing]
Hello?
Chantelle here?
No.
She went to town.
You the lady she...
she working for?
Yes.
I don'Őt know
when she'Ős going to be back.
You afraid of me?
Don'Őt be.
Is she okay?
Chantelle?
Sure. She'Ős fine.
Yeah. Happy?
Well, happy. I don'Őt know.
I mean, she seems okay.
She lives upstairs.
I don'Őt know if she'Ős happy.
Yeah, no reason you would.
I just live with her
24 hours a day.
Was she expecting you?
No, I don'Őt think
she really wants to see me.
Ah.
It'Ős nice to live
near the water.
Yeah. I suppose it is.
You can'Őt feel anything
in your bottom half?
That'Ős the general idea.
[sighs]
Yeah, I felt that once.
Yeah, it started in my feet.
And then it moved
to my knees.
And I remember thinking
how when it reached my heart,
I'Őd be dead.
What happened?
Well, I just did some more
of whatever it was
I was all messed up on, and...
and it shot me right past
into somewheres else.
Did she finish
with the detox?
Yes. I think so.
Yeah. When she make up her mind
to do something,
you do not want
to be in her way, Chantelle.
I'Őve noticed.
Well, you know,
that'Ős good.
She'Ős keeping it straight.
I don'Őt think I want
to wait around for her.
Don'Őt mind me.
No.
I just ain'Őt ready
to do this.
When you see Chantelle,
you tell her...
I'Őm sorry.
Who do I say came to call?
Bad news.
She'Őll know who you mean.
[camera clicks]
[country music
playing over radio]
It'Ős Chantelle
Who-don'Őt-have-time-for-me.
Sugar.
Yeah, you'Őre right.
Only thing good here'Ős
breakfast,
and that'Ős long over.
Then what are you
doing here then?
Coffee machine busted
over at work.
Come on with me,
get you some real food.
I have to be somewhere.
[laughs]
You got time to burn, girl.
I'Őve seen that old car
of your white lady'Ős
sitting over at
the Bourgeois Brothers garage.
Them boys is slower
than a three-legged mule.
Can'Őt tell you what to do
with the rest of your life,
Chantelle,
but I know you don'Őt want
to be spending
no five hours of it in here.
How'Ős that for you?
It'Ős fine.
That there on top
is court bouillon.
I made that myself.
Hm.
[horses galloping]
So all the women up north
so hard to get next to,
or is it just you?
Just me.
[Sugar]
Hey, darling.
Albertine,
say hi to Chantelle.
Hello.
Hi. Nice to meet you.
Albertine'Ős my first girl.
She stays with me
most of the summer.
You'Őve got more?
Yeah, by Albertine'Ős mama,
which was my first wife.
I had her and a boy, Henri.
Henri just got him
a scholarship to LSU.
Then with my second,
I had Cecile and Eugenie.
They live over
by Breaux Bridge now.
Don'Őt see enough of them.
Then, let'Ős see.
Rosalynn.
Ah, Rosalynn, yeah.
I had Andre,
Delia and Lorenzo.
Lorenzo just starting up
school now.
[Chantelle]
Whose horse is this?
Man who gonna put
his top stallion
on one of my mares.
You'Őre going to let him do that?
I'Őm getting paid,
darling.
Kind of bloodline
his stallion got,
cost me a fortune
for that semen.
You gonna do that, huh,
just like in the cowboy movies?
I'Őm a blacksmith.
You'Őre a black something,
all right.
[band playing
upbeat accordion music]
Are you following me?
Just giving you some space,
darling.
[inaudible]
-I can'Őt do it.
-Come on.
-I don'Őt know how.
-Ain'Őt nothing to it.
You have to show me
how to do it.
Show me how.
No, don'Őt be sorry.
Just don'Őt be so suspicious.
The man been married
25 times,
got more kids
than a field got corn.
How am I supposed
to trust you?
I never asked you
to trust me, darling.
I just want you
to be with me,
have some fun.
I already had enough fun
to last me a lifetime.
Will you spend the night
with me?
[laughs]
You don'Őt have to like it.
[both laugh]
You probably live
in the swamp, right?
You got dead raccoons and shit
hanging on your house.
[laughs]
[man, on TV]
Now, how can that be so?
The Lord can'Őt hate anyone.
How can he hate a small child?
Obadiah doesn'Őt explain it.
-He only--
-[turns TV off]
[screams]
[groaning]
Wow.
Ooh.
Oh, Reeves, I love you.
Ha, ha, ha.
[gasps softly]
[cries]
[thunder rumbling distantly]
I'Őm sorry.
I made love to women
who wasn'Őt satisfied before.
But you'Őre the first that
come out and cried about it.
No, it'Ős just me.
I been wondering
what you taste like.
Yeah?
More salt than sugar so far.
I'Őm sorry, I just don'Őt think
it'Ős going to happen.
Not tonight.
Yeah.
Well...
[sighs]
...you kind of took the wind
out of my sails there anyway.
Poor baby.
I got feelings too,
you know.
-Is that right?
-If I'Őm lyin'Ő, I'Őm dyin'Ő.
Could I stay
right here tonight?
Mm-hm.
What'Ős that name of yours,
the real one?
Ulysse.
Like that guy
in the story that...
went to fight the Trojan wars
with an army.
And he'Ős the only one
that make it back alive.
A survivor.
He was that.
[Chantelle]
May-Alice!
-May-Alice?
-[May-Alice] Don'Őt come in.
-Are you all right?
-Shut the door first.
I'Őm printing.
[May-Alice humming]
You get in late?
It'Ős morning.
Really?
I stayed all night.
They didn'Őt finish the car.
No sense of time in here.
I see you'Őve been busy.
[laughs]
I don'Őt need a sermon.
Do you think you can get
through a day without a drink?
-Sure.
-Okay.
Twenty-four hours,
starting right now.
You have enough problems
with your liver and kidneys--
Hey, you'Őre the addict,
not me.
What do you mean by that?
He was here?
In the afternoon.
I hope he didn'Őt scare you.
He wouldn'Őt hurt anybody.
I'Őm glad to hear it.
He didn'Őt seem too healthy.
Turn that light on,
would you?
Shoot.
This is the only part
I can'Őt remember how to do.
I cleaned up.
Finished detox a month ago.
Maybe the fixer'Ős worn out.
Am I fired?
I lied to the agency.
I gave them my records
from back in Chicago
and told them I'Őd been off
in Europe for two years.
Luther had some restaurants.
He owned a big car.
It was fun living high.
It was exciting.
And then we got
to freebasing,
and all of it
just fell away.
What stopped you?
I guess I didn'Őt want
to die.
I need this job.
You'Őre not fired.
And...
If I'Őm not going
to drink today...
I may as well go to bed.
[Chantelle]
How are you feeling?
Like shit.
How did you do it?
First, I was in the hospital.
There'Ős no place to score.
It'Ős back in the real world
that'Ős hard.
This isn'Őt the real world.
I know.
[engine sputters]
[camera clicks]
People been cutting your grass
all these years had any sense,
they'Őd have brought this inside.
You got you some rust.
A couple or three parts, though,
I can have her running.
Did Chantelle ask you
to fix this?
No, I just thought
I'Őd do it.
Why, you live by the water,
you want a boat.
So how'Ős your daddy
these days?
Oh, he'Ős dead.
Oh.
Yeah, he started him a fight
in Smokey'Ős
over at the Sabine Pass.
A couple of roughnecks
put him away in a parking lot.
Ah, that'Ős the way
he lived it.
I'Őll have her running someday,
I'Őll take your friend
and you out,
show you the neighborhood.
Sure.
You never did like it much
down here.
The place is all right.
I just had problems with
who people expected me to be.
You okay?
You seem a little upset
about something.
I'Őm fine.
I'Őm trying to...
I'Őve started a diet.
It makes you cranky,
raises your blood sugar
and all that.
So did you ever
get away from here?
Drafted.
Sent me to the Philippines,
guard ammunition
on the way to the war.
And all of us are real proud of
how you did on the TV.
Sure.
You know, I...
I never did see
your program.
Arlene won'Őt have it
in the house.
A critic.
No television, no radio,
no liquor, no card playing.
Can'Őt sing a song
unless the Lord'Ős name'Ős in it.
-That'Ős serious.
-Oh, she took religion
between the second
and third babies.
Her people were like that,
but she'Őd run off from them
when I met her.
She got the kids in it
with her now.
They pray for me a lot.
[chuckles]
Was I snotty to you
when we were kids?
Well, you...
you weren'Őt much
of anything to me.
You know, we kind of just
looked at each other.
I think you were real nice
to the people you knew.
You were different,
you know,
but, yeah,
you were real nice.
Then how'Őd I get like this?
I'Őm laying cement
over at Landry'Ős today.
I'Őll be by
in a couple of days.
Bye, Rennie.
[grunts]
All right, game'Ős over.
What game?
Where'Őd you put
all the liquor?
-I threw it out.
-It'Ős in the trash?
I poured it out.
The bottles are in the bin.
You poured it out?
The recycle people
don'Őt want
nothing left
in the bottles.
Look, Chantelle,
I am not ready for this.
When I get stronger,
I'Őll quit drinking.
If you keep drinking,
you will not get any stronger.
Okay. The deal was 24 hours,
right?
I'Őve already done that.
Ernie'Ős closes by 9:00.
I'Őm not getting you any more.
What?
You want it,
you get it yourself.
I can'Őt drive.
That'Ős something
to work towards, isn'Őt it?
Don'Őt hand me
that condescending bullshit!
Just go in and get me
some fucking wine!
-Listen to you.
-No, you listen to me.
I hired you, and I want you
to do what I tell you!
Dream on, girl.
Who made you
the fucking warden?
Who made you queen
of the whole damn world?
You sit around feeling sorry
for yourself,
you miserable, TV-watching,
dried-up old witch!
You can'Őt even go
for more than a day
without a drink, and you'Őre not
even a drunk yet!
You'Őre just fucking spoiled!
Most mornings I wake up,
I want to get high so bad
I can'Őt even breathe!
Cocaine is different!
Bullshit!
What do you know about it?
-Where are you going?
-I am going away from you.
I don'Őt want to be
around your shit anymore,
do you understand that?
Away from you!
[whimpers]
[breathing heavily]
-[screams]
-[dishes shatter]
[sobs]
You'Őve been cooking.
Got to do something
to keep busy.
Smells good.
Sit.
Nice plates.
I broke most
of the other stuff.
You did a number on them.
That'Ős okra gumbo there.
You can start with some of that.
Thank you.
I was going to make biscuits,
but I couldn'Őt find
the lard.
[sighs]
-Chantelle?
-Yeah?
Iced tea or Kool-Aid?
-[Chantelle] May-Alice.
-[May-Alice] Yeah?
-[Chantelle] We'Őve got company.
-[May-Alice] Who is it?
[Chantelle]
They say they'Őre from daytime.
[May-Alice]
Damn.
Ah!
[laughs]
Oh, hi.
-Dawn.
-Oh, baby.
It'Ős so good to see you.
May-Alice. Mwah!
You tracked me down.
Florida junket. They expanded it
to New Orleans this year.
Oh, May-Alice, Nina.
This is Nina Crossley.
-She'Ős playing you.
-Yeah, Scarlet.
-Hi.
I'Őm back in the story.
Mm-hm.
Vance thought it was time.
-I'Őm pregnant.
-Oh, I'Őm sorry.
Have a seat, please.
Oh, no, no, no.
Scarlet is pregnant,
on the show.
Oh. Wow.
I'Őm taking Lamaze classes.
You know, me, personally,
as a preparation, you know.
I had a hysterectomy.
Oh. I'Őm sorry.
On the show. Scarlet.
-[chuckles]
-My third season.
A hysterectomy?
They took the crib
and left the playpen.
[scoffs]
Oh. Something my mother
used to say.
-Was she from the South?
-She was from the south side.
Maybe that'Ős why the baby
had to be by Zon-Dar.
Oh, I haven'Őt been
keeping up lately.
Zon-Dar?
-He went back to his planet.
-Ah.
Well, this is a great
surprise.
-[laughs]
-Have a seat.
Would you like something
to drink?
Yes. Do you have
sassafras tea?
Oh, she read that someplace.
Wine spritzer?
We don'Őt have anything
alcoholic.
I'Őll just go and bring out
a bunch of stuff.
Chantelle isn'Őt my maid
or anything.
-Oh. I'Őm sorry.
-Oh.
Oh, I thought she was
a family retainer.
Right.
May-Alice,
this country is so...
It'Ős so laden, you know?
It'Ős--
Laden? With what?
Oh, just atmosphere
and portent.
It'Ős like the air
is thick with...
Oh, what'Ős it thick with?
Humidity.
Right. Right.
It'Ős liquid and heavy
with history and tradition.
It'Ős fecund.
Well, it must be great
for the soil.
This land,
deep and inviolate,
paid for in blood,
infused with the life spirit
of those
who would endure
on its face.
Standing in mute
and eternal reproach
to the cheap
intransigent babble
of the towns that fester
in its nether parts.
This land,
whispering
with overripe breath,
its tale of original sin.
[Nina]
That'Ős amazing. Who wrote that?
I forget.
That'Ős why
I'Őve never had kids.
After surviving me as a mother,
they'Őd grow up and write
more of that twisted
gothic shit.
-[laughs]
-May-Alice,
I think you'Őd make
a great mother.
Oh, Dawn, I couldn'Őt keep
a pet turtle alive.
And when I was married,
it was to that...
that actor.
He was on the show.
Jamie? On a soap?
He played Zon-Dar.
He got you pregnant?
Ha!
He'Ős got a sperm count
of two.
[all laugh]
Does this place have a name?
-[in Cajun drawl]
You mean Lake Arthur?
-Author?
Arthur, like the king.
May-Alice is turning back
into a cracker down here.
I meant the house. Does your
family have a name for it?
You mean like Belle Rive?
Well...
Your apartment in New York
have a name?
-14-G.
-[Nina laughs]
Jeffrey calls our apartment
in the Hamptons
-Uncle Tom'Ős Condo.
-[laughs]
Excuse me.
[Dawn sighs]
I feel terrible.
Here I am, I'Őm--
I'Őm sitting in your backyard,
having a nice time, and...
I'Őm the one
who stole your part
and had an affair
with your ex-husband.
And now I'Őm carrying
his baby.
An affair?
Oh, not in real life.
Oh, no, no, no.
No, she--
He was taken.
Taken?
[chuckles]
He'Ős grown a lot
since you knew him.
At least that'Ős what I thought,
anyway.
You poor baby.
How'Őd it come out?
He went back
to his planet.
Can I help you
with anything?
I'Őm fine.
Kim, she doesn'Őt eat meat.
And Nina, she'Ős just going
to open it up
and scrape out
the mayonnaise.
What about you?
Oh, I eat anything.
So...
you from around here?
-Chicago.
-Really?
[chuckles]
Me too.
Cooley High.
DuSable.
Where'Őd you live?
Euclid Street.
Ooh. Pill Hill.
Father must have been
a doctor.
I'Őm from out
of Cabrini-Green.
It'Ős a long way out.
Hmm. Yeah.
So...
how is she doing?
See for yourself.
I don'Őt think
I could handle it.
Are you and her
good friends?
We spent a lot of time
together.
Work, you know.
Yeah.
You two seem to get along
pretty well.
We spend a lot of time
together.
I did Blanche.
I did Laura.
I did Alma
in "Summer and Smoke."
I did Frankie
in "Member of the Wedding."
Where was this?
Minnesota. In school.
Oh, Minnesota, huh?
One more year on daytime,
save my money,
I am going to quit.
I'Őm going to go back to class
and I'Őm going to do theater.
Uh-huh. I think I'Őve heard
this one before.
I'Őve said that one before.
[Nina]
I didn'Őt ask for the anal probe.
Hm.
Four years starving
in New York,
doing showcases
I had to pay for myself.
That was my first big break.
[laughs]
My first feature, this,
like, zero-budget movie
about people who are taken up
into alien spaceships
and given physicals
against their will.
I go in for the audition,
and the director is really
intense and mysterious.
And he has me sit
with my eyes closed
and free-associate,
right?
We do these improvs
about the aliens
representing our most
primal fears.
And it'Ős great.
Finally, some real acting.
And they tell me before I leave
that I'Őve got the part.
Only I don'Őt know
what it is yet,
but I'Őm so thrilled,
because it'Ős this feature,
you know?
It'Ős not a student film
or anything.
So the agent gives me my script,
and I go through it
looking for Margaret,
the part that they say I have.
And I'Őve got my yellow
underliner marker in my hand,
only it'Ős drying out.
And finally I find only one page
with the corner folded over.
And I'Őm in this therapy group
of these people
who have had these
alien physicals.
And I'Őve got only one line.
"I didn'Őt ask
for the anal probe."
Not much to build
a character on.
But I'Őm a professional, right?
I prepared.
I had backstory
on this woman.
I knew that she had been
to the hairdresser
before she came
to the therapy group.
I knew that she didn'Őt trust
that guy
who sat next
to the fuchsia.
I knew that she
turned the TV set on
the minute she got back
to her apartment,
just for the sound of it.
And I even had my boyfriend--
My boyfriend at the time--
With a thermometer, you know,
for the sense memory, right?
I was loaded
for fucking bear.
So finally it comes time
to shoot the scene.
And they do one take
of the wide shot,
and they stop
before my line.
I was-- I was terrified
that they were going
to cut it.
They move in for reaction shots,
close-ups.
Mostly things that mean that
I have to go and sit outside,
because the camera is set up
where my chair is.
Well, by the time
they get to me,
the crew is grumpy
because it'Ős late
and they'Őre non-union,
and don'Őt get paid extra
for overtime.
The lead actor is gone.
He'Ős got his shrink
appointment.
And I'Őm...
I'Őm alone.
And I'Őm staring
at this piece of tape
stuck to a stand
next to the camera.
And the director says,
"Okay, let'Ős try it a few times
without cutting,
and show me
a few different colors."
[fearful] I didn'Őt ask
for the anal probe.
[shocked] I didn'Őt ask
[intense] I didn'Őt ask
for the anal probe.
[sad] I didn'Őt ask
That was it.
[sighs]
You come back up,
you let me know right away.
-You promise?
-I promise.
Take care.
[engine starts]
Bye, Chantelle.
[sighs]
I need a drink.
That'Ős too bad.
When do you think
I'Őll be strong enough
to have just a little?
Never.
Do you miss it much?
-Drinking?
-Acting.
It was the only thing
I was ever good at.
Chantelle?
Yeah?
I think I need help
dressing.
Do my legs look weird?
A bit pale.
More than the rest of me?
No, not really.
Shorts.
It'Ős what I'Őm wearing.
Oh, of course.
Do you have any
I could borrow?
Yeah.
Look at this.
Think you can do anything
with this?
I'Őm not a hairdresser.
Well, you have friends,
right?
Women friends help each other
with their hair.
My friends don'Őt have
your kind of hair.
Right.
And we don'Őt have time
for cornrows.
Why am I doing this?
Why do I give a shit?
Because he likes you.
You think he does?
He asked you out
on his boat.
He asked you out too.
He'Ős not after me.
He'Ős not after me either.
He'Ős just asking us out
to be nice.
He asked you out.
He asked me to come along.
Now, if you don'Őt want me to--
No! You have to come.
Oh, I feel like
I am fucking 13 years old.
-I am pathetic.
-You'Őre not pathetic.
Or maybe he just wants us
to see his boat.
Men like that,
to show women their machines.
Mm-hm.
Or maybe he really is
after you.
You are pathetic.
Are we lost?
Oh, no.
How can you tell?
I'Őve been coming here
all my life.
Look.
[Rennie]
Oh, yeah.
I saw one of those take off
with a two-foot mud snake
in his mouth.
My daddy almost
swallowed his tobacco.
It meant something to him?
Oh, yeah, everything
meant something to him.
He had all of them
coon-ass superstitions.
Catch something in his traps,
whatever it was,
turtle, gator, possum.
He'Őd cut open the stomach,
see what was inside,
tell the future.
Are there a lot of snakes
in here?
Oh, yeah. This is
cottonmouth heaven in here.
-I'Őll find some for you.
-Don'Őt go out of your way.
I ain'Őt never went out
on any boat.
Not my father'Ős style,
the nature stuff.
Of course,
maybe if he had had sons...
You had sisters?
No.
He wanted boys.
All he got was me.
[sighs]
Tough on your mother.
I lost her when I was 14.
Diabetes.
Are you still close
to your father?
I got married
right out of high school,
and he didn'Őt want me to.
So when we split up,
it was like, you know,
"I told you so."
And who needs that, right?
And later on, when I--
When I hooked up
with Luther, well...
We don'Őt talk anymore.
[Rennie]
Lunch.
Ew! That'Ős nasty looking.
She'Ős from Chicago.
Well, let'Ős check out what the
future'Ős got in store for us.
What'Ős that mean?
Is it good?
Passion fish.
Hold out your hands.
It'Ős real bad luck not to.
Squeeze that little fish
tight now.
Think about somebody
you want some loving from.
You'Őre making this shit up,
right?
Oh, no.
Ever since
there been Cajuns,
they'Őve been squeezing
the passion fish.
Some says you got
to swallow them raw.
I don'Őt need it that bad.
What is this island, Rennie?
-Does it have a name?
-Oh, yeah.
MisŹre.
"Misery."
[Chantelle]
Nice.
The story is some slave woman
went crazy out here.
Lost her only child
to pneumonia,
run off from her people,
holed up out here.
Then the trappers come by
in their pirogues.
They hear her moaning
and crying about her lost baby.
Isle of Misery.
You okay?
Mm-hm.
What'Őd she live on?
Oh, bird'Ős eggs, fish.
Everything out here
that flies, walks,
hops or crawls got a use.
It'Ős all good eating.
[turns engine]
[turning engine]
Something broke?
Yeah.
Can you fix it?
Yeah, but it'Ős going to take
a little time.
I'Őm real sorry about this.
No hurry.
Sure, we'Őll feed the bugs
while you fix it.
Well, I got just the thing
for that.
You-- You better do this.
It keeps the mosquitoes
off your legs.
-Mm, looks like fun.
-Help yourself.
[mouths]
He likes you.
Now are we lost?
No matter where you'Őre at,
there you is.
Your kids must love
being out here with you.
Oh, Arlene won'Őt
let them come.
Says the devil
lives out here.
That'Ős why the trees
won'Őt grow straight.
You getting cold up there?
We'Őre fine up here.
[screams]
Just fine.
I'Őm really sorry
about all this.
I loved it.
It was wonderful.
A thrill a minute.
You want to make a call
from the house?
Your wife.
Oh, no, she knows where I am.
She'Ős not worried.
Right.
Well, good night.
Night.
Good night.
His wife'Ős not worried.
Should she be?
Why worry about
some cripple
who'Ős got a freezer compartment
for a pussy?
Don'Őt be like that.
[sighs]
Look at me, I'Őm pitiful.
My palms are all sweaty.
They smell like fish.
Passion fish.
[hammering]
[hammering continues, echoing]
[Chantelle]
May-Alice!
May-Alice, I found her!
I found her! It'Ős okay!
May-Alice!
[Chantelle]
May-Alice.
[gasps softly]
May-Alice?
You okay?
[sighs]
I was dreaming.
You were in it.
You were on that,
ahem, island.
And you had
this little girl with you.
Don'Őt dream that anymore,
okay?
It'Ős a dream.
It'Ős time to go.
We'Őre going to have to get you
a car with hand controls.
I haven'Őt driven
in 20 years.
Hey, I lived in New York.
I took taxis.
Besides, I'Őd look like
fucking RoboCop.
Jesus, there'Ős Rennie.
Want me to pick you up anything
while you'Őre in session?
May-Alice?
I don'Őt know.
Some more film.
I wish she'Őd open up
a little more.
She'Ős carrying
a lot of weight around.
You'Őve gotten
a little more flexible.
What?
Especially in your neck
and shoulders.
Try to cross your chest.
She'Ős been all over me
about my drinking.
Give me some resistance.
I used to have a few glasses
of wine with dinner,
another while I learned
my lines for the next day,
then fall asleep.
The rest of the time
I was working.
The other one.
Then when I had the whole day
to face--
You'Őre getting stronger.
If I ask for a drink
she won'Őt give it to me,
like she'Ős the boss.
You think
it'Ős something
you can handle
on your own?
No.
How'Ős your bowel function?
Fine. If I eat at the same time
every day.
I almost feel like
we could be friends.
Only there'Ős so much garbage
in between us.
Any shortness of breath?
Pain in the lungs?
So, what do you think?
I'Őm not done yet.
I mean about her,
Chantelle.
I'Őm a physical therapist,
May-Alice,
not a marriage counselor.
Right.
You'Őve been doing
your standing?
Doc.
Don'Őt call me doc.
Call me Louise.
Did you ever fall in love
with a married man?
[shower running]
I got to go!
Sugar!
Oh, hi.
Hi.
I'Őm Chantelle.
I remember.
Sugar said that you
were at the track.
Albertine, when your parents
broke up
and Sugar wasn'Őt around,
were you mad at him?
Both of 'Őem.
Did you stay mad long?
No.
I figured
they'Őre just people.
They got their problems
and I got mine.
You got problems
at your age?
I'Őm working on some.
[no audio]
[May-Alice]
Chantelle?
-Chantelle.
-Yeah?
Could we drive on the right side
of the road for a minute?
Huh? Sorry. I spaced out.
So, what did you do
while I was with Louise?
Just killed time.
[man, on machine]
Hello.
I'Őm calling for Chantelle.
This is her father speaking.
It'Ős 5:00 on Thursday.
Denita and I would like
to visit you this weekend.
Please give me a call.
[answering machine beeps]
Denita?
My daughter.
Chantelle is such a wonder
in the kitchen.
I was never much of a cook
to begin with,
and then with my misfortune,
well...
You like that, darling?
It'Ős got rice in it.
[chuckles]
That'Ős what makes it boudin.
We'Őve never had someone
in the family work as a cook.
Oh, we do share the cooking.
Mine just doesn'Őt taste
like much.
Denita, it'Ős just so nice
to finally have you here
in person.
Chantelle talks about you
so much.
I feel like
I already know you.
[sighs and laughs]
You ever do any gardening,
Dr. Blades?
[Dr. Blades]
Can'Őt say that I have.
Me neither.
Don'Őt think my family
ever put anything in the ground
that wasn'Őt a drill pipe.
My grandfather
was a farmer.
Yeah?
Sharecropper. Alabama.
He must have had
some stories.
None that he cared
to pass on.
Do you think you'Őll continue
to employ my daughter?
As long as she'Őll have me.
Did she tell you I have
legal custody of Denita?
She never got
into the details.
The court gave her to me
when...
when Chantelle was unfit
to be a mother.
Right.
Denita'Ős got some school left
this year,
but for her vacation...
well, I was wondering...
a house, a place for her
to run around.
Well, I'Őm not going anywhere.
[laughs]
[Denita]
Real alligators?
[Chantelle]
Yeah, real ones.
There'Ős a man
that'Ős a friend of ours
who knows all about
where they live.
Maybe sometime he'Őll
take you out to see all that.
How big is it?
The lake?
This one spreads all the way out
to the... to the ocean.
You'Őve never seen the ocean,
have you?
Well, that'Ős something
we'Őll have to do.
I have been missing you
so much.
I messed up.
I got caught...
in something bad.
And I lost you, Denita.
You didn'Őt forget about me,
did you?
You remember what Mommy was like
when she was sick?
Yes.
You'Őre not ever going to see me
like that again. I promise.
["Zydeco Queen" playing]
♪ Went on down
To New Orleans ♪
♪ Just to see
The zydeco queen ♪
♪ From La Riége
To the Thibodaux ♪
♪ Everybody
We'’re doing the zydeco ♪
♪ I went on down
To New Orleans ♪
♪ Just to see
The Mardi Gras queen ♪
♪ When I got there
I didn'’t know ♪
♪ That kings would live
To do the zydeco ♪
Devil'Ős music.
I love it.
Last time I saw you,
before you went north,
-was at one of these.
-Yeah?
I must have sneaked over
with Darcell Moutant.
-My daddy didn'Őt approve.
-Yeah.
And I never got the nerve up
to ask you to dance.
Right.
And then I heard
you had gone away for good.
Well, my dancing days
are over.
-[music ends]
-[applause]
How'Ős your family?
They'Őre fine.
Rennie.
Yeah?
You don'Őt have to have
a job to do
or something to fix
to come over and visit.
Yeah?
Well, maybe I'Őll do that,
then.
Do it soon, okay?
All right, ladies and gentlemen,
you'Őre being entertained
by John De La Forest
and the Split Boys.
We'Őre going to do
the "Poor Man'Ős Two-Step."
[playing "Poor Man Two-Step"]
Excuse me, young lady.
May I have this dance?
[May-Alice] This is the part
that'Ős like magic.
Cute guy.
Did you get
his phone number?
[chuckles]
You got pictures
of alligators?
No, but I'Őm going
to get me some.
They make great subjects.
They'Őll hold still for hours
if they'Őre not hungry.
Hm.
It'Ős nice, isn'Őt it?
[Denita]
Mm-hm.
Of course, it'Ős easier to get
a smile out of an alligator
than it is to get one
from your mother.
[bus horn honks distantly]
But I'Őm fine now.
I really am.
I'Őll call you and your lady
at the end of the school year.
Well, can I come up?
I don'Őt think you should
be back in Chicago.
You'Őre not the damn
parole board.
I am Denita'Ős
legal guardian
for as long as I think
is necessary.
This seems like
a good place for you.
You show me
you can hold on here,
we'Őll make some plans
for Denita.
Goodbye.
Bye-bye, Daddy.
Thanks for bringing her down.
Excuse me,
where can I find Lake Arthur?
Oh, it'Ős right under my nose,
huh?
Actually,
I'Őm looking for somebody.
May-Alice Culhane.
We do a big blitz about
in response to the flood of mail
May-Alice Culhane
is returning to daytime.
What about Nina?
She'Ős been gone for weeks.
We sent Scarlet to
the Mayo Clinic for observation,
and we have hatched a great plan
to bring you back in.
We found a scene from before
where you leave Rhonda
in the living room set
and you actually walk
over to the door.
So we shoot a couch scene
on the set.
Right! You'Őre back from
the clinic, no improvement.
Then we cut to the tape of you
actually walking to the door.
You go outside,
we cut back to her,
watching from the doorway.
And I still have amnesia,
and I'Őm pregnant?
Bear with me a second.
We hold on Rhonda,
and then there is the sound--
Of screeching brakes.
Edna called you.
No, no. I'Őm just guessing.
Go on.
-[laughs]
-All right.
There was a screech of brakes,
Rhonda screams.
Cut.
Monday'Ős show:
First thing,
you'Őre on a stretcher,
lights flashing
all around you.
The driver of the car
that hit you steps forward.
-Guess who it is?
-Max.
[snickers]
Edna did call you.
No, no, really. Go on.
Max ran me over, and...
And he says,
"Scarlet, my God."
But I don'Őt recognize him
because of the amnesia.
No, no, you recognize
his voice, see,
because the impact of the car
cured the amnesia.
A traumatic blow
like that--
Can reverse the effects
of what happened
when I was pushed down
the elevator shaft.
Exactly. So Max is there.
And I remember him.
But now I'Őm paralyzed.
Right. That and...
well, Edna had to go
beyond that.
Go beyond?
[sighs]
See,
they'Őre doing
a wheelchair thing
with Brenda St. Clair
on "Santa Fe."
So we thought,
you'Őve lost the amnesia
and you recognize Max'Ős voice,
but...
I'Őm blind.
See, it works as a metaphor
for Scarlet'Ős--
I'Őm paralyzed
and I'Őm fucking blind.
It opens up
so many possibilities.
Sure.
I can run into walls
with my chair,
knock over props.
Have Max take me back
so that twit Jessica
can get it on with him
while I'Őm in the room!
None of this
is chiseled in stone yet.
Why not put me in a coma?
Total fucking veg.
Then you can shoot a few angles
of me in bed
and I can come down here
and phone in voice-over, Vance.
Brain death.
Think of the metaphoric
possibilities in that!
-I'Őd have to check with Edna.
-You do that.
May-Alice.
This is a chance that'Ős not
going to come around again.
You'Őd better think about it.
I'Őm at the Ramada
in Lafayette.
Call me.
[door opens]
Chantelle, right?
Uh-huh.
She seems really good,
don'Őt you think?
I guess.
I mean, she hasn'Őt gained
a lot of weight or anything.
Think I have a shot with her?
A shot?
Talking her into coming back
to the show.
I think she'Ős ready.
Ask her.
You know, I might need an ally
on this, Chantelle.
She'Őd have to come up
right away.
It'Ős her life.
Can'Őt have her going to seed
down here, can we?
[Chantelle] Guess he'Ős not
staying for dinner.
[May-Alice]
Help me onboard, okay?
I want to go out.
[turns motor off]
We have to talk.
Yeah.
Vance'Ős asked me
to come back to daytime.
-You could do it.
-Yeah.
I could.
So, what did
your father say?
He thinks you'Őre a good
influence on me.
[laughs, snorts]
-Shows how much he knows.
-I can'Őt believe
I still have to do whatever
he says, like I'Őm 13 years old.
I played the faithful daughter
in "Lear" once.
What'Ős her name?
Cordelia.
There'Ős not much you can do
but play it straight
till it'Ős over.
Haven'Őt spent a July down here
since I lit out.
It gets pretty steamy.
I'Őll bet it does.
You think he'Őd let Denita
stay with you this summer?
I have to have a job.
You'Őve got a job.
In New York City?
He wouldn'Őt go for that.
What'Ős New York City
got to do with it?
It'Ős where your show is.
Back to daytime? P'Őshaw.
Darling, it'Ős either Friday
nights at 10:00 or nothing.
You turned him down?
[sighs]
If I'Őm going to be here,
I need you working for me.
Bullshit.
If I'Őm lying, I'Őm dying.
Then we'Őre stuck
with each other.
Well, for the time being.
-Chantelle?
-Yeah?
You are going to have to learn
how to cook.
♪ There'’s a path
In the high country ♪
♪ That'’ll lead you
Down by the sea ♪
♪ By the evening
By the morning stars ♪
♪ There she waits
Watching over the garden ♪
♪ One took the road
That went to the forest ♪
That went to the shore ♪
♪ One took the road
Out over the border ♪
♪ One stayed home
In the garden ♪
♪ I put my shoulder
To the field ♪
♪ Singing mysteries
In the baseball night ♪
♪ Some people say
Time can heal ♪
♪ All my children
Do the best they can ♪
♪ Whisky river down the point
Go far ♪
♪ All my children
Do the best they can ♪
♪ All my children ♪
♪ Do the best they can ♪
♪ All my children
Do the best they can ♪
♪ One man gambles
And one man saves ♪
♪ One man'’s shadow
Is another man'’s shade ♪
♪ Hey, lady
Can'’t you see? ♪
♪ There'’s a man
And he wants to be ♪
♪ One took the road
That went to the forest ♪
That went to the shore ♪
♪ One took the road
Out over the border ♪
♪ One stayed home
In the garden ♪