Up off the ground.
That's right, pass it high.
Pass it high.
Sal. Take over, will you?
- Hey, I was just looking for you up there.
- I came out by the front.
- Well, you're pretty daring.
- It's perfectly legal.
I just looked it up. A man's allowed
to kiss any girl he's engaged to.
Hey, you're not gonna wear
those pants?
Not pants. They're slacks.
Watch your language.
Look. We got
a pretty delicate deal here.
This game isn't so much pleasure,
more business.
And I don't want anything
to go flooey.
They're pretty conservative people,
these Bemingers, and...
- It's too late now. Come on, let's go.
- No, no, wait. Wait.
Go.
Oh, mister, the things
I've done for this school.
This time it's worth it, honey.
Beminger's good and ripe.
For what?
Biggest donation
I've gotten all year.
- Hooray for our side.
- Your side especially.
He's really serious
about building us that new gym.
How fascinating.
Now, all we've got to do
is the right thing and say it.
- At your service.
- Well, number one, it's he and you...
...against Mrs. Beminger and me.
- Yes, sir.
I could make it look pretty good
and lose, but Mrs. Beminger's a whiz.
- Do or die, that's me.
- Just see that you win.
- Yes, sir. Do my best.
- Let's not blow this.
Yeah, yeah, do my best.
Just watch me.
I'll tell you what to do...
...and then let's hope
you can do it.
- Thanks.
- What?
Nothing.
Well, give us a kiss, honey.
I'm nervous as a cat.
- Good afternoon. Good afternoon.
- Hi.
- How are you, Mrs. Beminger?
- Quite well, thank you.
- Hi.
- Come on, Collier, let's go.
- Eighteen holes is a lot of holes.
- All set.
Say, that's quite a swing
you've got there, Mrs. B.
What do you say, Ma?
I say:
- After you, dear. Okay, Mr. B?
- Yeah.
- Go ahead.
- Got a tee, Coll?
Yeah.
Now, don't let me down, now.
Let's see the good one.
Oh, too bad.
You've got to tense
the gluteal muscles, dear.
If you don't tense
the gluteal muscles...
...why, your whole alignment is off.
- You want me to get you a soapbox?
- Play your cards.
- What?
Tee off.
Thank you, lady.
Thank you very much.
I wouldn't have known what to do
if you hadn't told me.
Thank you.
Oh, tense the gluteal muscles,
did you say?
Yes. That's right.
Tense.
Well, I see what you mean.
Makes all the difference.
- It does.
- All.
Gotta tense. Tense.
Well, for heaven's sake,
I know, don't I?
Beauty.
Take your time, partner.
It's all up to you now, don't forget.
Quiet, do you mind?
My dear, if you would
lean your weight...
...on your right foot, the way I do...
Take into consideration
an endowment...
...that has some permanent value.
What is the concrete thing
that you can point to...
...in the years to come with...?
So all I can say is to...
...consider that every time
you look up at that building...
...you're in a position
to point with pride and...
- that you'll find it is
to develop your reflexes.
Yes, you've got to learn to relax.
To give in.
We can settle this some other time.
- Forty, 60. Come here, boy.
- Yes, sir.
- Split that up.
- How about a nice, tall, cool one?
I'll take mine in the locker room.
See you in 20 minutes
in the lounge.
The one thing he can't stand,
Mr. B, is to lose.
With him, it's not the principle
of the thing, it's the money.
You know, dear, where you go bad
is your coordination.
Now, that is your story, coordination.
This and this and this should
all be parts of the same thing.
If you could possibly lift the needle...
...from that long-playing phonograph
you keep in your face.
Why, the very...
Watch this. Will you excuse me?
You know what you can do
with your gluteal muscle?
Give it away for Christmas.
Say, wait, wait here.
Wait a moment.
Sit down, Mrs. Pemberton,
sit down.
- What will you have to drink?
- Plenty.
- Lemonade?
- Why not?
- Right.
- Strong. Plenty of lemon.
- What do I care?
- All right. Plenty of lemon.
And another thing.
Don't call me Mrs. Pemberton.
- No?
- Pat, that's me.
Okay. I'll call you Pat.
- I want everybody to from now on.
- Why?
Friendless. That's how I feel.
I feel the whole world's against me,
and vice versa.
Did you ever feel that way, Charlie?
Every time I miss a shot.
There you are.
You've been golfing here
for quite a while.
- Quite.
- Then how come I never saw it?
Saw what?
- You're great.
- I must be.
- A natural.
- Fairly seldom.
- What's your handicap?
- My fella.
I mean on the board.
- Six.
- You ought to be two.
- I wish I were a two.
- You know what I'd like to do with you?
Enter you in the Women's National.
- Oh, no.
- Listen, if I don't know a champ...
...when I see one, what good am I?
- Oh, I haven't the time.
- We'll make it.
We'll coach hard the next 15 days.
We'll get out there, you qualify,
you play and you win.
No. I can't play golf.
I can't do anything...
- But what about out there? I saw...
- That was because I got mad. Mad.
- Well, we'll keep you mad.
- No, you see...
...I only play with Collier Weld.
And I can't do anything
when he's watching me.
- Listen, a chance like this...
- Give me Mrs. Beminger's money.
Do you mind, Charlie?
- I thought you wanted to help me.
- I tried to.
To what?
Jam me up with the biggest donor...
- I didn't mean to.
- Pat, I'm trying understand.
How could you,
when I don't myself.
- You don't what?
- Anything. Understand.
Why it is I fall to pieces
whenever you give me that look.
- What look?
- This look.
- That's me?
- Sure.
Makes me feel you don't believe in me
and never will.
- You're just overwrought.
- And you're just overpowering.
- Now, let's not squabble, huh?
- Okay!
I'll see if I can square things
with the Bemingers.
Why try?
Face it, Pat. He's a power.
He's out there screaming
about firing you.
- He couldn't.
- Why not?
- Because I've quit.
- When?
- Right now.
- Oh, no.
- Well, this is no place to talk now.
- Okay, later.
Don't get frazzled, dear.
Don't get frazzled.
Everybody frazzles everybody...
...then they turn around
and tell them, "Don't be."
What?
That true, Charlie?
What's true?
What you think I could do?
Scout's honor.
- All right, then.
- Great.
I'll show her.
- Show who?
- Show myself, that's who.
That's right. Because you know how
to not get yourself frazzled?
Get unfrazzled.
Nearly all of the 60 girls
who have entered...
...have turned in their scorecards.
Let me repeat, ladies and gentlemen,
only the 16 best will be eligible...
...to compete for match play,
which begins tomorrow.
Your attention, ladies and gentlemen,
we have another score.
Mrs. Patricia Pemberton
has just qualified with a sparkling 77.
That, ladies and gentlemen,
leaves one contender still to be...
Yes, here she comes now,
the mighty Babe.
We'll have her score for you
in just a second. Here it is now.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the top score of the day.
Mrs. Babe Didrikson Zaharias
has just qualified...
...with a sensational 73.
Now, fellas, here's the rundown.
From left to right,
Beverly Hanson, Babe Zaharias...
...Helen Dettweiler,
Betty Hicks, Mary Lorgan...
...Harriet Salter
and Mrs. Patricia Pemberton.
- Don't be scared, lady.
- What is this, anyway?
Sit down. Come over here
and sit down. Take it easy.
I never like to see an athlete
wear hisself out. Or herself.
- Lf this is a holdup or a robbery...
- We didn't come to be insulted.
- Take it easy.
- Tell her.
- Identify ourselves.
- Sit down.
You've been on your feet
the whole day.
Why don't you sit down
and take it easy.
Mrs. Pemberton, I'd like to
introduce myself. Mike Conovan.
And my associate, Barney Grau.
- Pleasure.
- Take a chair, Barney.
Thank you.
I have been watching you
like eagle eye the last couple of days.
And I'm here to tell you, you are
one beautiful thing to watch. In action.
I've been in this sports racket
as long as I can remember...
...and I'm here to say,
you are what I call, no doubt, fast.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
Let me ask you
a plain statement of fact.
You figure to win this?
- So does everybody.
- Never mind everybody.
Let's concentrate on you
for an instance.
- Yes or no?
- Yes.
Tell me, off the record,
what's your pitch?
- Well, I don't quite understand what...
- What is it with you?
Is it business, pleasure?
You wanna get a picture in the paper?
- I'm coming to that. I think...
- I really don't know what...
Figure it out, honey.
You're a cinch to win this, you know.
You can't miss copping
this thing in a walk.
- Without someone dismantles you.
- Oh, I don't know.
You're not supposed to know.
You're supposed to play.
I'm supposed to know, and I do.
Tell me...
How smart are you, anyway?
Very, in some things.
How's about money?
What kind of a thing is that?
- Not very.
- Oh, that's too bad. That's too bad.
Because I got a way for you
to stash away a roll, surprise you.
I'd like that.
You would?
How would you like
to come in second?
- I wouldn't.
- A square, like I figured.
That's too bad. That's too bad.
You come in second,
you could do very good in money.
Come in first, you get a cup.
It's too big to drink out of.
- I think you'd better get out.
- Mention a number. Think it over.
Here, this is me.
In New York, strictly legitimate
and well known.
I own and operate Davie Hucko.
- Davie Hucko, mean anything?
- No.
- Heavyweight champion of the world...
...in a couple of years.
Now to get back to you.
The only thing you gotta do
is to lose...
...and our only problem is gonna be
to find bushel baskets...
...to carry the stuff away.
- Yes?
- Room service.
Just a minute.
Whether you do or whether
you don't, I gotta tell you this:
You're a beautiful thing to watch.
In action.
Your opinion. How many do you think
you'd find honest out of 100?
Two on an average.
- I'd say three.
- All right, three.
Too bad she couldn't be one of the 97
instead of one of the three.
What a beautiful buck
we could've made with her.
- Maybe she'll change her mind.
- Not a chance.
- How you sure?
- See her face?
- Yeah.
- A real honest face.
- The only disgusting thing about her.
We're having magnificent weather
for the opening day...
...of the Women 's National
Match Play Championship.
And the last twosome, Miss Betty Hicks
and Mrs. Patricia Pemberton...
...will tee off in just a moment.
We'd like to remind you
that today is only the first day...
...of four days of tournament play.
And tomorrow's quarterfinal round
will begin promptly at 10:00.
On the tee now, Betty Hicks.
On the tee now, Patricia Pemberton.
Another bull's-eye.
Some straight shooter, this kid.
Yeah, that's our trouble.
This is the third twosome.
Pemberton 's still four up over Hicks.
- She's picking it up.
- Don't waste the shot, Pat!
Give me the wedge, will you?
I guess they all want
to see me take a shower.
The pressure gets greater and greater.
Today, with only four contestants left...
...we find we have three favorites
and one rank outsider still battling it out.
Beautiful shot, Bev. Beautiful.
Gee, Pat, that's a rough shot.
Today is payoff day.
Payoff day for one of these two girls
who have battled to the ranks...
...of America's top women golfers to
meet for the National Match Play Crown.
We won't hazard a guess as to which
of the girls will be the eventual winner.
Into the 16th,
Pemberton's still one up on Zaharias.
- I think I'll try a 3 here. Well...
- A little long for this hole.
Pemberton overshot the 17th.
Zaharias well-placed on the green.
Give me that wedge.
Zaharias won the 17th.
All even. Going to 18th.
You're out of it.
- Mike. Mike.
- I ain't in.
You think she could've
not understood you?
- Or misunderstood you?
- I'm trying to catch her eyes.
I'll settle for one eye.
If our signals got mixed,
I'm gonna cut off my arm.
You may have to,
if we're gonna eat tomorrow.
What happened? What happened?
Nothing good.
The Babe is on the green.
Clear the fairway, please.
The Pemberton ball.
The Zaharias ball.
This match is all square
and this is the final hole.
- Hello. Oh, hello.
- Was that on purpose or what?
- Or what.
- I'm glad to hear that, at least.
You see what happened anyway?
If you'd have been willing
to happen it on purpose...
...you could've been walking out
with a bushel basket.
- Like I said, it just goes to show.
- It certainly does.
Well, I still think you
got possibilities.
- Thanks.
- You got my business card?
- Yeah. Oh, yeah.
- Yeah. Get in touch with me.
There's a nice dollar laying around
waiting for you and I to pick it up.
- I'm afraid I'm not...
- I mean legitimate, you know.
Lady athlete, properly handled.
Always a market.
I don't think you've ever been
properly handled.
That's right. Not even by myself.
Very few brains.
- Yeah. There's one thing I gotta say.
- What?
- Nicely packed, that kid.
- She is at that.
Not much meat on her,
but what's there is choice.
Well, here we are. These two.
Here you go, porter.
- Well, off we go.
- Off we go.
- Feel any better?
- Well, no.
This too will pass away.
- Hey, who said that?
- I don't know.
How about looking at the bright side
of this, for instance?
Now, take this.
As long as your job's out of the way...
...we move our date up.
Tie the old knot.
I think you've worked long enough,
done enough, don't you?
- Too much.
- What are you trying to prove?
- Who you trying to lick?
- Myself.
You're just the kid who can do it.
Collier, do you sort of...?
I don't think you mean to...
...but do you think of me
as just a little woman?
That's right.
And myself as a little man.
Right now, l...
I feel sort of like a flop
that you're rescuing.
I'm flummoxed, that's what I am.
Maybe we ought to wait until
I don't feel so carved up, so nobody.
Why don't you just let me take charge.
- I have to be in charge of myself.
- But what's the good of this?
- I mean, after all, we...
- Board!
Have to have time
to think it over, is all.
Well, just see that you don't
think it under.
It's a nice long ride.
Just take your time.
That's right.
- And I'm not going to take it.
- Hey!
- I can't, that's all.
- Can't what?
Go back. Not this way.
What's there to go back to?
Don't you think you're just being...?
I've got to prove to you, to myself...
Lend me some money, will you?
- Prove to both of us,
in fact, everybody...
...that I'm not just a big...
- Say, Pat.
Pat, wait a second, will you?
I'm coming along too.
- No, please don't.
- You can't get off now, lady.
Watch me.
Ruby, let me get
a word in edgeways, will you?
Ruby, win, lose or draw...
...when did Hucko
ever not give you action?
Now, you know yourself
as well as I know myself...
...that that's what they pay for,
is action.
Yeah, Rub.
Even when he gets flattened,
he does it noisy, don't he?
Right. Let me know, huh, Ruby?
Right, boy, bye.
- What did you weigh today?
- Ninety-eight. Up 2.
- Why up 2? Did you eat extra?
- No, no, honest.
Let him talk himself, will you?
- What's the matter with you?
- Where's the control?
- I thought it could be he's still growing.
You'll be growing in Central Park,
the two of youse...
...if you don't watch out.
- Have another beer?
- No thanks, no more.
- You see that?
- Davie, what are you doing to me?
- Nervous, thirsty.
- Water.
Did you ever hear of water?
Well, why don't you drink water?
- Ashamed.
- You're what?
Nervous, thirsty.
I go in the place.
I'm ashamed to ask for free water.
Took one beer.
Yeah.
- Did you like it?
- Yeah.
- What?
- No.
Well, Hucko, I guess it's time to ask you
the three questions, ain't it?
Are you ready?
- Who made you, Hucko?
- You.
- Who owns the biggest piece of you?
What will happen if I drop you?
- I go right down the drain, Mike.
- And?
- And stay there.
- Who made you?
- You, Mike.
- Who owns you?
- You.
- Lf I drop you?
- Go right down the drain, Mike.
- And?
- And stay there.
- Take him back to the gym.
- We just come from.
- Go on back from.
And don't let him out
until he's back to 96 even.
He's liable to go on Friday. We can't
have him overweight. Get going.
I'll shake it when
it don't weigh so much.
We ought to enter him
in the sixth race next Saturday...
...if Little Nell's leg don't unstiffen.
What are you, a comedian?
An agent down the hall handles them.
- What about that leg?
- Loosening by the minute.
- What about her starts?
- Too slow.
- I think she feels depressed.
- She feels depressed, huh?
She's gonna feel
a good boring of a needle...
...if she don't get going,
I'll tell you that.
I'm getting...
Oh, no.
Come in. Well, well, who'd...?
Swing her around
and phone me the time. Goodbye.
- Sit down.
- Well, hello. Who'd have believed this?
- Well, I'm upside down with surprise.
- Why?
What can I do for you?
- Well, I came to ask you.
- Me? What?
- What you can do for me.
- What'd you have in mind?
Well, you said something
about a bushel basket.
Oh, yes, sure, I remember.
Well...
Well, now, let's start off
with a few statistics or two.
How much would you say
the people in the U.S. A...
...spend on sports a year,
total amount?
No idea.
- Surprise you if I said 150 million?
- Yes.
Well, it's 300 million.
And some of it belongs to us by rights.
- How do you like that?
- My.
You see, it's all built up
around personalities, see...
...which I figure you may be one of.
I can't be sure of that, but the way
things look to me, I think so.
- All right.
- Now, of course, what you need is:
A, a manager.
B, a promoter.
- And that's me, A and B.
- All right.
The first thing, you would
have to turn pro. Is that okay?
- Okay. Okay. My...?
- All right with your husband?
Mrs. Pat Pemberton,
ain't that how they introduced you?
- I'm a widow.
- What kind? Merry?
Settle down, will you?
All right, so now you're a pro.
Of course, we gotta go out
and find the competitions.
Trouble is, this time of the year,
they're far in between.
Aren't there other things?
I mean, not golf.
- What do you mean, other things?
- Other sports?
- You do other sports?
- I've only played golf for a year or so.
- That's all?
- Yes, my beau asked me to take it up.
What is this beau deal?
What's that?
If we're gonna be partners, I'd kind of
like to know what the layout is.
- Where is your beau?
- California.
- Live there? Work there?
- Pacific Tech.
Oh, this is all right with him?
This whole switch.
- No. That is, yes, yes.
- Wait a minute, don't go so fast.
You see, if we're partners,
we'd be on kind of a schedule.
I don't know how often
or how many times...
...we could get
to be around California.
That would be all right,
for the moment.
Yeah.
I see.
Now, what other sports?
Well, tennis.
That's number one.
I'm really good at that.
- You're better than with the sticks?
- Oh, yes. Much.
And then, of course,
the usual shooting.
- Shoot?
- Well, you know.
Skeet, range and some archery.
- Say, you're...
- Ice hockey, basketball...
...and a little baseball.
- Where did you play baseball?
Pacific Tech.
I was there several years.
What's the matter?
You couldn't pass?
No. I was faculty.
That's like a teacher.
Well, ain't it?
You're not, by some chance, a boxer?
Just 16-ounce gloves, I'm afraid.
- Eights have a tendency to...
- That's all, honey. That's all.
Say no more.
Of course, there's always a chance that
you could be an escaped fruitcake.
But if there is something, as a matter
of fact, anything in what you say...
...I am going to promote you
into the king of the world.
Queen, I mean. Let's go.
Would you like to see me
serve a few, Mr. Conovan?
Oh, no, no. Just hit a couple.
- Got to be notary public, don't it?
- Take care of that, don't worry.
We ought to have a glass for luck.
What do you mean, a glass for luck?
What am I, some kind
of an acey-deucey gambler?
Us two bumping into each other,
that's all the luck any man deserves.
From now on, it's hard work
and promotion and so forth.
- And promotion.
- Okay, I'll get these back to you.
- And yours too, miss.
- Thank you.
- So let's go.
- I'd like a martini, please. Very, very dry.
- Very, very nothing. Cancel that.
- What?
- Beer, beer.
- Corned beef, Swiss on rye.
- Corned beef.
- I'll have beef stew.
- Same.
- And for the lady?
- Oh, a small steak, rare.
- Medium.
- Rare, rare, rare...
...and a baked potato
and some spinach.
- Coffee?
- Yeah, yeah, coffee.
- Yes, please, large.
- No, no, milk.
- Please, will you, I'm a busy man.
- Two coffees and one milk.
Everybody keeps having to change
one another's minds.
Took a whole half an hour for one...
Could be here for...
- What's the matter?
- Who's talking to you?
- Who, then?
- Myself. Mind if I talk to myself?
I'd like a martini, please.
Look, girlie, do me a favor,
don't be hard to handle, will you?
It's gonna be hard enough
if you're easy.
- I don't see what right...
- Read your contract.
- What? Just silly.
- Training clause.
Well, that's not for you
to decide, you know.
- I have to watch your shape.
- There's nothing wrong with my...
- What shape are you talking about?
I'm in perfect condition,
if that's what you mean.
Good. Let's keep you that way.
- We got a long way to go.
- I must say.
Oh, now, now.
Don't race your motor.
- What is this?
- What?
What, you trying to needle me?
- I'm sorry, I don't...
- There's a sign, "No smoking."
- Where?
- I just put it up inside your head.
- See, the point of...
- What?
What's to prevent me smoking
when you're not around?
When am I not around?
Well, you don't expect
to be watching me every minute...
...out of every 24 hours...
...out of every day, do you?
- Lf I have to, sure.
- Not sure I'll like that.
Not asking you to like it.
But you'll see, pretty soon,
I'll trust you, because you'll trust me.
What's good for you is good for me.
And you for me. We're the same.
We're equal.
We're partners, see? 5-0-5-0.
You gotta realize
your body's important.
And it's important to me too.
I ain't letting you throw
no martinis down there, or no smoke.
No more than I let them down
Little Nell.
- Who's that?
- Oh, that's my horse.
She may win Saturday.
Hold the thought.
And another thing, no late hours.
And of course men are out.
In any manner, shape or form.
You're in training.
Go on, now. Eat your food.
Nice and slow.
Kind of, you know, relaxed inside.
Don't forget to throw me over
your shoulder...
...and burp me after lunch.
- I will if you need it.
I'm so glad...
...you plan to look after me
as well as you do your horse.
You wanna joke? Joke.
But I'll tell you something.
Someday you'll realize something,
and that is this:
We all gotta work together, see?
We all gotta cooperate.
Everybody's sitting around the place.
Everybody's sitting around the world.
And everybody's brain
has got something cooking inside, see?
Well, nobody's got
a better dream than me.
- Believe me, I stand them off.
- What is it?
I can see myself with greats.
I can wind up with the top man,
the top horse and the top woman.
Advantage,
Mrs. Pemberton and Mr. Parker.
Game to Mrs. Pemberton
and Mr. Parker.
They lead five games to three
in the first set.
- That's enough. You'd better quit.
- Not yet.
Don't wanna get all tired out.
You got a long day.
- Long and hard.
- Why hard?
Oh, I don't know.
This place and
all the different people turning up.
- You know, ones I know.
- Well, why? I don't dig that.
I should think you'd be great.
Your hometown. Did that flower...?
Maybe I would, if it weren't for...
Come on, now.
You'd better quit. You're puffing again.
Barney say that more than 100
of my Pacific Tech girls are out there?
No, no. They got a friend for me?
- Announcing.
- That's it. That's it.
Now, will you please remember,
start slow.
Don't show them
all your stuff at once.
Remember, you're the best.
Even if you don't think so, I do.
- Just play your regular game, you know?
- Yeah.
It's beautiful. Just like you.
You know what I'm going to do?
For luck?
- No.
- Give you a great big kiss.
If you don't start slow, by the 15th or
16th game...
...you're gonna start to press.
We gotta remember,
the money dates are coming up.
The big money dates.
Ladies and gentlemen...
...the next match will be between
Pat Pemberton of Oakland...
...and Gussie Moran
of Santa Monica, California.
- Where's he sitting?
- Who's sitting?
- Collier.
- Over here. X4.
- Introducing Gorgeous Gussie.
- Are you sure?
Am I sure?
- Paid for it myself. He's on the cuffola.
- Thanks.
I'd have paid better
if he'd stayed home.
And her opponent,
California's own Pat Pemberton.
Drop it.
- Rough it is. I'll start over there.
- I'll serve.
Wait, shake hands.
- That's it. Thanks a lot.
- Where's the smile, Pat?
- That's fine. That's it, girls.
- Thank you.
This is the feature event
of the afternoon...
...climaxing a cross-country tour.
As of today, Mrs. Pemberton
and Miss Moran...
...are tied with 22 matches apiece.
This match will be
the best two out of three sets.
Linesmen ready.
Players ready.
Mrs. Pemberton will serve first.
Play.
Fifteen, Mrs. Pemberton.
Thirty-love.
Forty-love.
Game to Mrs. Pemberton.
She leads one game to love
in the first set.
Mrs. Pemberton won the first set,
six games to three.
She now leads three games to two
in the second set.
Fifteen, Mrs. Pemberton.
Double fault. Fifteen-all.
Fifteen-30.
- Double fault, 15-40.
- She plays pretty good at times.
She just gets that way
every once in a while.
Game, Miss Moran.
Where's my racket?
- There she is.
- There she is, come on.
That's a girl.
All right.
I just couldn't make anything behave.
Oh, that happens.
You know, a little slump. A dip.
- A couple of weeks' rest.
- No, I'm okay.
We're going over to Elkwood Acres
over in New Jersey.
- Wonderful place.
- No, I'm all right.
You mean more to me than all them
bucks. I'm gonna take care of you good.
Who's that? Tell them to go away.
- Oh, you poor darling.
- Oh, hello, Coll.
I'm all right.
Wasn't that a mess, though?
- Oh, this is Mr. Conovan. Mr. Weld.
- Hello.
How do you do?
I'm taking you home, Pat.
- Now, get your things together.
- No. No, I'm all right here.
If you'll excuse us, please?
If it's about going somewhere...
...I'd like to stick around.
I'd like to kind of be on it.
- I'm sorry. We can't oblige.
- Well, I have a contract, you know.
- I'll send you a copy of it. It says plain.
- Look, friend.
You've been responsible
for wrecking this girl's health.
- I'm not gonna let her stay around.
- Let's not raise your voice, now.
You don't intimidate me.
I've never even heard of you.
No, but I've heard of you.
Joe Jinx, that's you.
Except when you're around, we got
a very valuable piece of property here.
And, you know, I ain't
the only one concerned, you know.
I own the biggest piece
of this kid, 51 percent.
But there are other guys, you know,
that are in too, that own small pieces.
And with her potential, I don't think
they'd like to see it all pulled...
...right out from under them.
Now, I am in no position
to mention their names by name...
...but I can tell you this:
They are the kind of types
that have been known...
...to act very hotheaded
in their day and age.
Look, Conovan, you may think
that you own 51 percent of her...
...but you'll find out
that I own all of her.
No, you don't.
Get away from me, all of you.
Nobody owns anything
of anybody except myself.
Go away, both of you.
Leave me alone.
- Just go away.
- Well, I'll...
- I'll be back.
- Go away. Go away.
Hey, what is this?
What's happened here?
What's happened?
Hey. Hey, hey, slow down.
- How you holding?
- Okay.
- Feet heavy?
- Mine's heavy, Mike.
Well, yours are supposed to be heavy.
You're a heavyweight, ain't you?
Yeah, that's right.
Like I told you.
Don't feel like running, slow down.
You're supposed to feel like it.
That shows you're in condition.
People do like they feel,
they go on sometimes...
...practically forever, some of them.
Guess you'll go on practically forever
if you stay on that bike.
You're the best
because you feel right.
I tell you, last week I was worried.
I'd just like to mention.
And it was my fault, too.
I'm sorry.
- Nothing to do with you.
- Yeah, pushed you too hard, too fast.
I know what it was.
- Can't you tell me?
- Too personal.
Hey.
There should be nothing too personal
between the two of you and me.
It was Collier.
I never can do anything
when he's watching me.
It's always been that way.
- Why?
- Love with him, I guess.
- Oh, like me with lobster.
- What?
Lobster.
The one thing I'm nuts about.
The one thing
that don't agree with me.
- Like you and him.
- Not exactly.
Why?
Well, you see,
this is a question of getting married.
You've never been married
to a lobster.
That's what you think.
- Hey, knock it off!
- Lights.
What do you think is this?
- Hold it, will you?
- It's Mike. Hurry up.
- What is this?
- Just finishing, Mike.
- Do you know what time it is?
- In a minute.
- Ten after 9.
- Oh, gee, now we'll never know.
I want you in bed,
asleep in five minutes, you get it?
No comic books.
Go right to sleep, get that?
Right to sleep, yeah, Mike.
- I'll give it to you for letting him.
- I lost my head.
In your position,
you shouldn't get so engrossed.
Let's go.
I was thinking about all that stuff
on the road.
- Me too.
- Yeah.
Funny how things come out like that.
Yeah, sure is.
- Good night.
- Well, I'll go in with you.
- Yeah? Why?
- Some things I wanna go over with you.
Well, couldn't they wait?
Well, maybe they could,
but I don't know if I could.
- The only thing is my manager.
- Your manager?
He's a little strict, and to tell you
the truth, I'm a bit scared of him.
You are?
I don't drink.
That's on account of him.
Or smoke. That's him too.
- The thing he's strictest about is men.
- Men, huh?
Yeah, you know, dates and late hours
and emotional involvements.
- And...
- He's got a point there.
In fact, he doesn't even want me
to have anything to do with my fella.
- No.
You make him sound
like an awful gumboil.
Oh, I don't know.
He's not so bad, really.
I think I'm just an animal to him,
like Little Nell.
- Is that what you think?
- Yeah.
You sound like a gumboil yourself.
- Good night.
Come here, little girl.
Come here.
If you only were, honey.
Hey, Barn.
Hey, where'd you drop from?
- Hello, Barn.
- Something happen?
- The bout off?
- No, on.
- So far.
- Then what?
I have to talk to him,
Mike, is all I know.
- So why couldn't you use the phone?
- Because people hang up.
- Where is he?
- Inside.
With her.
You go to the head of the class.
- What are they doing?
- He's examining her.
- Why?
- Why do you think?
He wants to see into her condition.
Why don't he examine me?
Ain't I fighting Friday?
Because you he's not worried about.
- He's worried about her.
- He's worried about her condition.
He'd like to see her make out
next week down at that pro match.
Why don't he examine
into my condition?
Ain't I fighting Friday?
Davie, talking to you sometime is like
taking a ride on a merry-go-round.
The last time I was
on a merry-go-round, I threw up.
- That's good.
- I went on that up-and-down one.
- That's what did it.
- Going up and down?
Everybody goes up and down.
Why don't he examine me?
Quit bugging me, will you?
I mentioned about my stitch,
but he don't care.
Because I've been knocked out
the last four times, he's lost faith in me.
- Funny guy.
- I don't think it's his fault.
I think it's her fault.
Boy, I'd like to take a poke at her.
What are you looking for,
five straight knockouts?
Fifty hops.
Better turn out you're okay.
Otherwise we skip
the whole tournament.
- Feel fine.
- I'll let you know soon how you feel.
- I'd feel even better if I didn't do this.
- Quiet.
Forty-eight, 49, 50.
- Still going?
- What?
I say, is it still going?
- All right, lay down.
- Gladly. On my back or what?
On your what.
If I hurt you, just yell out.
- You got a knot in there.
- Can work it out.
Hello. Hello. Hello.
Who?
What?
Long distance?
Okay, wait a minute. Wait a minute.
It's for you.
Yes?
How are you, dear?
Oh, fine.
No, honestly, much better.
In fact, all.
What?
Yeah.
Well, to tell you the truth, Coll...
...I'd just as soon you didn't,
such a long trip and all...
...and you know how I get when you...
Nothing, really.
He wants to come to the tournament.
Tell him not to, will you?
He won't listen to me.
Don't come.
What? No. No, wait.
You do understand, don't you, darling?
Well, all right. No, no.
I'll write to you too.
L... What?
Now we gotta build
that left arm up...
...otherwise your whole swing
goes cockeyed.
Sit up.
When you gonna get wise
to this Collier bash?
Know what happened
when I was rubbing?
You know what happened
to your muscles, huh?
You got as tense as cold spaghetti.
I could feel it.
- I'll get over it.
- Five'll get you 10 you don't.
- Bet.
- Okay, I'll tell you what you do.
Don't use the right at all, see?
Use the left until I tell differently.
Don't use the right for nothing.
Not even to eat with, see?
Everything with the left.
All right, lay down.
Come on, push.
Push.
- Now, to get back to this Collier thing.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, I don't think so.
- In what way?
- In no way.
- I mean, in what way not?
- In no way not.
- How would you know?
Oh, just by keeping my ears
and my eyes open and my so forth.
I've been around. This man-woman thing,
that's gotta be a fifty-fifty thing.
My feeling.
He's 75.
You'll never be 5-0-5-0 with him.
Why do you get yourself hooked
with a guy who's got his horns on you?
That's all.
- Let me ask you, Barney.
- Ask.
- Why don't he examine me? Ain't l...?
- What?
What's this? What are you doing?
You should be weighing in.
- Tomorrow.
- What are you hanging around here for?
- What's the matter with you?
- I don't wanna go in alone no more.
Like lately.
What do you want us to do?
All go with you? That'd be fine.
The three of us could lick the guy,
but you're a big boy now.
- You gotta learn to go in alone.
- I mean in the corner. You used to.
- I'm busy.
- Yeah...
- Busy.
- I gotta get ready to go south.
What do you want me to do?
Tear myself into little pieces?
Sure not.
Trouble is, I haven't asked
the three big questions lately.
- I don't wanna go in alone no more.
- Who made you, Hucko?
What's the matter?
Can't you hear good? Who made you?
- You, Mike.
- Who owns the biggest piece of you?
- What'll happen if I drop you?
- Go right down the drain.
- And?
- And stay there.
- And don't ever forget it.
Go back and tell Gibby if he lets you
loose again, he'll go down the drain too.
- He'll go? I got it.
- Yeah.
Now, what is with Little Nell?
Hey.
I don't like you.
- I wish you did.
- But I don't.
Why not?
You made everything different
from what it used to in the old days.
Last year.
- How old are you, Hucko?
- A hundred ninety-seven and a half.
- What?
- Pounds.
No. How old?
Twenty-four.
Five. Three. Why?
Anyhow, too old
for the three big questions.
Hey, you want me to tell Mike on you?
He didn't make you
and doesn't own you...
...and you wouldn't go down
the drain if he dropped you.
- And stay there.
- You wouldn't.
Ought to belong to yourself.
What do I want with myself?
When you're in that ring, you shouldn't
worry about anyone, Mike or anyone.
Yeah?
What about that guy I'm fighting?
Not even him.
You see, it's never you
against the whole world.
Yeah, that's good.
I couldn't lick the whole world.
- I don't think.
- Just you against yourself.
Yeah?
Well, I could lick myself, all right.
- I think.
- You could?
I think.
That's all you have to do.
Lick yourself.
Make yourself and own yourself.
Never mind Mike or anyone.
Hey, don't he never ask you
the three big questions?
I wouldn't let him.
See, I'm trying to lick myself too.
Hey, the only thing...
Why don't he examine me?
So then:
And then the bell:
End of the sixth.
So then I breathe,
in and out, in and out.
Oh, button it up, will you, Hucko?
We've been through this 40 times.
- It's the seventh coming up. The end.
- Go ahead.
I rush him. He's on his bike.
He starts coming in.
That's when it happened, the thing.
The big thing.
He's coming and I look.
And who you think it is?
It's me. It's me coming at me.
So I get mad.
I'm hollering down his ear,
"Okay, Hucko."
"Get this, Hucko."
Kidney punch.
"You're through, Hucko."
Now I go in. Before I throw it, even,
I knew already it was the one.
And I seen him drop.
And then after, when Gibby jumps in
and grabs me and gives me a kiss...
...I says to him,
"You see me, how I flattened myself?"
So he starts in putting cold towels
on my head.
Okay. Take a walk.
Okay, Mike.
- Hey, can I lift her up?
- No.
Just once?
- All right, then blow.
- Yeah.
Thanks, Mike.
Could be he had his brains
knocked loose.
Oh, he's fine.
What's all this
fighting-yourself malarkey?
How does a guy like that
pick up stuff like that?
I wonder.
Hey...
- Me?
- What's doing here?
You been talking at him?
- Do you mind?
- No. No.
I was gonna suggest maybe
you have a talk with Little Nell.
- Mike?
- Now, we gotta go over schedules...
- Yes, Mike.
- Yeah.
This thing about getting the same room
as the last time I was down here.
Is that just a coincidence,
or did you arrange it?
Just a coincidence.
Tell me the truth.
I arranged it.
- I thought so.
- Why?
- Because I'm getting to know you.
- About time.
And it turns out you're
just a big sentimental slob.
Yeah, that's me.
My, my, my.
My, my, my, what?
Oh, excuse me. I forgot to knock.
Come in.
- Guess who's here.
- Them.
- How'd you know?
- Tell them to swing it in.
- The boys.
- What boys?
- The partners.
- I thought they were anonymous.
Well, maybe they decided
to be non-anonymous.
After all, these gentlemen
are no hoodlums.
They're businessmen.
Plain, ordinary businessmen.
- Investors.
- All the same.
You can't have it perfect.
Okay.
- Hello, Spec.
- Hello, Mike.
- Glad to see you. Hank, how are you?
- Could be worse.
- Thought we'd like to see you, man.
- Well, you know me.
Never too busy to say hello.
- There she is.
- How do you do, gentlemen?
- How do you do?
- Pleased to meet you.
Likewise.
Wouldn't you like to sit down?
Yeah, sit down. Sit down.
You can all find chairs.
Why don't you sit over there.
Oh, thanks, Barney.
Thank you, boy.
Let's everybody have a drink,
on me
I never allow no alcoholic beverages
around the lady here.
Who said alcoholic?
I mean, you know, like beer
or something like that.
- Even beer.
- Milk?
- Milk's okay.
- How's about everybody a glass of milk?
All right, some milk. Fill them up.
There seems to be quite a lot of dough...
You know, money.
- Around that says you can make it.
- You know, win it.
- Well, money talks.
Here, here.
Have one yourself, Barney.
Golf is what I call a nice game.
Very nice.
I mean, it's dignified.
And fresh air.
Men and women both.
Now, you take those lady wrestlers.
That's something I can't stomach.
Stand. Lady wrestlers.
That's something that shouldn't
ought to be allowed, but golf...
...that's different.
- Yeah. Well, we don't wrestle.
- Not yet.
Mike, tell Barney to go out,
do you mind?
- Go out.
- Nothing personal, Barney. Business.
Business?
Wait a minute.
The thing is, Mike, we wanna know
how you figure this thing to come out.
No idea.
You mean, not yet.
I mean that after it's over,
I'll let you know how it come out.
Wait a second.
- Maybe she ought to go out too.
- No thank you.
Mike, look, we don't care
what way it comes out.
Only thing, we'd like to know ahead.
You want my opinion?
I think she'll win it.
- For sure she's...?
- No, not sure.
Makes a sick bet.
The win, you can't be sure.
The lose, that's insurance.
No, no. No, don't say anything.
Wait a minute.
Don't say anything.
Oh, boys, it's no-go. No-go.
Now, you remember I told you
when you come in on this kid?
I promised nothing
but a great lady athlete.
No tricks, no deals, no nothing.
You think it's fair to us
to all of a sudden go legitimate?
- How'd you get in such a jam?
- Look at the books, will you?
I never knew there was
so much money to be made honest.
I don't think it's right,
you being unfriendly.
I don't think it's right neither.
In fact, it's wrong.
Excuse me for not finishing my milk.
Only thing is, it gives me the gas.
I'll do whatever you say
about it, Mike.
- Whatever's best for you.
- What's the matter with you?
- Don't talk like that. Listen here.
- I don't care.
I caught something from you.
And it's good. I like it.
But don't you catch nothing from me,
I ain't got nothing good to catch.
If there's trouble,
I want my share of it.
Yeah, it looks like there's going to be
plenty to go around.
No, I mean the way
you said things ought to be.
- How?
- 5-0-5-0.
- Lay down.
- Now?
Yeah. Yeah, I'll let you get a little nap
and then have dinner.
Take a little walk.
Then turn in nice and early.
And don't worry about nothing.
Don't worry about a thing.
You're a great girl.
You're the best.
Thanks.
And I'm gonna tell you
another thing, furthermore.
After you cop this in the morning...
...I'm gonna start lining up
some shots in Europe.
Boy, will they go for you,
all them Europeans.
- I haven't copped it yet.
- Sure you have.
In my head you have.
The way I figure,
you've got the thing done.
- The thing you're gonna do.
- That's nice.
I can feel it in your bones.
Sure pretty dress
you got covering you.
Thank you.
You certainly are carrying
the right silks tonight, kid.
It does more for you than
them pants you're always wearing.
Easier to play in,
is why I wear the pants.
I think sometimes you ought to
change around. Give the public a break.
I'm not sure
that I'd be able to play in...
- What is this?
- Sorry to barge in.
Well, barge out.
Wait a second, Mike.
Something you don't know.
- Sam's out.
- In fact, it was us bought him.
I never seen him so upset since lately.
See, Sam suffers
from the high blood pressure.
He can't stand the gaff.
He can handle any situation
so long it's a situation...
...without aggravation. Otherwise, no.
And the minute he realized
you were not going to play ball...
...it was a situation with aggravation.
Okay. Thanks for the flash.
Now, get out of here, will you?
Can't you see we're talking
important business? Strategy.
That's just what we want
to talk to you about, Mike. Strategy.
We've been considering...
...and we think you're very foolish,
the both of you.
You don't see it our way.
It's a very full hatful
we can grab off here.
- Blow.
- You shouldn't talk like that, Mike.
- Not to us.
- Please...
What's the matter?
What're you trying to do?
Destroy your own property?
What's wrong with you two pinheads?
Look, can't you see
you're getting her all tensed up?
You're absolutely right, Mike.
I think the best would be for us
to step outside and talk over.
That would be good.
Why outside?
- Well, you know, quiet.
- We wouldn't get the lady all upset.
All right, let's go.
- You stay here. I'll be right back.
- You will?
Well, I hope so.
I ain't finished my baked potato.
Come on, what about it? Let's talk.
- You wanna go to your hometowns?
- We'll talk down over here.
- Mike.
- You stay out of this.
- I wanna go with you.
- You think I can't take care of myself?
- No, I don't.
- I can take care of myself...
...you and them.
Now, stay out of this. Go on.
All right, let's go.
Come on, let's get on with it.
We'll get on.
We want to know what you'll do.
I told you already. I ain't gonna
make no deals with you, see?
- Two against one, huh?
- That's right. Two against one.
And that's how it is
in this business too, wise guy.
- Two against one.
- You want your usual percent...?
Hey, my glasses.
What's the big idea?
Hey, that's no fair, I'm telling you.
Hey, where are my glasses?
- What is it, anyway?
- It's no fair.
Did you ever see
a thing like this before?
Ever see a thing like this before?
What is it?
My glasses.
It's no fair, I'm telling you.
Which one of you belongs to this?
- Where'd you get it, Kronski?
- From the lady.
- Where did you get it?
- Out of his hand.
- Where'd you get it?
- In the head.
- I wanna make a complaint.
- We'll get to that.
Now, which one of you
wants to report bodily injury?
- Nothing.
- Me. Look at that.
And see that?
And where do you think I got that?
- Okay.
- Internal injuries.
All right. What happened?
- Anybody.
- This women blew her top, that's all.
- Did you see the whole thing?
- I sure did. L...
- Could I say a word? Just one word.
- You bet.
I don't think anybody wants a big thing
out of this. We all know each other.
These two gentlemen and I,
we're in business together.
- What kind of business?
- Well...
You see, the three of us,
we own her.
- The three of you?
- Yeah, sure.
She's our lady athlete.
Very well-known, captain.
We got her entered in a tournament
here tomorrow.
- I know.
- Yeah, we had this little disagreement.
You know, a kind of
a misunderstanding.
Why don't you just forget
about the whole thing.
Well, what about this thing?
- Want me to forget this thing too?
- No, sir, I...
- Just show me what happened.
- What's the point?
I'd like to see what happened.
Well, we were standing over
by the car, the three of us.
- Just talking.
- And where were you?
I was in the middle,
where I usually am.
- And you?
- I was up on the porch.
You're in the middle,
get in the middle.
You on the porch, stay there.
You three were arguing.
We were arguing.
They came up behind me there.
In self-defense.
This guy with the glasses on started
like he was gonna throw a punch.
- I got kind of excited.
- That was when I ran down.
Yeah, like Count Fleet
she ran down there.
- What happened to your punch?
- I never threw no...
- No, he didn't get the chance to.
- What happened when you got there?
Well, the first thing,
I disengaged this fellow.
How?
Well, like:
- Oh, I'm sorry. Sorry.
- Let go of me. Let go of me.
What am I around here?
I'm gonna kill somebody here.
Am I a sack of potatoes
around here or something?
And what were you doing
all this time?
- Just what I'm doing now.
- Nothing?
- What else was there to do?
- Then what?
Then...
Well, I am very sorry about this.
I should like to apologize
to this man for doing it.
- Doing what?
- For throwing away his eyeglasses.
She sure did.
I couldn't think of
anything else to do.
Then he went down
to hunt for them...
...and I turned, sort of
to lead Mr. Conovan away.
To lead me? I thought
you were gonna carry me
- Go ahead.
- Then the little one came toward Mike.
- No. No, I come toward you.
- Anyway, Mike started toward him.
Yeah, I started,
I came at you, remember?
- But I pushed him out of the way.
- What did you do that for?
Well, I didn't want him to get hurt.
No, she didn't want me to get hurt.
Then I think I took
this little one by the wrist.
Go away from me.
Yeah, she grabbed him by the wrist
and he went halfway down like this.
So she took the jack out of his hand
and looked at it...
...and conked him right on the head,
then he fell rest of the way like this:
And what were you doing
all this time?
Just watching.
I hope you fellas
have been on the ball.
- You could learn something.
- She's okay.
- Where'd you pick that up?
- I've been around physical ed for years.
- Physical Ed? Who's he?
- Education.
Okay, come here, all of you.
Henry Tasling, that you?
- That's right.
- Also known as Harry Creavy?
- That's been a long time since.
- Also as Ray Bryler?
Only once. I was little and they used...
Under these names,
have you been apprehended...
...seven times in this state on charges
of illegal betting, bookmaking, assault?
Something like that, yeah.
Are you aware
that a court order signed...
...by Judge Evan McEnroe
August 12, 1949, prohibits you...
...from carrying on any business
of any nature whatsoever in this state?
- I wasn't doing no business.
- He says you were.
- What business?
- Silvester Cauley, that you?
- Yeah.
- Also known as...
Yeah, yeah, that's right.
Yeah, you got it down there all okay.
- Anything on him?
- Nothing.
All right, I wanna hold these two men
pending a report to Judge McEnroe...
...as to a violation of his order.
That's all. See you in the morning.
- Handle that, Kronski.
- Thanks.
Okay, we're adjourned.
How does it look
for tomorrow, anyway?
- Who knows?
- Well, good luck.
- I've got a few savings riding on you.
- Oh, thank you, goodbye.
Mike.
Mike!
- Mike, listen.
- I've been listening all night.
Then do you want to talk? I'll listen.
Leave me alone, will you?
I can understand your being upset,
but why with me? What have I done?
- Too much, that's what.
- But...
- Mike, don't be like this.
- Like what?
Lmpossible.
Oh, so that's what I am.
Impossible.
- Right now, yes.
- I don't happen to agree with you.
I think I'm possible.
I also think I'm stupid.
- Why?
- For the way I handle you, that's why.
I've built you up into some kind
of a Frankenstein monster.
That's what you are, you're just
a great big Mrs. Frankenstein.
You don't think this will get around?
You don't think everybody will know it?
I won't even be able
to show my face in Lindy's.
I don't like the combination.
I thought I would, but I don't.
I like everything to be 5-0-5-0.
I like a he to be a he
and a she to be a she.
But you said...
- Hold it.
- What?
- Go in the back way.
- Why?
- Quiet down.
- Why? Why?
- Oh, Pat!
- I think somebody's yelling "Pat."
No, cat. They're calling their cat.
- Pat, what's the matter?
- Hello, Collier.
Now, you come back
any time after the match.
- You're a little early now.
- Listen...
- Don't touch her right arm.
- Well, how about you?
- I got the other arm. Now, go away.
- Listen here, old man.
- Old man?
- I've got as much right as you have.
Come back in the morning...
Stop handling me, everybody, please!
You got a tough deal, all right,
there, buster. I feel for you.
Oh, you do?
That chick is sure stuck on you.
I can't quite understand why,
but there it is.
She's so stuck on you
that you jinx her.
You're in this business.
Have you ever heard of anything like it?
Oh, only two or three million times,
that's all.
You see, athletes,
they ain't like us, you know.
They're like what you call freaks.
Nobody can understand
how they do what they do.
They can't understand it themselves.
And different things throw them.
So who knows what,
why, where, when, see?
Yeah.
It's just like...
Now, you take little Joe Palone.
- Who?
- The jockey.
- Oh, yeah.
- Yeah.
For a long time my horse, Little Nell,
couldn't win nothing.
She couldn't win?
Say, she had trouble coming in last.
And I couldn't figure it.
And then I figured it.
She couldn't win
because Joe Palone was riding her.
I got rid. She won great.
It's the same in this case, buster.
You are the wrong jockey
for this chick.
- You don't say.
- Yeah, I do say.
So how about giving us all
a nice big break...
...and making yourself
scarce tomorrow?
- Why?
- Because, don't you understand?
When you're around,
she's no good. She's dead.
What you do after her working hours,
I don't care, go as far as you like.
But when she's on, you stay off.
- Can we deal?
- No.
- Why not?
- Your business doesn't interest me.
Tell me something, will you?
Were you born stubborn,
or did you learn this in college?
See you in the morning, Conovan.
On the first tee.
What?
Don't use your right arm.
- What is it?
- Go on. Be quiet. Go back to sleep.
How long have you been here?
I just came in
to check up, that's all.
The windows. I do it every night.
- You do what every night?
- Check the windows, fix the covers.
Sure.
Sometimes you kick them off.
What's the matter? You can't sleep?
Don't say anything.
Nothing, just shut up.
Why I didn't get on this
sooner than I have.
Always funny when it's happening
to some other guy, but not to me.
What makes you think
I'd stand in your way?
You want him? Go to it.
Looks to me you're perfectly suited.
- Two slick articles.
- Help!
Too nice to you,
that's my mistake.
- Too considerate.
- Mike!
- Be quiet.
Help!
- Help!
- Pipe down, will you?
You want everybody up here
and involve me in some kind...
- No. No. Mike, help.
- Quiet down, will you?
You're hurting me.
Collier, leave me alone.
Leave me alone.
What are you, some wild man?
No, just the wrong jockey.
But I guess you're the right one, all right.
- What's he talking...?
- Oh, come, come, now.
- Let's not give it the innocent.
- You don't think that...!
Tell him, will you? Talk!
What's the use?
No use, that's the use.
Well, congratulations.
But I wouldn't be surprised
if I'm not the lucky guy.
- What do you figure got into him?
- I don't know.
- He frightened me.
- I can imagine.
- Why I called you.
- Well, you done the right thing. Did.
I mean, what would I have did
if you hadn't been around?
- Done.
- I figure you can take care of yourself.
- No, I can't.
- Yeah, I bet you could even lick me...
- No, I couldn't.
- Sure, I think so.
No, I couldn't.
I need someone to look after me.
- Yeah? What about me?
- Why not?
I don't know if I can lick you...
...but I'll tell you one thing I do know.
- What?
- Together we can lick them all.
You bet.
I can't handle this in my head.
It rocks me.
- Why?
- Well, be as it don't figure.
It's like as though Hucko walked in
and handed me an engagement ring.
- I'm not Hucko.
- No, that you ain't.
- So?
- So I mean...
- There's one thing only about us.
- What?
Coming together,
that's what I call a plenty long shot.
- Nothing wrong with a long shot.
- Lf you come out on top.
We will, Mike.
As somehow, you don't seem to...
An upper-cruster like you
and my kind of type...
...that can't even speak
left-handed English yet.
- The whole jismo, it's hard to believe.
- It's not hard for me.
- I think so.
- I know so.
Okay, kid.
You got yourself a deal.
I'm gonna ask you
the three big questions.
- Go ahead.
- Who made you?
You did.
- Who owns the biggest piece of you?
- You do.
- What would happen if I dropped you?
- I'd go right down the drain.
- And?
- Take you right down with me, shorty.