♪ ["STREETS OF PHILADELPHIA"
BRUCE SPRINGSTEEN]
♪ I WAS BRUISED AND BATTERED
I COULDN'T TELL WHAT I FELT ♪
♪ I WAS UNRECOGNIZABLE
TO MYSELF ♪
♪ SAW MY REFLECTION
IN A WINDOW ♪
♪ AND DIDN'T KNOW
MY OWN FACE ♪
♪ OH, BROTHER
ARE YOU GONNA LEAVE ME ♪
♪ WASTIN' AWAY ON THE STREETS
OF PHILADELPHIA ♪
♪ I WALKED THE AVENUE
'TIL MY LEGS FELT LIKE STONE ♪
♪ I HEARD THE VOICES OF FRIENDS
VANISHED AND GONE ♪
♪ AT NIGHT I COULD
HEAR THE BLOOD IN MY VEINS ♪
♪ JUST AS BLACK AND WHISPERING
AS THE RAIN ♪
♪ ON THE STREETS
OF PHILADELPHIA ♪
♪ AIN'T NO ANGEL
GONNA GREET ME ♪
♪ IT'S JUST YOU AND I
MY FRIEND ♪
♪ AND MY CLOTHES
DON'T FIT ME NO MORE ♪
♪ I WALKED A THOUSAND MILES
JUST TO SLIP THIS SKIN ♪
♪ NIGHT HAS FALLEN
I'M LYIN' AWAKE ♪
♪ I CAN FEEL MYSELF
FADIN' AWAY ♪
♪ SO, YOU RECEIVE ME, BROTHER
WITH YOUR FAITHLESS KISS ♪
♪ OR WILL WE LEAVE EACH OTHER
ALONE LIKE THIS ♪
♪ ON THE STREETS
OF PHILADELPHIA ♪
[MAN] THIS "PESTILENT DUST"
THE COUNSELOR REFERS TO APPEARED
ON ONLY THREE OCCASIONS.
EACH TIME IT WAS TESTED,
AND THE RESULTS: LIMESTONE!
IT'S MESSY...
BUT INNOCUOUS.
INNOCUOUS?
DEFINED BY WEBSTER'S
AS HARMLESS.
I KNOW WHAT IT MEANS.
MAY I? THANK YOU.
YOUR HONOR.
IMAGINE HOW THE CHILDREN
IN THIS NEIGHBORHOOD
ARE BEING MADE TO FEEL.
THE CONSTANT POUNDING
OF CONSTRUCTION RINGING
IN THEIR EARS...
AS THIS SKYSCRAPER,
A TRIBUTE TO MANKIND'S GREED,
GROWS DAILY,
CASTING AN OMINOUS SHADOW
OVER THEIR LIVES,
FILLING THEM WITH DREAD
EVEN AS THEY ARE SURROUNDED
BY THIS TOXIC DUST.
YOUR HONOR,
KENDALL CONSTRUCTION...
BUILDS NEIGHBORHOODS,
IT DOESN'T DESTROY THEM.
GRANTING A RESTRAINING ORDER
AGAINST THIS
CONSTRUCTION SITE...
WILL THROW 753 PHILADELPHIANS
OUT OF WORK,
AND LEND VALIDATION
TO THIS CONTEMPTIBLE
AND GROUNDLESS NUISANCE SUIT.
IT'S AN EXAMPLE OF
THE RAPACIOUS LITIGATION...
THAT TODAY IS TEARING AT
THE VERY FABRIC OF OUR SOCIETY.
LET'S NOT GO OFF
THE DEEP END, GENTLEMEN.
YOU'VE MADE AN ARTICULATE
AND COMPELLING PRESENTATION,
MR. MILLER.
BUT I DON'T BELIEVE YOU'VE
PROVEN IRREPARABLE HARM.
NOT YET, YOUR HONOR.
9:42, WHEREAS DECEDENT--
[CONTINUES INDISTINCT]
[INDISTINCT]
[RINGING]
...CONTINUE PROPER USE
OF TRADE NAME WITHOUT--
[RINGING]
WITHOUT THE--
IS THAT YOU?
YEAH, THAT'S ME.
MILLER. YES.
HELLO, IRIS.
CLIENT OF YOURS?
[CHUCKLES]
FUNNY! HOLD ON, IRIS.
EXCUSE ME, SIR?
YO! YO!
[MAN]
MY SONS AND I
WENT TO A RESTAURANT.
WE ORDERED COFFEE.
THE WAITER COMES UP.
HERE'S THE LITERATURE.
"WOULD YOU LIKE SUGAR
OR SWEET 'N' LOW?"
I SAID, "DO I LOOK LIKE
I SHOULD BE ON A DIET?"
ANDY!
HI, DOC.
YOUR BLOOD WORK
CAME BACK THIS MORNING.
I'M GONNA COME BACK
IN A FEW MINUTES
AND TALK TO YOU ABOUT IT.
I'LL BE RIGHT HERE.
GOOD.
HI.
HOW ARE YOU FEELING?
FEELING PRETTY GOOD.
GREAT.
MAKE A FIST FOR ME.
ONCE MORE.
GONNA HAVE TO START LOOKING
FOR VEINS IN YOUR FEET,
SWEETHEART.
PATIENCE, TYRONE.
OKAY.
ONCE MORE.
ANDY, TERRIFIC JOB
ON THE KENDALL SITUATION.
TOP-NOTCH,
MR. BECKETT.
THANKS, KENNETH, ROBERT.
HI, MR. BECKETT.
HI, ROSE, ANTHEA.
JUST THE
PARALEGAL EXTRAORDINAIRE
I WAS HOPING TO SEE.
I KNOW WHAT THAT MEANS.
THE ANSWER IS NO.
I'M TALKING DINNER
AT FELICIA'S.
I'VE GOT A CLASS.
I'VE GOT SOME COMPELLING
BRIEFS THAT NEED PROOFING.
YOU CAN EXPLOIT
SOMEBODY ELSE.
SINCE YOU'VE ASKED--
YOUR EXAM!
THANK YOU.
NINETY-EIGHT.
NINETY-EIGHT?
NINETY-EIGHT,
CONGRATULATIONS!
I HAVE TO PICK UP AMY,
BUT I WANT TO TALK TO YOU
ABOUT THAT HANSEN THING.
GIVE ME A CALL. TELL AMY
I LOVED HER PAINTING.
IT'S ON MY WALL.
HI, ANDREW.
CONFERENCE CALL'S UP.
ROLL CALL JUST STARTED.
THIS IS THE
SETTLEMENT AGREEMENT. THE
RED-LINE COPY'S ON YOUR DESK.
YOU NEED ME IN THERE?
NO!
IT'S 6:30. GO HOME.
[PHONE BEEPING]
HELLO.
[ANDREW]
HEY, MOM!
HI, DARLING.
WHAT A WONDERFUL SURPRISE!
HOW ARE YOU?
GOOD.
WHAT DOES
DR. GILLMAN SAY?
DR. GILLMAN SAYS I AM FINE.
MY BLOOD WORK IS EXCELLENT.
MY T-CELLS ARE STEADY.
HOW 'BOUT YOUR PLATELETS?
WHAT DID SHE SAY?
EVEN MY PLATELETS
LOOK GOOD.
GREAT.
MOM, MORE IMPORTANTLY,
HOW ARE YOU?
MOM?
[SIGHS] I'M FINE.
HOW IS DAD?
DAD IS FINE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOIN'?
[CLOCK CHIMING]
"ACTION FOR THE WRONGFUL
INTERFERENCE WITH PROSPECTIVE
ECONOMIC RELATIONS."
OKAY.
ANDY?
AM I INTERRUPTING?
YO!
IN A WORD, BOB--
CHARLES WANTS
TO SEE YOU UPSTAIRS.
I WAS JUST ABOUT
TO TAKE A BREAK.
YOU'RE SURE I'M NOT
UNDER-DRESSED FOR THIS?
NO.
CHARLES, ANDY HAS EXPRESSED
A KEEN INTEREST...
IN HIGHLINE
VERSUS SANDER SYSTEMS.
ISN'T THAT RIGHT,
ANDY?
THE FATE OF THE PARTICIPANTS
INTERESTS ME. YES, SIR.
IT'S AN
ANTITRUST ACTION.
IT IS...
AND IT ISN'T, CHARLES.
SANDER SYSTEMS COPIES
HIGHLINE SPREADSHEET
PROGRAM.
FOR ME,
THE LEGAL PRINCIPLE INVOLVED...
IS COPYRIGHT INFRINGEMENT.
HMM.
TELL ME THIS, ANDY.
WHICH SIDE OF THIS
CONFLICT WOULD YOU WISH
TO SEE EMERGE VICTORIOUS?
AND DON'T ALLOW MY CLOSE
PERSONAL RELATIONSHIP
WITH BILL WRIGHT,
SANDER SYSTEMS' C.E.O.,
TO INFLUENCE YOUR ANSWER
IN ANY WAY.
[CHUCKLING]
I'D LIKE TO SEE HIGHLINE
WIN THIS ONE.
OH! WHY, BECKETT?
IF SANDER SYSTEMS WINS,
AN ENERGETIC, YOUNG COMPANY
IS DESTROYED.
THE LAWS FOR ANTITRUST
AND COPYRIGHT WERE ENACTED
TO PREVENT EXACTLY...
THE KIND OF BULLSHIT
THAT SANDER SYSTEMS
IS TRYING TO PULL.
YOU KNOW WHO
REPS HIGHLINE?
RODNEY BAILEY.
OH, I OBJECT!
[LAUGHING]
RODNEY BAILEY, WHO
COULDN'T FIND HIS WAY AROUND
COPYRIGHT LAW WITH A MAP.
WELL, APPARENTLY THE FELLAS
AT HIGHLINE AGREE WITH YOU.
WHICH EXPLAINS WHY,
AS OF 9:03 THIS EVENING,
RIGHT AFTER DESSERT,
HIGHLINE, INC.
IS NOW REPRESENTED BY...
WYANT, WHEELER, HELLERMAN,
TETLOW AND BROWN.
OUTSTANDING!
AND MORE SPECIFICALLY...
SENIOR ASSOCIATE
ANDREW BECKETT.
BRAVO!
YES!
[PHONE RINGING]
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU, ROBERT, THANK YOU.
WE'VE GOT TO GET
ON HIGHLINE RIGHT AWAY.
STATUTE OF LIMITATIONS.
I'M RIGHT ON IT.
TEN DAYS BEFORE
WE HAVE TO FILE.
TOKYO ON LINE FOUR,
BOB.
WALTER, THANK YOU.
THANK YOU.
KENNETH, THANK YOU.
CONGRATULATIONS.
AW, THANKS.
I'M OVERWHELMED.
WHAT'S THAT ON
YOUR FOREHEAD, PAL?
WHAT? WHERE?
THAT, ON YOUR FOREHEAD.
OH, I GOT WHACKED IN THE HEAD
WITH A RACQUETBALL.
OOH!
EXCUSE ME.
CHARLES, I--
I SINCERELY APPRECIATE YOUR FAITH...
IN MY ABILITIES.
FAITH, ANDY, IS A BELIEF
IN SOMETHING FOR WHICH
WE HAVE NO EVIDENCE.
IT DOES NOT APPLY
TO THIS SITUATION!
WELL, GO HOME.
OH, NO! GO BACK TO WORK.
YEAH.
THANK YOU, CHARLES.
NO SWEAT, BUDDY.
THE COMMITTEE MEETING
PLANNED FOR NEXT WEEK--
TOMMY,
HOW ARE YA?
[ANDREW]
THE HIGHLINE COMPLAINT
IS ON MY DESK, SHELBY.
IT'S ALL SET TO GO,
SO MAKE SURE
JAMEY IS ON TOP OF IT.
SURE, YOU GOT IT.
ANYTHING ELSE?
NO, THAT'S IT. I'M GONNA
BE WORKING OUT OF THE
HOUSE FOR THE AFTERNOON.
SO, THANKS A LOT.
BYE, BYE.
[WOMAN] YOU'RE GONNA WANT
TO APPLY...
THIS FOUNDATION AS EVENLY AS YOU CAN.
MM-HMM.
YOU DON'T WANT IT TO LOOK LIKE
YOU THREW IT ON WITH A SPOON.
YEAH.
YOU TRY THIS RIGHT THERE.
CHANDRA, YOU DON'T THINK
THIS IS JUST TOO ORANGE
FOR ME?
IT'S TAHITIAN BRONZE.
THAT WORKS BEST
ON THESE LESIONS.
THINK OF IT AS THE "I JUST
GOT BACK FROM ARUBA" LOOK.
EXACTLY! I'VE CALLED
IN SICK FOR FOUR DAYS.
NOW, THEY'RE GONNA THINK
I WAS TAKING A CRUISE.
FAX.
THANK YOU, BRUNO.
[CHANDRA]
WE CAN TRY THIS
LIGHT EGYPT--
AH, OW.
WHAT?
OH, OW!
[BRUNO]
ANDY?
EXCUSE ME.
[GROANING]
JUST LIKE
MY COUSIN FREDO.
[DOOR SLAMS]
HI.
DOES ANYBODY WANT
A BAGEL?
[CRYING]
YOU OKAY,
ANDY?
I TH-- I THINK I NEED
TO GO TO THE HOSPITAL.
[WOMAN]
WATCH OUT!
[SIREN WAILING]
HELLO, HELLO.
OH, IT'S AWFUL.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I'M GETTIN' OUTTA HERE.
I'LL TALK TO YOU LATER.
OKAY.
OH, ONE MORE, ONE MORE.
THANK YOU FOR DRIVING
LIKE A BAT OUT OF HELL.
DR. GILLMAN
IS OUT OF HER OFFICE.
I TOLD HER TO TAKE A DAY OFF
AND SHE TOOK A DAY OFF.
CAN YOU BELIEVE THAT?
THEY TOOK BLOOD?
A SPECIMEN OR SOMETHING?
BLOOD, YES.
A SPECIMEN, I'M EMPTY.
DID YOU FIND SOMEBODY
TO TAKE YOUR CLASS?
DON'T WORRY.
LET ME SEE.
OH, YOU GOT FEVER, BABY.
OH, THERE'S MY GUY!
EXCUSE ME.
DOCTOR?
HELLO, HI.
JUST ONE SECOND.
I CAME THAT CLOSE
TO NOT MAKING IT
INTO THE BATHROOM AGAIN.
I ALMOST LOST IT
IN FRONT OF EVERYBODY.
SO WHAT?
IT'S NOTHING
TO BE ASHAMED OF.
I'M NOT ASHAMED, IT'S JUST--
WHAT ABOUT
MY BLOOD WORK?
WE'RE WAITING.
I WANT TO PREP YOU FOR
A COLONOSCOPY. WE WANT
TO TAKE A LOOK INSIDE.
IT SOUNDS DELIGHTFUL!
WAIT A MINUTE.
WHY YOU NEED TO DO THIS?
WHO ARE YOU?
WHO ARE YOU,
UH, DR.--
THIS IS MY PARTNER.
YEAH.
AH, HE KEEPS RECORDS
OF MY HOSPITAL VISITS.
IT'S NOTHING PERSONAL.
OH, I'M DR. KLENSTEIN.
YOU'RE RIGHT. A COLONOSCOPY
IS NOT A PLEASANT PROCEDURE.
BUT IF THE K.S. IS
CAUSING THE DIARRHEA,
WE'VE GOT TO KNOW RIGHT AWAY.
NO, NO, NO.
IT COULD BE PARASITES,
AN INFECTION--
REACTION TO THE A.Z.T.
THESE ARE POSSIBILITIES,
BUT WE'VE GOT TO GO FORWARD--
LISTEN TO ME.
HE'S NOT GOING THROUGH
SOME PAINFUL PROCEDURE...
UNTIL WE'VE CANCELLED OUT
EVERYTHING ELSE.
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
I'M TRYING TO HELP
YOUR PARTNER.
YOU'RE NOT A MEMBER
OF HIS IMMEDIATE FAMILY.
I'M NOT?
I COULD HAVE YOU REMOVED
FROM THE E.R.
REALLY?
LOOK, HE'S UPSET.
HE'S SORRY.
NO, DON'T APOLOGIZE
FOR ME, OKAY?
OKAY,
HE'S NOT SORRY.
LET'S DO THIS. LET'S FIND OUT
WHAT THE BLOOD WORK TELLS US.
I WILL TRY TO
GIVE YOU A SPECIMEN.
SOME HOSPITAL FOOD MAY HELP.
THEN WE MIGHT HEAR
FROM DR. GILLMAN, AND
WE CAN START FROM THERE.
EVERYBODY HAPPY?
ALL RIGHT?
I'LL GET ON THE LAB
ABOUT THE BLOOD WORK.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
I'M SORRY.
[BEEPING]
OH, THAT'S--
THAT'S THE THIRD TIME
THE OFFICE HAS BEEPED ME.
I BETTER GO.
I GOTTA GIVE THEM A CALL.
KLENSTEIN.
I WANT YOU TO SIT DOWN,
AND I WANT YOU TO RELAX.
I AM RELAXED.
OH, GOOD, GOOD.
IS THERE A PHONE AROUND
SOMEWHERE NEARBY?
DOWN THE HALL.
THANK YOU.
IF YOU OR SOMEONE YOU KNOW
HAS BEEN INJURED THROUGH
THE FAULT OF OTHERS,
YOU MAY BE ENTITLED
TO A TAX SETTLEMENT...
OR MONEY DAMAGES
FOR YOUR PAIN AND SUFFERING.
I'M ATTORNEY JOSEPH MILLER.
[CHUCKLING]
GOOD LORD.
- MR. BECKETT'S OFFICE.
- AH, SHELBY, IT'S ME.
JAMEY'S BEEN BEEPING ME.
I'M SO GLAD
YOU CALLED.
I WANT TO LET YOU KNOW
WE HAVE A MINOR CATASTROPHE
IN THE MAKING.
IT'S ABOUT THAT
HIGHLINE COMPLAINT. JAMEY
IS GOING ABSOLUTELY BALLISTIC!
CALM DOWN!
PUT HIM ON.
ONE SECOND.
THIS IS A DISASTER!
WE CAN'T FIND THE REVISIONS
ON THE HIGHLINE COMPLAINT.
WAIT, WAIT.
SLOW DOWN.
I TOLD 'EM YOU WERE WORKING ON
IT AT HOME. IT WAS SUPPOSED
TO BE HERE THIS MORNING.
NO, NO. I BROUGHT IT INTO
THE OFFICE LAST NIGHT.
I WAS THERE 'TIL 3 A.M.
THERE SHOULD BE A COPY
WITH CORRECTIONS ON MY DESK.
IT'S NOT HERE, ANDY.
SHELBY CAN'T FIND IT, EITHER.
ALL RIGHT. AH... THE
HARD DISK ON MY COMPUTER.
PRINT IT UP AND RUN IT THROUGH
WORD PROCESSING YOURSELF.
OKAY. WHAT DID YOU
FILE IT UNDER?
H-L-1.
I DON'T HAVE TO REMIND YOU
WE ARE UP AGAINST THE STATUTE OF
LIMITATIONS ON THIS COMPLAINT.
IT RUNS OUT IN...
IN 75 MINUTES!
IT'S NOT HERE, ANDY.
NOT THERE?
I'M ON MY WAY.
[SIGHS]
EVERY PROBLEM
HAS A SOLUTION.
PUSH, BABY. PUSH.
AH, IT'S COMING!
YEAH, BABY, IT'S COMING!
IT'S...
IT'S A GIRL.
OH, MY GOD!
TAKE A PICTURE, JOE.
I CAN'T GET
THE FILM IN THERE.
OH, MY GOD!
HELP ME, BABY.
[LAUGHING]
OH, LOOK AT HER.
THAT LITTLE, SWEET LITTLE--
GET HER BEFORE
SHE GETS TOO OLD.
SHE'S PERFECT, LISA.
SHE HAS LONG HAIR.
GO TO FAMOUS 4TH STREET DELI,
GET A POUND OF SCOTCH SALMON.
SHE LIKES THAT.
YEAH, SOME ONION ROLLS, BAGELS.
HERE, GIVE ME A CALL.
CHAMPAGNE,
NICE CHAMPAGNE.
YOU'RE THAT TV GUY.
I DON'T CARE HOW MUCH IT COSTS.
GET SOME DOM PERIGNON.
THANK YOU.
HOW MUCH? OH, $100.
DON'T GET ME DOM PERIGNON.
GET A NICE CALIFORNIAN.
GET IT ALL OVER HERE
BECAUSE SHE'S STARVING.
NO, IRIS, NOT THE BABY!
LISA IS STARVING.
YEAH, LISA.
IRIS, IRIS, IRIS, LISTEN.
ANYBODY CALL?
AN ANDREW BECKETT CALLED.
BECKETT?
WHO'S ANDREW BECKETT?
THERE HE IS!
JOSEPH!
[JOE]
I WANT YOU TO EXPLAIN THIS TO ME
LIKE I'M A SIX-YEAR-OLD.
THE ENTIRE STREET IS CLEAR
EXCEPT FOR ONE SMALL AREA
UNDER CONSTRUCTION,
THIS HUGE HOLE CLEARLY
MARKED AND BLOCKED OFF.
YES.
YOU DECIDE YOU MUST CROSS
THE STREET AT THIS SPOT.
YOU FALL INTO THE HOLE.
NOW YOU WANT TO SUE THE CITY
FOR NEGLIGENCE. RIGHT?
YES.
DO I HAVE A CASE?
YES. YEAH, OF COURSE
YOU'VE GOT A CASE.
GREAT!
GO WITH
MY ASSISTANT IRIS.
ALL RIGHT.
SHE'LL HAVE YOU FILL OUT FORMS.
TELL YOU ABOUT
OUR FEE ARRANGEMENT.
YOU KNOW WE TAKE NO CASH
UNLESS WE GET CASH JUSTICE
FOR YOU.
HOW'S YOUR BACK?
GOT ANY LOWER BACK PAIN,
DIZZINESS, NIGHTMARES?
FUNNY YOU SHOULD MENTION THAT--
IRIS WILL TAKE
GOOD CARE OF YOU.
IRIS, YOU TAKE GOOD CARE
OF MR. FINLEY.
I WILL.
MR. BECKETT'S HERE.
THANKS A LOT.
TAKE CARE.
MR. BECKETT?
MR. BECKETT,
COME IN.
IT'S GOOD TO SEE YOU AGAIN,
COUNSELOR.
JUDGE TATE.
KENDALL CONSTRUCTION.
INNOCUOUS!
HOW ARE YOU?
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOUR FACE?
I HAVE AIDS.
OH!
OH, I'M SORRY,
I, UH--
CAN I SIT DOWN?
YEAH.
THANK YOU.
OH, LOOK AT THIS!
YOU HAVE A NEW BABY.
YEAH.
A LITTLE BABY GIRL.
OH...
"IT'S A GIRL."
CONGRATULATIONS.
YEAH.
ONE WEEK OLD.
KIDS ARE GREAT.
YEAH, THANK YOU, BECKETT,
I'M REAL EXCITED ABOUT IT.
LISTEN, I--
[CLEARS THROAT]
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
I'VE... I'VE BEEN FIRED
BY WYANT, WHEELER.
I PLAN ON BRINGING A
WRONGFUL TERMINATION SUIT...
AGAINST CHARLES WHEELER
AND HIS PARTNERS.
YOU WANT TO SUE WYANT, WHEELER,
HELLERMAN, TETLOW AND BROWN?
CORRECT.
I'M SEEKING REPRESENTATION.
CONTINUE.
I MISPLACED AN
IMPORTANT COMPLAINT.
THAT'S THEIR STORY.
WANT TO HEAR MINE?
HOW MANY LAWYERS YOU GO TO
BEFORE YOU CALLED ME?
NINE.
CONTINUE.
THE NIGHT BEFORE IT WAS DUE,
I WORKED ON THE COMPLAINT
IN MY OFFICE.
I LEFT A COPY ON MY DESK.
THE NEXT DAY,
THE COMPLAINT VANISHED.
NO HARD COPY.
ALL TRACES OF IT MYSTERIOUSLY
GONE FROM MY COMPUTER.
[ANDREW] MIRACULOUSLY,
A COPY OF THE COMPLAINT WAS
LOCATED AT THE LAST MINUTE,
AND WE GOT IT
TO COURT ON TIME.
BUT THE NEXT DAY,
I WAS SUMMONED TO A MEETING
WITH THE MANAGING PARTNERS.
THEY WERE WAITING FOR ME
IN THE CONFERENCE ROOM.
HELLO, ANDY!
COME ON IN.
WOULD YOU MIND HITTING
THE WINDOWS?
THANKS.
HEY, COME ON IN.
ROBERT, CHARLES, WALTER
AND LYDIA.
[CHARLES]
THANKS FOR COMING IN.
OF COURSE!
ANDY, BEFORE WE BEGIN,
I'D JUST LIKE TO SAY...
THAT EVERYONE IN THIS ROOM
IS YOUR FRIEND.
I KNOW THAT,
CHARLES.
MORE THAN YOUR FRIEND...
FAMILY.
CHARLES,
I MUST APOLOGIZE AGAIN...
FOR THE HIGHLINE MISHAP
YESTERDAY.
THAT WAS SOME SCARY MOMENT...
AROUND HERE.
WOW! THANK GOD
THE COMPLAINT WAS FOUND...
AND NO DAMAGE
WAS DONE.
THIS TIME.
WHAT ABOUT NEXT TIME?
THERE WON'T BE A NEXT TIME.
I GUARANTEE IT.
YEAH. IT'S JUST THAT
SOMETHING'S COME OVER YOU
LATELY, ANDY.
I DON'T KNOW.
SOME KIND OF STUPOR
OR FOGGINESS--
SOME PEOPLE THINK YOU HAVE
AN ATTITUDE PROBLEM, BECKETT.
REALLY?
WHO THINKS THAT?
I DO.
EXCUSE ME.
AM I BEING FIRED?
LET ME PUT IT THIS WAY,
ANDY.
YOUR PLACE IN THE FUTURE OF
THIS FIRM IS NO LONGER SECURE.
WE FEEL IT ISN'T FAIR
TO KEEP YOU HERE...
WHEN YOUR PROSPECTS
ARE LIMITED.
AND NOW... I DON'T WANT
TO RUSH YOU OUT.
WE'VE GOT A
COMMITTEE MEETING.
EXCUSE ME. CHARLES?
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT,
THIS... THIS IS PREPOSTEROUS!
IT DOESN'T MAKE
ANY SENSE!
- YOU'RE RIGHT. YOU DON'T HAVE
AN ATTITUDE PROBLEM.
- TAKE IT EASY, WALTER.
IF YOU HAD LOST CONFIDENCE
IN ME, WHY DID YOU
GIVE ME THE HIGHLINE SUIT?
ANDY, YOU NEARLY BLEW
THE ENTIRE CASE, FOR CHRISSAKES.
THAT ALONE IS INEXCUSABLE!
[ROBERT]
IT WOULD'VE BEEN
CATASTROPHIC FOR US.
UH-HUH.
SO YOU WERE CONCEALING
YOUR ILLNESS.
THAT'S CORRECT.
EXPLAIN THIS TO ME LIKE
I'M A TWO-YEAR-OLD, OKAY?
BECAUSE THERE'S AN ELEMENT
TO THIS THING I JUST CANNOT
GET THROUGH MY THICK HEAD.
DIDN'T YOU HAVE
AN OBLIGATION TO TELL
YOUR EMPLOYER...
YOU HAD THIS DREADED,
DEADLY, INFECTIOUS DISEASE?
THAT'S NOT...
THE POINT.
FROM THE DAY THEY HIRED ME,
TO THE DAY I WAS FIRED...
I SERVED MY CLIENTS
CONSISTENTLY, THOROUGHLY
WITH ABSOLUTE EXCELLENCE.
IF THEY HADN'T FIRED ME,
THAT'S WHAT I'D BE DOING TODAY.
AND THEY DON'T WANT TO FIRE YOU
FOR HAVING AIDS.
SO, IN SPITE OF YOUR BRILLIANCE,
THEY MAKE YOU LOOK INCOMPETENT.
THUS THE MYSTERIOUS LOST FILES.
IS THAT WHAT YOU'RE TELLING ME?
CORRECT.
I WAS SABOTAGED.
I DON'T BUY IT,
COUNSELOR.
THAT'S VERY
DISAPPOINTING.
I DON'T SEE A CASE.
I HAVE A CASE.
IF YOU DON'T WANT IT
FOR PERSONAL REASONS--
THANK YOU.
THAT'S CORRECT, I DON'T.
WELL, THANK YOU
FOR YOUR TIME, COUNSELOR.
MR. BECKETT?
UH, I'M SORRY ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU.
IT'S A BITCH, YOU KNOW?
HAVE A NICE DAY, MR. BECKETT.
WHAT THE HELL'S THE
MATTER WITH THAT GUY?
IRIS, FIND OUT IF ARMBRUSTER
CAN SEE ME.
[PHONE RINGING]
JOE MILLER'S OFFICE.
IRIS, FIND OUT IF
ARMBRUSTER CAN SEE ME.
ARMBRUSTER? WHEN?
SOMETIME THIS AFTERNOON.
NO, RIGHT AWAY, IRIS.
RIGHT AWAY, IRIS.
OKAY.
EXCUSE ME.
THE H.I.V. VIRUS CAN ONLY
BE TRANSMITTED THROUGH THE
EXCHANGE OF BODILY FLUIDS:
NAMELY BLOOD, SEMEN
AND VAGINAL SECRETIONS.
RIGHT. YEAH.
BUT ISN'T IT TRUE THEY'RE
FINDING OUT NEW THINGS ABOUT
THIS DISEASE EVERY DAY?
YOU TELL ME TODAY
THERE'S NO DANGER, GO HOME.
I GO HOME. I PICK UP
MY LITTLE BABY GIRL.
THEN I FIND OUT SIX MONTHS
FROM NOW ON THE NEWS:
WHOOPS! MADE A MISTAKE.
YEAH, YOU CAN CARRY IT...
ON YOUR SHIRT
OR YOUR CLOTHES OR--
WHAT ARE YOU DOIN'?
WE'RE GONNA DRAW BLOOD.
WHY ARE WE
GONNA DO THAT?
JOE. LITTLE JOE.
I'VE KNOWN YOU
SINCE YOU WERE A KID.
AND I DON'T CARE A WHIT
ABOUT YOUR PRIVATE LIFE.
THANKS, DOC.
I DON'T NEED AN AIDS TEST.
THANKS ANYWAY.
JUST SEND A BILL
TO MY OFFICE.
OKAY?
THANKS FOR THE INFORMATION.
REALLY.
YOU HAVE A PROBLEM
WITH GAYS, JOE.
NOT ESPECIALLY.
YES, YOU DO.
HOW MANY GAYS
DO YOU KNOW?
HOW MANY DO YOU KNOW?
LOTS!
LIKE WHO?
KAREN BERMAN.
MY AUNT TERESA.
COUSIN TOMMY
WHO LIVES IN ROCHESTER.
EDDIE MEYERS
FROM THE OFFICE.
STANLEY, THE GUY WHO'S
PUTTING IN OUR KITCHEN CABINETS.
AUNT TERESA IS GAY?
THAT BEAUTIFUL, SENSUOUS,
VOLUPTUOUS WOMAN
IS A LESBIAN?
DUH.
SINCE WHEN?
PROBABLY SINCE
SHE WAS BORN.
OH, MAN.
WELL, HEY, I ADMIT IT,
OKAY?
I'M PREJUDICED.
I DON'T LIKE HOMOSEXUALS.
THERE, YOU GOT ME.
I MEAN, THE WAY THESE GUYS
DO THAT... THING.
DON'T THEY GET CONFUSED?
"I DON'T KNOW, IS THAT YOURS?
IS THAT MINE?"
[LAUGHING]
I DON'T WANT TO BE IN
THE BED WITH ANYBODY...
WHO'S STRONGER THAN ME,
OR HAS MORE HAIR ON
THEIR CHEST THAN I DO.
YOU CAN CALL ME OLD-FASHIONED,
YOU CAN CALL ME CONSERVATIVE.
JUST CALL ME A MAN.
BESIDES, I THINK
YOU HAVE TO BE A MAN
TO UNDERSTAND HOW...
REALLY DISGUSTING
THAT WHOLE IDEA IS ANYWAY.
YEAH?
YEAH.
WELL, WELL.
LITTLE CAVEMAN OF THE HOUSE.
YOU DAMN SKIPPY!
HERE YOU GO, BABY.
STAY AWAY FROM YOUR
AUNT TERESA TOO.
JOE, DON'T SAY THAT
TO HER.
THINK ABOUT THOSE GUYS PUMPING
UP TOGETHER, TRYING TO BE MACHO
AND FAGGOT AT THE SAME TIME.
I CAN'T STAND THAT SHIT!
HEY, I'M BEING TOTALLY HONEST.
OH, YEAH, YOU ARE.
ALL RIGHT.
I GOT A QUESTION.
WOULD YOU ACCEPT
A CLIENT IF YOU WERE
CONSTANTLY THINKING,
"I DON'T WANT THIS PERSON
TO TOUCH ME.
I DON'T WANT HIM
TO EVEN BREATHE ON ME"?
NOT IF I WAS YOU, HONEY.
THAT'S WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT.
MM-HMM.
WHAT?
HO-HO-HO!
MERRY CHRISTMAS!
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
HEY, MERRY CHRISTMAS!
HO-HO-HO!
THANK--
HAPPY NEW YEAR.
YOU'RE THE...
TV GUY.
SIR?
THIS IS
THE SUPPLEMENT.
YOU'RE RIGHT. THERE IS
A SECTION ON H.I.V.
RELATED DISCRIMINATION.
OH, THANK YOU.
THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
WE DO HAVE A PRIVATE
RESEARCH ROOM AVAILABLE.
I'M FINE RIGHT HERE.
THANK YOU.
EXCUSE ME. DO YOU KNOW
WHERE I CAN FIND THE
STATE VERSUS MURDOCK CASE?
[LIBRARIAN]
JUST A MOMENT.
I'LL BE RIGHT WITH YOU.
[SIGHS]
WOULDN'T YOU BE
MORE COMFORTABLE
IN A RESEARCH ROOM?
[COUGHS]
NO. WOULD IT MAKE YOU
MORE COMFORTABLE?
OH, AH... BECKETT.
HOW YOU DOIN'?
COUNSELOR.
HUH.
WHATEVER, SIR.
EXCUSE ME.
[COUGHS]
WHO'D YOU GET?
WHAT?
DID YOU FIND A LAWYER?
I'M A LAWYER.
HEY, HOW'S YOUR BABY?
OH, YEAH, SHE'S...
WONDERFUL, GREAT.
WHAT'S HER NAME?
LARICE.
THAT'S A BEAUTIFUL NAME!
NAMED HER
AFTER MY SISTER.
LOOK, I'M, UH--
HOW'D THEY FIND OUT
YOU HAVE THE AIDS?
ONE OF THE PARTNERS NOTICED
A LESION ON MY FOREHEAD.
UM... BUT HOW
DO YOU GO FROM--
HOW DO YOU GO FROM A LAWYER
SPOTTING A LESION, WHICH
COULD'VE BEEN ANYTHING,
TO THE PARTNERS DEDUCING
THAT YOU HAVE AIDS,
AND TERMINATING YOU ON THE
BASIS OF THAT CONCLUSION?
THAT'S A GOOD POINT.
THE PARTNER WHO SPOTTED
THE LESION, WALTER KENTON,
WORKED FOR WALSH,
ULMER AND BRAHM IN D.C.
A PARALEGAL THERE,
MELISSA BENEDICT,
SHE SHOWED LESIONS ON AND OFF
FOR THE BETTER PART
OF TWO, THREE YEARS.
IT WAS COMMON KNOWLEDGE
AROUND THE OFFICE THAT HER
LESIONS WERE CAUSED BY AIDS.
BUT THEY DIDN'T
FIRE HER.
NO.
THEY DID NOT FIRE HER.
SO YOU GOT A
RELEVANT PRECEDENT?
MM-HMM.
THE ARLINE DECISION.
ARLINE?
SUPREME COURT.
"THE FEDERAL VOCATIONAL
REHABILITATION ACT OF 1973...
"PROHIBITS DISCRIMINATION
AGAINST OTHERWISE QUALIFIED
HANDICAPPED PERSONS...
"WHO ARE ABLE TO PERFORM
THE DUTIES REQUIRED
BY THEIR EMPLOYMENT.
THE RULING DID NOT ADDRESS
THE SPECIFIC ISSUE OF H.I.V.
AND AIDS DISCRIMINATION."
"SUBSEQUENT DECISIONS HAVE HELD
THAT AIDS...
"IS PROTECTED AS A HANDICAP
UNDER LAW, NOT ONLY BECAUSE...
"OF THE PHYSICAL LIMITATIONS
IT IMPOSES, BUT BECAUSE THE
PREJUDICE SURROUNDING AIDS...
"EXACTS A SOCIAL DEATH
WHICH PRECEDES--
WHICH PRECEDES THE
ACTUAL PHYSICAL ONE."
"THIS IS THE ESSENCE
OF DISCRIMINATION.
"FORMULATING OPINIONS
ABOUT OTHERS NOT BASED
ON THEIR INDIVIDUAL MERITS,
BUT RATHER ON THEIR
MEMBERSHIP IN A GROUP WITH
ASSUMED CHARACTERISTICS."
[CHATTERING]
CHARLES WHEELER!
JULIUS ERVING!
BY GOLLY,
I'M GLAD TO SEE YOU!
KEN STARR.
HOW ARE YOU?
IT'S ONLY GOING TO TAKE
A MINUTE.
CHARLES WHEELER.
HOW YOU DOIN'?
HOW ARE YOU?
VERY GOOD, VERY GOOD.
SUMMONS FOR YOU.
TAKE A LOOK AT IT.
HEY, DR. J., I LOVE YOU, MAN.
YOU'RE THE BEST.
IF YOU EVER NEED A LAWYER,
GIVE ME A CALL.
IF YOU SLIP AND FALL,
ACCIDENTS, ANYTHING,
LET ME KNOW.
SEE YOU IN COURT.
YOU'RE THE TV GUY.
YEAH, THE TV GUY.
SAY, CHUCK,
WHAT'S UP?
[CHARLES] REGARDING ANDY,
I WANT TO KNOW EVERYTHING
ABOUT HIS PERSONAL LIFE.
DOES HE FREQUENT THOSE PATHETIC
BARS ON CHESTNUT STREET?
JESUS!
WHAT OTHER HOMOSEXUAL
FACILITIES DOES HE GO TO?
ABSOLUTELY.
WHAT DEVIANT GROUPS
OR ORGANIZATIONS DOES
HE SECRETLY BELONG TO?
WAIT A MINUTE!
BOB, WHAT IS IT?
LET'S MAKE A FAIR SETTLEMENT
OFFER, AND PUT THIS WHOLE
TRAGIC BUSINESS BEHIND US.
BOB, ANDY BROUGHT AIDS...
INTO OUR OFFICES,
INTO OUR MEN'S ROOM!
HE BROUGHT AIDS
TO OUR ANNUAL
GODDAMN FAMILY PICNIC!
WE OUGHT TO BE SUING HIM.
WHERE IS YOUR COMPASSION,
GENTLEMEN?
BOB, WE GAVE HIM HIGHLINE!
DID ANDREW BECKETT SAY,
"I MIGHT NOT BE ABLE
TO SERVE OUR CLIENT TO
THE BEST OF MY ABILITY"?
HE SAID NOTHING!
NOW, DISCARDING
THE TRUST AND AFFECTION
I CONFERRED UPON HIM,
ANDREW BECKETT PROPOSES
TO HAUL ME INTO COURT.
TO SLING ACCUSATIONS AT ME.
TO CALL ME A BIGOT...
IN FULL VIEW OF
THE ENTIRE PHILADELPHIA
JUDICIAL ESTABLISHMENT.
MY GOD!
EXCUSE ME.
BECKETT DOESN'T WANT TO GO
TO COURT. HE'S LOOKING
FOR A QUICK SETTLEMENT.
A JURY MIGHT DECIDE
THAT HE HAS A CASE.
WAIT A MINUTE.
HE WAS FIRED
FOR INCOMPETENCE,
NOT BECAUSE HE HAS AIDS.
YOU DIDN'T KNOW HE WAS SICK,
DID YOU, BOB?
HOLY SHIT!
NO, NO.
NOT, NOT REALLY.
OKAY, OKAY, EVERYBODY.
EVERYBODY, THIS IS THE HOUSE
THAT I GREW UP IN.
RIGHT HERE IN THE TOWN OF
LOWER MERION, PENNSYLVANIA.
WAIT, HERE... HERE'S PROOF.
THERE!
MY HANDPRINTS FROM WHEN
I WAS A CUTE, LITTLE BOY.
TODAY IS THE 40TH WEDDING
ANNIVERSARY OF MY MOM AND DAD.
THE BECKETTS.
ISN'T THAT SOMETHING?
[MIGUEL]
PRETTY TOUGH LIFE AMONG
POVERTY SO MANY YEARS, HUH?
THOSE CAN BE MEAN STREETS.
DON'T LET APPEARANCES FOOL YOU.
HERE'S THE FRONT DOOR.
NOW, I ONCE SLAMMED...
THIS FINGER IN THE FRONT DOOR
AND I BROKE IT.
WHERE'S MY BROTHER?
HEY, HEY.
HEY, THERE'S MY SISTER JILL,
EVERYBODY.
SAY HELLO, ALEXIS.
MOMMY'S PREGNANT AGAIN!
WHAT?
ARE YOU REALLY?
YES.
HI, MEGHAN.
IT'S UNCLE ANDY!
WHERE'S DAD?
HE'S TRYING TO GET
THE SNOW BLOWER FIXED.
IT SNOWS ONCE
IN SEVEN YEARS, DAD
BUYS A NEW SNOW BLOWER.
OH! HOW ARE YOU?
MOM, TODAY'S A GOOD DAY.
MEGHAN, KEEP THAT UP.
YOU'RE DOING A GREAT JOB.
I GOT TO SAY HELLO
TO THE BRONTE SISTERS.
HOW ARE YOU?
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
HI, LEE.
HOW ARE YOU?
HEY, HEY, HEY.
PUT ME DOWN.
[MAN]
♪ IF YOU LET ME LOVE YOU
♪ IT'S FOR SURE
I'M GONNA LOVE YOU ♪
♪ ALL THE WAY
♪ ALL... BUD AND SARAH
THERE ARE GONNA BE THINGS
SAID AT THE TRIAL THAT
ARE GONNA BE HARD TO HEAR...
ABOUT ME AND
MY PERSONAL LIFE.
THERE'S GONNA BE PUBLICITY.
I WANT TO MAKE SURE
IT'S OKAY WITH EVERYBODY.
ANDY, WANT ME
TO TAKE HER?
NO, NO.
SHE'S... SHE'S FINE.
I THINK IT'S GREAT THAT
YOU'RE ASKING, ANDY, BUT...
THIS IS REALLY
YOUR CALL.
ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU, BROTHER.
THANK YOU.
HEY, YOU'RE
MY KID BROTHER.
THAT'S ALL THAT MATTERS,
OKAY?
TO BE HONEST, I'M WORRIED
ABOUT MOMMY AND DADDY.
THEY'VE BEEN THROUGH
SO MUCH ALREADY.
AND IT'S POSSIBLE
THERE ARE GONNA BE SOME
VERY TOUGH TIMES AHEAD.
ANDY, THE WAY...
THE WAY YOU'VE HANDLED
THIS WHOLE THING,
YOU AND MIGUEL,
WITH SO MUCH COURAGE,
I DON'T BELIEVE
THERE'S ANYTHING...
THAT ANYONE
COULD SAY...
THAT WOULD MAKE US
FEEL ANYTHING...
BUT INCREDIBLY PROUD
OF YOU.
[SARAH]
WELL...
I DIDN'T RAISE MY KIDS
TO SIT IN THE BACK OF THE BUS.
YOU GET IN THERE AND YOU FIGHT
FOR YOUR RIGHTS, OKAY?
GEE, I LOVE YOU GUYS!
[JOE]
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN
OF THE JURY,
FORGET EVERYTHING
YOU'VE SEEN ON TELEVISION
AND IN THE MOVIES.
THERE'S NOT GOING TO BE ANY
LAST-MINUTE SURPRISE WITNESSES.
NOBODY'S GOING TO
BREAK DOWN ON THE STAND
WITH A TEARFUL CONFESSION.
YOU'RE GOING TO BE PRESENTED
WITH A SIMPLE FACT:
ANDREW BECKETT WAS FIRED.
YOU'LL HEAR
TWO EXPLANATIONS
FOR WHY HE WAS FIRED:
OURS... AND THEIRS.
IT IS UP TO YOU TO SIFT
THROUGH LAYER UPON LAYER
OF TRUTH...
UNTIL YOU DETERMINE FOR YOURSELVES
WHICH VERSION SOUNDS THE MOST TRUE.
THERE ARE CERTAIN POINTS
I MUST PROVE TO YOU.
POINT NUMBER ONE:
ANDREW BECKETT WAS...
IS... A BRILLIANT LAWYER,
A GREAT LAWYER.
POINT NUMBER TWO:
ANDREW BECKETT, AFFLICTED
WITH A DEBILITATING DISEASE,
MADE THE UNDERSTANDABLE,
THE PERSONAL,
THE LEGAL CHOICE TO KEEP
THE FACT OF HIS ILLNESS
TO HIMSELF.
POINT NUMBER THREE:
HIS EMPLOYERS DISCOVERED
HIS ILLNESS.
AND, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
THE ILLNESS I'M REFERRING TO
IS AIDS.
POINT NUMBER FOUR:
THEY PANICKED!
AND IN THEIR PANIC,
THEY DID WHAT MOST OF US
WOULD LIKE TO DO WITH AIDS,
WHICH IS JUST GET IT
AND EVERYBODY WHO HAS IT...
AS FAR AWAY FROM
THE REST OF US AS POSSIBLE.
NOW, THE BEHAVIOR OF
ANDREW BECKETT'S EMPLOYERS
MAY SEEM REASONABLE TO YOU.
DOES TO ME. AFTER ALL, AIDS
IS A DEADLY, INCURABLE DISEASE.
BUT NO MATTER HOW YOU COME
TO JUDGE CHARLES WHEELER
AND HIS PARTNERS...
IN ETHICAL, MORAL
AND HUMAN TERMS,
THE FACT OF THE MATTER IS...
WHEN THEY FIRED ANDREW
BECKETT BECAUSE HE HAD AIDS,
THEY BROKE THE LAW.
FACT:
ANDREW BECKETT'S PERFORMANCE
ON THE JOB...
VARIED FROM COMPETENT,
GOOD...
TO OFTENTIMES
MEDIOCRE,
TO SOMETIMES FLAGRANTLY
INCOMPETENT.
FACT:
HE CLAIMS HE'S THE VICTIM
OF LIES AND DECEIT.
FACT:
IT WAS ANDREW BECKETT
WHO LIED,
GOING TO GREAT LENGTHS TO CONCEAL
HIS DISEASE FROM HIS EMPLOYERS.
FACT:
HE WAS... SUCCESSFUL
IN HIS DUPLICITY.
THE PARTNERS AT WYANT,
WHEELER DID NOT KNOW...
THAT ANDREW BECKETT HAD
AIDS WHEN THEY FIRED HIM.
FACT:
ANDREW BECKETT IS DYING.
ANDREW BECKETT
IS ANGRY...
BECAUSE
HIS LIFESTYLE,
HIS RECKLESS
BEHAVIOR...
HAS CUT SHORT
HIS LIFE.
AND IN HIS ANGER,
HIS RAGE,
HE IS LASHING OUT.
AND HE WANTS SOMEONE
TO PAY.
THANK YOU.
ANDREW BECKETT REPRESENTED
YOUR COMPANY IN A LAWSUIT
IN 1990. CORRECT?
THAT'S CORRECT.
WERE YOU PLEASED
WITH HIS WORK?
WE WERE SATISFIED WITH THE
OUTCOME OF THE LITIGATION.
SATISFIED.
MR. LAIRD,
WHEN I APPROACHED YOU
ABOUT BEING A WITNESS,
YOU GAVE SWORN TESTIMONY
IN A DEPOSITION,
IS THAT CORRECT?
THAT'S CORRECT.
IN THAT DEPOSITION,
YOU SAID THAT YOU WERE
"IMPRESSED AND DELIGHTED...
WITH THE QUALITY OF
ANDREW BECKETT'S WORK."
DO YOU RECALL
SAYING THAT?
IN ALL HONESTY,
I WAS DELIGHTED...
WITH CERTAIN ASPECTS
OF ANDY'S EFFORTS.
BUT IN GENERAL,
I FOUND THE WORK TO BE...
MERELY SATISFACTORY.
UH-HUH.
DO YOU AGREE...
THAT A BOLOGNA SANDWICH
IS A SATISFACTORY MEAL?
WHEREAS CAVIAR
AND CHAMPAGNE...
ROAST DUCK AND...
BAKED ALASKA,
THAT MIGHT BE CONSIDERED
A DELIGHTFUL MEAL?
WE OBJECT.
THESE GASTRONOMICAL COMMENTS
ARE IRRELEVANT, YOUR HONOR.
[JOE]
THEY ARE NOT IRRELEVANT.
YOUR HONOR, FIVE MONTHS AGO
THIS WITNESS CHARACTERIZED
ANDREW BECKETT AS CAVIAR.
NOW HE'S CALLING HIM
A BOLOGNA SANDWICH.
I THINK THE JURY
IS ENTITLED TO KNOW...
WHAT POWERFUL FORCE
HAS CAUSED HIM
TO CHANGE HIS MIND.
HE HASN'T CHANGED
HIS MIND.
HE'S AMPLIFIED
HIS ANSWER.
OBJECTION SUSTAINED.
ALL RIGHT.
MR. LAIRD, EXPLAIN
THIS TO ME LIKE I'M
A FOUR-YEAR-OLD, OKAY?
DID ANDREW BECKETT
WIN YOUR LAWSUIT FOR YOU?
YES, WE WON.
OH, CONGRATULATIONS!
THAT MUST'VE BEEN A VERY...
SATISFACTORY EXPERIENCE.
[CHANTING]
HOMOPHOBIA'S GOT TO GO.
HEY, HEY!
[CHANTING CONTINUES]
READY, MR. BECKETT?
GET READY.
HERE THEY COME.
[CHANTING]
NO RIGHTS FOR SODOMITES!
ADAM AND EVE!
NOT ADAM AND STEVE!
THOU SHALT NOT LIE
WITH MANKIND.
DO YOU SEE THIS AS
A GAY RIGHTS ISSUE?
I AM NOT POLITICAL.
I JUST WANT WHAT IS FAIR,
WHAT IS RIGHT.
BUT YOU ARE GAY,
AREN'T YOU?
I DON'T SEE HOW THAT'S
ANY OF YOUR BUSINESS.
BUT, YES, I AM.
TOTALLY IRRELEVANT.
DOESN'T MATTER.
DO YOU THINK THAT
HOMOSEXUALS DESERVE
SPECIAL TREATMENT?
HELL NO!
[JOE]
WE'RE IN PHILADELPHIA,
THE CITY OF BROTHERLY LOVE,
BIRTHPLACE OF FREEDOM...
WHERE THE FOUNDING FATHERS
AUTHORED THE
DECLARATION OF INDEPENDENCE.
I DON'T RECALL THAT
GLORIOUS DOCUMENT SAYING...
ANYTHING ABOUT ALL STRAIGHT MEN
ARE CREATED EQUAL.
I BELIEVE IT SAYS
"ALL MEN ARE CREATED EQUAL."
GIMME A GODDAMN BREAK.
[TV]
AS FAR AS SOMEONE BEING FIRED,
FROM A LAW FIRM OR A BUSINESS,
IF WE FOUND THAT THEIR ACTION
WAS DISCRIMINATORY,
THEY COULD NO LONGER DO BUSINESS
WITH THE CITY.
THANK YOU, MAYOR.
JOE.
YOU'RE NOT GETTIN' A LITTLE
LIGHT IN THE SNEAKERS,
ARE YOU, PAL?
[LAUGHING]
YEAH, I AM, FILKO.
I'M, UH... I'M CHANGING.
I'M ON THE PROWL.
AND I'M LOOKING FOR A HUNK,
NOT JUST ANY HUNK.
I MEAN A MAN,
A REAL MAN LIKE YOU.
YOU CAN TELL EVERYBODY ABOUT IT.
YOU KNOW WHAT WE DO.
YOU WANNA PLAY SAILOR?
YOU REMEMBER? I'M COLUMBUS,
YOU'RE THE FIRST MATE?
THAT'S NOT FUNNY!
LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING.
THESE PEOPLE MAKE ME SICK.
BUT A LAW'S
BEEN BROKEN.
YOU REMEMBER THE LAW,
DON'T YOU?
AT LEAST WE AGREE
ON ONE THING, JOE.
WHAT'S THAT,
CHARLIE?
TUTTI-FRUTTIS
MAKE ME SICK TOO.
[JOE] MRS. BENEDICT,
IS IT TRUE YOU WORKED FOR
WALSH, ULMER AND BRAHM...
THREE YEARS AGO AT THE SAME TIME
AS WALTER KENTON?
THAT'S CORRECT.
AT THAT TIME, DID
WALTER KENTON KNOW...
THE K.S. LESIONS ON YOUR FACE
AND ARMS WERE CAUSED BY AIDS?
DEFINITELY. I TOLD
ALL THE PARTNERS.
HOW DID WALTER KENTON
TREAT YOU AFTER YOU
TOLD HIM YOU HAD AIDS?
EVERY TIME HE'D COME
IN CONTACT WITH ME,
HE'D GET THIS LOOK
ON HIS FACE.
I REFER TO IT AS THE
"OH, GOD" EXPRESSION.
AS IN, "OH, GOD, HERE COMES
THAT WOMAN WITH AIDS."
THANK YOU, MRS. BENEDICT.
NO MORE QUESTIONS, YOUR HONOR.
MRS. BENEDICT, HOW DID YOU
CONTRACT THE AIDS VIRUS?
THROUGH A TRANSFUSION.
I LOST A LOT OF BLOOD GIVING
BIRTH TO MY SECOND CHILD.
SO, IN YOUR CASE
THERE WAS NO BEHAVIOR
ON YOUR PART...
WHICH CAUSED YOU TO BE
INFECTED WITH THE VIRUS.
IT WAS SOMETHING YOU
WERE UNABLE TO AVOID.
ISN'T THAT CORRECT?
I GUESS.
THANK YOU.
[MRS. BENEDICT]
BUT I DON'T
CONSIDER MYSELF...
ANY DIFFERENT FROM ANYONE
ELSE WITH THIS DISEASE.
I'M NOT GUILTY.
I'M NOT INNOCENT.
I'M JUST TRYING TO SURVIVE.
THANK YOU,
MRS. BENEDICT.
NO FURTHER QUESTIONS
AT THIS TIME, YOUR HONOR.
[JUDGE]
YOU MAY STEP DOWN,
MRS. BENEDICT.
[JOE]
BEYOND NOTICING THE MARKS
ON HIS FACE,
WERE THERE OTHER THINGS
ABOUT HIS APPEARANCE,
MISS BURTON,
THAT MADE YOU SUSPECT
THAT ANDREW HAD AIDS?
HE WAS GETTING THINNER
AND SEEMED VERY TIRED SOMETIMES.
BUT HE WAS WORKING SO HARD.
I FELT SOMETHING WAS WRONG.
AND I CAN'T BELIEVE THEY'RE
TRYING TO PRETEND THAT
THEY DIDN'T NOTICE ANYTHING.
OBJECTION.
JUST ANSWER THE QUESTION,
PLEASE.
HAVE YOU EVER FELT
DISCRIMINATED AGAINST
AT WYANT, WHEELER?
WELL, YES.
IN WHAT WAY?
WELL, MR. WHEELER'S
SECRETARY, LYDIA,
SAID THAT MR. WHEELER
HAD A PROBLEM WITH
MY EARRINGS.
REALLY?
APPARENTLY MR. WHEELER
FELT THEY WERE...
TOO "ETHNIC"
IS THE WORD SHE USED.
SHE TOLD ME HE SAID HE WOULD
LIKE IT IF I WORE SOMETHING
A LITTLE LESS GARISH,
A LITTLE SMALLER
AND MORE... "AMERICAN."
WHAT'D YOU SAY?
I SAID, "MY EARRINGS
ARE AMERICAN.
THEY'RE AFRICAN-AMERICAN."
[CHUCKLES]
[LAUGHING]
[JUDGE]
LET'S HAVE ORDER, PLEASE.
THANK YOU.
NO MORE QUESTIONS.
MISS BURTON,
WEREN'T YOU
RECENTLY PROMOTED?
YES. I'M IN CHARGE
OF THE PARALEGAL DEPARTMENT.
CONGRATULATIONS ON
YOUR UNFETTERED ASCENDANCY
AT WYANT, WHEELER.
I DON'T KNOW IF I'D GO SO FAR
AS TO CALL IT UNFETTERED.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN...
THE PROMOTION
OF AN OBVIOUSLY...
INTELLIGENT, ARTICULATE,
QUALIFIED
AFRICAN-AMERICAN WOMAN...
IN A FIRM WHICH PRACTICES
DISCRIMINATION...
AS WANTONLY AND CONSISTENTLY
AS YOU AND MR. BECKETT CLAIM?
I CAN'T EXPLAIN IT.
COULD IT BE...
THAT THESE...
INSTANCES
OF DISCRIMINATION...
ARE IN FACT
MISUNDERSTANDINGS...
THAT HAVE BEEN BLOWN
COMPLETELY OUT OF PROPORTION?
I THINK COUNSEL TENDS TO
OVERSIMPLIFY THE ISSUE SOMEWHAT.
THANK YOU, MISS BURTON,
I'LL...
TAKE THAT NOTE
UNDER CONSIDERATION.
[LAUGHTER]
HOW'S THE
TRIAL GOING?
EXCUSE ME?
IT'S A GREAT CASE.
I SAW YOU ON TELEVISION.
I'M A LAW STUDENT AT PENN.
HOW YOU DOIN'?
I'M ALL RIGHT.
HOW ARE YOU?
SAW ME ON TV?
YEAH.
IT'S A GOOD SCHOOL, PENN.
WHAT YEAR ARE YOU IN?
SECOND. LISTEN,
I JUST WANT TO TELL YOU...
THIS CASE,
IT'S TREMENDOUSLY IMPORTANT.
I WANTED TO LET YOU KNOW
I THINK YOU'RE DOING
A FANTASTIC JOB.
HEY.
THANK YOU.
WHEN YOU GRADUATE,
YOU GIVE ME A CALL.
ALL RIGHT. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
LISTEN, JOE?
YEAH?
WOULD YOU LIKE TO HAVE A DRINK?
I JUST FINISHED A GAME
AND COULD USE A BEER.
AH, NO, I CAN'T.
MY WIFE IS--
I DON'T PICK UP PEOPLE
IN DRUGSTORES EVERY DAY.
WHAT?
YOU THINK I'M GAY?
AREN'T YOU?
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
I LOOK GAY TO YOU?
DO I LOOK GAY TO YOU?
JOE, RELAX.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN, RELAX?
I OUGHTA KICK YOUR
FAGGOTY LITTLE ASS.
TAKE IT AS A COMPLIMENT,
GEEZ!
THAT'S EXACTLY THE KIND
OF BULLSHIT THAT MAKES
PEOPLE HATE YOUR...
FAGGOTY ASS.
YOU WANT TO TRY
AND KICK MY ASS, JOE?
ASSHOLE.
NO, YOU'RE THE ASSHOLE,
BUDDY!
[ATTORNEY]
PLEASE CONTINUE, MISS O'HARA.
WE WERE GOING CRAZY LOOKING
FOR THIS COMPLAINT.
I FELT LIKE I WAS IN
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
MR. BECKETT WAS SCREAMING
AT EVERYBODY AND HE JUST--
HE LOOKED SO FREAKY.
MR. KENTON KEPT SAYING,
"YOU LOST THE HIGHLINE
COMPLAINT?"
AND HE CALLED MR. WHEELER,
AND ALL OF A SUDDEN...
JAMEY COMES IN WITH
THE COMPLAINT IN HIS HAND.
HE SAYS, "IT WAS IN
CENTRAL FILES, ANDY."
CENTRAL FILES?
CENTRAL FILES IS A PLACE
WHERE PAPERWORK IS SENT
WHEN CASES ARE CLOSED.
JAMEY RAN IT OVER TO
THE COURT JUST IN TIME,
AND EVERYBODY JUST STOOD
THERE COMPLETELY WASTED.
AND MR.--
AND MR. BECKETT
JUST KEPT SAYING,
"I'M SORRY. SORRY.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND THIS."
THANK YOU,
MISS O'HARA.
NO FURTHER QUESTIONS
AT THIS TIME, YOUR HONOR.
[JUDGE]
ALL RIGHT.
MR. MILLER.
MAY I?
CERTAINLY.
OH, THANK YOU.
YOU OKAY?
YES.
YOU WANT A GLASS
OF WATER OR SOMETHING?
NO.
WAS ANDY
A GOOD BOSS?
YES.
HE WAS VERY SWEET.
HOW WOULD YOU CHARACTERIZE
HIS WORK AS AN ATTORNEY?
HOW WOULD I KNOW?
I JUST WORKED FOR HIM.
[LAUGHTER]
EXCUSE ME, YOUR HONOR,
BUT IS THIS FOR THE RECORD?
MR. MILLER, PERHAPS YOU SHOULD
RETURN TO COUNSEL'S TABLE.
YES, SIR.
MISS O'HARA?
YES?
WERE YOU AWARE,
AT ANY TIME,
OF ANY PROBLEMS THAT
THE SENIOR PARTNERS HAD...
WITH THE QUALITY OF
ANDREW'S WORK PRIOR TO
THIS MISSING FILE EPISODE?
NO. NO, I WASN'T.
THANK YOU.
NO MORE QUESTIONS, YOUR HONOR.
[JOE] IS ANDREW BECKET
THE KIND OF LAWYER WHO
MISPLACES CRUCIAL DOCUMENTS?
NOT TO MY KNOWLEDGE.
NO.
MR. COLLINS, IF YOU WANTED TO
MAKE A LAWYER LOOK INCOMPETENT,
WOULD THIS BE A GOOD WAY?
HIDING AN IMPORTANT DOCUMENT
MAYBE FOR A FEW HOURS,
AND THEN MAKING IT LOOK LIKE
THE RESPONSIBLE LAWYER
MISPLACED IT?
WHY WOULD MR. WHEELER
AND THE OTHERS BEHAVE
SO OUTRAGEOUSLY?
BECAUSE THEY FOUND OUT
ANDY WAS SICK?
[WHISPERS] HE'S NOT
ANSWERING THE QUESTION.
PERHAPS.
WE'VE HAD LAWYERS WHO'VE HAD
HEART ATTACKS, ULCERS,
PROSTATE CANCER, LEUKEMIA!
NO ONE
SANDBAGGED THEM.
DID YOU HAVE SOMETHING TO DO
WITH THIS FILE BEING LOST
ACCIDENTALLY ON PURPOSE?
OBJECTION.
I'LL REPHRASE.
DID YOU HAVE ANYTHING
TO DO WITH THIS FILE
BEING MISPLACED?
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
ARE YOU
A HOMOSEXUAL?
WHAT?
ARE YOU A HOMOSEXUAL?
ANSWER THE QUESTION!
ARE YOU A HOMO?
ARE YOU A FAGGOT?
A QUEEN,
PILLOW BITER, FAIRY?
BOOTIE SNATCHER,
RUMP ROASTER?
ARE YOU GAY?
OBJECTION!
[GAVEL POUNDING]
ORDER!
WHERE DID THIS COME FROM?
SUDDENLY COUNSEL'S ATTACKING
HIS OWN WITNESS?
MR. COLLINS' SEXUAL
ORIENTATION HAS NOTHING
TO DO WITH THIS CASE.
PLEASE HAVE A SEAT,
MISS CONINE.
[JUDGE]
WOULD YOU APPROACH
THE BENCH, MR. MILLER?
[JUDGE, QUIETLY]
COULD YOU KINDLY
SHARE WITH ME...
EXACTLY WHAT'S GOING ON
INSIDE YOUR HEAD,
BECAUSE AT THIS MOMENT,
I DON'T HAVE A CLUE.
YOUR HONOR,
EVERYBODY IN THIS
COURTROOM...
IS THINKING ABOUT...
SEXUAL ORIENTATION,
SEXUAL PREFERENCE,
WHATEVER YOU WANT
TO CALL IT.
WHO DOES WHAT TO WHOM
AND HOW THEY DO IT.
THEY'RE LOOKING
AT ANDREW BECKETT.
THEY'RE THINKING ABOUT IT.
THEY'RE LOOKING AT
MR. WHEELER, MISS CONINE,
EVEN YOU, YOUR HONOR.
THEY'RE WONDERING
ABOUT IT.
[CHUCKLES]
TRUST ME, I KNOW THEY'RE LOOKING
AT ME AND THINKING ABOUT IT.
SO LET'S JUST GET IT OUT
IN THE OPEN.
LET'S GET IT OUT
OF THE CLOSET.
BECAUSE THIS CASE IS NOT
JUST ABOUT AIDS, IS IT?
SO LET'S TALK ABOUT WHAT
THIS CASE IS REALLY ALL ABOUT:
THE GENERAL PUBLIC'S HATRED,
OUR LOATHING,
OUR FEAR
OF HOMOSEXUALS.
AND HOW THAT CLIMATE
OF HATRED AND FEAR...
TRANSLATED INTO THE FIRING
OF THIS PARTICULAR HOMOSEXUAL,
MY CLIENT,
ANDREW BECKETT.
PLEASE HAVE A SEAT,
MR. MILLER.
VERY GOOD.
IN THIS COURTROOM, MR. MILLER,
JUSTICE IS BLIND...
TO MATTERS OF RACE,
CREED, COLOR,
RELIGION AND
SEXUAL ORIENTATION.
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT,
YOUR HONOR,
WE DON'T LIVE IN THIS
COURTROOM, THOUGH, DO WE?
NO, WE DON'T.
HOWEVER, AS REGARDS
TO THIS WITNESS,
I'M GOING TO SUSTAIN
THE DEFENSE'S OBJECTION.
HOW MANY WEEKS WOULD
YOU BE OUT TO SEA
WITHOUT STOPPING AT PORT?
OH, ANYWHERE FROM
TWO WEEKS TO SEVERAL MONTHS.
ANY WOMEN ON BOARD?
AH, NOT WHEN I WAS
IN THE NAVY.
SO, DURING THESE
LONG VOYAGES,
MONTHS AT A TIME OUT TO SEA,
NO WOMEN IN SIGHT,
HUNDREDS OF HARDWORKING, ROBUST YOUNG
MEN IN THE PRIME OF THEIR LIVES,
AT THE PEAK OF THEIR NATURAL
APPETITES AND DESIRES,
THEIR GOD-GIVEN HORMONAL
INSTINCTS, ANYTHING GOING ON?
GOING ON?
LIKE WHAT?
LIKE TWO SAILORS DOWN BELOW
MAKING FLIPPY-FLOP.
[MISS CONINE] OBJECTION.
[JUDGE] MR. MILLER.
WE HAD ONE GUY
LIKE THAT.
YOU HAVEN'T RULED ON
MY OBJECTION, YOUR HONOR.
[JUDGE]
GO ON, MR. MILLER.
YOU HAD ONE GUY "LIKE THAT."
YOU MEAN A HOMOSEXUAL?
HE STRUTTED AROUND QUARTERS NAKED
TRYING TO GET EVERYBODY TO NOTICE HIM.
MADE EVERYONE SICK.
HE WAS DESTROYING
OUR MORALE.
SO WE LET HIM KNOW THIS KIND
OF BEHAVIOR WAS NOT ACCEPTABLE.
HOW'D YOU DO THAT?
WHAT'D YOU DO?
WROTE HIM A LETTER?
WE STUCK HIS HEAD
IN A LATRINE AFTER
TEN OF US HAD USED IT.
YOU TAUGHT HIM A LESSON,
DIDN'T YOU?
YES, WE DID.
LIKE FIRING ANDREW BECKETT
TAUGHT HIM A LESSON.
OBJECTION.
I WITHDRAW. YOU WERE
AWARE WHEN YOU WORKED
WITH MELISSA BENEDICT...
THAT SHE HAD AIDS,
IS THAT CORRECT?
SHE DIDN'T TRY
TO CONCEAL IT.
SO YOU ARE AWARE OF THE
DIFFERENCE BETWEEN A BRUISE
AND A LESION. CORRECT?
BECKETT TOLD ME HE HAD
BEEN HIT BY A RACQUETBALL,
AND I BELIEVED HIM.
DIDN'T YOU TRY TO AVOID CONTACT
WITH MRS. BENEDICT AFTER
YOU FOUND OUT SHE HAD AIDS?
SHE SAYS AND I QUOTE,
THAT YOU...
"WERE REPULSED BY HER,
YOU AVOIDED HER."
IS THAT CORRECT?
I FELT, AND
I STILL FEEL NOTHING...
BUT THE DEEPEST SYMPATHY
AND COMPASSION FOR PEOPLE
LIKE MELISSA...
WHO CONTRACTED THIS
TERRIBLE DISEASE THROUGH
NO FAULT OF THEIR OWN.
♪ [OPERA]
[MIGUEL]
DON'T MOVE NOW.
OKAY.
BOY.
IT'S NOT GOING THROUGH.
WE MAY HAVE
TO FLUSH IT OUT AGAIN.
OH.
THE VEIN'S CLOSED.
WE'VE GOT
TO CALL BARBARA.
NURSE RATCHETT!
WAIT A MINUTE.
TELL HER
TO COME OVER.
LOOK, I'VE--
THERE'S SO MUCH STUFF
THAT I NEED TO GET DONE.
CAN WE--
CAN WE JUST SKIP THE
TREATMENT FOR TONIGHT?
NO. NO, WE ARE NOT
SKIPPING THIS TREATMENT.
IT'S MY ARM
AND IT'S MY TREATMENT.
AND I SAY SKIP IT.
WELL...
YOU KNOW SOMETHIN'?
HMM?
THAT STUFF IS
SAVING YOUR LIFE.
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH YOU TONIGHT?
CLOSE THE LAW BOOK.
WILL YOU JUST--
[SIGHS]
THE LEAST YOU CAN DO...
IS LOOK AT ME,
AND GIVE ME A LITTLE
OF YOUR TIME, MAN.
GOT IT?
YOU ARE WORRIED...
THAT WE DON'T HAVE
VERY MUCH TIME LEFT,
NOW AREN'T YOU?
NO. NO.
I'LL TELL YOU
WHAT I'M GONNA DO.
I'M GOING TO START PLANNING
MY MEMORIAL SERVICE.
I'M GOING TO START PREPARING
FOR THE INEVITABLE.
MAYBE YOU SHOULD
THINK ABOUT IT.
NO.
NO, NO, NO.
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO,
NO, NO.
I'VE GOT A BETTER IDEA.
[INDISTINCT CHATTING]
HI, ANDREW.
HI, MIGUEL.
HEY, HEY!
OH, JOE MILLER, COUNSELOR.
MY WIFE, LISA.
ARE YOU LISA?
NICE TO MEET YOU.
MIGUEL, LISA.
YOU LOOK WONDERFUL!
LISA, JOE.
MIGUEL'S SISTER, MARIA.
DO YOU CARE FOR
SOMETHING TO DRINK?
I'LL TAKE CARE OF JOE.
YOU'RE LOOKIN', UH,
ALIVE TONIGHT!
I HAD A BLOOD TRANSFUSION
AND I FEEL GREAT.
AH! SO, YOU LIKE IT?
I'M A LAWSUIT.
YOU GET IT?
IT'S NOT BAD.
LAW...SUIT.
WHAT ARE YOU DRINKING?
WINE IS GOOD.
CAN I HAVE SOME
OF THE RED, PLEASE?
WE'VE GOT TO GET TO THIS
Q & A SOMETIME TONIGHT,
YOU KNOW?
SURE.
JUST ONE PROBLEM.
I'M AT A PARTY RIGHT NOW.
FINE. WHATEVER.
WE'LL GET TO IT,
JUST LATER, THAT'S ALL.
THANK YOU.
HI, JOE MILLER.
DO I KNOW YOU?
MONA LISA.
AH!
UH, LAWSUIT.
NICE.
HAVE FUN.
♪ BUM, BUM, BUM, BUM
BUM, BUM, BUM, BUM ♪
♪ MR. SANDMAN
♪ BRING ME A DREAM
♪ MAKE HIM THE CUTEST BOY
THAT I'VE EVER SEEN ♪
♪ GIVE HIM TWO LIPS
LIKE ROSES AND CLOVER ♪
♪ THEN TELL ME THAT
MY LONESOME NIGHTS ARE OVER ♪
♪ MR. SANDMAN
♪ I'M SO ALONE
♪ DON'T HAVE A BOYFRIEND
TO CALL MY OWN ♪
♪ OH, WON'T YOU PLEASE TURN ON
YOUR MAGIC BEAM ♪
♪ MR. SANDMAN
BRING US A DREAM ♪
♪ IT IS HARD TO IMAGINE
♪ OH, THAT NOTHING AT ALL
♪ COULD BE SO EXCITING
♪ OOH, AND SO MUCH FUN
♪ OH-OH, HEAVEN
♪ IS A PLACE
♪ WHERE NOTHING
OOH, NOTHING ♪
♪ CAN GO WRONG
♪ OH-OH, HEAVEN
♪ IS A PLACE
♪ WHERE NOTHING
OOH, NOTHING ♪
♪ CAN GO WRONG
THANK YOU.
♪ [OPERA,
"ANDREA CHENIER"]
AH! THANK YOU.
SURE.
CONGRATULATIONS,
COUNSELOR.
CONGRATULATIONS?
YOU'VE SURVIVED
WHAT I ASSUME TO BE...
YOUR FIRST GAY PARTY
INTACT.
LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING,
ANDREW.
WHEN YOU'RE BROUGHT UP THE WAY
MOST PEOPLE ARE IN THIS COUNTRY,
THERE'S NOT
A WHOLE LOT OF DISCUSSION
ABOUT HOMOSEXUALITY,
OR WHAT DO YOU CALL IT...
ALTERNATE LIFESTYLES.
AS A KID YOU'RE TAUGHT
THAT QUEERS ARE FUNNY,
QUEERS ARE WEIRD.
QUEERS DRESS UP
LIKE THEIR MOTHER, THAT
THEY'RE AFRAID TO FIGHT,
THAT THEY'RE A DANGER
TO LITTLE KIDS.
THAT ALL THEY WANT TO DO
IS GET INTO YOUR PANTS.
THAT PRETTY MUCH SUMS UP
THE GENERAL THINKIN' OUT THERE,
IF YOU WANT TO KNOW THE TRUTH.
THANK YOU FOR
SHARING THAT WITH ME.
YOU'RE VERY WELCOME.
LET'S GO OVER THIS TESTIMONY.
WE'VE GOT A BIG DAY ON MONDAY.
OKAY.
FIRST I'LL ASK YOU,
"CAN YOU DESCRIBE THE
CIRCUMSTANCES IN WHICH...
YOU JOINED THE FIRM
WYANT, WHEELER, HELLERMAN,
TETLOW AND BROWN?"
MILLER?
DO YOU EVER PRAY?
ANDREW, THAT IS NOT
THE ANSWER TO THE QUESTION.
BUT, YES, I PRAY.
WHAT DO YOU PRAY FOR?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
I PRAY THAT, UH--
I DON'T KNOW!
I PRAY MY BABY IS HEALTHY.
I PRAY MY WIFE MADE IT
THROUGH DELIVERY.
I PRAY THE PHILLIES
WIN THE PENNANT.
NOW, CAN WE GO THROUGH
THESE QUESTIONS?
NUMBER ONE: "CAN YOU DESCRIBE
THE CIRCUMSTANCES IN WHICH...
YOU JOINED THE FIRM
WYANT, WHEELER, HELLERMAN,
TETLOW AND BROWN?"
CAN YOU DO THAT FOR ME?
THERE'S A POSSIBILITY
I WON'T BE AROUND TO SEE
THE END OF THIS TRIAL.
YES, I'VE CONSIDERED THAT.
I'VE MADE SOME PROVISIONS
IN MY WILL FOR SOME CHARITIES.
MIGUEL WILL NEED A LAWYER.
I KNOW IT'S NOT YOUR AREA.
I KNOW A GOOD
PROBATE LAWYER.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
NOW, "CAN YOU DESCRIBE
THE CIRCUMSTANCES IN WHICH...
YOU JOINED THE FIRM
WYANT, WHEELER, HELLERMAN,
TETLOW AND BROWN?"
♪ [OPERA CONTINUES]
DO YOU MIND THIS MUSIC?
DO YOU LIKE OPERA?
I AM NOT THAT FAMILIAR
WITH OPERA, ANDREW.
♪ [ARIA, "LA MAMMA MORTA"]
OH, THIS IS MY
FAVORITE ARIA.
IT'S MARIA CALLAS.
♪ [IN ITALIAN]
IT'S "ANDREA CHENIER."
UMBERTO GIORDANO.
♪ [CONTINUES IN ITALIAN]
THIS IS MADELEINE.
♪ [VOLUME INCREASES]
SHE'S SAYING...
HOW DURING THE
FRENCH REVOLUTION...
THE MOB SET FIRE
TO HER HOUSE.
AND HER MOTHER DIED...
SAVING HER.
SHE SAYS, "LOOK!
"THE PLACE THAT CRADLED ME
IS BURNING.
♪ [ADAGIO,
VOICE SADDENS]
I AM ALONE."
♪
♪ [CONTINUES ADAGIO]
DO YOU HEAR THE HEARTACHE
IN HER VOICE?
CAN YOU FEEL IT, JOE?
♪ [CONTINUES
IN ITALIAN]
NOW, IN COME THE STRINGS,
AND IT CHANGES EVERYTHING.
IT'S LIKE THE MUSIC...
IT FILLS WITH A HOPE.
♪ [ACCELERANDO]
AND THAT'LL CHANGE AGAIN.
LISTEN.
♪ [ADAGIO]
♪ [VOICE SADDENS,
ANGUISHED]
"I BRING SORROW
TO THOSE WHO LOVE ME.
♪ [CELLO]
OH!
OH, THAT SINGLE CELLO!
♪ [VOICE SADDENS,
ADAGIO]
♪
"IT WAS DURING THIS SORROW
THAT LOVE CAME TO ME.
♪ [CONTINUES
IN ITALIAN]
[SOBBING]
"A VOICE FILLED
WITH HARMONY.
"IT SAID, LIVE STILL.
"I AM LIFE.
"HEAVEN IS IN YOUR EYES.
♪ [CRESCENDO]
♪
♪ [CONTINUES
IN ITALIAN]
♪
♪ [CRESCENDO,
VOICE ANGUISHED]
♪
"IT'S EVERYTHING AROUND YOU.
IT'S THE BLOOD AND THE MUD.
"I AM DIVINE!
"I AM OBLIVION.
♪ [CRESCENDO]
"I AM THE GOD...
"THAT COMES DOWN FROM
THE HEAVENS TO THE EARTH...
"AND MAKES OF THE EARTH
A HEAVEN.
♪ [CONTINUES
IN ITALIAN]
♪ [CRESCENDO]
"I AM... LOVE.
I AM LOVE."
♪
♪ [ARIA ENDS]
WELL, UH--
HEY! GEEZ,
I BETTER GET OUT OF HERE.
LISA'S, UH--
I TOLD HER THAT, YOU KNOW--
UH, I'LL LOOK OVER
THE Q & A.
NAH, YOU'RE READY.
YOU'RE READY.
UM--
[SIGHS]
♪ [ARIA BEGINS AGAIN]
♪
JESUS.
♪ [ARIA CONTINUES]
♪
HUH. GOD.
♪ [ARIA, "LA MAMMA MORTA"
CONTINUES IN ITALIAN]
♪
♪ [ARIA CONTINUES]
[WHISPERS]
YES, BABY.
[CRYING]
OH, I LOVE YOU,
LITTLE LARICE.
♪
♪ [ARIA CONTINUES]
♪ [CRESCENDO]
♪
♪ [ARIA ENDS]
PLACE YOUR LEFT HAND
ON THE BIBLE.
RAISE YOUR RIGHT HAND.
DO YOU SWEAR TO TELL
THE WHOLE TRUTH,
SO HELP YOU GOD?
I DO.
PLEASE
BE SEATED.
[JOE] ANDREW,
CAN YOU DESCRIBE THE
CIRCUMSTANCES IN WHICH...
YOU JOINED THE FIRM
WYANT, WHEELER, HELLERMAN,
TETLOW AND BROWN?
[CLEARS THROAT]
WYANT, WHEELER
AGGRESSIVELY RECRUITED ME.
THEY WERE THE
MOST PRESTIGIOUS FIRM
IN PHILADELPHIA,
FULL OF OPPORTUNITY.
AND I WAS IMPRESSED
WITH THE PARTNERS.
INCLUDING
CHARLES WHEELER?
PARTICULARLY CHARLES.
WHAT IMPRESSED YOU
ABOUT HIM?
HE WAS THE KIND OF LAWYER
I THOUGHT I WANTED TO BE.
WHAT KIND OF LAWYER
IS THAT?
POSSESSED OF AN
ENCYCLOPEDIC KNOWLEDGE
OF THE LAW,
A RAZOR-SHARP LITIGATOR,
GENUINE LEADER;
GIFTED AT BRINGING OUT
THE VERY BEST IN OTHERS,
AND AN AWESOME ABILITY
TO ILLUMINATE...
THE MOST COMPLEX
OF LEGAL CONCEPTS TO
A COLLEAGUE, A COURTROOM,
TO THE MAN IN THE STREET.
THE KIND OF PERSON WHO CAN
PLAY THREE SETS OF TENNIS,
BUT DOESN'T SWEAT.
UNDERNEATH AN
ELEGANT SURFACE,
HE HAS AN
ADVENTUROUS SPIRIT.
[JOE] IN THE YEARS
YOU WORKED AT WYANT, WHEELER,
DID YOU EVER TELL
CHARLES WHEELER
YOU WERE GAY?
NO, I-I DIDN'T.
WHY NOT?
YOU DON'T BRING YOUR
PERSONAL LIFE INTO A LAW FIRM.
YOU'RE NOT SUPPOSED TO HAVE
A PERSONAL LIFE, REALLY.
ANYWAY, I DID PLAN
TO TELL CHARLES EVENTUALLY.
BUT THEN SOMETHING HAPPENED
AT THE RACQUET CLUB...
ABOUT THREE YEARS AGO.
SOMEBODY STARTED TELLING
SOME JOKES.
[LAUGHING]
WHAT DO YOU CALL A WOMAN
WHO HAS P.M.S. AND E.S.P.
AT THE SAME TIME?
I DON'T KNOW!
WHAT DO YOU CALL HER?
A BITCH
WHO KNOWS EVERYTHING.
SOUNDS LIKE
SOMEONE I KNOW.
HEY, WALTER, HOW DOES
A FAGGOT FAKE AN ORGASM?
HE THROWS A QUART OF
HOT YOGURT ON YOUR BACK!
[JOE]
HOW'D THAT MAKE YOU FEEL?
RELIEVED...
THAT I NEVER TOLD HIM
I WAS GAY.
JUST VERY RELIEVED.
ALL RIGHT.
ARE YOU A GOOD LAWYER,
ANDREW?
I'M AN EXCELLENT LAWYER.
WHAT MAKES YOU
AN EXCELLENT LAWYER?
I LOVE THE LAW.
I KNOW THE LAW.
I EXCEL AT PRACTICING.
WHAT DO YOU LOVE
ABOUT THE LAW, ANDREW?
I--
MANY THINGS.
- WHAT I LOVE THE MOST
ABOUT THE LAW?
- YES.
IS THAT
EVERY NOW AND AGAIN,
NOT OFTEN,
BUT OCCASIONALLY,
YOU GET TO BE
A PART OF...
JUSTICE BEING DONE.
THAT REALLY IS...
QUITE A THRILL
WHEN THAT HAPPENS.
[JOE]
THANK YOU, ANDREW.
[MISS CONINE]
YOU SAID EARLIER...
YOU ASPIRE TO BE THE
KIND OF PERSON WHO HAD
AN ADVENTUROUS SPIRIT.
- IS THAT CORRECT?
- SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
DO YOU TAKE RISKS?
IN MY WORK, YES:
CALCULATED RISKS.
YOU HAVE TO.
DID YOUR DOCTOR EVER TELL YOU
TO REDUCE STRESS?
THAT LONG HOURS AND
STRESSFUL WORKING CONDITIONS...
MIGHT DAMAGE THE IMMUNE SYSTEM
AND SPEED UP YOUR ILLNESS?
MY DOCTOR MENTIONED
THE IMPACT AIDS--
EXCUSE ME.
MY DOCTOR MENTIONED
THE IMPACT STRESS COULD HAVE
ON THE IMMUNE SYSTEM.
HAVE YOU EVER BEEN...
TO THE STALLION SHOWCASE CINEMA
ON 21ST STREET?
I, I'VE BEEN TO... THAT--
I'VE BEEN TO THAT THEATER...
THREE TIMES IN MY LIFE.
WHAT KIND OF MOVIES
DO THEY SHOW THERE?
GAY MOVIES.
GAY PORNOGRAPHIC MOVIES?
YES.
OBJECTION,
YOUR HONOR.
YOUR HONOR,
THIS LINE OF QUESTIONING...
IS VITAL TO THE ISSUE
OF CREDIBILITY.
[SIGHS]
LET'S, UH--
LET'S SEE WHERE THIS IS GOING.
CONTINUE, COUNSELOR.
DO MEN HAVE SEX WITH EACH OTHER
IN THAT THEATER?
SOME MEN.
HAVE YOU EVER HAD SEX WITH
ANYONE IN THAT THEATER?
I'M ROBERT.
ANDY.
YES.
ONCE.
WHEN?
APPROXIMATELY WHAT YEAR
DID THAT EVENT TAKE PLACE?
I GUESS IT WAS, UH...
1984.
'84, '85.
WERE YOU AWARE
IN 1984, '85...
THAT THERE WAS A FATAL DISEASE
OUT THERE CALLED AIDS,
AND THAT YOU COULD CONTRACT IT
THROUGH SEXUAL ACTIVITY?
I'D HEARD OF SOME--
I'D HEARD OF A THING, UH...
THE GAY PLAGUE,
THE GAY CANCER.
WE DIDN'T KNOW HOW
YOU COULD GET IT...
OR THAT IT KILLED YOU.
DO YOU NEED A BREAK,
MR. BECKETT?
NO.
NO, I-- I COULD USE
SOME WATER, THOUGH.
[JUDGE] JOHN, WOULD YOU
BRING MR. BECKETT SOME WATER?
[MISS CONINE] WHILE YOU
WERE EMPLOYED AT WYANT, WHEELER
YOU DID EVERYTHING YOU COULD...
TO MAKE SURE NO ONE
KNEW THAT YOU WERE...
AN ACTIVE HOMOSEXUAL.
IS THAT CORRECT?
NO.
THAT'S NOT CORRECT.
I NEVER LIED ABOUT IT.
[MISS CONINE]
AS A HOMOSEXUAL,
ONE IS OFTEN FORCED TO
CONCEAL ONE'S SEXUALITY.
ISN'T THAT RIGHT?
IN SOME CIRCUMSTANCES,
YES.
ISN'T IT TRUE YOU'VE SPENT
YOUR LIFE PRETENDING TO BE
SOMETHING YOU'RE NOT,
SO MUCH SO THAT THE ART OF
CONCEALMENT AND DISHONESTY...
HAS BECOME SECOND NATURE--
YOUR HONOR, I OBJECT!
I'LL WITHDRAW IT,
YOUR HONOR.
MR. BECKETT,
WERE YOU LIVING WITH...
MIGUEL ALVAREZ...
IN 1984 OR '85
WHEN YOU HAD YOUR...
ANONYMOUS SEXUAL ENCOUNTER
IN THE PORN THEATER?
YES.
SO YOU COULD HAVE INFECTED HIM,
ISN'T THAT RIGHT?
MIGUEL HAS NOT
BEEN INFECTED.
YOU DIDN'T ANSWER
MY QUESTION.
YOU COULD HAVE INFECTED
MR. ALVAREZ AT THAT TIME.
IS THAT CORRECT?
YES.
YOU'VE TESTIFIED THAT
THE LESIONS ON YOUR FACE...
WERE VISIBLE TO THE PEOPLE
THAT YOU WORKED WITH,
CORRECT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
AND IT'S YOUR CONTENTION
THAT WHEN THE PARTNERS WERE
MADE AWARE OF THE LESIONS,
THAT THEY LEAPT
TO THE CONCLUSION THAT
YOU HAD AIDS AND FIRED YOU.
IS THAT CORRECT?
AS PAINFUL AS IT IS,
TO ACCUSE
MY FORMER COLLEAGUES...
OF SUCH REPREHENSIBLE
BEHAVIOR,
IT IS THE ONLY CONCLUSION
I COULD COME TO.
DO YOU HAVE ANY LESIONS
ON YOUR FACE AT THIS TIME?
ONE... HERE,
RIGHT BY MY EAR.
YOUR HONOR, MAY I
APPROACH THE WITNESS?
YES, YOU MAY.
REMEMBERING THAT
YOU'RE UNDER OATH,
ANSWERING TRUTHFULLY,
CAN YOU SEE THE LESIONS
ON YOUR FACE IN THIS MIRROR...
FROM THREE FEET AWAY?
ANSWERING TRUTHFULLY.
WELL, I--
AT THE TIME I WAS FIRED,
I HAD FOUR LESIONS,
AND THEY WERE MUCH BIGGER.
COULD YOU ANSWER
THE QUESTION, PLEASE?
WELL, UH, NO.
NO, I CAN'T REALLY SEE IT.
NO.
NO MORE QUESTIONS,
YOUR HONOR.
[JUDGE]
THIS WOULD BE A GOOD TIME
TO BREAK FOR TODAY.
WE CAN RECONVENE
IN THE MORNING.
I HATE THIS CASE.
YOUR HONOR, MAY I HAVE, UH,
FIVE MINUTES IN REDIRECT?
MR. BECKETT, CAN YOU GO ON
FOR FIVE MINUTES?
[JOE]
THREE MINUTES.
YES.
MAY I BORROW
YOUR MIRROR, PLEASE?
ANDREW,
DO YOU HAVE ANY LESIONS
ON ANY PART OF YOUR BODY
AT THIS TIME...
THAT RESEMBLE THE LESIONS
YOU HAD ON YOUR FACE...
AT THE TIME
THAT YOU WERE FIRED?
YES.
ON MY TOR-TORSO.
YOUR TORSO.
IF IT PLEASE THE COURT,
I WOULD LIKE TO ASK ANDREW
TO REMOVE HIS SHIRT...
SO THAT EVERYONE HERE
COULD GET AN ACCURATE IDEA
OF WHAT WE'RE TALKING ABOUT.
OBJECTION!
YOUR HONOR, IT WOULD
UNFAIRLY INFLUENCE THE JURY.
[JOE] YOUR HONOR, IF ANDREW
WAS FORCED TO USE A WHEELCHAIR
DUE TO HIS ILLNESS,
WOULD THE DEFENSE ASK HIM
TO PARK IT OUTSIDE...
BECAUSE IT WOULD
UNFAIRLY INFLUENCE THE JURY?
WE'RE TALKIN' ABOUT AIDS,
ABOUT LESIONS. LET'S SEE
WHAT WE'RE TALKIN' ABOUT.
I'LL ALLOW IT.
MR. BECKETT, WOULD YOU PLEASE
REMOVE YOUR SHIRT?
MY GOD,
WHAT A NIGHTMARE!
HE ASKED FOR IT.
ANDREW,
CAN YOU SEE THE LESIONS
ON YOUR CHEST IN THIS MIRROR?
YES.
THANK YOU.
[COUGHING]
DO YOU SWEAR TO TELL
THE WHOLE TRUTH,
SO HELP YOU GOD?
[WHEELER]
I DO.
PLEASE BE SEATED.
[MISS CONINE]
MR. WHEELER, WERE YOU AWARE
THAT ANDREW BECKETT...
WAS SUFFERING FROM AIDS
AT THE TIME OF HIS DEPARTURE
FROM WYANT, WHEELER?
NO.
FOR ABSOLUTE CLARITY,
DID YOU FIRE
ANDREW BECKETT...
BECAUSE HE HAD AIDS?
NO, I DID NOT FIRE
ANDREW BECKETT
BECAUSE HE HAD AIDS.
MR. WHEELER, CAN YOU EXPLAIN
IN A WAY THAT LEAVES NO DOUBT...
WHY YOU PROMOTED ANDREW BECKETT
THROUGH YOUR FIRM?
AND THEN,
MOST IMPORTANTLY,
WHY YOU EVENTUALLY
ASKED HIM TO LEAVE?
IF, UH, YOU'RE THE OWNER
OF A MAJOR LEAGUE BALL CLUB,
YOU RECRUIT
THE HOT ROOKIE.
AND ANDY WAS
TREMENDOUSLY PROMISING
AS A YOUNG ATTORNEY.
FRESH OUT OF PENN.
CRACKERJACK.
THAT'S WHY WE WENT AFTER HIM,
THAT'S WHY WE HIRED HIM.
AND THAT'S WHY WE STUCK WITH HIM
YEAR AFTER YEAR.
[GASPING]
[MISS CONINE]
WHY DID YOU GIVE HIM...
OPPORTUNITY
AFTER OPPORTUNITY?
WELL, WHEN YOU
GROOM SOMEONE...
THE WAY WE GROOMED ANDY,
NURTURING HIM,
LAVISHING ALL KINDS OF
SPECIAL TREATMENT ON HIM,
YOU MAKE
QUITE AN INVESTMENT.
WE WERE WAITING FOR
THE PROMISE TO KICK IN
AND DELIVER.
BUT, UH, ULTIMATELY
WE COULD NO LONGER...
IGNORE THE GAP BETWEEN
THE REALITY AND THE PROMISE.
THANK YOU,
MR. WHEELER.
NO MORE QUESTIONS
AT THIS TIME, YOUR HONOR.
MR. MILLER?
[MISS CONINE]
OBJECTION!
YOUR HONOR, OBJECTION!
ALL RIGHT,
MR. MILLER.
THAT'LL BE SUFFICIENT.
MR. WHEELER, YOU
ARE MAGNIFICENT.
YOU ARE... MY HERO.
ANDREW IS RIGHT.
YOU ARE THE GREATEST.
ARE YOU GAY?
OBJECTION.
[CHUCKLING]
HOW DARE YOU!
WITNESS WILL KINDLY ANSWER.
NO, I AM NOT
A HOMOSEXUAL.
ISN'T IT TRUE THAT
WHEN YOU REALIZED...
ANDREW BECKETT, YOUR GOLDEN BOY,
YOUR FUTURE SENIOR PARTNER,
WAS GAY AND HAD AIDS,
IT DROVE A STAKE OF FEAR
RIGHT THROUGH YOUR
HETEROSEXUAL HEART?
REMEMBERING ALL THE HUGS
AND HANDSHAKES, THE
INTIMATE MOMENTS IN THE SAUNA;
THE FRIENDLY PATS ON THE
BACKSIDE THAT YOU AND ANDREW
EXCHANGED, LIKE I HAVE.
IT MADE YOU SAY, "MY GOD!
WHAT DOES THIS SAY
ABOUT ME?"
OBJECTION,
YOUR HONOR.
THE WITNESS WILL PLEASE
RESPOND TO THE QUESTION.
MR. MILLER, YOU MAY TAP DANCE
AROUND ME ALL YOU WISH...
WITH YOUR INNUENDOES
AND LOCKER-ROOM FANTASIES.
BUT THE TRUTH STILL REMAINS
THAT YOUR CLIENT...
WORKED WHEN
HE WANTED TO WORK,
TELLING US WHAT HE THOUGHT
WE NEEDED TO KNOW
ABOUT WHO HE REALLY WAS.
ANDY INSISTED ON
BENDING THE RULES.
AND HIS WORK SUFFERED
TREMENDOUSLY IN THE LONG RUN
AS A RESULT OF THAT.
[JOE] EXPLAIN THIS TO ME
LIKE I'M A SIX-YEAR-OLD,
'CAUSE I JUST DON'T GET IT.
WHO MAKES THESE RULES THAT
YOU'RE TALKIN' ABOUT, HUH?
YOU?
READ YOUR BIBLE, MR. MILLER:
OLD AND NEW TESTAMENT.
PRETTY VALUABLE RULES
IN THERE.
[GASPING]
EXCU-- EXCUSE ME.
ANDREW?
EXCUSE ME.
I-I CAN'T S--
AGH!
OOH!
ANDY!
EXCUSE ME.
FOR CHRISSAKES,
SOMEBODY GET A DOCTOR!
[GROANING]
TURN OVER NOW.
CALL AN AMBULANCE, PLEASE.
RIGHT AWAY!
AN AMBULANCE, PLEASE!
LET HIM BREATHE!
PLEASE MAKE ROOM
FOR HIM.
[INDISTINCT CHATTING]
IT'S NOT WORKING!
IT IS MAKING IT WORSE.
[JOE] DID YOU NOTICE
ANY CHANGES WHATSOEVER
IN ANDREW'S APPEARANCE...
OVER THE COURSE OF THE YEAR
LEADING UP TO HIS TERMINATION?
YES, I DID.
WERE THESE CHANGES
FOR THE BETTER OR WORSE?
SOMETIMES FOR THE BETTER;
BUT GENERALLY,
FOR THE WORSE.
MR. SEIDMAN, WHAT DID YOU
THINK CAUSED THESE CHANGES
IN ANDY'S APPEARANCE?
I WAS... AFRAID.
I SUSPECTED
ANDY HAD AIDS.
[CROWD MUMBLING]
[JUDGE] ORDER! ORDER!
[JOE] THANK YOU.
YOUR WITNESS.
MISS CONINE?
MR. SEIDMAN, DID YOU
SHARE YOUR SUSPICIONS
WITH MR. WHEELER...
OR ANY OF THE OTHER MANAGING
PARTNERS AT ANY TIME...
BEFORE THE DECISION TO FIRE
ANDREW BECKETT WAS MADE?
NO, NO.
I DIDN'T.
I DIDN'T MENTION IT TO ANYONE,
NOT EVEN ANDY.
I DIDN'T EVEN GIVE HIM
A CHANCE TO TALK ABOUT IT.
AND I THINK I'M GOING
TO REGRET THAT...
FOR AS LONG AS I LIVE.
[JUDGE]
ANY MORE QUESTIONS?
THAT'S ALL, YOUR HONOR.
THEY ARE SAYIN'
HE WASN'T A GOOD LAWYER,
HE WAS MEDIOCRE.
AND THE FACT THEY GAVE HIM
THE MOST IMPORTANT LAWSUIT
THEY EVER HAD,
FOR ONE OF THEIR
MOST IMPORTANT CLIENTS,
THEY SAY THAT DOESN'T
PROVE ANYTHING BECAUSE
THAT WAS JUST A TEST.
WHAT'D THEY CALL IT?
A CARROT?
WHAT'S UP, DOC?
TO SEE IF HE WOULD RISE
TO THE OCCASION. OKAY!
SAY I'VE GOT TO SEND A PILOT
INTO ENEMY TERRITORY,
AND HE'S FLYING A PLANE
THAT COSTS $350 MILLION.
WHO AM I GONNA PUT
IN THAT PLANE?
SOME ROOKIE WHO CAN'T CUT
THE GRADE BECAUSE I WANNA SEE IF
HE CAN RISE TO THE CHALLENGE?
OR AM I GONNA GIVE
THAT ASSIGNMENT
TO MY BEST PILOT,
MY SHARPEST,
MY MOST EXPERIENCED,
MY TOP GUN,
THE VERY BEST I'VE GOT?
I JUST DON'T GET THAT.
WOULD SOMEBODY PLEASE
EXPLAIN IT TO ME...
LIKE I'M A SIX-YEAR-OLD.
[BAILIFF]
JUROR NUMBER SIX.
I AGREE.
JUROR NUMBER SEVEN.
JUROR NUMBER EIGHT.
AGREE.
JUROR NUMBER
NINE. I AGREE.
JUROR NUMBER TEN.
I DISAGREE.
JUROR NUMBER ELEVEN.
I AGREE.
JUROR NUMBER TWELVE.
AGREE.
HAVE YOU AWARDED
ANY DAMAGES?
YES, YOUR HONOR,
WE HAVE.
FOR BACK PAY AND
LOSS OF BENEFITS,
WE AWARD $143,000.
FOR MENTAL ANGUISH
AND HUMILIATION,
WE AWARD $100,000.
AND FOR PUNITIVE DAMAGES,
WE AWARD $4,782,000.
[APPLAUSE]
[JUDGE]
YOU MAY RECORD THE VERDICT.
EVERYONE REMAIN SEATED
UNTIL THE JURY IS REMOVED.
[WHISPERING]
HOW COULD THEY DO THAT?
THIS TRIAL IS NOW CONCLUDED.
JOE!
HA-HA!
CONGRATULATIONS!
[MISS CONINE]
WE'LL STRAIN OURSELVES
GETTING A REVERSAL ON THIS.
WE'LL GET STARTED
IN THE MORNING.
THAT'S THAT.
CONGRATULATIONS.
WE'LL SEE YOU AT THE APPEAL.
WELL DONE.
THANK YOU.
OH, MAN!
THANKS A LOT.
I'LL SEE YOU
AT THE HOSPITAL.
MR. MILLER,
HOW YA DOIN'?
DO YOU KNOW WHERE
HIS ROOM IS?
DOWN THE HALL.
THE ONE OFF
THE LOUNGE.
THANKS.
[DR. GILLMAN]
IF HE LEAVES THE HOSPITAL,
WHICH IS UNLIKELY,
DON'T EXPECT HIM
TO BE LIKE HE WAS
BEFORE THIS CRISIS.
HE'S LOST THE VISION
IN HIS RIGHT EYE.
BECAUSE OF THE C.M.V.,
HE WILL NOT REGAIN VISION.
NEXT DOOR TO THE RIGHT.
THE C.M.V. HAS
RAVAGED HIS BODY.
HI.
HEY, JOE!
WAY TO GO!
MAN OF THE HOUR.
HEY, JOE.
HI.
WE ARE SO GRATEFUL TO YOU.
YOU WERE WONDERFUL. THANK YOU.
CAN I TAKE THAT?
YEAH.
I BROUGHT SOME CHEESE... AND STUFF.
WONDERFUL. THANKS.
♪ [OPERA]
HOW YA DOIN'?
MMM.
WHAT DO YOU CALL
A THOUSAND LAWYERS...
CHAINED TOGETHER
AT THE BOTTOM OF THE OCEAN?
I DON'T KNOW.
A GOOD START.
EXCELLENT WORK,
COUNSELOR.
I THANK YOU.
IT WAS GREAT
WORKING WITH YOU,
COUNSELOR.
[GASPING]
[MONITOR BEEPS]
I'D BETTER GO.
UHH.
Y-YEAH. SURE THING.
I'LL SEE YOU LATER?
THANKS FOR
STOPPING BY.
I'LL SEE YOU AGAIN.
WELL, I'LL...
KEEP IT ON ICE FOR YOU.
SEE YOU.
JOE, I JUST WANT
TO SAY THANK YOU.
WE REALLY APPRECIATE IT.
WE'LL SEE YOU AGAIN?
ALL RIGHT.
HE'S A FIGHTER.
WE JUST WANT
TO GET HIM HOME.
THANK YOU, JOE.
OH, SORRY.
[MOANING]
[GASPING]
WHAT DO YOU CALL A THOUSAND
LAWYERS CHAINED TOGETHER
AT THE BOTTOM OF THE OCEAN?
A GOOD START?
[CHUCKLING]
VERY AMUSING.
I'LL SEE YOU TOMORROW,
BUDDY. OKAY?
SEE YOU TOMORROW.
GOD BLESS YOU, ANDY.
GOOD NIGHT, SON.
TRY TO GET SOME REST,
OKAY? OKAY.
I LOVE YOU, ANDY.
I LOVE YOU TOO,
DAD.
SEE YOU FIRST THING
TOMORROW.
YEAH. OKAY.
[MUMBLES]
IT'S OKAY.
DON'T WORRY.
I'LL SEE YOU
TOMORROW.
IT'S OKAY.
SEE YOU TOMORROW.
COME ON, SWEETHEART.
COME ON.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
GOOD NIGHT,
MY ANGEL.
MY SWEET BOY.
♪ [OPERA]
[SNIFFLING]
[MOANING]
LET ME HELP YOU.
MIGUEL?
I'M READY.
[PHONE RINGING]
[RINGING]
HELLO.
JOE, IT'S MIGUEL.
♪ ["PHILADELPHIA"
PERFORMED BY NEIL YOUNG]
♪
HI.
NICE TO SEE YOU.
EVERYBODY'S
UPSTAIRS.
♪ [PIANO]
[CHILDREN LAUGHING]
♪ SOMETIMES I THINK
THAT I KNOW ♪
♪ WHAT LOVE'S ALL ABOUT
♪ AND WHEN
I SEE THE LIGHT ♪
♪ I KNOW
I'LL BE ALL RIGHT ♪
♪ I'VE GOT MY FRIENDS
IN THE WORLD ♪
♪ I HAD MY FRIENDS
♪ WHEN WE WERE
BOYS AND GIRLS ♪
♪ AND THE SECRETS
CAME UNFURLED ♪
LOOK AT MY BOY.
♪ [PIANO]
OH, HI.
YES, I KNOW.
♪ CITY OF BROTHERLY LOVE
♪ PLACE I CALL HOME
♪ DON'T TURN YOUR BACK
ON ME ♪
♪ I DON'T WANT
TO BE ALONE ♪
♪ LOVE LASTS FOREVER
♪ SOMEONE
IS TALKING TO ME ♪
♪ CALLING MY NAME
♪ TELL ME
I'M NOT TO BLAME ♪
♪ I WON'T BE ASHAMED
OF LOVE ♪
♪ PHILADELPHIA
♪ [PIANO]
♪ CITY OF BROTHERLY LOVE
♪ BROTHERLY LOVE
♪ SOMETIMES I THINK
THAT I KNOW ♪
♪ WHAT LOVE'S ALL ABOUT
♪ AND WHEN I SEE
THE LIGHT ♪
♪ I KNOW I'LL BE ALL RIGHT
♪ PHILADELPHIA