Miss Williams apartment.
Miss Williams?
- Yep.
Say.
It's a hat alright.
Sure it is. What you think it was?
- Take it easy.
He's a secret service man.
- Secret service?
Oh.
I'd swear I heard something ticking.
Are you wearing a wristwatch?
- Yes, sir.
Start the car.
A hat for Miss Williams.
Thank you.
Would you care to join
me in a cup of tea?
No thanks.
Anything doing this afternoon?
I really couldn't say.
Come in.
It has arrived.
Thank you, Grace.
Come in.
It's here.
Do you think she will like it?
- We'll soon see.
Come in.
Your Highness. The hat.
This is the hat I told you about
that I saw in the window.
I thought you may like it.
Yes.
I don't know when you bought one last.
I think it's very pretty.
If you don't like it I can return it.
- I do though.
It's perfectly alright to return it.
I couldn't be more pleased with it.
If I may be excused.
Are you feeling alright, dear?
- Yes, Uncle.
Do you wish to go to a motion picture?
- I don't think so.
Horseback riding in Central Park?
- No thanks.
A drive in the car?
I'd rather stay here and read.
I will keep you company.
[ Door knocks ]
Come in.
Count de Candome.
Have him come in.
Two is company.
- Stay.
Maria. He has come to see you, not me.
Please stay.
If you insist.
Your Highness.
Your Highness is looking well.
- Thank you.
I hope you're in good health, sir.
Couldn't be better. And you?
I am fine. Thank you.
I'm in the neighborhood and thought you
might care to take in a motion picture.
No. I don't think so.
Or a horseback ride in the park?
I'm afraid not.
A drive in the car? A lovely day for it.
Lovely.
It's very kind of you but the truth
is I have a slight headache.
I am very sorry.
A drive in the open air may
be just the thing for it.
It's worse. I think I should lie down.
- I lie down when I have a headache.
Will you forgive me?
- Of course.
Good day.
Good day, sir.
- Good day.
I hope for Your Highness's
early recovery.
Thank you.
How do you feel now?
- A little better.
Don't you like him?
He comes from a very good family.
The Candomes are one of the
oldest bloodlines in Europe.
One of his ancestors was at the Battle
of Watling with your great grandfather.
On the other side.
If I remember rightly his ancestor
was killed in that battle.
Drowned.
- Drowned?
I thought the battle of
Watling was fought on land.
He was getting a drink from a brook.
He leaned in too far wearing his armor.
Only two feet of water but he drowned.
Went right to the bottom.
To tell you the truth, Maria.
The Count's mother has been hinting.
In normal times I would not
give him a second thought.
I must admit the match isn't
out of the question today.
After all, let's face it. Who's left?
Peter of Yugoslavia is 18 years old.
Leopold of Belgium just got married.
The Duke of Hempel is 66.
There aren't any suitable alliances.
Then I'll be an old maid.
If you are you, you should be ashamed.
It's not the first time our country has
been overrun and our family in exile.
We'll be back.
And in the meanwhile, Maria.
Frankly, you should be busy
having children. Boys.
I'll do what I can at the proper time.
The Count's family produces
a very high rate of boys.
For nobility.
I want to ask you something.
When he goes.
Is that hereditary?
Your children won't have it, but your
grandchildren. It skips a generation.
He has Bellini blood, hasn't he?
And if they go.
That means a great grandchild would go.
The baby could break its neck.
We'd investigate every possibility
before we came to any decision.
It's unfair to the count
to wait any longer.
You must tell his mother
to look elsewhere.
Let's not be too hasty.
I'm positive I am not attracted to him.
That's not the important
quality in a husband.
I understand the relationship
is quite intimate.
You're speaking like a shop-girl.
I don't ask for any wild,
impassioned mating.
Only for a man with whom I
can have something in common.
I have to spend a lifetime with him.
Is that too much to ask?
It might be.
You are a royal princess, Maria.
Are you proposing I marry him?
- I want you to think about it.
I will think about it.
I want you to get into a
happier frame of mind.
I will try, Uncle.
How would you like to visit a place?
- As you say.
We can go to the White House.
You'd like that?
We visited two weeks ago.
- What of it?
The president likes you.
You enjoyed it and the food is good.
Two weeks is too soon. We'd be imposing.
- Nonsense.
That is my opinion, Uncle.
You know what I think?
You need a change from me.
Untrue.
All you see during a day is me, your
secretary and a secret service man.
There isn't a pleasant
face in the group.
Why not go to Ambassador
Harrison's ranch?
At least you will see horses.
That is a good idea, Maria.
You'd do a lot of riding.
And you have a change of climate.
I'd as soon stay here in New York.
When you return you may feel
differently toward the count.
It's possible.
Book a plane ticket to San Francisco
in the name of Mary Williams.
No address. I'll pay for the ticket
by check at the ticket office.
Yes, sir.
Must I go by aeroplane?
I am frightened in an aeroplane.
It's all in your mind.
[ Bird twittering ]
Chirp, chirp.
What's that, dear?
Nothing, Uncle.
There will be a secret-service man
to meet her in San Francisco.
He'll go with the Harrisons
and her to the ranch.
I mean Her Highness and
the Harrisons. Excuse me.
I wonder if a secret-service
man is necessary at the ranch.
I'm trying to give her some privacy.
That decision is not
in my province but ..
With a guest of the country like the
princess, that would not be allowed.
There's nothing to fear, Your Highness.
- I am not frightened.
It's all in your mind, anyway.
The berth is made up. When you
get into it take this sleeping pill.
And you'll wake up in San Francisco
with the Harrisons waiting for you.
Only one pill?
I think one will be enough.
Have you ever taken any before?
People react differently to them.
If you wake up in the middle of the
night ask the stewardess for another.
"All aboard for Flight 5."
"Flight 5. Will passengers
please board the plane."
Come, dear.
Stewardess. Stewardess.
Yes?
- May I have a sleeping pill?
Certainly.
Here we are.
- Thank you.
Goodnight. Happy dreams.
- Goodnight.
Okay, son. Take it.
Is it hard, daddy?
- Nothing to it.
What do I do first?
- Fiddle around. It'll come to you.
Excuse me.
May I have a sleeping pill?
Indeed you can, Miss.
How you doing with that band leader?
A stewardess is not permitted social
engagements with passengers.
Miss.
Thank you.
Sleep tight.
Here.
Don't hurt yourself.
Excuse me. May I have a sleeping pill?
A sleeping pill coming up.
Here you are, Miss.
Just swallow it. It will never hurt you.
Take another. They are pretty mild.
Another?
Go on. There's nothing to them.
Don't you want any water?
Don't you want ..
Any water?
Well. Happy dreams.
Right.
Put your hand out, son.
We're turning back to New York.
Why, master?
- The man says it's foggy down there.
At both airports.
You have to get up now.
We'll not be leaving New York tonight.
When will we be leaving?
We'll call you, sir.
As soon as it clears.
You will have to get up.
Miss.
You will have to get up now.
Miss. Wake up.
Wake up.
I can't wake up Lower 6.
Miss. Wake up.
Lady.
All out. Fire.
That's what I call a clear conscience.
How she sleeps like that
on one pill beats me.
I only gave her one.
- You gave her one?
That makes two.
- Uhuh. Four.
Well.
Let's get her dressed.
- We'll toss.
The odd man dresses her.
You go home to your wife, married man.
- Who's in charge here?
I see what you mean. I'll wait outside.
You are doing fine. Keep walking.
I think she's going to say something.
Il fait très chaud
ce soir, n'est-ce pas?
Come again?
- Il fait très chaud.
What's that?
- She's speaking French.
She must know English.
She asked for the sleeping pills.
Do you know any French?
About four words, but she
hasn't said them yet.
I can say, 'where are you?'.
Ou et vous?
Paris.
Paris? Fine. She is only
three thousand miles off.
I can't understand how
you haven't her address.
Only her name is listed.
Where do you live?
Ou do vous live?
How do you do?
She sure is good natured.
You go home. I'll walk her around until
this wears off. It can't last forever.
Sure you don't mind?
- No.
Go on.
- Goodnight.
Where do you live?
Honey, are you lucky I was raised right.
Or was I?
Yes. I guess I was.
A drunk.
- Come, Matilda.
Hiya, Kids.
Oh me.
Hello?
Williams?
Excuse me, sir.
Have you a daughter named Mary?
You haven't.
I am sorry ..
Goodnight.
Getting any clearer?
If I could only sleep.
Another cup of coffee.
Hello?
Williams?
Excuse me, madam.
But have you a daughter named Mary?
You have? Where is she now?
Oh. You are nursing her.
I beg your pardon, ma'am. Wrong number.
This is not practical.
There are five pages of Williamses.
I think I'll just try one at random.
The girl can't sleep.
That I fix. Where's my sleeping pills?
In the little drawer.
Not sleeping is terrible.
Terrible.
Within half an hour. Boom. Like a rock.
Not 'Harry'.
Mary.
Never mind. Thank you.
Two sugars?
Baby.
Open your eyes wide.
Wider.
That's it. Now.
Now think.
Maybe you live in a hotel?
Some hotel?
Hotel.
Yes.
Now we're getting someplace. What hotel?
The coffee is getting cold.
- What's the name of the hotel?
The Waldorf? The Plaza?
St. Regis?
Is it one name or two?
The coffee gets cold.
- Quiet.
Coffee.
Yes. Here.
Drink this. This will do it.
You bet.
Now.
Is it coming to you?
Not so quick but in half an hour.
What hotel?
Say, that is quick.
Mama.
She's sleeping already.
I never saw anything so quick.
Maybe one sleeping pill
would have been enough.
Did you give her a sleeping pill?
- Two.
You mean to say ..
No charge. I was paid to do it.
[ Telephone ]
Hello?
We had an accident.
She passed out altogether.
That girl in Lower 6.
Listen. She can sleep it off at my
place but I want Jean to undress her.
Hurry over.
Jeanie. Get up.
What's the matter?
Get dressed.
What for?
Eddie wants you to
undress a girl for him.
Huh?
I thought a thousand-dollar reward
to whoever locates Her Highness ..
Might spur them on.
Make that two thousand.
- She's here. Her Highness is here.
Her Highness is here.
Thank you, commissioner.
Where have you been?
- I've been sleeping.
Where were you sleeping, Maria?
I took too many pills and the
plane turned and came back.
I found that out. Where did you sleep?
At the airport.
- At the airport?
That's impossible.
I went through the airport 20 times.
Where in the airport?
- In the ladies lounge.
The ladies lounge?
Thank you.
- Yes, sir.
I'm glad you are safe, Your Highness.
- Thank you.
Her Highness all night
in a ladies lounge.
Maria, sometimes I wonder
if you know your position.
I would like to take a bath.
- How do you feel?
I am alright.
- Maybe you have a cold coming on.
No, Uncle.
I remember drinking coffee.
But after that ..
I got undressed by myself.
But the birthmark.
I undressed myself.
What is that, dear?
Nothing, Uncle.
I thought you said something.
When I think of you all
night in that ladies lounge.
That airplane won't turn around
again without me knowing it.
I'll get reports on its progress every
hour until it reaches San Francisco.
I would rather not leave tonight, Uncle.
You might be right.
Get over that experience
in the ladies lounge.
I'll telephone the Harrisons.
How did he know about the birthmark?
What's that?
Nothing. Uncle.
I thought you said something.
I'm just going for a walk in the park.
- Yes, Your Highness.
I'll only be a moment. No reason
to tire yourself out following me.
Is there?
No, Your Highness.
- Sit down and read your paper.
Go on.
Goodbye, Your Highness.
Turn this corner.
Come on, turn the corner.
A wise guy. Just watch this.
I made a mistake.
I'll say you did.
Somebody was following you.
He was right behind us.
I don't know how he got away.
Don't you remember me?
Go on, peddle your papers.
You slept in my room last night.
Why, you ..
Oh no.
That is true. I did.
I didn't recognise him.
Excuse me, buddy.
I'm out of here.
- I am terribly sorry.
Can I help you?
Then this fellow got knocked down
again and she helped him up.
As near as I can make out she
met him someplace before.
Right now, they're both
having cherry cokes.
Cherry cokes?
What's that?
Don't let them out of your sight.
And keep calling me.
Yes, sir.
How does it feel now?
Fine. I don't feel anything.
I'm terribly sorry I
didn't recognise you.
It wasn't your fault.
Where did you learn to speak French?
How do you know I can?
You were speaking it last night.
- What did I say?
I don't know. I couldn't understand you.
You thought you were in Paris.
- I did?
Have you travelled in Europe a lot?
I was born there.
I came to this country only recently.
How do you speak English?
I had a very good education.
My family insisted I know languages.
I see.
Where are they now? Your family I mean.
They are still abroad.
I'm sorry.
I hope they are safe.
- They are in London now.
They lost everything I guess?
They lost a great deal.
What does your father do?
Do?
- For a living.
He had an income.
If you want me to change the
subject don't be ashamed to say so.
It might be better.
You poor kid.
What you must have gone through.
You are a stranger here.
I'll show you the town.
Would you like to see Grant's tomb?
You have heard of Grant?
He was a great civil war general
who later became president.
I've seen Grant's tomb.
You have?
That's funny. I haven't.
What's it like?
Very impressive. You'd like to see it?
- Okay.
Oh no.
I'm showing you the town.
- I wouldn't mind seeing it again.
You stayed over on my account.
You'll get more than a usual date.
I would much rather you
make this a 'usual date'.
If you worry about money,
I can afford it.
No. Do the same things you do when
you take out an ordinary girl.
I mean any girl.
Go to the same places
and act the same way.
You are sure?
- I am very sure.
I usually go out with two friends.
We can make it a foursome.
That would be nice.
Boy. Check.
Don't expect anything
out of the ordinary.
Eddie.
How do you do.
Remember me?
I gave you one sleeping pill.
Oh, yes.
That's my wife.
- How do you do.
How do you do.
- You met?
I guess you don't remember her.
Oh Eddie.
Tears.
I didn't get any of that. I'm the
husband. I get a kiss on the cheek.
They're going away to
the army to be fliers.
Jean, you knew it.
You went with us when we signed up.
I know. But I didn't think
they would take you.
I thought you might have some disease.
That's fine.
Would you want us not to go?
I got none of that.
Would you like to hug me a little
just so we don't seem conspicuous?
Well.
Get away from that girl.
- There you are. Equal rights.
Shall we go in?
You get dressed and we go someplace.
- I can't.
Why?
Today is for women's defense work.
- Can't you skip it for a day?
Are you crazy? She'd be court martialed
and shot. She's a general now.
A Major Lieutenant.
- There's no such thing.
There is in her army.
Everybody's something.
Mrs Mulvaney is a double Sergeant
General Colonel, 2nd Class.
Whipped cream with a cherry on it.
If you'd like help us a
little we can use you.
Then we spend the evening together.
- That's not right. It's no fun.
It would be fun for me.
Really it would. I'd like to do that.
All set. Let's play some handball.
You sure this suits you?
- I couldn't be having a better time.
You're easy to please.
Leave your things here.
We work in our basement.
That's a cute dame.
- No kidding.
I didn't think she would stay over.
- You didn't?
A pity she hasn't got more time.
Hitler will pay for that.
Have you ever seen Grant's tomb?
- No.
That is because we were born here.
Now I'd like to spend the next
two weeks sightseeing like a hick.
I'd like to spend some time with Jean.
She thought we'd stay home for two
weeks before joining the air force.
She had all kinds of plans
for both of us to be alone.
Then I had to break it to her that the
company wanted us to keep working.
I never want to see that
look on her face again.
She never cried. Nothing.
Until she got in the bathroom.
I heard her with the shower on.
Now that you are going, don't
you wish you'd never met Jean?
So you wouldn't feel this way?
Is that funny?
You worry how I feel leaving Jean.
I worry how you can go. Leaving nobody.
I wouldn't like to go if I didn't have
Jean waiting for me to come back.
Don't move the patient.
Don't ever, until you have
determined the nature of the injury.
If possible, the patient
should be kept warm.
Wrapped in blankets supplemented
by hot-water bottles.
Do you see why it bunches? Here, let me.
In an emergency, a telephone directory,
a magazine or even a rolled newspaper ..
Can be used as a splint for an arm.
A cravat folded handkerchief will do.
Tie the splint in place.
The new women.
This way please.
Mrs Mulvaney. Would it disturb
you if we play handball?
Of course not.
Your name?
- Anna.
Your second name?
- Pulaski.
Mrs Pulaski.
I am married.
Well?
You warm up. I'll be right up.
What would you like to do, Anna?
Well, maybe ..
I like to learn Red Cross.
Can you read?
No, ma'am.
It will be very hard, Anna.
There are some things you must study.
You tell me and I will learn.
You'd be useful doing what you know.
What do you think you can do best?
I can do everything.
I raised nine children.
I ought to know everything.
Anna, with nine children ..
I don't know if it's right for you
to take afternoons away from home.
But I haven't got nine
children at home now.
Only seven.
I have one boy in the army.
One boy in the navy.
And I have only seven at
home and I have lots of time.
Lots of time. The house is so empty.
Well, Anna.
The truth is we can use anyone
with her own sewing machine.
Sewing?
I am the best sewer you've ever seen.
You don't need anybody else.
Send them home.
Alright, Anna.
Miss Jeffreys will tell you what to do.
This way.
I thank you so much.
- Thank you, Mrs Pulaski.
Name please?
Mary Williams.
Can you run a sewing machine?
I am afraid I can't.
We need sewing.
Can you sew by hand?
I've never tried.
I've done petit point.
Petit point?
It may be a long war but ..
I don't think it will be that long.
Still, I'd like to see a soldier
in a petit point nightgown.
Let's see.
Can you cook?
No. I can't.
No sewing or cooking?
You are not a home girl.
Can you operate a typewriter?
No.
Are you a filing clerk?
I can go on guessing but
there is an easier way.
What can you do?
I can ..
Roll bandages.
I am sorry. We're all out of bandages.
Thank you anyway.
Would you step aside please?
Your name please?
- Clara Stillwell.
I can use a sewing machine.
But I think I'm a better cook.
Excuse me.
There must be something I can do.
Even if only for this afternoon.
I would appreciate it if you
would find some task for me.
That is the right spirit, Miss Williams.
Mrs Bower.
Yes?
You can use Miss Williams
here instead of the dummy.
Will you join them please.
Now, girls. Don't get excited
because we have a live dummy.
We must learn to keep our heads.
Would you lie down?
On your back.
There you are. That's fine.
Now, girls. Control yourselves.
I'm going to make this a
friendly little competition.
The left against the right.
Left leg, are you ready?
Right leg?
Left arm. Right arm.
Get ready.
Get set.
Go.
You are stopping the
circulation in the right arm.
The patient is getting no blood.
She is so anxious.
Later we are going to break your back.
What do you mean, she's being bandaged?
What's happened?
She is a dummy?
Who's a dummy?
Say, are you out of your mind?
There's nothing to worry about, sir.
Take my word for it.
Want to know something?
Children of people who used to be rich.
Have it pretty tough.
- What do I care?
Say.
You're on our handball court.
I understand. Thank you.
Patient, please.
Mr Connelli says we have to
get the truck back by tonight.
The truck is on the handball court.
Do you think two men could empty a
truckload of sand into sacks by tonight?
I am sure they could.
- No, no.
It's our day off.
I wonder where we could find two men.
You faint. I'll carry you off.
He's fainted. I'll take him to hospital.
This war stinks.
My back.
Know what you boys should do?
- What?
Take a nice steam bath.
Keeps you from getting stiff.
Thanks. You got one on you?
- Sure.
Next to the boiler room.
I make it myself.
Oh, brother.
Keep the awareness of
danger alive in your group.
Have frequent air raid rehearsals.
Practice blackouts.
Fight, fight the urge to relax.
Eternal vigilance, it has been
said by a better speech maker.
Is the price of liberty.
I'm sorry we had to stay as
late as we did today, but ..
We made our quota.
Tell that to your husbands.
Turn me over, will you.
I'm done on this side.
The way I look at it, the
rich have a responsibility.
To equip their children
for the practical world.
I don't want to go to heaven.
I like heat.
But Mrs Campbell, you've been having
two air raids a week here regularly.
That's the point. We've been having
them regularly. Everybody expects them.
After the last air raid, we had a
buffet supper for the whole building.
Right now.
Everybody is eating dinner.
This is the best time.
When they don't expect it.
Eternal vigilance is
the price of liberty.
I don't know.
- Mr. Mookle.
Are you with us in this war or not?
Have your air raid, ladies.
Money is alright.
I'm not saying anything against money.
Money will be glad to hear it.
But if you've been raised
in the lap of luxury.
Can you fit yourself ..
What is that?
- Someone is playing with the switch.
It might be a short.
- Let's get out of here.
Where's the door?
Follow me. I'm a regular cat.
Take my hand.
There ought to be another door here.
Here it is.
Feel around for your clothes.
How you doing?
- I got a table.
Let's sit on it.
The lights will be on in a minute.
Lights.
Dave's getting a stomach.
Who didn't have any clothes on?
It was all an accident, sir.
She has not been out
of my sight a moment.
Right now, they are in
a Chinese restaurant.
It is a very reputable place, sir.
I am sure the food is safe.
Yes, sir.
Mary, go on where you left off.
About your experiences in New York.
What happened after you
were fired as a waitress?
Well.
I didn't know where to turn.
How did you eat?
I didn't, very often.
I got weaker and weaker.
Finally, one day I was
walking in the street.
And everything turned
black and I fainted.
And when I woke up.
I was in the home of a kind old lady.
And she took an interest
in me and got a job ..
For me in San Francisco.
With her grandmother.
And that's where I'm going.
To get this job.
As an upstairs maid.
With the old lady's grandmother?
I mean, granddaughter.
The old lady is the grandmother.
And the other one, the younger
one, is the granddaughter.
Being an upstairs maid isn't easy work.
Well, anyway.
Let's not talk about me anymore.
Right. We're getting her depressed.
Let's talk about me.
What would you like to know about me?
Were you two ..
Childhood sweethearts at school?
We had a very romantic courtship.
She picked me up one night on a bus.
Are you going to start that again?
We were sitting next to each other
and she had to get off at 149th Street.
When she started to leave
her dress peculiarly enough ..
Caught on the button on my sleeve.
Get it?
Very funny.
- It just wouldn't come loose.
She had to get off so I, like
a gentleman, got off too.
When I opened my eyes ten days
later I was a cooked, married goose.
You only knew each other ten days?
She said it was ten days. I was drugged.
I haven't regretted it more
than half the time since.
You can still get out of it.
I'm getting used to you.
You sure look cute in that dress.
It was .. something like that. It had ..
It had. Say.
Isn't that the same dress?
Yes it is.
Why are you wearing it tonight?
Why do you think, you big lunk?
Stand up. There is no law
against married people dancing.
Would you care to dance?
I would love to.
You shouldn't be an upstairs maid.
I've friends in San Francisco.
When we get off the
plane I'll call them up.
You couldn't do that.
I'm not leaving on the plane.
Why not?
This old lady who's taken me in.
Besides, she and her granddaughter.
Are going on the train .. next week.
Then this will probably be
the last time I ever see you?
Yes it is.
It's a little crowded.
Isn't it.
What are you thinking?
Maybe if he had ten days.
Where the pomegranates used to grow.
Nothing fools anymore.
No-one smiles anymore.
When the China moon begins to glow.
No-one sings anymore.
No-one but a lonely little maid.
Trembling.
And yet somehow.
Unafraid.
Honorable moon.
Each night I sing a song of sorrow.
How soon before the new tomorrow?
When we'll come at them too, we'll be.
And to broken lullabies.
When will come an end.
To flaming dragons of a China ..
Sky.
Honorable moon.
Smile on my man where he is fighting.
Fighting through the endless
night to keep the good earth free.
And then.
When life is worth living.
Send him home.
Send him home to me.
May honorable day come soon.
Honorable moon.
I am not crying.
Your nose is shiny.
I'll meet you outside.
Check, please.
She is ..
She is very sentimental.
What do you think of her?
She's very good looking.
- I know.
Yeah. I mean, what do you think of her?
Her character?
To know a girl's character you got
to go with her a couple of years.
You only knew Jean for ten days.
- I took a chance.
They say you never really know
a girl at all until you marry her.
That's only a saying.
I've got a funny hunch about something.
What with you being a refugee
and Eddie going away to war.
Having two rum drinks in him
which will give him nerves.
I think he's going to
ask you to marry him.
What do you think?
I think he might.
- He's quite a guy.
I'm sure he's quite a guy.
On the other hand,
don't get your hopes up.
He may not.
Will you answer me something truthfully?
Do you wish he would ask me?
Yes.
Thank you.
But.
I know more about you than he does.
- What do you mean?
Girlie, I put you to bed last night.
Oh.
You did?
It's a nice night.
Would you like to walk a while?
Alright.
I'm sure you want us
to keep you company.
Madame.
If I don't see you again
it will be your own fault.
Thank you .. for everything.
Goodbye.
Don't keep him out late.
If he falls asleep at the
controls I fall just as far.
Goodbye.
You're not tired or anything?
No. I feel like walking.
You won't get into any
trouble staying out this late?
That old lady won't be angry?
No.
It's hot.
Forget about San Francisco.
We are going to get married.
Excuse me.
Would you marry me?
I can't marry you.
Why can't you?
I can't.
Come here.
Now listen.
I never before asked a girl to marry me.
I swear it.
- I believe you.
You like me, don't you?
- Yes. I do.
That's enough to start on. People never
know each other until they are married.
We can have dates for a year
and not know each other.
That may be.
- Give me a chance.
This war won't go on forever. I don't
know if I'll be able to find you later.
I promised the company
I'd work another two weeks.
After that, I still have five days
before I'm in the air force.
We'll have those five days together.
Then I'll have some leaves
and we can be together then.
When we're separated
we'll write each other.
The most important thing
of all is someday ..
I'll be back.
I want you waiting for me.
No. I can't.
I want to go home.
- I know it's sudden. It is for me too.
I'll tell you everything about me.
I am conservative. I don't drink.
I have $1,200 in the bank.
We'll get a little apartment.
- Please don't go on.
Is it on account of your parents?
In a way.
I can support your parents.
Now, honey.
Thank you for asking me to marry you.
I will remember it.
For the rest of my life.
Look. I don't know what's inside that
head of yours but we're getting married.
I won't leave you until it's settled.
You're marrying me. You hear me?
You are marrying me.
I want to hear you say
you want to marry me.
Go on, say it.
Say it.
I want to marry you.
You'll never be sorry.
Now, there's some things
we have to arrange.
I'll be back the day after tomorrow.
Where can I call you?
Let me call you. It will be
easier because of the old lady.
Okay.
Here is the number.
I get in at eight in the morning.
I'll be by the phone at 8:20 waiting.
What number?
Let me get out here.
The old lady might be
waiting in front of the house.
Okay, honey.
I'll be waiting for your call.
I'll call you.
Goodnight.
Can I come in?
- Yes. Certainly.
Hope I didn't wake you up.
- No.
I got something to tell you.
No.
Eddie.
- Congratulations.
You know what I want to say?
How'd she do it?
Her dress catch your sleeve?
I had a hard time convincing her.
- That's the way they do it.
You chase them until they catch you.
I thought maybe you'd help me, Jean.
I haven't much time.
- Sure. What do you want me to do?
I want you to pick out an engagement
ring for me. And a marriage ring.
You think she needs an engagement ring?
Yes.
Nothing fancy.
About a hundred dollars.
That's alright?
It won't be vulgar.
You know girls.
That's important to them.
I must have a place for her to live too.
Mine is kinda ..
There's a lovely apartment in this
building and it's leased furnished.
Really?
The only thing is, the people are
taking their icebox with them.
And you just can't get an icebox.
What good is a place with no icebox?
She must have an icebox.
Take it easy.
It's ridiculous.
She can't be without an icebox.
I'll look around tomorrow.
Maybe I can find one.
Please do. She can't live
without an icebox.
Holy mackerel. Go home. You're making
me nervous. Jean will do everything.
I am not nervous.
I might be a little excited but ..
Not nervous.
You thought I was going
to walk into the closet.
That's too old.
Well.
Goodnight.
- Night.
You're not nervous.
Goodnight.
Of course, it's incomplete.
We've not had much time.
But so far.
'Edward J. O'Rourke'.
'Born November 7th, 1914
in Brooklyn, New York'.
'Attended public school, high school
and worked his way through college'.
'Had measles, mumps and other
usual childhood illnesses'.
'Employed in his present position as
commercial pilot for four years'.
'Considered by his company as
sober, industrious and dependable'.
'Enlisted in the US Army
Air Force. Accepted'.
'Due for induction late this month'.
His family.
'One of nine boys. All living'.
- Nine boys?
Yes, sir. His father is
one of eleven boys.
Eleven? All boys?
- Yes, sir.
Extraordinary.
Yes, sir. But it happens.
Shall I go on?
Proceed.
'Played second base for his
high school baseball team'.
'Had 3 stitches in his head after diving
in the shallow side of swimming pool'.
When he was twelve.
And.
He has all his teeth.
We'll have more detailed
information later today.
Call the state department. Say I want
to speak with His Majesty in London.
Yes, sir.
Thank you, gentlemen.
- Thank you, sir.
I hope it's nothing serious.
Hello.
This is Mary.
I didn't want to wait until
tomorrow to call you.
I was thinking about you, Mary. All day.
Come on. Hurry that call.
I want you to know I will always
remember you asking me to marry you.
Always.
Honey, you're sweet to call
but I'm in kind-of a hurry.
Kind of a hurry?
Listen.
I can't listen. Please look for
an icebox. That's all we need.
Hang up that phone.
- Goodbye, honey.
It had to happen, Your Majesty.
With a girl her age
you only have to wait.
A boy will get to her
like a bee to honey.
I'm sure it's the right thing.
After all, the major purpose
of a royal marriage ..
Is to cement relations
between two countries.
He is American.
A country we are certainly
eager to cement with.
And they have no royal family.
I've known for thirty years
we would come to this.
Frankly, I was hoping for one
of the sons of the president.
But my feeling now is ..
It is even cleverer for Maria
to marry a simple commoner.
His family?
Your Majesty, it is extraordinary.
This young man is a
veritable goldmine of boys.
His family doesn't seem to
give birth to anything else.
Between us, sir.
The nobility bloodlines in
Europe are getting rather thin.
Everybody is bleeding.
Thank you for your
confidence, Your Majesty.
Hello?
Honey, don't tell me
you've got an icebox.
I want you to know.
I will always remember you
asking me to marry you.
That's fine. You didn't have to call me
long-distance. Sweet of you anyway.
I have to run, dear. See you tomorrow.
No, no. You won't see me tomorrow.
You will never see me again.
I only promised to call you
so you'd let me go last night.
Listen, honey.
If this is a feminine reaction to the
way I asked you, you must overlook it.
I love you. That's all to think about.
- Are you going to hang up?
No. You don't love me.
You pitied me because I'm a homeless
refugee and have to be an upstairs maid.
That is all. You will forget about me.
But I want you to know I'll always
remember you asking me to marry you.
It was the proudest moment.
Stop repeating that. Honey, I want
you waiting for me when I come in.
Give me that phone.
- Listen. I say yes.
I want you waiting at the airport.
Hello, hello.
Get in that plane, O'Rourke.
Did she give you any reason?
No.
I tell you, something has happened.
She loves me. I know she does.
That may sound funny
after one day, but ..
I tell you, last night that
girl was in love with me.
I could not be wrong.
Maybe she'll call you
at the next airport.
Maybe.
Go on.
Fly away.
It won't, Maria.
It's been caged for so many generations.
It has adapted itself to confinement.
Luckily, it doesn't know
of the joys of wild birds.
Therefore it doesn't realise
it's missing anything.
Yes.
Not knowing is better.
Maria, we must discuss something to
which I've given a good deal of thought.
Your marriage.
Please, Uncle. Not now.
- Will only take a minute.
In view of the disturbed
world conditions.
And the greater need for
advantageous alliances.
Do you think it would be ridiculous
for you to marry an American boy?
I'd like to have your opinion.
Mine?
There may be a lot in what you say.
Sometimes I think it's a good idea.
Sometimes I don't.
It's awfully clever.
Politically, I mean.
- Politically, eh?
Awfully clever.
It still couldn't be just anyone.
No.
Once we make up our minds on an
American boy. And we haven't yet.
No.
It would have to conform
to a certain pattern.
Yes.
An ordinary American boy who
works for a living is best.
Don't you think?
- That would be best.
He needs to have a job
somewhat romantic and dashing.
It will sit better with the public.
Yes. It can sit better.
For instance, if he were a
dentist it wouldn't do at all.
No. It wouldn't.
Nothing wrong with a dentist.
It's a necessary vocation.
It is.
The world would be
uncomfortable without them.
But it is too prosaic.
It's terribly prosaic.
On the other hand,
aren't we being hasty?
A dentist might be just the right
prosaic note that people would like.
I don't think a dentist is a good idea.
You don't?
- No. A dentist is too ..
You are right.
I wonder what would be ideal.
A lawyer?
No. A lawyer is too ..
Maybe you're right.
A schoolteacher?
- No.
Too ..
Yes.
Let me see.
An airplane pilot? No.
- Yes. Oh yes.
I think an airplane pilot might be.
You do?
I do, Uncle. I do.
The moment you said it, it
just seemed to strike me.
Well, that's a good sign.
I wonder what his name ought to be.
His name?
- Yes.
Some names are more
appealing than others.
You'll decide what his name must be and
then look for a pilot with that name?
Why not?
- That's impossible.
No it isn't.
Let me see. What name sounds appealing?
How does Edward O'Rourke sound to you?
Uncle, it is absolutely
impossible to expect ..
What seems to be the trouble?
Uncle, sometimes you frighten me.
I couldn't have picked a
better husband myself, Maria.
Do you know he's one of nine boys
and his father is one of eleven?
We expect great things of you two.
You mean, I can actually marry him?
I am allowed to?
- Indeed you can.
I am not going to cry now.
I want to speak to Mr Washburn
in the US State Department.
Yes, sir.
You left the cage open.
Maybe she'll call you at home.
She has your number.
Hello?
Yep.
Honey, listen to me.
I want you .. Hello?
Jean?
It's Jean.
She's found an icebox.
That's fine.
Jean, something has happened.
I have to talk to her.
I don't know where she lives.
Go to the company's accounts department.
And see if they'll give you the address
of the old lady who paid for her ticket.
She may have paid by check.
If she did, they'll have her address.
Will you do that, Jean?
Thanks.
She'll get it. You know Jean.
She's a regular detective.
Hello?
Yep.
Hello Mary?
Please meet me tomorrow and
at least let me talk to you.
If you want me too.
Where shall I meet you?
Any place you say. Would ..
Would Jean's apartment be alright?
Tomorrow morning?
You know where it is? You're sure?
Alright, Mary. I'll be waiting for you.
Goodbye, Mary.
That's something.
He is so considerate.
Did I tell you he is one of nine boys?
He isn't only considerate.
He is so sincere.
His father is one of eleven boys.
You know what this is?
The Cinderella story.
Only the boy is Cinderella.
It's just turned about.
A rich princess and a poor boy.
He isn't penniless.
He has $1,200.
He has, eh?
That will come in handy.
I know very few women in
our family married well.
Only for love.
I certainly never counted on it.
I never would even let
myself think about it.
Not since I was a little girl.
One of nine boys.
Extraordinary.
I'm not entitled to be this happy.
His father one of eleven.
Remarkable.
Hello baby.
I thought I'd welcome you.
- That's what I like.
Hi Eddie.
Jean, we'd better hurry.
Mary's meeting me at your place.
She is?
Are you sure?
She called right after you did.
What is the matter?
Nothing.
Come on, Jean.
You're sure you want to hear?
If it's about her I want to hear it.
Her ticket wasn't paid for by a woman
but by a man. A middle-aged man.
She lives at the St. Charles in
a private apartment in the hotel.
The apartment is registered in his name.
She wouldn't marry me.
I give her credit for that.
I respect her for it.
A poor homeless refugee.
Who knows what she went through?
If she confesses, I'll forgive her.
Gladly.
I only ask her to tell me the truth
and that's all I'm entitled to.
Who am I to ..
Come on.
Hello Mary. Won't you come in?
Hello Mary.
Hello Jean.
Dave.
Hello Eddie.
Hello Mary.
We must be going. Excuse us.
We have to see a fellow. You see ..
- Come on, dear.
Won't you ..
Sit down?
It was nice of you to come here.
- Nice of you to insist I come.
Before you go any further,
there's something I'd better tell you.
What?
I have changed my mind again.
I will marry you.
You will?
Unless you've changed your mind?
You needn't be ashamed to say.
No, no.
Do you still want to marry me?
Yes. Certainly.
I couldn't understand why you
changed your mind before.
Then I imagine you ..
Have your reasons.
Aren't you going to kiss me?
Of course.
Don't you feel well?
I feel fine.
Now.
One more thing.
I can't accept your offer of marriage.
Until you know something about
that you don't even suspect.
I haven't told you the
truth about myself.
You don't have to tell me a thing.
But I do.
- But you don't.
I want you to come with me to
the St. Charles Hotel. Please.
Can't you tell me here?
- It's better if you come to the hotel.
Mary, I want you to know ..
You will never regret this.
Come, dear.
Hold my hand.
Mr O'Rourke - Mr Holman.
Mr Washburn.
- How do you do.
How do you do.
This is the man I am going to marry.
Any objections?
No.
I guess this is a surprise to you.
Mr O'Rourke, would you care
to step into the next room?
Gladly.
If he makes a move to you, holler.
I hope he tells it to
him diplomatically.
Mr Washburn is a member of the
United States state department.
He will be diplomatic.
I hope he doesn't faint.
[ Crashing noise ]
I just bumped into a small table.
I could not be happier.
I think I hear them, father.
He is coming out now.
One minute, father.
My father would like to speak to you.
Your father?
He is in London.
Call him 'Your Majesty'.
Hello.
Hello?
Hello Your Majesty.
Thank you.
I saw you in the newsreel.
Yes, sir.
I heard a click.
The three minutes were up.
Hello, hello.
I guess you're not working tomorrow.
No. Mr Washburn of the state
department fixed it with the company.
He's got a lot of pull.
What about the air force?
- He fixed that too.
He says I'm going to
do something important.
You'll probably be a general.
What shall I do about the icebox?
I don't think you'll need it.
Maybe you can sell it.
Don't you think I should at least
take the engagement ring back?
It isn't a very big diamond, is it?
I can get the money back.
No. I ought to give her something.
She ought to be here any minute.
What does a Prince Consort do?
I don't know yet, but that's
what he told me I would be.
Mr Washburn says I am doing a
wonderful thing for morale.
He is representing me.
Hello.
I guess this is quite a surprise.
Yes it is, Your Highness.
He was surprised too.
Yes I was, Your Highness. I mean ..
Young man.
You've just been invited
to the White House.
White House?
I kept it for you.
I hope that was alright.
Yes. Fine.
Mr and Mrs Campbell - Mr Holman.
Mr Washburn.
- How do you do.
I imagine you never expected to
sleep in the White House, young man.
No, sir.
It's very considerate of
the president to do that.
The president probably
wants to look him over.
I think we have to be going.
Yeah. We have to go.
I'll see you to the door.
Goodbye. Glad to have met you.
Likewise.
- Goodbye.
Goodbye.
I'll be right back.
I'm only going to the door.
So long, Eddie.
Lots of luck.
When will I see you again?
- Maybe when you come back.
I doubt I can call you 'Eddie' though.
Probably: 'Your Highness'.
No. I will only be a prince.
Goodbye, Eddie.
Bye, Jean.
Bye, Dave.
- So long, kid.
Take care of yourself.
Prince.
Here, Prince.
The Duke?
Your Grace.
- The Baron.
Your Lordship.
- The Baronet.
Your ..
Excellency?
- 'Sir'. Plain Sir.
Sorry.
- It will come.
In a few months everyone will think
you were born to the purple.
Purple what?
- Just purple.
It's a saying.
Why can't I see Mary .. Maria ..
Her Highness?
Her uncle expects you to see
little of her until the ceremony.
It is customary.
Will he have much to say
after we are married?
Royalty is very strict
about age and precedence.
I don't think that's such a terrible
price to pay for $150,000 a year.
That's your allowance.
Besides your normal living expenses.
It is customary.
A lot of things seem to be customary.
You're unhappy because you're marrying
a beautiful girl who's also a princess?
No, sir. I am very happy.
Who wouldn't be?
Let's use this time profitably.
In a group which contains people
outside the immediate family.
You're not to leave the room
until dismissed by Her Highness.
You merely look at her questioningly.
Her permission will be given by a nod.
Shall we practice that?
Mr Washburn.
- Yes?
What does a Prince Consort do?
I mean all day.
Well, there are many social functions
you will be obliged to attend.
Flower shows. Horse shows.
Things like that.
You said I'd have something important
to do once I'm out of the air force.
So you have.
Your position in the royal
family is most important.
You are to have children.
If possible, boys.
That is not a full day's work.
What else do I do?
Nothing else.
Nothing?
- Nothing.
Where did we leave off?
For permission to leave the room,
you look at Her Highness questioningly.
Try that.
No.
I'll race you.
[ Dog yapping ]
That's a good dog.
I know him.
I'll show you everything.
One room at a time.
That is the president's study.
Next to it is his bedroom.
Is he in there now?
No. He's at the office.
He won't be home until late.
This is my room. Come.
This is called The Lincoln room.
That was his bed.
The emancipation proclamation
was signed here.
That freed the slaves, you know.
You aren't very comfortable, are you?
I've never been here before.
- I mean with me.
Why.
Yes I am.
Don't mind when they tell you how to act
with me. That's only in front of others.
When we're together we act as we please.
I'll get used to it.
It's a little new yet. That's all.
Nothing has changed, has it?
Changed?
- Since two days ago.
No it hasn't, Mary.
Maria.
When we're alone, don't
you ever call me Maria.
Maria.
The usher will show you to your room.
Please manage not to be alone with
Her Highness unless you're chaperoned.
It is customary.
Yes, sir.
[ Door knocks ]
Come in.
Hello young man.
- Hello, Mr Washburn.
We are waiting for you.
Excuse me.
I was looking out the window.
I guess I forgot myself.
You are feeling well, aren't you?
- Yes, sir.
You hardly touched your dinner.
I was not hungry.
Is the president there?
- No. The president is still working.
Unfortunately for him, there's no
such thing as a President's Union.
Sit there please.
Is that alright?
- It's perfectly alright.
This is as good a time
as any to get this done.
These are the premarital agreements
between you and Her Highness.
They are to be included in the marriage
contract and they are customary.
You could read them yourself,
which would take all night.
Or you can let me
explain what's in them.
I guess you had better explain them.
The first is your marriage license.
The district of Columbia was willing to
waive the waiting period of three days.
We thank them.
The second is your agreement to give up
any right to a succession to the throne.
Since you are not of royal birth.
Even though the male heirs who
now outrank you should die.
The succession will skip you and
pass to the next heir of royal birth.
That is customary for a prince consort.
Is that alright?
That's alright.
In the next, you give up the right to
the physical possession of the children.
You understand that?
Not exactly.
What it means is, the manner of their
education is left to the royal family.
Okay.
The next is merely you giving
up your American citizenship.
What's that?
You give up your American citizenship.
That did it.
Why?
It's customary in our family.
It's not customary in my family.
Your family?
Yes. I've got a family.
I didn't grow on a bush.
I don't like your tone, young man.
I can't help that.
You will apologise and immediately.
Or?
Or there will be no marriage.
I was just coming to that.
What's that?
I'm not marrying Her Highness.
Not marrying Her Highness?
Let's not be hasty.
We must discuss this alone.
No. It's better this way.
I'm not giving up any
American citizenship.
I've never gotten over how lucky I was
to be born here in the first place.
And I didn't ask any
Highness to get married.
I asked a girl I thought was a homeless
refugee who was getting a job as a maid.
I thought other things about her too.
You'd be surprised what I thought.
- The man is demented.
I can't take an allowance from my wife
or ask her permission to leave a room.
But that is not important.
What will I say to my kid when he
asks me what I did in the war?
Know what I'd have to say?
Son.
There was a big fight.
The biggest fight the world was ever in.
The most important.
But I couldn't make it.
I was at a flower show.
I'd be ashamed of myself.
I thought you were ashamed when you told
the women you can't sew or knit or cook.
But you could learn something.
Even knitting a sweater helps.
And if it's knit badly.
I'll wear it just the same.
You knit and I'll fly an aeroplane.
What do you say, Mary?
Don't dignify him with an answer.
I wish you'd marry me.
- You heard me, Maria.
I'm crazy about you, Mary.
He can't do a thing after we're married.
We'll have a lot of fun.
We love each other.
Our family goes back 1,200 years.
Mine goes back to Adam and Eve.
Your child will be Alfred the 8th.
We'll start over with Eddie the 1st.
- Maria.
Don't say one word.
Isn't she allowed to talk?
Maria. Go to your room.
Remember who you are.
You are a royal princess.
Go to your room.
A royal princess.
You are nothing but a slave.
Get out.
Goodbye, Mr Washburn.
Thank you for everything.
- Goodbye, Mr O'Rourke.
Hey, buddy.
You've been walking around
here quite a while.
That's alright, isn't it?
- There is no law against it.
What's your business here?
I got no business here.
I'm just walking.
Are you broke?
As a matter of fact, I doubt
I've enough to get a hotel.
Wouldn't make a difference if you had.
You can't get a room in Washington now.
I'll stake you to half a
buck if you're hungry.
No thanks. I've enough to eat on.
And I know where I can sleep.
Excuse me.
What are you doing here?
I was invited here.
That's what I'm doing here.
I've got as much right
here as you have. More.
Shush.
Goodnight, Maria.
I didn't have ..
I didn't have any place else to sleep.
Was the president angry when
he found out what I did?
No. But he is very fond of Maria.
So, of course he was
a little disappointed.
If he wants me to marry her.
If it's for morale or something.
I'll go through with it.
In my country we can ask a man to charge
a machine gun with his bare hands.
But we can't ask him to marry
a girl he won't be happy with.
It's too much.
Also, it's probably democracy.
I thought for a minute she
was going to marry me.
So did I, son.
But she's a grown girl.
Nobody can help her but herself.
Goodnight.
Goodnight, Mr Washburn.
That's what I am: a slave.
A slave.
Lincoln freed the slaves
but he didn't free me.
This is his bed.
You'd think he'd come into this room.
Lincoln?
Shush.
Isn't the president
supposed to free slaves?
Take it, Fala.
Go ahead. Take it.
Please Fala.
Go on, Fala.
Go on.
Go to him, Fala. Go on.
The president is up.
Yes, sir?
Shush.
I brought along a guard in
case we're short of a witness.
Fine.
Take your shoes off.
Her uncle is a very light sleeper.
Come on. Get 'em off.
Take your shoes off.
Will you marry your refugee?
Will I?
Shush. For heaven's sake.
Go into the study, everybody.
Take off your shoes.
Let's hurry this. My feet are cold.
Let's talk lower.
Or we may start a brand-new war.
You got everything?
- Is there a marriage license?
Right here.
You two are witnesses.
That's all we need.
Where is that boy?
- Come on, son.
Have you got a ring?
Yes, sir.
It's on my keychain.
- Hurry up.
Just a minute please.
I'd like to give you
this engagement ring first.
For heaven's sake.
The diamond is small.
But my love for you is not.
It's a beautiful diamond.
Excuse me, folks. But my feet are cold.
You can talk like that later. Go ahead.
Take this man to be your wedded husband?
- I do.
Take this woman to be your wedded wife?
By powers invested in me I now
pronounce you man and wife.
Put the ring on. Get me my shoes.
Say, is that all?
I don't think that is legal.
He's a supreme court judge.
If he can't make a marriage legal,
everyone in America is Ipso Facto.
Will you get out of here?
Come, dear.
I don't know if I have enough money.
- For heaven's sake.
Excuse me.
It was wonderful of them to do that.
But I am worried.
- Why?
I know the supreme court
judge can't get in trouble.
He has a life job. They can't fire him.
Mr Washburn is a big man in the
state department. He is alright.
But that guard.
Who was watching. Who I bumped into.
He may get into trouble.
That wasn't any guard you bumped into.
That was the President.
The President?
Holy mackerel. I tipped him a buck.
And he took it.
Come.
..w-g..