"Flash, the freighter,
Star of Capetown,
"was sunk today off the north coast
of Africa by a mysterious explosion.
"All hands accounted for
"with the exception
of two unidentified stowaways."
Look at us.
Two on a raft, sunny-side up.
"I'll tell you how to get home," you said.
"We'll stow away," you said.
"No, sir," I said. "Don't be a
sap," you said. "No, sir," I said.
"We're stowing away,
and that's that," you said.
"No, sir," I said.
Yak, yak, yak, yak,
yak, yak, yak, yak.
What a brilliant
conversationalist you are!
I took one look at that crate and
knew it would blow up in our faces.
Wait till they find out who was
smokin' in the powder room.
Never mind that now.
Look at us.
Food gone, water gone.
Hey! What's that bulge
in your pocket?
Oh, that's...
Yeah, that.
That there.
It's just an old
tobacco pouch. It's...
Tobacco pouch? When did
you start smokin' a pipe?
I... Ever since this morning. Cigarettes
make me nervous. Oh, this morning?
You just went down to the store and got
yourself a meerschaum and some tobacco?
Yes, I did.
You notice...
That's clever. Come on, come on.
Dig, dig.
Hand it over here. Let's see.
Come on, reach.
Oh! I forgot.
Surprised, huh?
I figure two of 'em
for one of us is better
than one of 'em for two of us.
Yeah.
Here, you can spit
your teeth in there.
Just dunk it lightly.
Well, Junior, we gotta face it.
We may be days, and days, and days,
without seeing a ship or land.
We're gonna get hungry,
mighty hungry.
What do you mean "get hungry"?
We'll toss a coin.
What's the date?
Hea...
1910!
Pretty close.
1911.
Well, that's the way it goes.
Somebody loses, somebody wins.
Okay, so you win the nickel! See if you
can find any white meat on that buffalo.
I got a TL for you. We tossed for
something much deeper than that.
I remember a story once
about two fellows like us.
Castaways.
They tossed a coin, too.
They figured there's no use
both of them starving.
Well, naturally.
The fellow who survived used to tell his
grandchildren about his pal's sacrifice.
Hey, that's very...
Wait a minute.
What pal's sacrifice?
I don't know, though.
You should've eaten more
oatmeal when you were a kid.
You're kind of scrawny.
No firmness there.
I don't think you'd do me more than a
week, and there's no icebox aboard.
Jeff, Jeff, you're losing
your buttons.
You mean, you'd eat me,
without vegetables?
Calm down, now.
Calm down, Junior.
I'm not gonna
do anything right away.
I might not do anything for a week or so.
Not until I get desperate.
Oh, Jeff!
You wouldn't like me. Once I bit
my tongue and I tasted awful.
Help!
Jeff, don't...
Turkey, look!
Look, am I seeing things?
What?
Look here.
What is that over there?
Land! Land!
We're saved!
Hey! Hey!
A submarine!
Man the pumps!
Last stop!
Got a stone in my shoe.
Hey, wait a minute!
A fine pal. All I hope is that Aunt
Lucy's lookin' down from above
and seein' the way
you're treating me lately.
You gonna start stuffing that
Aunt Lucy down my throat again?
Yeah, well, never mind.
She saw you tossin'
that coin and lickin' your chops.
You're certainly sloughing off
your promise to her.
Aunt Lucy. I can see her
now lying on her dying bed
lookin' at you with those big,
trusting eyes.
"Before I go, Jeff, promise
me one thing," she said.
"Promise me you'll always be a
friend to little Orville," she said.
"No matter what happens, you'll never
leave the little jerk," she said.
"Promise me, Jeff.
Promise me," she said.
Yeah, then she up and died
before I had a chance to say no.
Who you shushing?
What's the matter?
I hope she didn't hear. The dead
have a way of comin' back, you know.
Get out. When they're
dead, they're dead.
Not Aunt Lucy.
She was a Republican.
Okay, Junior, I'm sorry.
I guess I shouldn't have said that.
All right.
You know how I feel about you.
I guess in my own way
I sort of love you.
All right, but you don't
have to slobber all over me.
I guess I kind of love you, too.
Yeah. Now wait a minute, Junior.
Stop kissing me.
What are you talkin' about?
I didn't...
You did, too!
Look, are you crazy?
I don't mind being kissed,
but this is ridiculous.
There, you did it again.
I did not.
You didn't?
No.
Well, I felt something.
Something like a wet paint brush.
You did?
I did, too.
I thought it was you.
And I thought it was you.
You see!
Aunt Lucy's come back.
You did it with all that
disrespectful talk. Aunt Lucy!
What's that?
What?
What's the matter?
You yellow?
It's only a kangaroo.
Yeah.
What're you gettin' scared for?
Let's take a ride.
This is probably...
Good girl.
You think we got enough gas?
I got her carburetor
cut down to nothin'.
Where do you suppose we are?
This must be the place where they
empty all the old hourglasses.
I think this is what's left
after I clean my spinach.
Hey, look!
Could've thought of another
way to get us here.
Here we go again, Junior.
♪ We're off
on the road to Morocco
♪ This taxi
is tough on the spine
Beats the bus, huh, Junior?
Oh, beats me.
♪ Where we're goin'?
♪ Why we're goin'?
♪ How can we be sure?
♪ I'll lay you 8-5 that
we meet Dorothy I amour
♪ Off on the road to Morocco
♪ Hang on till
the end of the line
♪ I hear this country's
where they do
♪ The dance of the seven veils
♪ We'd tell you more
but we would have Shh!
♪ The censor on our tails
♪ We certainly do get around
♪ Like Webster's Dictionary
♪ We're Morocco bound
♪ We're off on the road
to Morocco
Look out!
Well, clear the way!
'Cause here we come.
♪ The men eat fire,
sleep on nails
♪ And saw their wives in half
♪ It seems to me there should
be easier ways to get a laugh
♪ We're off on the road
to Morocco
♪ And somewhere
I feel kind of numb
♪ For any villains we may
meet we haven't any fear
♪ Paramount will protect us 'cause
we're signed for five more years
♪ We certainly do get around
Like a complete set
of Shakespeare
that you buy in the corner
drugstore for $1.98.
♪ We're Morocco bound
Or like a volume of Omar Khayyam
that you buy at a department
store at Christmastime
for your cousin Julia.
♪ We're Morocco bound
Wonder if you can get a handout
in this burg? Boy, I'm starved.
If that guy wasn't lookin',
I'd eat a rug.
Plain?
Orville, where are you?
Right over here, behind
these goose pimples.
Reckon there's been some sort of shootin'
ruckus down at the Buckeye Saloon, huh?
Hey, I ain't lookin'
for trouble, partner,
but if trouble comes lookin' for me,
I'm gonna be mighty hard to find.
Say, fuzzy...
Huh?
Who is that headstrong,
impetuous boy?
He is Mullay Kasim,
the desert sheik.
What'd he come to town for?
A manicure?
He loves the Princess
Shalmar of Karameesh.
He has come here
to ask her to marry him.
I'd hate to be around
when he comes for a divorce!
You short of blades?
It's a strange country, buster.
It's a strange country.
Yeah.
Well, not too strange.
It's food we're after.
That's what I say, food. Yes.
Remember?
Food.
No, thanks,
we ate four days ago.
I wish I had
my drool cup with me.
Allah be praised. Allah be praised.
Allah be praised.
What is this? Free cold cuts!
Everything on the house.
Well, what are we waiting for?
Shangri-La.
Allah be praised, brother.
We'll get loaded.
This is living!
Hey, what's the idea? The other
fellow did it. Why can't he?
Allah has seen fit to dim
the light of his wisdom.
To us, such unfortunate ones
are sacred.
Well, I don't think that's...
Shh!
Hey, what's the matter?
What are you doing?
What are you lookin'
at me like that for?
Turkey, from now on,
you're sacred.
What do you mean, sacred?
You just became a
full-blooded American idiot.
No, you do it. Who's gonna
believe I'm an idiot?
Well, will you look at
the head start you got?
Now, all you gotta do is
go into a shop, put on that
silly look, and talk like this.
Now watch.
I'll take some of those, some
of these and some of those.
Let me have that slow.
Like this.
I'll take some of these,
and give me a few
of them there...
You feel all right, daddy?
Let me hear you do it now,
come on.
I'll take some of those,
and some of those over there.
That's great. That's great.
That's wonderful.
The first shop we go into,
the guy'll load us up and throw
in his daughter. Come on.
His daughter?
Yes.
I'll take some of those
and some of those, too.
Don't over-train.
Save it.
Give me some of those over there
and you want some, too? Okay.
What can I do for you,
gentlemen?
Go, ahead.
Tell him, Junior.
I want some of those
and some of those
and some of those...
Hey! Are you making fun of me?
Oh, no, I always talk like this.
Oh, you do, huh?
Well, why do you?
Oh, because I can't help it.
I'm an idiot. I'm sacred.
So you're saying
I'm an idiot, too?
Oh, if you think you're an idiot
I'm not gonna argue with you...
What's that?
Okay, I'll take some of those,
and some of those,
and some of those...
Well, what do you think of that?
How do you like that?
Jeff, Jeff!
Mother told me there'd be
moments like this.
I wonder how she knew.
Hey, Turkey.
Where've you been?
I've been lookin'
everywhere for you.
Do it some more.
What's the matter with you?
Kiss it again.
What'd the guy hit you with?
A piano?
Hey, come on.
Snap out of it. Hey!
It's a strange country.
A minute ago she came
along in a gold box,
fellows carrying it with sticks.
She took my hand, kissed my
fingertips, my knuckles, my wrist.
My toes are still braided. Oh, it
was wonderful. Do it some more.
Hey, hey. Come on, now.
You're delirious.
You need something
in your stomach.
Come on, boy.
You'll be all right.
Here we go.
Hey, how do you figure
on paying for all this?
What? Are you scared?
You got red blood, ain't you?
Yeah, but I don't
wanna get it all over strangers.
Go ahead. Eat up. Eat up, son.
I'll think of something.
These guys don't monkey around.
They got knives.
They're liable to try and get
the food back the hard way.
You have already eaten
to the amount of 230 kolacs.
You have money to pay, yes?
Yeah. Yeah, we'll pay.
But we're still eating.
Put it on separate checks, too.
Oh, and bring us a couple of more
portions of those jellied-turtle eggs.
Yes, and the turtle
that laid them.
Bring her in.
And don't be afraid to spread a
lot of pixie dust, double layer.
You have already
eaten six portions.
Well, can we help it
if we're turtle-egg fiends?
First chance we get, we better
dash for the nearest exit.
Yeah, but how about
that guy's knife?
We're gonna look silly stumbling
out of here on a set of stumps.
Have a nut burger
and forget about it.
I can hardly wait
for the dessert.
What are we having?
Say, what do you usually tip?
Ten percent?
Let's not spoil him.
Go ahead, buster.
Blubber wants to talk to you.
I think I better...
I'd better go, huh?
If he gets tough,
don't worry about a thing,
I'll be right here
under the table.
Buy a rug for me.
Garcon!
Who is that?
The local bookmaker?
Here's 287 kolacs for the
little snack and five for you.
Get yourself a facial, huh?
Well, come, come. Let little
Orville in on this deal.
How'd you get the spinach,
old boy?
There's a funny thing. A guy I've
never seen before in my life
gives me 2,500 kolacs. That's 200
federal diplomas. Are you listening?
Two hundred skins?
Why, what for?
I sold him something.
Well, you've got
nothing to sell.
We've already
hocked your pivot tooth.
Well, it wasn't much
but it was all I had,
and was he anxious to get it.
What did you sell him?
Look, Orville,
I want you to keep very calm now.
And don't get excited.
What did you sell him?
You.
Oh, well,
for a minute, I... Huh?
Me! Wait a minute.
Get that guy and give
him those fish back!
What's the matter with you?
You can't sell me.
I'm not a horse. It's just
the way I comb my hair.
I know, Orville. You and I
know you're not a horse.
But these people
are peculiar around here.
What are you talking about? Are you
going nuts? Why would a guy buy a guy?
I don't know. I don't know. They
buy anything. Any old junk.
But you can't do that to me.
You can't sell me.
You don't own me.
Oh, no, not now.
No. He does.
Why would he buy me?
What does he want me for?
I didn't ask him.
Wait a minute?
You sold me
to a zombie like that,
and you don't even know
what he wants me for?
You've got to
be careful, Turkey,
when you're dickering
with these people.
You gotta knock 'em off
while they're hot.
Do you know why they buy guys in
a country like this? For slaves!
They hit you with whips,
they put you to pickin' cotton,
they beat you,
and they beat you...
Wait. They don't
pick cotton here.
Well, they beat you
for whatever they're pickin'.
I know, I saw
Uncle Tom's Cabin twice.
Now, look, will you
relax a minute?
I've got this thing all figured out.
See, I've got plans.
But I...
I've got the guy's address
and I'm gonna get you back.
And when I do, we'll be where we
are now, only 200 bucks ahead.
What's that, nothing?
Well, that's something.
It might work out.
And a 100 of that is mine.
That's what I'm telling you.
Well, come on.
Put me in the higher brackets.
There's no use
giving it to you now.
If anything goes wrong, with the
plans, why, the money'd be wasted.
If anything goes wrong?
Yeah.
Well, I'm gettin' out of here.
See, you might have sold me, see, but
you're not gonna deliver me, see,
because I'm not
gonna be here, see.
Wait, wait, wait.
No, sir, see.
I don't have to deliver you.
They're coming to pick you up.
Coming to...
What? Pick me up?
Well, who do you think you're
playing with, children?
You're talking to Turkey,
the man with the muscles. I...
Wait a minute.
Turn the lights on.
What's going on here?
Wait just a second.
Aunt Lucy! Aunt Lucy!
The least you could do
is wrap me as a gift.
Geoffrey.
Geoffrey!
Huh?
What do you want?
You're a naughty, naughty boy.
You shouldn't have done that
wicked thing to little Orville.
You must find him, Geoffrey, you must
find him at once and bring him back.
Oh, I'm so distressed.
Well, I didn't know, Aunt Lucy.
Honest, I didn't.
The fellow I sold him to
was only a jobber and he
resold him later at a profit.
He wouldn't tell me to who.
"To whom," Geoffrey,
"To whom."
Yes, ma'am, to whom. But I
still don't know where he is.
Well, you've got to find him, Geoffrey.
Little Orville needs you.
Well, what can I do, Aunt Lucy? I've
been looking for him for a week.
Geoffrey, you remember that song you
used to sing? The one Orville loved?
Which song was that, Aunt Lucy?
Oh, you know.
♪ Ho-ho-hum,
you hear me shoutin'?
♪ Ho-ho-hum, zoot?
You remember.
Well, go through the streets
singing that song.
And little Turkey... I mean, Orville,
will hear you and reveal himself.
It might work.
It might work at that.
But look, Aunt Lucy, you being up there
and all, you must see everything.
Gee, you could save me a lot of trouble
if you just tell me where he is.
Oh, I'm not supposed to, Geoffrey.
It's against the rules.
Oh, come on, Aunt Lucy.
Gee, I won't crack to nobody.
Well, if you go to the marketplace,
then head east about 200 paces,
you'll come to... Oh, I can't talk
to you anymore now, Geoffrey.
Here comes Mr. Jordan!
Aunt Lucy!
♪ Ain't got a dime to my name
♪ What a terrible shame
♪ Just found a hole in my shoe
♪ And my stockin' shows through
♪ I know that when you're
as free as a bird in a tree
♪ Life is a wonderful whim
♪ Look at the crank
with his dough in the bank
♪ Don't you feel sorry for him?
♪ Rollin' along at a loss
♪ Never gatherin' moss
♪ Take it
♪ I'm no terrific success
♪ I ought to worry I guess
♪ I like a shady old tree
♪ What's the matter with me?
♪ There's nothin'
quite as grotesque
♪ As a man at a desk
♪ Lookin' outside at the sun
♪ Shirts made of silk
and a diet of milk
♪ Maybe he thinks he has fun
♪ I've got the vagabond itch
♪ Guess I'll never get rich
"Dear Jeff, flee for your
life before it is too late.
"You can't do anything for me now.
If you stick around,
"you will get us both into
trouble, maybe killed.
"Leave the country
and forget you ever knew me.
"Say nothin' to nobody about this.
Flee! Flee!
"Respectfully yours,
Turkey Jackson.
"P.S. I am being tortured
day and night. Flea!"
"Flea," F-L-E-A.
That's Turkey, all right.
Don't worry, old boy. I won't let you down.
I'll get you out, all right.
♪ Constantly
♪ I look for you
♪ No day or two
♪ But constantly
♪ Constantly
♪ I wished you near
♪ And now you're here
♪ So close to me
♪ And it isn't magic
♪ And you do exist
♪ For after all
♪ I know when I've been kissed
♪ And you are meant to be
♪ My heart's delight
♪ Not just tonight
♪ But constantly
♪ Constantly
♪ I looked for you
♪ No day or two
♪ But constantly
♪ Constantly
♪ I wished you near
♪ And now you're here
♪ So close to me
♪ And it isn't magic
♪ And you do exist
♪ For after all
♪ I know when I've been kissed
♪ And you were meant to be
♪ My heart's delight
♪ Not just tonight
♪ But constantly
Well, that's pretty good. What kind
of an animated esquire is this?
"Leave the country. Forget
you ever knew me," he says.
"Flea," he says. "Say nothing
to nobody about this," he says.
"Flea," he says.
Why, you dirty,
double-crossing hoarder, you!
Turkey, this is me, Jeff, your friend.
Say something.
Turkey?
Oh, the fellow is mad.
Take him away.
Toss him to the crocodiles.
Hey, he's my friend, I tell you.
Tell them who I am, Turkey.
He's just jokin'.
Let me go.
Wait.
Do you know this man?
Why, I never saw him
before in all my life.
Why, you dirty,
underhanded sickle-snoot!
We were kids together in the same
class for years until I got promoted.
Let him go.
Leave, all of you.
You stay.
Oh, but, hon!
Come. Sit here beside me.
Well...
Now, Orville, I want you
to tell me the truth.
Do you know him?
Well, I used to,
but I kinda outgrew him.
I don't dally much
with riffraff these days,
and he's a pretty
raffy kind of a riff.
Yeah. What...
Why didn't you tell me
you had a friend in Karameesh?
And such a friend.
Oh, so you didn't tell her
about me, huh?
Well, I didn't want to dicker too much.
It might've queered the deal.
This kid can't
handle competition.
You can understand why,
can't you, ma'am?
Yes, I can.
Here we have a proverb.
"A goose is beautiful
until it stands beside a peacock."
Say, goose...
What are you made up for anyhow?
What is this?
Ladies' night in a Turkish
bath or something?
What time do you light up, Jack?
It might interest you
to know, buster,
that you're looking at the
future prince of Karameesh.
Who?
I'm gonna be a pasha,
with the accent on the "pash."
What?
We're going to be married on...
When is the big day,
dream thing?
When the moon,
in its last quarter,
silvers the blossoms
of the almond tree.
That's Tuesday night,
about 9:00.
Oh, drat! I shall be
listening to Hobby Lobby.
Say, how can a dream like you
go for a drip like this anyhow?
It is written in the stars.
I've been counseled
by Hyder Khan, the wise one,
to take this man for my
husband, and I must obey.
Yeah, well, all I can say, old Hyder Khan
must've been out of focus at the time.
Oh, is that so? Well, the nuptial
knot's practically tied, see,
and there's nothing
you can do about it, see.
I'm her Heathcliff. She
bought me for 200 skins.
And it looks like I'm gonna
get your money's worth.
She bought you? Where did
she meet up with you?
She's the dame I told you about
in the gold box with the sticks.
Come on, baby. Give your little
princie a big kiss, king size.
Now kiss him on the nose. See
if you can straighten that out!
Oh, my.
Well, this defeats me.
I gotta give you
credit, though, Junior.
You certainly did
all right for yourself.
To show you there's
no hard feelings,
I'm gonna stick around
for the wedding.
I'll even give you away.
Oh, now, just a second.
You've already given me away.
Just because I hit the jackpot,
you wanna stick around
and pick up the nickels, huh?
Well, come on, blow
before I press a button
and have your head
served up in a cup and a saucer.
Oh, wait a minute.
Quit shoving,
or there'll be a roomful
of teeth around here.
Now, listen, I'm talking
nice to you,
but you'd better get out of here
before I forget that I'm the Prince.
Do that again.
He did it!
Gentlemen, please.
What is your name?
Geoffrey.
Geoffrey, I want you
to stay here with us.
Well, I think I could
be very happy here.
Oh, come on, honey. Daddy's tired
and it's getting near my bed time,
and I have to
catch up with my reading.
Good night, Geoffrey.
Good night.
Do it some more.
Come on, bub, rub.
Why is the Princess
going to marry you, Orville?
She was to have married
Mullay Kasim, the desert sheik.
Why has she changed her mind?
Oh, I guess sheiks
have gone out of style.
What the modern girl wants
is a nice, reliable wolf.
Do it some more.
I'll get you time-and-a-half
for overtime.
There's something
very strange about it all.
Something very, very strange.
Yeah, it's
a strange country, baby.
Orville.
Huh?
Listen.
If this were known,
it would mean my death.
But in my heart,
there is a great love for you.
You, too?
Say, if this keeps up,
I'll have to buy myself a scooter.
Is my love hopeless, or do you perhaps
have some crumbs of affection for me?
Oh, you know how a prince is.
I may set you up with a
little hat shop or something.
What a racket!
We're trying a new shade,
nightingale's blush.
Nightingale's blush,
that's sweet.
You get a complete
recondition and guaranteed job,
and you'll still look like a warthog.
Come on, gals, get a breath of fresh air.
Go ahead, beat it. Scat.
Just a second! I'm giving
the orders around here.
Besides, she's only done
nine toes.
Well, she can do
the other three later.
Go on, I want to put him
under the dryer. Beat it.
You'll bring on the rash. You'll spoil him.
Go on. Beat it.
Don't go far,
girls. I may need you.
Who are these Christmas tigers?
Who are they yessin'?
Well, the Princess' old man used
to use this for a courtroom.
He never lost a case.
That's very nice.
That's nifty.
Now, look, puffy, I want to have
a talk with you, man-to-man.
Yeah, who's gonna
hold up your end?
I'll see you in a couple weeks.
I have no time for riffraff.
You think you're pretty cute,
don't you?
Sending me that note they're
torturing you night and day.
Get out of town. There's
nothin' I can do for you.
That's right. There is nothing.
I can handle it all myself.
Now, look, buster, I want you to leave.
I know how you operate.
I don't want a best man.
You figure you'll move in, huh?
You figure maybe
you'll wind up the Prince.
Could be.
Yeah, well, you're takin'
a powder, see,
and you're taking it right now.
That's gratitude, huh?
That's nice.
You seem to be forgettin' that I'm
the guy that sold you into all this.
Now you want to toss me out.
Oh, don't give me that!
You thought you were selling me
into pickin' cotton with whips.
Yeah. Hey, now,
wait a minute. Hey!
Wait a minute. Where do
you think you're going?
What's in there?
Oh, it's nothing,
just milady's boudoir.
"Milady's boudoir"? What are
you doing going in there?
It's a strange country, chum.
It's a strange country.
Oh, find my friend,
Mr. Peters, a little corner
to sleep in over at the snake house.
You big phony.
Go ahead, buster. Get yourself
a rattle to play with.
It's a nice parlay
from you to the snake.
Cuddle with a cobra.
Happy fangs!
Now wait a minute. You can't do this to me!
Bye, fellows.
♪ Moonlight becomes you
♪ It goes with your hair
♪ You certainly know
the right thing
♪ To wear
♪ Moonlight becomes you
♪ I'm thrilled at the sight
♪ And I could get so romantic
♪ Tonight
♪ You're all dressed up
to go dreaming
♪ Now don't tell me I'm wrong
♪ And what a night
to go dreaming
♪ Mind if I tag along?
♪ If I say I love you
♪ I want you to know
♪ It's not just because
there's moonlight
♪ Although
♪ Moonlight becomes you so
♪ Moonlight becomes you
♪ What a beautiful view
♪ Moonlight and you
♪ You're all dressed up
to go dreaming
♪ Now don't tell me I'm wrong
♪ And what a night
to go dreaming
♪ Mind if I tag along?
♪ If I say I love you
♪ I want you to know
♪ It's not just because
there's moonlight
♪ Although
♪ Moonlight becomes you so ♪
Orville, Orville,
wake up! Wake up!
Okay, Ma, I'll get
a job tomorrow.
No, no, no. Wake up! Wake up!
What's the matter?
The Princess is unfaithful.
She cares nothing for you.
Look, I'll see you
in the hat shop later.
No, listen!
At this moment,
she and your best friend
are in each other's arms
in the gardens below.
Yeah, well, I...
What?
Yes. Look.
Why, the lowdown, filthy,
double-crossing centipede!
Trying to climb into my shoes
and pull the roof in over his head!
That's what he's trying to do!
Why, the crawling lizard!
I'll show him what a salami
has gotta go through.
No, no, no. Don't waste
your anger upon them.
Let us fly.
Let us fly together.
Okay, but let go
of my landing gear.
You and I, thus,
and thus... And thus will
my love consume you.
From manufacturer
direct to consumer.
I go!
Excuse me.
Beloved. Beloved!
Thus.
I...
Say, let me ask you something,
Princess.
Suppose you, sort of, put off
this wedding for a little bit,
and I, sort of,
hung around a little bit,
and you grew
to like me a little bit,
wouldn't that change things
a little bit, huh?
No, Geoffrey, it would not.
I like you now.
The more I get to like you,
the more reason
I will have to marry Orville.
You like me so you're gonna
marry Orville.
Boy, that's a new kind of brush.
That is the way it must be.
There are many, many things
you don't understand.
Later you will know.
Well, now, look, before you
figure on getting hooked up
to that chisel-chinned character,
I think there's a few things
you ought to know about him.
Why, Geoffrey, what do you mean?
Sit down a minute.
Just to give you an idea
of what kind of a double-crossin'
hoodlum he really is...
Did you know...
Oh, no. It's too fantastic.
You'd never believe it.
Go on, Geoffrey, what happened?
Well, we're broke,
see, and he sells me,
his best friend, for 200 bucks!
Practically gives me away.
Did you know that?
I thought you sold him?
That's the way he tells it. There's
two sides to everything, you know.
But that's impossible. The
men brought Orville to me.
Don't you see, they come to pick
me up and get him by mistake.
But I don't understand...
So you see, by rights, I
should be in his spot.
You should be marrying me
instead of him.
There's two sides
to everything, you know.
What's the big idea?
There's two sides
to everything, you know.
Princess! Princess, he's here.
Mullay Kasim, he's here!
Mullay Kasim, my lord.
Where is he this...
This dog?
Hold your anger, Kasim.
Wait until you've heard...
I've already heard.
It's whispered
throughout the land
that on the very day
set for our wedding,
you're planning to marry
this American!
Is it true? Tell me.
Yes, Kasim, it is true.
But it is only because...
Enough!
Come, Ahmed Caspa.
Let us find this man.
Let us see the color
of his liver.
Let us hang his filthy carcass
for the jackals to nibble at!
No, no, wait.
First you must hear the words
of Hyder Khan, the wise one.
Hyder Khan?
Very well, Shalmar.
Five more minutes does not matter
in the life of a cockroach. Come.
And it is here, written in the
stars, O Lion of the Desert,
that the first husband
of the Princess Shalmar,
will die a violent death within
the week of the marriage.
What is that you say?
It is also written
that her second husband will be
blessed with long life and happiness.
Now do you understand?
The American, as my first husband,
will die within the week.
Then, as the wise one said, I will
be free to marry the man I love.
This is a great joke.
It'll be told and retold as
long as men live in Karameesh.
First time I ever saw
steam heat in print.
Orville?
Just when it was
getting interesting.
Hello, hon.
Did you tell Geoffrey he's
not to stay for the wedding?
That we didn't
want him here at all?
Well, I just hinted at it.
I gave him a map and
provisions for three months.
I can't understand
why you don't like him.
I think he's one of the
nicest men I've ever met.
Oh, he's a nice fellow, as nice
fellows go and... Why don't he?
Orville, there's something
I must tell you.
You know, this is
a very strange country.
Yeah.
Like you running into me and
buying me like I was a potato.
And me baked
ever since. Ho-hum.
No, I mean we have very strange
customs, very strange laws.
For the first week of a marriage,
a man and wife live separately.
Yeah, well, every...
Huh?
It is a custom
thousands of years old.
Oh, little customs, you make 'em, you
break 'em, they come and they go.
Did I ever tell you
about Prohibition?
It has been so
for thousands of years.
There can be no other way.
Oh, honey, don't take on so.
It's only a week.
Yes, only a week.
Oh, Orville, when I look at you
and think of our marriage,
I can't help crying.
You're so young...
Much, much too young.
Oh, you don't have to
worry about me, baby.
I just read a book.
Oso Bucco, come here!
When was this American born?
I can't finish his tomb
until I have the date.
I don't know, Ahmed.
We don't know what we're doing.
Another thing. I tell you we're
making his coffin too small.
I tried my wife
in it this morning.
Her feet were hanging out.
What are we going to do?
We're just guessing.
If we are not careful, we're
going to do a sloppy job.
While the American is still alive,
why don't we measure him?
Oh, we couldn't do that!
He would find out.
There are ways.
There are ways!
Come on.
Right now I could use
a hole in my head.
Could we disturb you, Master?
Oh, sure, fellas,
what do you want?
If it is not too much trouble,
we would like to measure you.
Yeah, what for?
We are making something for you.
It's a surprise.
Oh! Something for the wedding.
No, Master.
This is for after the wedding.
Oh, sort of
a male trousseau, huh?
Yes, Master, sort of
a male trousseau.
Well, all right, fellas.
Go ahead. Measure away.
Thank you. Thank you, Master.
It will be brief.
Waist, 34.
So, you know, the Princess kind of has
an eye for beauty, so pretty me up.
Sew in plenty of muscles.
Make it zooty.
Do not worry, Master. We will make you
look even better than you do now.
Oh, thanks.
Chest normal, 41.
Chest expanded, 41.
Chest...
Give me lots of room.
I like to spread out.
Now, perhaps
the Master would lie down.
Oh, certainly.
5' 11" overall.
Say, put a lot of padding
in it, will you, fellas?
I want it nice and comfortable.
I don't want anything stiff.
I assure you, Master. It will
be no stiffer than yourself.
Well, good day, Master.
Good day.
Oh, one question, Master. What
is the date of your birth?
Birth? What do you want that for?
What's that got to do with...
It is for the record.
Oh! September 13th, 1913.
On a Friday.
Thank you, Master. We must go now.
We have to carve it on...
Carve it on?
And what was that business?
Orville?
Those two men.
What were they doing here?
Oh, they were measuring me
for some sort of outfit.
Measuring you!
Do you know who they are?
Well, I guess, they're
the royal dressmakers.
No, my beloved! No!
They're royal undertakers.
Yeah, well, that...
Huh?
Yes!
You mean, they were measuring
me for a graveyard gabardine?
Jeff! Jeff!
Okay, there you are.
I've been looking everywhere for you.
I got to have a talk with you.
Now, look, Orvie, I've been
doing a lot of thinking.
There's no use of you and I
talking and arguing anymore.
I'm gonna beat it on
out of here.
No. That's it... You're not.
You don't have to.
Oh, I admit I tried to cut in on you.
I made a big play.
But, whatever you've got,
that Shalmar's going through with it.
Now that's all been changed.
Huh?
Well...
I'm the guy that's shoving off.
I've been watching you two and
you're just made for each other.
You look good together.
You're just the right size.
And, you're taking her.
See, I'm giving her to you.
Now, wait a minute.
What are you cooking up here?
The last gal you gave me was that lady
wrestler up at the St. Nicholas rink.
What's behind all this?
Well, I got to thinking
about the burying...
I mean, the marrying, and I
got a hunch it wouldn't last.
So, I got a feeling,
in a week, I'd be cold.
And, besides, I got a girl.
I met mine.
I got her at the harem,
right off the assembly line.
Nice model.
He's gonna fly with me.
My love will consume him thus...
And thus, and thus...
Aunt Lucy?
You know, a girl
can eat too much yeast.
But, my very own...
Yeah, yeah, later.
You know, you gotta catch me when I'm
in the mood for that sort of thing.
You ain't been
out of it for 20 years.
Well, this is a whole new shuffle, huh?
You two!
Wait till Shalmar
hears about this.
Oh, yeah, but it's not
gonna be easy, you know.
It's gonna be a pretty tough assignment
to get Shalmar to give me up.
That'll be a struggle. But you can
handle it, old boy, I'm sure.
After all, you've got
everything I've got,
and you've had it
many years longer, too.
Yes, only, I got rid of mine.
Yeah, well, you...
It's gonna just really tear the heart
out of her to give you up, I guess.
But I'll catch her sort of on the rebound.
She might settle for me.
Yeah, well, that's the spirit
and I'll be right behind you.
I'm gonna see you right
through to the end, old pal.
I will leave no stone unturned.
My beloved!
Why don't we fly right away?
Look, honey, why don't you just fly
around and warm your motor up?
I'll join you later.
Orville? Orville.
Orville!
Orville, this is disgraceful!
Disgraceful!
Orville, I'm not gonna let you do
this dreadful thing to Geoffrey.
Oh, you'll be
the death of me yet.
Please, Aunt Lucy!
You've got to talk
to him, Orville.
You've got to
tell him the truth.
But, I ain't doing nothing.
Look what he did to me!
Orville, I insist.
If you don't tell him, I will.
But, you can't talk to him.
You're in my dream.
Oh, goodness, gracious me!
That's right.
We're only allowed to be
in one dream a week.
Mr. Jordan doesn't like us to
go around pestering people.
Well, I can understand that.
I've got to make him hear me.
Geoffrey! Geoffrey!
Geoffrey!
Take your hands off me!
Stop it! No! Help!
Guess that'll show her.
Your feet are cold.
You see, Master.
Wings!
And more than that,
they have legs.
Insects! Fireflies!
By the heavens, what are
they doing in my telescope?
I don't know. I haven't cleaned
the lenses for a week.
Dear, oh, dear!
Oh, dear!
I must have mistaken these
fireflies for Jupiter and Venus.
Oh, yes, Master, you've
certainly gummed up the works.
Indeed, I have.
My prophesies for
the American's death
were based on the fixed
positions of Jupiter and Venus.
I don't know.
This just doesn't add up.
I want you, and you say
you want me,
and Orville says it's okay,
and still you're gonna marry him.
I told you, Geoffrey.
It's something I can't explain.
Orville and I are going to be married
and that's all I have to say.
Well, I've got something
to say, too, see!
We're not suited, see. I'm not
in love with you anymore.
I got another girl.
No more talk.
Go to your room
and prepare for the wedding.
I just got one thing
to tell you, Princess...
I'm going to my room
and prepare for the wedding.
Okay, fellas,
who's got the dice?
Boy, he's a pip, isn't he?
Brushing off a dream like you.
Instead of a wedding, you'd think
he was going to his own funeral.
Yes... Wouldn't you?
Princess!
Oh, mistress of my life,
listen and be merciful.
I have made a calamitous error.
You must not
marry that American.
You must marry Mullay Kasim!
Mullay Kasim?
Speak.
I must hear everything.
You see, my Princess,
your life is influenced by the
planets Jupiter and Venus,
and so, it is my painful duty
to tell you what I've learned.
You are indeed the favored
one of Allah, O Master.
For to marry the Princess, most men
in Karameesh would gladly die.
Yes.
That's what's worrying me.
So you see, they turned
out to be fireflies.
I was wrong about everything.
Geoffrey!
Geoffrey, don't you see?
Isn't it wonderful?
Oh, yes, it's pretty good. I
mean, what's wonderful about it?
It just means Turkey's
back in circulation,
and you get tied up
to Mullay Kasim.
Mullay Kasim.
Oh, Geoffrey, you may feel strange
about marrying a Princess,
but I'll spend the rest of my
life trying to live it down.
You mean, me?
You mean, you and me?
Is that what you mean?
Mmm-hmm.
Mistress!
You see, Hyder Khan?
You see what your fireflies
have done?
Oh, how about this! Wait till I
break the news to doodlebug.
So, that's why little Orville was so
anxious to hand you over to me, huh?
I don't know how, but I think he
got wind of this whole thing.
Well, don't say anything to him, Geoffrey.
Not just yet.
Don't you worry about me.
I'll handle him.
Yeah, you see, Shalmar and I
had a little talk, Orville,
and we've decided
to accept your generous offer.
Generous offer.
What generous offer?
You giving me to her.
She's decided to accept me.
The guys are working
on the nuptial knots right now.
No kidding!
That's right.
Boy, I knew you'd see it.
You two, what a pair!
Hand-in-hand!
Brother, you're gonna
have the happiest week.
I mean, what a marriage! You're gonna
be in clover! Yes, sir, deep in clover.
Have you told me all?
Oh, Sheik.
I have told you
what has befallen,
trusting in your generosity
to reward me.
Here.
You must hurry, O Mighty One!
When I left the palace,
the Princess and her consort
were preparing to leave the country.
Hurry, hurry!
There isn't too much time.
Hey, why don't you get some
sense into your noggin,
and just you and me blow?
We're going to the United States
to get hooked up, I tell you.
That's not gonna save your life.
That guy, Hyder Khan's got that jinx
of his spread all over the world.
Oh, yeah? Let's see him
mess around in Brooklyn.
Here comes Murder, Incorporated.
Call me later.
So, that is your plan!
Running away with this dog.
I could show a dog a few things
about running right now.
I'm not mixed-up
in this at all.
I just work here. I'm just
tending the gardens. I...
My, these tulips need pruning.
Have one?
You lie to Kasim?
No, but it's a big switch now.
I gave her up. I'm on your side.
I'm your friend.
They're ducking out on you,
the dirty double-crossers!
What do you think
we ought to do with them?
What is this?
So, there's another one!
That's nice going, Junior.
Remind me to throw you a piece
of cheese in the morning.
Kasim, I must say...
Silence!
Who is this goat? This moon-faced
son of a one-eyed donkey?
I wouldn't let him call me that
even if there is a resemblance.
Listen here, big boy. Where do
you come off cutting in here?
Go on. Go play cops and
robbers someplace else!
Beat it, scat, shoo!
Go on, now you tell him. Go ahead, slap
his teeth out. I'll hold your coat.
Well, I'll hold your coat, too.
Kasim, please.
Please!
Quiet! You would dare
oppose the will of Kasim?
Oppose your will? I'll have you writing
one if you mess with me, Jack!
Now, you're talking. Go ahead.
Take a poke at him.
We're not afraid
of him. Are you?
Enough!
You are coming with me.
Caspa, take one of the
girls for yourself.
Now, just a minute here.
Okay, pal, I'm with you.
He says she's going with him.
Oh! She's going with him?
He make joke.
Funny boy.
♪ Patty cake, patty cake,
baker's man!
♪ Bake a cake as...
Yes, sir, Junior!
That thing sure got around.
Yeah, and back to us.
Run! Run for your lives!
This way! Come on,
nipper, shake a slipper!
Okay, lover, head for cover!
Hurry!
Now, wait! You two girls
hide in there, quick! Hurry up!
No, no, no!
Not you!
We'll stay here
and hold them off.
Yeah, we'll hold them off.
Who, us? Who are you kidding?
Hold who off?
Let's spread out.
Two of you, that way. Search the tower!
Search the palace!
Two of you, in there.
Come on, now!
Search, you dogs! Search!
My white stallion to the man
who brings me their heads.
Come on, now!
They must learn what it means to
incur the wrath of Mullay Kasim.
They're not in here.
There's no trace of them.
Searched everywhere.
Highness, we cannot
find them in here.
They cannot be far. We must find
them and slit their throats.
Yes, Your Highness!
They shall die slowly. Their
tongues shall be ripped out!
Their ears shall be sliced
off and dried on sticks.
Search the corridors! We'll find them
if we have to tear down the palace!
Yes, Your Highness.
Call the men!
Stand up, you dog!
Oh, you thought you'd slip
through my fingers, huh?
Caspa, after him!
Get the horses ready!
I was just going for a broom to
sweep this stuff up, that's all.
Mullay Kasim will take
care of you in the desert!
Aunt Lucy!
I never thought I'd wind up
in a camel's snood!
A fine pal you are,
letting me give her up!
And all the time you knew
you weren't gonna die!
That's what's killing me.
You weren't gonna die!
Yeah, well, give me credit.
That's pretty hard to do,
beating you and the embalmer.
I feel like the morning mail.
RFD.
Look, they're leaving us! All
alone out here in the desert.
There's no food,
no water, no nothing!
Well, come on.
Let's start the sack race.
Where do we go?
Let's hop over the hill
and see what's doing.
Must be a gas station
somewhere around here.
Say, what are you
still hopping for?
We've been out of
those nets all day.
I know, but I want to
keep my watch going.
Say...
How did we get loose with our hands
and feet tied and everything?
If we told anybody,
they'd never believe it.
Oh! Let's not
tell them, huh?
Proceed.
See anything?
Nothing.
Come on.
Courage, boy!
"Courage," he says.
Look at that! You know what they
are, don't you? They're buzzards!
Yeah. They're carrying
finger bowls, too.
Fine way to end up,
a box lunch for a bird.
Turkey, look!
Hey, what's a drive-in doing
in the middle of the desert?
I'm no quiz kid.
Come on, let's eat!
Well, I'll force something.
Hey, toss us a couple
of mugs of java!
We got our own sugar.
Two tall double-dip hamburgers!
Not too well done, please.
And a couple of mile-high beers!
Hey, it's moving!
We better grab it.
Hey, come back!
Wait a minute! Hey!
Hey!
Hey, what's this "now you see
it, now you don't" stuff?
We might have known.
It's a mirage!
It sure was a good one.
I could even smell the onions.
Come on!
I'm getting out of here.
Yeah, me, too!
♪ Moonlight becomes you
Why, it's Shalmar!
♪ It goes with your hair
She must've been
visiting a gopher friend.
♪ You certainly know
the right thing to wear
♪ Moonlight becomes you
♪ I want you to know
♪ It's not just because
there's moonlight
♪ Although,
moonlight becomes you so
♪ Moonlight becomes you
♪ It goes with your hair
♪ You certainly know
the right thing to wear
♪ Moonlight becomes you
♪ I'm thrilled at the sight
♪ And I could get
so romantic tonight
♪ I'm all dressed up
to go dreaming
♪ Now don't tell me I'm wrong
♪ And what a night
to go dreaming
♪ Mind if I tag along?
♪ If I say I love you
♪ I want you to know
♪ It's not just because
there's moonlight
♪ I know
♪ Moonlight becomes you so
Shalmar needs a shave!
Well, that's an omen.
We've gotta find the girls and
save them from that wolf, Kasim.
Come on!
I don't know, pal.
I don't know whether I can make it.
My legs feel like they're cut
off near my Adam's apple.
I guess that kiss took too
much out of you, huh?
Yeah.
Come on.
Get aboard.
If I'm too heavy,
I'll throw my hat away.
Yeah. Leave your head
in it, huh?
Hey, come on!
Look! Water!
Water!
This is a bit of all right!
How about this!
Well!
What are you doing?
My radiator's dry.
One thing about it, where there's
water, there's life, people!
All we gotta do is
follow the stream.
Oh, there's a herring.
Come along, mister.
Come along! Come along!
Come along!
What do you make of it?
I don't know.
We'd better take it easy until we
find out just whose joint it is, huh?
It might be a camel motel.
Hey, those guys! Those are
Mullay Kasim's gorillas!
Yeah, and that joint
must be their hideout, huh?
Well, we gotta save the girls.
It's up to us now, Turkey.
We'll have to storm the place.
You storm.
I'll stay here and drizzle.
I got something that can't miss!
So have they. Guns!
Now, look. Now, listen
to every word, see.
We don't have to
wait for night, see.
We just go up
on the place and we...
There's no one.
I tell you, there were two
men in the horse lines.
When they ran away,
I shot at them.
Ah! You've been
drinking koolash again!
Do you think they know we're here?
We're still wearing
our heads, aren't we?
That was the dopiest idea
I've ever heard.
You thinking you could
skin a horse and put me inside.
How would I look being a horse?
Just the same.
Look, we gotta get back to where we
started from and wait till dark.
Let's go.
Okay.
I think we just went
through a red light.
I'd feel better
if we had a periscope.
Will you trust me? Now, I've got
a great sense of direction.
Go right.
You think we're still okay?
Sure, sure. We were
headed due north.
North, huh?
Yeah.
Don't look now, Junior,
but I think we're standing on a rug.
It is those pigs!
Orville!
Geoffrey, Orville! Don't stand there!
Hurry, run!
Take them outside and
bring me back their ears.
No, wait!
There must be no shedding of
blood on our wedding night.
Hey! Did you hear that?
"Wedding."
I stopped listening
when he said, "blood."
Lock them up!
Look out!
I just had this pressed!
Let's not be vulgar, bully!
A fine thing. First you
sell me for 200 bucks,
then I'm gonna marry the
Princess, then you cut in on me!
Then we're carried off
by a desert sheik,
now we're gonna have
our heads chopped off.
I know all that.
Yeah, but the people who came in
the middle of the picture don't!
You mean, they missed my song?
Who's that?
Who are they?
That's the great sheik
Neb Jolla and his men.
Friend of Kasim's?
No, the enemy of Kasim.
For 10 years,
they have been at war,
but tonight, Kasim has
invited him to his wedding
as a token of peace.
But I do not trust
either one of them.
Halt!
You ought to take something
for your throat.
What have you got there?
I've brought food for these men.
They have not eaten.
It cannot matter when it is
their last night to live.
Very well. Give it to
them through the window.
Any word from the governor?
Now, listen carefully.
In this bowl there's a magic
ring from the Princess.
With it, you can make
three wishes.
Perhaps it will
help us all to escape.
Oh, what good is a ring? Why didn't
you bake us a cake with a file in it?
The ring will not work
for everybody.
If we are fortunate, it might
work for you, Geoffrey.
Should it fail,
lift the jewel and inside you
will find poison, for two.
Here.
What is this talking?
Go on, be gone!
Goodbye, honey.
Don't forget to write.
Just send it to the Dead
Letter Office. Poison.
Three wishes.
All right, start the acka-muracas.
Come on, ring.
Oh, you ring.
Come on.
Get the four of us out of here.
Magic ring.
What does she think we are?
A couple of chowderheads?
No pictures, huh?
Nothing.
Well, get the poison pills.
Let's get it over with, huh?
Oh, in here, huh?
There they are.
Yeah.
Close your eyes, pal, and I'll shoot
you one of these concentrated mickeys.
Wait. Wait. What's the matter
with me shooting them to you?
Well, you don't want to fall and
get a big knot on your head.
I gotta stay behind
and hold you up.
No, no. I'll stay behind
On me, huh?
Yeah.
Don't let me fall too hard.
Oh, no.
Set the table, Aunt Lucy.
There'll be two more for dinner.
Boy, I sure wish I had a drink.
Junior! Junior, it worked!
How about that? The magic
ring, it worked on you.
Well, I'll be a monkey's uncle!
Jeff, I'm back! Jeff, I did it!
I'm back!
Boy! For a minute, I thought
I only had a one-way ticket!
Hey, hey!
Cut it out!
What am I doing, huh?
You know, I think I liked
you better the other way.
Yeah, well...
Well, you've used up our last wish.
We'll never get out of here.
Oh, stop worrying.
I'll think of something.
That's what I'm afraid of.
What's going on here?
Oh, nothing. Say, did anybody
ever escape from this jail?
Once, about a year ago,
two men got out.
Oh, yeah? Tell me, chum,
how'd they do it?
It was an accident.
To light a cigarette, I placed my
rifle in the window like this.
Hello.
Oh, interesting.
And then what happened?
One of the fellows reached
through the window,
grabbed the rifle
and pointed it at me.
Oh, you mean, like this?
Exactly! Except that he put
it right up against my head.
You mean, like this.
Yes! Yes!
What's wrong?
Put them up!
What?
You heard me!
Come on, give us those keys!
Hurry, or we'll spread you.
Ahmed, we have done it again!
Say, I don't get this setup.
What's frying?
I'm cooking up
some small sabotage here.
We'll have them at one another's throats
in no time. A little internal dissension.
Oh, I get it. Divide and conquer.
Brother against brother.
Yeah.
Sort of an Arabian Gestapo?
You've got it, Tyrone.
Hasn't missed yet.
Then we grab
the gals and cut out.
Here, hold this a minute,
will you?
Allez!
What are you gonna do with that?
Look and learn.
Hey, what are doing?
Making reefers?
This'll give them that lift.
I got a pip.
What now?
Brilliant! Good boy.
Where's the dribble-glass?
Here. Slip them
the drip, drip.
Neb Jolla, so great is my joy tonight
that I wish to share it with you.
May our tribes live together
in peace for 1,000 years!
My hand on that, Kasim.
You are fortunate indeed to win the
love of so beautiful a princess.
She cannot wait
for my kisses upon her lips.
Can you, my dove?
Kasim, you shall soon know
how I feel about you.
There, you hear?
Yeah.
I drink to my friend
who was my enemy,
and to the eternal peace
that has come between us.
I drink to that,
and also to the beauty
of my bride-to-be.
My apologies, O Great Sheik.
It's an accident.
There must be
a hole in the goblet.
Yes, I see there is!
I trust you do not do this as a joke?
Do you?
No, my friend,
my very dear friend!
Happy Fourth of July.
Kasim, what is the meaning of this?
What's going on here?
My friend, I give you
my assurances.
Eat, drink, music!
Let us all be like brothers.
Do you bring us here to
make fools of us? Do you?
I tell you, this is
no doing of mine.
Be of good faith.
There will be no more.
Kasim, when will
these outrages cease?
Neb Jolla, please, patience.
I humble myself
at your feet in apology.
Come, come, sit down.
This is the screwiest picture
I was ever in!
At the word from our master, for these
insults, we would tear you to shreds!
But, believe us. We are
as mystified as you.
We came here to eat,
not to be mystified!
That's right.
Do not trust him.
His is an empty
gesture of friendship.
Neb Jolla, I am at a loss
to understand!
Kasim, why do you persist on
playing these pranks?
It's just as much a surprise
to us, as it is to you.
Please forget about
the whole thing.
Your Highness,
I give you my assurance...
I am trying to control myself,
but my patience cannot last!
Neb Jolla, I tell you...
I'm on fire!
Water, water!
I am on fire!
Enough, enough!
This is war!
Fire! Fire!
This means war!
When I see how
silly people behave,
I'm glad I'm a camel.
Oh, I'm glad you're a
camel, too, Mabel!
Hurry up!
Let's go! Come on.
I'll race you!
You know, this thing pinches me a little.
You got another one?
Yeah.
It won't be long before we're
seeing little old New York.
Three long years we've
been waiting to get back.
Yep! I'm gonna grab a piece of
the good old USA and eat it.
Something down
around New Orleans.
You know, Geoffrey,
I get the strangest feeling
that we've been through
all of this before.
Looks like I trapped you again.
And, get me! This time I'm
bringing home the bacon, too.
And what a slab!
Orville!
Then the answer's yes?
Yes, but don't think I'm
marrying you for her money.
Why are you marrying me?
I'll think of something.
Say, I want the Statue of
Liberty to be proud of me,
so I think I'll powder my nose.
I don't think it'll help.
♪ Moonlight becomes you
♪ It goes with your hair
I can't go on!
No food, no water!
It's all my fault.
We're done for.
It's got me!
I can't stand it!
No food, no nothing!
No food, no water!
No food!
What's the matter
with you, anyway?
There's New York. We'll be
picked up in a few minutes!
You had to open your big mouth
and ruin the only good scene
I got in the picture.
I might have won
an Academy Award!