Garbage....
All l've been thinking about
all week is garbage.
l mean, l just can't stop thinking about it.
What kind of thoughts about garbage?
l just...
l've gotten real concerned over
what's gonna happen with all the garbage.
l mean, we've got so much of it.
You know, I mean, we have to run out
of places to put this stuff eventually.
The last time l started feeling this way
is when that barge was stranded
and, you know, it was going around
the island, and nobody would claim it.
-Do you remember that?
-Yes, l remember.
Do you have any idea
what may have triggered this concern?
Yeah. Yeah.
You see, the other night
John was taking out the garbage,
and he kept spilling things
out of the container.
And that made me... l started imagining,
like, a garbage can that produces garbage,
and it doesn't stop.
lt just keeps producing garbage,
and it just keeps overflowing.
And what would you do, you know,
to try to stop something like that?
And do you see any pattern here?
-What do you mean?
-Well...
Last week we were talking
about your obsession
with the families of airline fatalities.
Now, we're talking about your concern
over the garbage problem.
Yeah. So?
Well, if you think about it,
l think you'll see that the object
of your obsession is invariably
something negative
which you have no control over.
Yeah.
But how many people, do you think,
run around
obsessing over how great and how happy
things are? You know, l mean...
Maybe they do,
but l don't think they're in therapy.
Anyway,
being happy isn't all that great.
l mean, the last time l was really happy
l got so fat.
l must have put on 25 pounds.
l thought John was gonna have a stroke.
So what are you worried about?
What am l looking at here?
ls this a mistake or what?
lt depends on your point of view.
l don't think so.
ln fact, l'm gonna tell you a little secret.
Yeah?
As soon as you've got a ring on your finger,
you start getting the most spectacular
attention from the opposite gender.
-That's bullshit.
-Seriously.
God, l wish l had Super Bowl seats
for every time some filly would come up
and start talking to me
without the slightest provocation.
lt's critical. lt's just marvellous.
Yeah, but that happened to you
before you got married.
No! No, no, no, no.
lt never happened before l got married.
lf l'd known that, l'd have gone out
and bought myself a ring
when l was 1 8 and saved myself...
-Yeah, right.
-...a lot of time and money.
No, l wish somebody had clued me in.
l'm telling you. lt's too weird.
Shit, l gotta be someplace.
So, listen, racquetball Thursday, right?
-How about 7:30?
-Yeah, fine.
-Great. Bye-bye.
-See you later. Bye.
-Yes, sir?
-Janet.
Reschedule Kirkland for Friday, 1 :30.
-Yes, sir.
-All right.
Are you still keeping these thoughts
from John?
Yeah.
Well, are you afraid of his reaction
of his finding you silly
at thinking these things?
No, it's not that. lt's just...
-Well, l'm really angry at him right now.
-Why?
Well, he invited this college friend of his
to come stay at our house,
and, well, he didn't even ask me.
l'm gonna say yes, of course,
but, you know, it just would have been nice
to have been asked.
What upset you about that?
l guess it makes me angry
because l can't justify being angry.
lt's his house. He pays the mortgage.
Yes, but he asked you to quit yourjob,
and you do have housework.
Yeah. l have housework. That's true.
Now, this unexpected guest
notwithstanding,
how are things with John?
They're fine. l mean, they're fine.
Except for l'm kind of
going through this thing
where l don't want him to touch me, but...
Well, when did you begin
having this feeling?
Well, last week.
l don't know. l just...
l got this really strange feeling
and just didn't want him to touch me.
Prior to this feeling,
were you comfortable
with your physical contact with John?
Yeah. Sure. Yeah.
Except for... Well...
l've never really been that much into sex.
l mean, l like it and everything,
but, you know,
l just don't think it's such a big deal,
and l wouldn't miss it,
you know, kind of thing.
But...
Well, lately l've just been kind of curious
about how things have slacked off.
Well, perhaps he senses your hesitancy
at being touched.
Yeah, but, you see, that's the weird thing,
because he started not touching me
before l started feeling like that.
l mean, l'm sure he probably wishes
that l would initiate things once in a while.
And l would, except for...
lt just never occurs to me and...
Well, the few times l have felt like it,
l was by myself.
Did you do anything?
What do you mean?
Did you masturbate?
God, no!
No.
l take it from your response
that you never masturbate.
Well...
l tried once. lt just seemed so stupid.
l don't know.
lt just seemed like a dumb thing to do.
God, you know, then l started worrying
that my dead grandfather was maybe
watching me, you know, and...
lt just seemed so stupid.
You know, especially when you don't know
what to do with all the garbage.
So it was recently when you tried this?
Well, it was kind of recently,
but not real recently.
l am just not up to having
a guest in the house.
l gotta go to the office.
l gotta get back to the office.
l only get one today? Gee, how exciting.
l already skipped one meeting.
l gotta get back.
Look, John, if you wanna leave, leave.
My life doesn't revolve
around these little get-togethers.
l mean, don't flatter yourself.
Hey, don't feel like you gotta treat me
with kid gloves, Cyn.
l mean, tell me how you really feel.
Listen, l got a friend coming into town,
an old friend of mine
that l haven't seen in years.
From what l can tell, l think he's a little lost.
l think l may have to spend
a little time with him.
Meaning we'll have to cool it for a while?
Yeah.
You know, l wish you'd quit
that bartending job of yours.
Why?
l just hate the thought
of all those guys hitting on you.
-l can handle it.
-l'm sure.
Besides, the money is good
and some of the guys are cute.
And you are in no position to be jealous.
Who said l was jealous?
l did.
You know,
l'd like to do it at your house sometime.
l must admit,
the idea of doing it in my sister's bed
gives me a perverse thrill.
l wish l could just come right out
and tell everyone Ann's a lousy lay,
the beautiful,
the popular Ann Bishop Mullany.
Could be risky.
How about l just start a rumour, then?
No, no. l mean, doing it at my house.
-Afraid of getting caught?
-Yeah.
You should be.
-Can l meet this friend of yours?
-Who? Graham?
l gotta tell you, we were very close
many years ago, but l...
l think we're very different now.
-Yes?
-Ann? My name is Graham Dalton.
Yeah.
-Sure.
-May l use your bathroom?
Come on in. Come on.
-Where is it?
-Straight back there to the left.
-l'm sorry.
-Do you like strawberries? l brought you...
-Thank you. That's real sweet.
-...some strawberries.
Hi. John Mullany, please. This is his wife.
That's all right. Thank you.
Well...
-That was quick.
-False alarm.
Have a seat.
l'm sorry. You know,
we don't let people smoke in the house.
-But if you'd like to, we could...
-Oh, no, no, no.
-...go outside.
-l...
l can wait.
-Do you have any other things?
-Yes.
You mean to bring in? No, no.
l mean, l do have some other things,
but this is all l need to stay here.
Have you ever been on television?
Television? No. No. Why? Why?
l was just curious.
Graham. That's an unusual name.
Yeah, yeah. l guess it is.
My mother is a complete Anglophile.
Anything British makes her drool
like a baby, so she...
l think she heard the name in a movie
or something.
She's a prisoner of public television now.
How do you like being married?
l like it just fine.
What about it do you like?
l don't mean to be critical.
-No, no. That's okay.
-l'm curious.
Well, you know the cliché
about the security of it.
Well, that's true.
And we own this house.
lt's a nice house.
And...
John was just made junior partner,
and l really like that.
You know, l like the fact that
he's just not freelance or whatever.
Yes.
So how long has it been
since you've seen John?
-Nine years.
-Nine years?
Yeah. l was surprised he invited me
to stay here until l found a place.
Didn't you...
-Didn't you know him very well?
-No. l knew him very well.
John and l
were very much alike.
Really?
lt's kind of hard to believe.
l mean, you just seem so different now.
Yeah. l would imagine
we are pretty different now.
-l'm ready to use the bathroom finally.
-Okay.
Graham,
l gotta tell you,
l almost called the cops
when l saw you today.
l thought to myself,
"This couldn't possibly be the same guy
"that once held private services
in the back of the chapel on a weekly basis."
-You did that?
-Well, yeah.
Everybody has a past, and that's mine, so...
So what's with the getup?
Somebody die or...
-John.
-l'm sorry. Did...
-No, no, no. Nobody died.
-l'm sorry.
-So...
-l mean, well...
What do you think the Greeks would think
of this rather sombre attire?
l don't know.
Dinner was very good.
-Yeah. lt wasn't bad, honey.
-Thanks, thanks, thank you.
Usually Ann achieves a kind of critical mass
with the salt,
but tonight was... l always tell her,
"You can always add more,
but you can't take it away."
Yeah. You say that, don't you?
So, do you have family here?
Mother, father, my sister.
-Sister older or younger?
-Younger.
Are you close?
l'm sorry... l'm prying again. l'm sorry.
Were you prying before?
Yeah, this afternoon l was grilling Ann
about your marriage.
-How'd it go?
-Well, very well.
So l was asking about your sister.
Yeah. Well...
We get along all right. lt's just that...
Well, l think she's an extrovert.
l just think she's loud.
She probably wouldn't agree.
No. Definitely wouldn't agree.
So, listen,
you gonna see Elizabeth while you're here?
l don't know.
-Who's Elizabeth?
-lt's a girl Graham dated in school.
Well, after the chapel episodes.
She still lives here,
to the best of my knowledge.
So, Graham and l were talking about
apartments today,
and l told him that they've got those lovely
little apartments in the Garden District
and that they're really nice,
the garage apartments...
-There's critical crime in the Garden District.
-John, come on. That is not true.
l don't know what kind of place
you're looking for,
but there are plenty of studio apartments
available elsewhere.
l'm sorry?
No, it's just right now l have one key.
You know, everything l own is in the car.
l just... l like that.
lf l get an apartment, that's two keys.
lf l get a job, you know,
l might have to open or close.
That's more keys. You know, buy some stuff.
Then l'm afraid it's gonna get ripped off
or something.
Then l get more keys.
You know, l just like having the one key.
lt's clean.
Don't have to worry about losing them.
l always lose my keys. l hate that.
Get rid of the car
when you get the apartment.
-No. l like having the car.
-You'd still have one key.
Car is important. Gotta be mobile.
ln case you have
to leave someplace in a hurry?
Yeah, or go someplace in a hurry.
Excuse me.
-Do you want some help? Sure?
-No, no. Really.
l'm fine. There's not that much to do.
Graham, do you pay taxes?
Yeah, l pay taxes. Yeah, l pay taxes.
What do you mean?
lf you don't pay taxes, you're a liar.
l'm not a liar.
Liars are the second-lowest form
of human being on the planet.
-What's the first?
-Lawyers.
That's you, honey.
Annie, why don't you go with Graham
and hunt for apartments?
Show him how the city's changed.
-Would you mind, Graham?
-No, l'd love that.
-l'd like that, too. Let's do that.
-All right. How about tomorrow?
-That'd be great.
-Good.
One key, huh?
Great idea.
-Yeah.
-Cyndi, John.
Meet me at my house in exactly one hour.
You are scum. l'll be there.
As you can see,
there's plenty of room for two.
No. lt will just be me.
-No party of two?
-No.
You can hang a shower curtain in the bath.
And make sure you put something
in the tub so you won't fall.
-Okay.
You said about 350?
Yeah, and plus the first
and the last month's rent.
All right. Will you lease month to month?
Not for 350.
How about 400?
l can live with that. l can live with that.
-Okay. lt's a deal.
-All right.
-Ready?
-Okay.
-John?
-ln here.
Well, ain't you a picture?
Well, do you like it?
lt's lovely.
ls it for me?
Yeah. lt's for you.
ls that for me?
You're amazing, dear.
Can l tell you something personal?
lt's up to you.
Yeah. Yeah.
Well, you gotta go first.
Okay.
l think that...
l think that sex is overrated.
l think that people
place far too much importance on it.
And l think that stuff about women
want it just as bad as men is crap.
l mean, l think that women want it.
l just don't think that they want it
for the same reason that men think they do.
And l'm getting confused.
-Do you understand what l'm...
-Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. l remember reading somewhere
that men learn to love
the person that they're attracted to
and that women become
more and more attracted
to the person that they love.
God. That's beautiful.
That's really beautiful.
-l like that.
-l'm just quoting.
So are you gonna
tell me something personal?
-Do you want me to?
-Yeah, yeah. l do.
l mean, l don't want it to be something gross
about some scar or something.
l want it to be something
really personal about yourself.
All right. Okay.
l'm impotent.
-You're what?
-lmpotent.
You are?
Yeah. l mean... Well, l can't...
l can't get an erection
in the presence of another person.
So, for all practical purposes, l'm impotent.
Does that bother you?
No.
Does it make you feel self-conscious?
Not usually.
No... Yeah, l'm self-conscious.
Not in the same way that you are, though.
Me? Me? You think l'm self-conscious?
Well...
l've been watching you.
You know, l've been watching you...
l watch you eat. l watch you speak.
Watch you move, and l...
l see somebody who is extremely aware
of people looking at you.
You know, my therapist...
-You're in therapy?
-Aren't you?
No. No, l'm not. No.
l was a miserable failure in therapy.
So you don't believe in therapy?
No, l... l believe in it for some people.
l don't know. lt was silly for me.
l was confused going in.
So l just formed my own theory
that you should never take advice from
someone that doesn't know you intimately.
Well, l know my therapist intimately.
-You've had sex with your therapist?
-No! No! No!
l'm... That's what l meant.
Someone you've had sex with.
l'm... l don't understand.
l mean, how would you know?
l mean, you know. How...
No. l wasn't always impotent.
Okay.
So let me see.
You said...
You said that l should never take advice
from someone that l haven't had sex with.
Right? Right?
-Basically.
-Right.
And we haven't had sex.
-Right?
-No.
So l guess from your own advice,
l shouldn't take your advice.
-l wouldn't.
-You wouldn't. Okay.
All right.
-And drive safely.
-Yeah, right.
-How was your weekend?
-lt was okay.
Did you confront John about the visitor?
The visitor?
The friend of John's
that was staying at your house.
-Graham.
Yeah. l mean... No.
That actually turned out to be interesting.
You know, l was expecting him
to be just like John,
you know, 'cause they went to school
together and everything,
you know,
talking about getting drunk together
and secret handshakes and...
He turned out to be,
really, this character.
He's kind of arty,
but okay.
ls he still at your house?
No. No, no. He's gone.
-So where's he from?
-l don't know.
He used to live in New York
and Philadelphia.
l think he just, kind of, travels around.
Must be nice.
So what's he like? ls he like John?
No. l don't think John likes him any more.
He says he thinks
he's gotten kind of strange.
ls he? Strange, l mean.
No.
l mean,
if l saw him on the street l might think so.
But after meeting and talking to him,
l just say he's kind of unusual.
-So what's he look like?
-Why?
-l just wanna know what he looks like, is all.
-Why? So you can go after him?
Jesus, Ann. Get a life.
l just asked what he looked like.
Besides,
even if l decided to fuck his brains out,
what business is that of yours?
Why do you have to say that?
-Say what?
-You know what.
-You say it just to irritate me.
-l say it because it's descriptive.
Well, he doesn't strike me
as the kind of person
who'd go in for that kind of thing, anyway.
Ann, you always underestimate me.
l wonder why.
l think you're afraid to put us
in the same room together.
l think you're afraid
he'd be undeniably drawn to me.
Really, Cynthia, l don't think he's your type.
My type?
How would you know what my type is?
l have a pretty good idea.
Ann, you don't have a clue.
Look, l don't even know
why we're discussing this.
l mean, l'll just go over and call him myself.
He doesn't have a phone.
Well, l'll call him when he does.
He won't.
What are you talking about?
He doesn't like to talk on the phone.
He's not getting a phone.
Oh, please.
Okay, so give me the Zen master's address.
l'll think of a reason to stop by.
Please. Just let me talk to him first.
Why? Just give me the address.
You won't even have to be involved.
l don't feel right just giving you the address
so that you can go over there and...
-And what?
-Do whatever it is you do.
"Do whatever it is you do."
-Listen to the way you talk.
-l talk fine.
Thank you. l was still smoking that.
What did you lose?
My goddamn pearl earring.
lt cost me a fucking fortune.
l must have left it somewhere.
So what are you getting Mama
for her birthday?
l don't know. l'll get her a card or something.
A card for her 50th birthday?
-Yeah. What's wrong with that?
-Well, the woman gave birth to you.
l think you might be giving her something...
Will you stop? Jesus.
-l just thought that maybe for once...
-Okay, Ann. Okay.
How about this?
You get her something nice,
and l'll pay for half, all right?
Fine. Fine.
-Fine.
Okay, now, if you'll pardon me,
l have to go to work.
What is the most unusual location
you've ever masturbated in?
Well,
one time l was flying
from Los Angeles to New York.
And l was... lt was a really crowded flight,
and l was sitting in the middle.
l didn't get a window. l didn't get an aisle.
lt was really funny.
l was just bored.
My magazines were just boring.
l think l had, like, a woman's magazine.
You know, they touch on a lot of
sexual issues and stuff like that.
And l was just thinking to myself,
"God, that's what I need.
l need a little, you know,
"something to take my mind off this trip."
So l was just thinking away.
And then l just...
l just did it on the plane
just between these two people.
And nobody knew. l mean...
How were you able to not betray
what was going on
to the people around you?
Well, you know, l have really strong muscles.
lt's open.
-Hi.
-Hello, Ann.
-l hope l'm not bothering you.
-No. No.
l would have phoned.
-You busy?
-No. l can finish later.
l just wanted to come by and see what
the apartment looked like with furniture.
Yeah. l'm afraid there's not much to see.
l'm sort of cultivating this minimalist vibe.
-You could use a bookshelf.
-Yeah? You think so?
l don't know. They're all library books.
-What are these?
-Those are videotapes.
l can see that. Of what?
lt's a personal project l've been working on.
What kind of personal project?
-What?
-What kind of personal project?
Personal project
like anyone else's personal project.
Mine's just a little more personal, l guess.
Who's Donna?
-What?
-Donna. lt says Donna here on the tape.
Donna was a girl l knew in Florida.
You went out with her?
No. Not really.
Why do these tapes
all have women's names on them?
Well, l enjoy interviewing women
more than men.
-lt's iced tea.
-Thanks.
l'm sorry. Do you want some lemon?
No. This is perfect. This is perfect.
So all of these are interviews?
-Yes.
-Can we watch one?
No, l'd... No.
Why not?
Well, l promised each of the subjects
that no one would see the videotapes
except for me.
What are the interviews about?
The interviews are about sex.
Sex?
What about sex?
Everything about sex.
Like what?
What they've done. What they do.
What they want to do
but are afraid to ask for.
What they wouldn't do even if asked.
Anything l can think of. Your iced...
You just ask them questions?
Yes.
-And they answer them?
-Yeah.
-Mostly. Sometimes they do things.
-To you?
No. For the camera.
-Graham, this is just so...
-l'm sorry this came up. l'm...
No, l'm sorry. l'm sorry this came up.
l'm gonna go.
-Here. l'll take...
-l'm...
-Goodbye.
-Okay. Yeah, all right.
Okay.
He doesn't want you to come over.
What do you mean he doesn't want me
to come over? Did you tell him about me?
-No, l didn't.
-Why not?
-Look, Cynthia. l didn't have time.
-Well, why?
John's right. He's very strange.
And you don't wanna get involved with him.
What happened over there?
-Did he make a pass at you?
-No.
Well, what's the story, then? What's
this "strange" bullshit all of a sudden?
-l mean, is he drowning puppies?
-lt's nothing like that, okay?
-Well, what? ls he dangerous?
-No, not physically.
Well, what, then?
l don't wanna talk about it.
-Then why did you call me?
-l don't know.
-Hello?
-Cynthia, John.
Not today. l've got other plans.
Well, when, then?
How about inviting me over to dinner?
-You know what l mean.
-Yeah, l know what you mean.
lt's open.
Hi.
Hello.
l... Can l help you?
l'm Cynthia Bishop.
l'm sorry. Do l know you? l don't...
l'm Ann Mullany's sister.
The extrovert.
She must've been in a good mood when
she said that. She usually calls me loud.
Yeah. She called you that, too.
So what are you doing here?
-You want me to leave?
-No.
l just want to know what you're doing here.
Well, like l said, Ann is my sister.
Sisters talk.
You can imagine the rest.
No, l think it's probably better
if l don't characterise that conversation
that l didn't hear.
l don't have any idea really what you or Ann
said about me or anything else.
-Do you want some iced tea?
-Sure.
l don't have any lemons.
The last time l saw Ann,
she left here very confused, l'd say,
-and upset.
-She still is.
So are you here to make me feel bad
for making her feel bad?
No.
-She didn't tell you why she was upset?
-No.
Thanks.
So l don't understand.
What made you wanna come here?
l can't imagine Ann painted
a very flattering portrait of me.
Yeah, well, see,
l don't really listen to Ann
when it comes to men.
l mean, look at John, for Christ sake.
But then you went to school with him,
didn't you?
You're probably friends or something.
No.
No. l think John is a liar.
l think you're right.
So, come on. l came all the way over here
to find out what got Ann so spooked.
Would you tell me what happened?
"Spooked"? The...
The videotapes are what got Ann
so spooked.
-l think l get it.
-Oh, yeah? What do you get?
lfAnn got freaked out by these,
they must be something sexual.
Are these tapes of you
having sex with these girls?
No, not exactly.
Well, either you are or you aren't.
Which is it?
Why don't you let me tape you?
-Doing what?
-Talking.
About what?
About sex, your sexual history,
sexual preferences.
What makes you think
l'd discuss that with you?
Nothing.
And you just wanna ask me questions?
l just wanna ask you questions.
-That's all.
ls this how you get off or something,
taping women talking about
their sexual experiences?
Yes.
-Would anyone else see the tape?
-Absolutely not.
Nobody else sees the tapes except for me.
How long will it take?
Well, that depends on you.
One woman used up only three minutes.
And another used three two-hour tapes.
How do we start?
l turn on the camera, and you start talking.
Do l sit or stand?
-Whatever you prefer.
-l prefer to sit.
Are you ready?
Okay, l'm recording. So tell me your name.
Cynthia Patrice Bishop.
-Speak in a normal voice.
-Okay.
So describe for me
your first sexual experience.
My first sexual experience,
or the first time l had intercourse?
-First sexual experience.
l was
eight.
And... ls this the kind of thing that...
Yeah, okay.
l was eight years old,
and Michael Green, who was also eight,
asked if he could watch me take a pee.
And l said he could
if l could watch him take one, too.
So, we went to the woods behind my house,
and l got this feeling
that he was chickening out,
because he kept saying, "Ladies first."
So l pulled down my little panties
and urinated,
and he ran away before l even finished.
So, was it a topic of conversation
between the two of you after that?
No! He kind of avoided me
for the rest of the summer,
and then his family moved away.
To Cleveland, actually.
-What a shame.
-Yeah.
When did you finally see a penis?
When l was 14.
So what did you think?
Was it what you expected it to be?
No. Not really. l...
l didn't... l sort of pictured it...
l didn't think it would have veins
or ridges or anything.
l just thought it would be smooth,
like a test tube.
lt's weird, thinking about it now.
The organ itself seemed like a separate thing
and a separate entity to me.
l mean, when he finally pulled it out,
and l could look at it and touch it,
l completely forgot
that there was a guy attached to it.
l remember literally being startled
when the guy spoke to me.
What did he say?
He said my hand felt good.
Then what happened?
And then l started moving my hand,
and then he stopped talking.
-Yeah?
-John. Cynthia.
-How'd you get through?
-l told Janet l was Ann.
-She bought it?
-Well, obviously.
Look, l want to see you.
-Well, when?
-Right now.
l don't know if l can do that.
l've got a client waiting.
l've already rescheduled him once.
l'll have to do
some pretty heavy duty juggling.
Then get those balls in the air,
and get your butt over here.
-Yes, sir.
-Janet.
Listen, l want you to reschedule Kirkland.
l know. l know. l know.
See if he can come in Monday anytime.
Tell him... Tell him...
-Family crisis. Family crisis.
-Okay.
-l'll slip out the back.
-Yes, sir.
All right. Bye.
Would you like me to take my skirt off?
lf you wish.
You're not wearing any underwear.
Do you like the way l look?
Yes.
Do you think l'm pretty?
Prettier than Ann?
Different.
John and Ann don't have sex any more.
ls that what he tells you?
He doesn't have to tell me.
You're on fire today.
Yes.
You can go now.
He just asked me questions.
What kind of questions?
Questions about sex.
Well, what did he ask exactly?
Well, l don't wanna tell you exactly.
You let a total stranger record
your sexual life on videotape,
but you won't tell your own sister.
Apparently.
Did he ask you to take your clothes off?
Did he ask me to take my clothes off?
No, he didn't.
-Did you take your clothes off?
-Yes, l did.
-Cynthia!
-What?
-Why did you do that?
-Because l wanted to.
-But why did you want to?
-Because l wanted him to see me.
You're crazy.
He could be bouncing that off some satellite.
Some horny, old men in South America
could be watching you.
Ann! He wouldn't do that.
-You don't know that for sure.
-Well, it's too late now, isn't it?
-Did he touch you?
-No.
-Did you touch him?
Did anybody touch anybody?
Well, yes.
Don't tell me.
Don't tell me!
Don't tell me! You didn't!
-l did.
-You didn't!
-l did. l did!
Oh, my God! Cynthia!
You're in trouble.
Listen to you. You sound like Mama.
What are you talking about?
God, Cynthia!
l couldn't even do that in front of John.
You couldn't even do it, period.
You know what l mean.
You don't even know him.
-l feel like l do.
-You don't!
You can't possibly trust him. He's perverted!
Look, Ann, l don't understand
why this freaks you out so much.
You didn't do it. l did. And if it doesn't
bother me, why should it bother you?
-l don't wanna talk about it.
-Okay, then don't!
Are you an assassin?
Excuse me?
You're just an errand boy,
sent by the grocer to collect the bill.
lt's my Brando. That's pretty good, isn't it?
-Marlon Brando?
-lt's great. Pardon me.
Okay. Yeah.
l was thinking we needed time apart.
Maybe you should be there for a while.
Hi. So why don't you get
an answering machine?
-There's a phone here.
-lt's busy.
Why don't you keep trying?
Okay.
Well, here it is.
-What is it?
-lt's a sundress.
Looks like a tablecloth.
lt does not.
Why would she want a sundress? l mean,
she's got spots on her shoulders
and varicose veins.
Well, Missy Thing, so will you someday.
Yeah. When l do,
l won't be wearing sundresses.
-God, Cynthia...
-Hold on.
-Bayou.
-Cynthia. John.
Well, this is timely. Your wife is here.
-Would you like to speak with her?
-What's she doing there?
She came by to show me a present that
she and l are buying for your mother-in-law.
-So, when can l see you?
-l don't know.
l'm not sure l can duplicate
the intensity l had the other day.
Nothing wrong with trying.
l don't think my sister would agree.
Do you want me to stop calling?
-Look, l'll call you, okay?
-Roger.
Hi. This is too much.
l'm wearing red. You're wearing red.
That's quite a coincidence,
wouldn't you say?
-Look, l'm married.
-Really?
-Are you very married?
-Married enough.
l see. Well, that shouldn't stop us.
l'm just here to see my sister, okay?
Really? Who's your sister? ls she married?
So what's my share on the dress?
$32.50.
-lt's a nice dress.
-Thank you.
-l thought so, too.
-Looks like a tablecloth,
-but it's very nice.
-Keep the change. And, Ann,
don't worry about the dress.
l'm sure she'll like it.
Yeah. l think... You have to go?
Okay. Goodbye.
l'll see you later. l'll call you.
Bye.
John?
l called you last Monday at 3:30,
and they said you weren't in.
Do you remember where you were?
On Monday?
Last Monday.
l had a late lunch.
So who did you have lunch with?
l ate by myself.
Come on.
ls there something wrong?
Are you having an affair?
Jesus Christ!
l have a late lunch by myself,
and now l'm fucking somebody?
-Well, are you?
-No, l'm not.
God, l'm offended at the accusation.
Come on.
lf l'm right, l wanna know.
l don't want you to lie. l'd be upset,
but l'd be more upset if you lied to me.
Well, there's nothing to know.
l can't tell you
how upset l'll be if you lie to me.
ls this paranoia?
l mean, if anybody should be paranoid,
l should be.
Every time l try to touch you,
you act as if l'm dipped in shit.
l think there are a lot of women out there
that would be glad to have a young,
straight male,
making a pretty good living,
beside them in bed with a hard-on.
-My sister, for one.
-For God's sake, Ann.
-ls that who it is?
-Ann, l'm not fucking your sister.
l don't find her that attractive, for one thing.
-ls that supposed to comfort me?
-No, l'm just saying...
l'm just saying l didn't get paranoid
when you didn't want to make love to me.
l mean, l could have easily assumed
that you didn't want to
because you were having an affair.
l'm not.
-Well, l'm not either.
-Then why don't l believe you?
Look, this is ridiculous.
-Maybe when you have some evidence...
-Evidence? There's some evidence?
No, no. That's not what l'm saying. l'm just
saying that we shouldn't not ever talk.
Just don't give me conjecture and intuition.
-Always a lawyer.
-Goddamn right!
l mean, can you imagine? "Well, Your
Honour, l'm just positive the man is guilty.
-"l can't place him at the scene..."
-All right. All right. All right.
-"...but l have this strong feeling."
-All right. You made your point. Okay.
All right.
l'm sorry.
l'm just under a lot of pressure
with this Kirkland thing.
You know,
it's my first big case as junior partner.
l work all day, and l come home,
and l look forward to seeing you.
lt hurts that you'd accuse me like that.
l'm sorry.
What? Come on.
l've just got all this time on my hands,
and l just sit around and start
inventing these, like, intricate scenarios.
And then l don't want to have wasted
all my time, so l want to believe them.
-lsn't therapy helping at all?
-John, l don't know.
l just feel so stupid sitting there
talking about my little problems
when l know
those poor children are starving.
Well...
Quitting your therapy is not going
to feed the children in Ethiopia.
l know.
You never used to say the word "fucking."
Fuck!
lt's so blatantly stupid,
l have a hard time believing you did it.
What's so stupid about it?
You don't even know the guy.
Well, you know him. He's a friend of yours.
Do you think he can be trusted?
l don't know.
From what you've told me, l don't know.
l should have known
when he showed up dressed
like some undertaker for the art world.
l like the way he dresses.
What if this tape gets into the wrong hands?
"The wrong hands"?
John, we are not talking
about military secrets here.
They're just tapes he makes
so he could sit around and get off.
And he doesn't have sex with any of them?
They just talk?
They just sit around and talk.
l could almost understand it
if he had sex with them. l mean, almost.
Why doesn't he just buy some magazines
or some porno movies or something?
lt doesn't work.
He has to know the people.
He has to be able to interact with them.
"lnteract"?
Whatever that means.
Did you have to masturbate in front of him?
l felt like it. Goddamn!
You and Ann make such a big deal out of it.
-You told Ann about this?
-Yeah, she is my sister.
-l do tell her almost everything.
-l wish you hadn't done that.
Why not?
lt's just something l'd prefer
she didn't have to know about.
She's a grown-up. She can handle it.
Ann...
-Ann is just very...
-Hung-up!
-lt just wasn't a smart thing to do.
-Oh, God!
Did you sign any sort of paper, or...
Did he have a contract with you saying
that he wouldn't broadcast these things?
No, sir.
You realise you have no recourse legally.
lt's not funny. lt's not funny, Cynthia.
Those tapes could show up anywhere.
They won't. l trust him.
You trust him. That's funny.
Yeah, l do,
a hell of a lot more than l trust you.
-What do you mean?
-Just what l said.
l'd trust him before l'd trust you.
God, it hurts that you'd say that to me.
Come on, John!
You're fucking your wife's sister.
You're a liar,
but at least l know you're a liar.
l know. l know.
Second-lowest form of human being,
and the first.
-What are you talking about?
-Nothing.
By definition, you're lying to Ann, too.
Yeah, right,
but l didn't take a vow in front of God
and everyone to be faithful to Ann.
Look, are we gonna do it or not?
Actually, no.
l've changed my mind.
l shouldn't have called.
l'm here now.
l need to do something.
Would you like to help me straighten up?
Jesus! ls there one chair
in this place that works?
Well, why don't you go sit somewhere else?
Come on, John.
You should be happy.
We've gone this far without Ann finding out.
l'm making it real easy on you.
Just walk out of here.
-Did he put you up to this?
-Who?
-Graham.
-No, he didn't put me up to this.
Jesus, l don't need people to tell me what
to do. l've just been thinking, that's all.
Now, just leave.
Well, maybe l don't want to leave.
Maybe l want to talk.
John, we don't have anything to talk about.
Yeah, you're right.
Things are getting complicated.
No, they're getting real simple.
lt's open.
Hello.
Want something to drink?
Yeah. Thanks.
Sorry. l don't have any iced tea left.
Thank you.
John and Cynthia have been fucking.
Yes, l know.
-You know?
-Yes.
How did you know?
She said it on her tape.
Thanks for telling me. l really appreciate it.
Well, l haven't seen you.
l don't think l would have told you
even if l had seen you.
Why not?
Because it's not really my place.
My life is shit.
lt's just shit.
Nothing is what l thought it was.
John's a bastard.
Let's make a videotape.
No, l...
l don't think that's a good idea.
Why not?
Because l don't think it's a choice that
you'd make in a normal frame of mind.
And what would you know
about a normal frame of mind?
That's a good question.
So what do you have to do to get ready?
Load a tape and turn on the camera.
Do it.
So, where do you get your money from
for rent and tapes, stuff like that?
Underneath my mattress.
And what are you gonna do
when this money runs out?
lt won't.
Are you comfortable there?
Yeah, l'm comfortable.
Okay, l'm recording. Tell me your name.
Ann Bishop Mullany.
Margaret. Hi, it's John.
Fine. Fine.
Listen, have you seen Ann at all today?
This afternoon?
Well, no, l just... She's home.
Bye-bye. Everything's fine. Thanks. Bye.
Thank God. You had me worried sick.
l come home, the door is open,
the car is gone.
l thought you'd been abducted
by some mad fucker.
-Honey, you all right?
-l want out of this marriage.
What?
l want out of this marriage.
Why?
You're asking me why?
Well, l'm married to you.
You want out of this marriage.
l think you could tell me that.
Fuck you.
All right.
Can you tell me where you went?
l drove around.
Then l went over to Graham's.
Graham's?
Graham.
Oh, God damn it! That son of a bitch!
The backstabbing son of a...
Mr Honesty, huh?
Mr Apostle of Truth!
Well, l know you didn't fuck him.
Did you make one
of these goddamn videotapes?
Annie...
Answer me, God damn it.
God damn it, answer me. Did you?
Yes, l did.
God!
Don't you touch him!
Okay. Cool down.
What?
Hello?
John, what are you...
What the hell are you doing over here?
Damn.
Okay, l'm recording.
Tell me your name.
Ann Bishop Mullany.
So what do you want to talk about?
What do you usually
talk about on these tapes?
Sex.
Okay. Let's talk about sex.
Do you have sex?
Not very often. No.
When you do, who usually initiates it?
He does.
ls the sex satisfying?
l don't know.
l don't know. l don't know what you mean.
Do you have orgasms?
l don't think so.
l mean, l guess since l'm not sure
that l've never had one, l...
Have you ever thought about having sex
with someone other than your husband?
Here we go.
-Why don't we stop?
-No.
l don't wanna stop.
Have you ever thought about having sex
with someone other than your husband?
l've thought about it.
-Did you act on it?
-No.
Why not?
Because that's how Cynthia thinks.
l hate it when l have feelings that she has.
lt bothers me when l think about men,
because l know that's the way she thinks.
What other men have you thought about?
l thought about you.
-Have you thought about me?
-Yes.
What did you think?
l thought about what you would look like
having an orgasm.
l'd like to know what l look like
Can you do that, give a woman an orgasm?
Yes.
Could you do that for me?
No.
Why not?
-Because l can't.
-Can't or won't?
l can't because l won't.
You said you weren't always impotent.
No. Yeah, that's correct.
-So you have had sex?
-Yes.
So, what happened?
Was it so bad it turned you off, or...
-No, that wasn't my problem.
-What was the problem?
l was the problem. l was a...
l was a pathological liar.
Or l am, l should say.
Lying is...
Lying is like alcoholism.
You're continually recovering, you know.
So that's it?
You lied?
-That was part of it.
-So what else happened?
Well, at that time, l...
l used to express my feelings nonverbally
and often scared people
who were close to me.
Are you still like that?
No.
So you're never gonna make love again.
l don't know. l haven't made any plans.
lf you were in love with me, would you?
-l'm not in love with you.
-But if you were.
l can't answer that.
-Why not?
-l told you.
-l don't understand.
-Ann...
Forget about the sex, you know.
l'm not the same person that l was,
even remotely.
You know, l'm different in so many ways
that have a profound effect on the way
that l relate to other people,
the way l communicate.
l mean, this, for instance.
l mean, the way she and l are talking,
that could never have been possible.
"She? The way she and l are talking"?
"She"? Who's "she"?
l'm sorry, l was...
l was... That isn't what l was doing.
She's Elizabeth? ls that who it is?
ls that the girl that John talked about?
ls that who it is?
l guess. l guess.
-So you're still in contact with her, then.
-l'm sorry.
-With Elizabeth?
-No, l'm...
So what do you think Elizabeth
is gonna think about all these videotapes?
l can't imagine her being too understanding.
But you're gonna tell her about them, right?
Since you don't lie any more.
As l said, l don't
know what l'm gonna do exactly. l mean...
Perhaps l won't do anything. l don't...
So you just came back here
so that you could think about it.
No. l moved back here for some...
A sense of closure, you know?
A resolution of some sort.
l wanted somebody
who is very important to me
to understand that, l guess.
That's...
That's pathetic.
l mean, you can't just...
My God, Graham, you...
You just can't walk up to her
and show her you've changed,
like it's some gift or something.
And look what you've changed into.
Nine years.
Nine years,
and this is what you come up with.
ls this what you wanna be
the rest of your life?
Why are you doing this?
Can you tell me that?
Why are you doing this to yourself?
-You gonna answer me?
-No, please, don't do that.
-Why not?
-No, really, don't do that.
Why not?
l just wanna ask you a few questions.
Like why do you tape women
talking about sex?
-Why do you do that? Can you tell me why?
-l can't tell you like this.
Come on. l'm just gonna keep asking.
Ann, l just don't find the turning-the-tables
thing very interesting.
Well, l do. Tell me why, Graham.
-Why?
-What? What do you want me to tell you?
"Tell me why? Why?"
Ann, you don't even know who l am.
You don't have the slightest idea who l am.
Am l supposed to recount all the points
in my life leading up to this moment,
and then just hope that it's coherent,
that it makes some sort of sense to you?
lt doesn't make any sense to me.
l was there.
l don't have the slightest idea who l am,
and l'm supposed to be able
to explain it to you.
And why? You tell me why.
Why do l have to explain myself to you?
Because maybe l can help you.
-Help me with what?
-Your problem.
My problem? Do l have a problem?
l look around me in this town and
l see John and Cynthia and you, and l...
l feel comparatively healthy.
You've got a problem.
You're right.
l've got a lot of problems.
And they belong to me.
You think they're yours, but they're not.
Everybody that walks in that door
becomes part of your problem.
Anybody that comes in contact with you.
l didn't want to be part of your problem,
but l am.
l'm leaving my husband.
And maybe l would have anyway,
but the fact is l'm doing it now.
And part of it is because of you.
You've had an effect on my life.
This isn't supposed to happen.
l've spent nine years structuring my life
so that this didn't happen.
You know, l never told you this
'cause l knew it would crush you.
But now...
l fucked Elizabeth before you broke up,
before you were having trouble, even.
She's no saint. She's good in bed.
She could keep a secret.
That's about all l can say about her.
-l gotta make a call.
-Yeah, sure. Go ahead.
-Brian Kirkland's office.
-Yeah, John Mullany for Brian Kirkland.
-Just one moment, please.
-All right.
Anyway, as l've always said, work is critical.
l can be happy without a marriage,
but if you take away my work...
l mean, that's different.
And ifAnn can't handle that,
well, that's her problem.
-Mr Mullany.
-Yeah?
Mr DeForest would like
to see you in his office.
All right. ln a minute. l'm on with a client.
He said immediately.
All right. Jesus.
-Mr Mullany.
-Yeah.
Mr Kirkland has asked me to inform you
that he's obtained
legal representation elsewhere.
And that if you have a message
for Mr Kirkland, you could leave it with me.
Thank you.
-No message.
-All right, Mr Mullany.
Thank you.
Fool. Well...
Hope he knows what he's doing.
-Mr Mullany.
-Yeah.
Mr DeForest is waiting.
All right. Tell him l'll be in, in a minute.
Jesus. The old man thinks that
the world revolves around a game of golf.
Listen, why don't l catch up to you
at the courts in a few minutes?
-l'd better go talk to DeForest.
-Sure.
Okay.
Fuck.
No, just one's fine. Thanks.
This is my favourite part.
You know what l was thinking?
l was thinking
we should name our first child Rusty.
What do you think of that name?
Okay.
You know, l spend a lot of money in here.
l should at least know your name.
-Hey.
l brought you this.
l knew it was your birthday.
-Thanks.
-lt's a nice plant. Looks like a tablecloth.
Look, l can't stay. l gotta go.
Can l call you?
-Do you have my work number?
-No.
Got a pen?
Okay, now, you're wearing blue,
l'm wearing blue.
ls this some sort of weird coincidence?
l don't think so. l think it's something more.
-Do you live here?
-No. Just passing through.
Look, don't call between 3:00 and 5:00,
'cause l get real busy. Okay?
-Okay.
See you.
-Bye.
-Okay, bye.
l like her. She's a very nice girl.
Very nice.
-Hey.
l think it's gonna rain.
lt is raining.
Yeah.