- Bud.
- Deanie, please.
Bud, I'm afraid.
Oh, Bud.
- Don't, Bud.
- Deanie.
No. We mustn't, Bud.
No. No.
Bud, don't be mad.
I'd better take you home.
We've had enough kissing for tonight.
Deanie.
Has Bud left?
Yes, Mom.
Oh, there's wonderful news tonight.
The Stamper oil stocks-- Drink your milk.
--went up 14 points today.
Think of it, honey.
That means if we sold those stocks
we'd make $15,000.
Maybe we can even send you away
to college next year.
Well, we're not going to sell.
Your father says
that everyone at the Elks says...
...that the stocks are going up
even higher.
Mmm.
Didn't Bud say anything about it tonight?
He doesn't know anything
about his father's business, Mom.
Oh. Hmm.
He doesn't care about that.
What were you and Bud doing
all this time, for heaven's sake?
We were studying together.
I'm going to bed, Mom.
I'm awfully tired.
Deanie?
Now, Wilma Dean.
Deanie.
I wanna talk to you.
Now, Wilma Dean, Bud Stamper
could get you into a whole lot of trouble.
And you know how I mean.
Boys don't respect a girl
they can go all the way with.
Boys want a nice girl for a wife.
Wilma Dean, you and Bud
haven't gone too far already, have you?
No, Mother.
Tell me the truth, Wilma Dean.
No, Mom, we haven't gone too far.
That's a relief. That's a relief.
- Mom?
- Mm-hm?
Is it so terrible
to have those feelings about a boy?
No nice girl does.
- Doesn't she?
- No. No nice girl.
But, Mom, didn't you ever...?
Well, I mean, didn't you ever
feel that way about Dad?
Your father never laid a hand on me
until we were married.
And then I-- Well, I just
gave in because a wife has to.
A woman doesn't enjoy those things
the way a man does.
She just lets her husband...
...come near her
in order to have children.
Deanie, what's troubling you?
Oh, nothing, Mom.
I'm just tired.
I wanna go to bed now.
Now, Deanie...
...you tell Bud Stamper
to bring you home earlier after this...
...especially on school nights.
Good night, sleep tight.
Don't let the bedbugs bite.
Night.
My sandwich.
Our Father which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
- Del. Del.
- Huh? Something wrong?
Wilma Dean and the Stamper boy
are in love.
- They're in love, I tell you, Del.
- Go back to sleep, Mama.
He'd be the catch of a lifetime, Del.
Put it right in there.
I hope we bring in a gusher
for you every day, boss.
Take it, that's yours.
- Hold it, hold it.
- That's yours, go on, take it.
- Boss, Bud's here. Here's Bud, boss.
- Come on in here, my boy.
Bud, your old man's gonna
get us in trouble with our wives.
We're gonna go home
smelling like brew...
...and they're gonna wonder
where we got it.
- They're gonna want some too.
- Get something to eat, son.
- I gotta go up to bed.
- Wait a minute, son. I wanna talk to you.
You men go on, entertain yourselves.
I wanna have a few words with my boy.
Murph, have some more venison.
You don't get meat like that every day.
They don't make that home brew
like that anymore, huh?
This is a pretty late hour for a boy
keeping football training, isn't it?
Come on here. I wanna talk to you, son.
You're the captain of the team, son.
Those other boys look up to you.
You gotta run with the ball.
I wasn't much older than you, Bud,
when I fell off that crown block...
...and I hit that rig floor.
And my running days was long gone.
So....
So you doing the running
for both of us now, boy.
- I wanted talk to you--
- I brought in a well today.
She's flowing over a hundred barrels
an hour. Our stocks are going way up.
Big Eastern companies, they beginning
to sit up and take notice of us.
Them damn people
are really beginning to take notice of us.
- You been out with the little Loomis girl?
- Yes, sir.
You watching yourself with her now,
ain't you, son?
You not doing anything, boy,
you gonna be ashamed of, are you?
No, sir. I--
She's a nice kid, son.
She's a good-looker.
I've known her folks ever since--
Well, old Del and I were boys together.
I got nothing against them, Bud,
because they're poor.
I'm not a snob or anything like that.
The only difference between me and Del
is that I got ambition.
Ha, ha. Hey, Dad, I--
But if anything was to happen,
you'd have to marry her.
You'd have to marry her, son.
You realize that, don't you?
You get a girl in trouble, boy,
and you gotta take the consequences.
- Dad, I'm not--
- Sit down. Well, sit down.
- Well, I wanna talk to you about--
- Sit down, Bud.
I wanna talk to you about
some stuff-- -All right, lay it on me.
Come on, lay it on me.
Lay it on me. Attaboy.
There you go. Lay it on me.
Lay it on now. That's great.
- Lick like a bear. We got a future, boy.
- Yeah.
You and me, we got a future.
The first thing we gonna do,
we gonna get you an education.
Four years at Yale.
Can I tell you a secret, Bud?
- I'll tell you a secret, son. Come here.
- What's that?
My company is gonna merge with one
of those big Eastern companies.
I'm gonna put you in there.
I'm gonna put you in there, boy.
- I'm lining up a future for you, boy.
- I've been thinking about some--
There ain't nothing in this world
that I wouldn't do for you, boy.
There's nothing I wouldn't do,
if you do right.
If you do right, Bud.
Now, don't disappoint me, son.
Don't disappoint me, boy.
God knows
I've had one disappointment already.
- She asleep?
- Yes, finally.
- Is sis back?
- Hello, Bud.
Your mother brought her home
from Chicago a little while ago.
- Welcome home, Mom.
- It was a miserable trip, just miserable.
How's Deanie?
I don't know.
I'm gonna go to bed, Dad.
I'm going to bed too,
but I'm afraid I won't sleep a wink.
Yeah, you go to bed, son.
Got a football game to win tomorrow.
Bud?
I got all my hopes
pinned on you now, boy.
How you men getting on in there?
Well, you certainly
spoiled that girl.
First you send her off
to finishing school--
- Here you go.
- Thank you, Bea.
She breaks all the rules
and they kick her out.
Then you send her off to university. She
goes hog-wild and flunks all her courses.
Then you had to learn your lesson
all over again, didn't you?
Let her go off to art school
in a wild place like Chicago.
She gets tied up with
some cake eater...
...gets her into trouble
just so he can marry her.
- But your lawyer got it annulled.
- You're damn right, I got it annulled.
When I made it perfectly clear
to Mr. Cake-Eater...
...that I was gonna cut off her
allowance, he backed out in a hurry.
Well, she's just
a headstrong little flapper.
But I'm gonna keep her home here
and teach her a little discipline.
Yes, sir.
I'm gonna keep that young lady home,
teach her a little discipline.
If you think I'm going to stay here
in the godforsaken town...
...and have people laugh at me and
gossip, you've got another thing coming.
I'll really give them something
to gossip about.
- Why, sister, you're up so early.
- I can't sleep in this house.
I'm going to California and live
with Aunt Blossom and study art.
Art who?
- Welcome home, Miss Virginia.
- Phoebe.
I hate it here. I'm a freak in this town.
Everybody stares at me
like I was something out of a carnival.
Because you peroxide your hair
and paint your face like an Indian.
Morning, everybody.
- Hey, how are you?
- Just great.
He's gonna make me stay home
a whole year just to punish me.
There aren't any more schools left
that will have you.
Ginny, there's nothing so distasteful
about being at home--
This is the ugliest place
in the whole world.
Everywhere you look,
there's an oil well.
I'll bet you'd drill for a well
in the dining room.
Damn right I would, if I thought
there was any oil under there.
I'll see you later.
How do you
want your eggs, Bud darling?
Hey, you come back here
and eat a decent breakfast.
You have a good breakfast.
You come on back here, boy.
You can't play a football game
on a breakfast like that.
Oh, dear, neither of my children
gets any real nourishment.
- Hi.
- Hey, want a peach?
What? Don't. Bud, don't.
You.
Hi, Bud. Hi, Deanie.
- Hey, Bud.
- Hi.
Hey, Deanie.
Hey, Bud. Bud.
Hi.
- Hi, Deanie.
- Hi.
- Hello.
Hi, Bud.
Hi, Juanita.
Hey.
Wilma Dean,
hereafter I shall count you tardy...
...if you are not in your seat
when the bell rings.
I'm sorry, Miss Metcalf.
Alan, please.
All right.
Now, for the first few weeks
we have been reading...
...the stories of King Arthur
and the Knights of the Round Table.
Now, the literature of the age
was characterized by...?
All right, Alan.
By high ideals.
True. And by what else?
You going with us to the football game?
- All right, Carolyn?
- They were very religious.
Yes, religion played a very
important part...
...in the lives of the knights
and their fair ladies.
What else?
I'm going,
but I'm waiting for Bud after the game.
Oh, we knew that, crazy.
Rusty?
Uh....
The Knights of the Round Table--
- Just because his father's got money--
- That's not true, Kay.
Well, they were very brave
and, uh, things like that.
Bud Stamper isn't
stuck on himself at all.
What do you mean, he isn't stuck on--?
Now what in the world do you mean
by "things like that," exactly?
Well, I don't know exactly.
Let us learn to express ourselves...
...with as much precision as possible.
Juanita, you had your hand up?
The Knights of the Round Table
had a very high regard for women.
In what way, Juanita?
Well, they looked on women
as very pure.
They wouldn't look on her as very pure.
All right now,
I want it quiet in this classroom.
Now, the next time that there is talking
while this class is in session...
...I am going to send the culprit
to the principal's office.
Yes, Juanita, you're quite right.
The knights did have
a very high regard for womanhood.
In fact, they put women on a pedestal.
Some people say
that chivalry is not dead.
Well, how about it, girls?
Do any of you feel
that you're on a pedestal?
Well....
That's unnecessary roughness.
Fifteen yards.
Aw, come on.
You've been on me all day.
You're out. You're out of the game.
Who you taking out
tonight, Toots?
Never mind who I'm taking out.
Juanita, Juanita
Okay, okay, what's so funny about that?
Juanita's the only girl in school...
- ...who knows what it's all about.
- You can say that again.
I'll never look twice at those other girls.
Spend good money on them...
...and they expect you to feel satisfied
if they even kiss you good night.
- Hi, Bud.
- Hi, Juanita.
Say, did you see Toots in there?
Uh, yeah, yeah. He should be right out.
Gee, you played a wonderful game, Bud.
Thank you.
Uh, he should be right out.
Hi, sweetheart.
I suppose you wish I were
more like Juanita Howard, don't you?
What?
I saw the way you were looking at her.
I think she's disgraceful.
The way she stands there
waiting for one of the players.
Wait a minute.
There isn't any reason in the world
why I shouldn't speak to her.
You were more than speaking to her.
You think I'm supposed to not notice
her? Is that what you expect out of me?
I'm not even supposed to know
girls like that exist, huh?
- Bud, I'm sorry.
- Ahh.
- I'm sorry, Bud, honest.
- All right. You're sorry.
Mr. Loomis, a customer for meat.
Oh, Bud. Bud, please don't be mad.
- I'm not mad, Deanie.
- Hi, Bud. Deanie.
- Hi, Mr. Loomis.
- Hi, Dad.
Bud.
Bud, I just can't stand it
when you're mad at me.
Aw, Deanie, I don't know
what's the matter with me lately.
I'm always losing my temper.
You're the only girl in the world for me,
don't you know that?
I wanna be.
And if it weren't for you....
If it weren't for you, Deanie, I'd....
I don't know, I--
- Oh, Bud.
- What?
Bud, it's broad daylight.
- Who cares?
- Stop it. Stop it.
Bud. Come on now.
Bud, people can see us.
- I don't care.
- Stop it, Bud, stop it.
Come on, now.
Mom?
Come on. Come on.
Is she not here?
- Mom?
- Stop it.
- Nobody's here.
Come on now, Bud, now, stop that.
Mom.
Mom?
Yes, Mrs. Harper,
here's your change.
Bud, now, stop it.
- Why?
- I have to pull down...
...the shade to the store.
- Mrs. Loomis, are you--?
- Stop it.
You're nuts about me, aren't you?
You're nuts about me.
I've got your 10-pound sack
in the back of the store, Mrs. Thatcher.
No, Bud.
Bud?
- At my feet, slave.
- Bud, don't.
- Now tell me you love me.
- You're hurting me.
Tell me you can't live without me.
- Say it.
- I do.
- You do what?
- I do love you.
And you can't live without me.
You'd be everything I ever ask you to be.
I'd do anything for you.
Deanie, I didn't mean to hurt you.
Deanie.
Deanie. Deanie, I was just kidding.
Look, I'm the one. I should go down
on my knees to you, Deanie.
Deanie, I was just kidding.
I thought you knew that.
I can't kid about these things.
Because I am nuts about you.
And I would go down on my knees to
worship you if you really wanted me to.
Bud, I can't get along without you.
And I would do anything
you'd ask me to. I would.
I would.
Anything.
Oh, Bud.
Bud.
- Let's speak up at the next meeting.
- I certainly will if you will.
I'm going to go in and fix supper now.
- Bye-bye, Nell.
- Bye, Frieda.
Bud.
Hi, Mom.
The coast is clear.
Are we going to the victory dance?
I can think of things I'd rather do.
I'll be ready.
Okay, I'll pick you up
right after dinner then.
- Did he tell you about his sister, Ginny?
- No.
Well, Ginny Stamper is too low
for the dogs to bite. Come here.
She met some man in Chicago,
put her in the family way.
Mrs. Stamper had to go out there
and get her, take her to a doctor--
Store's all locked up.
Good.
--to have one of those
awful operations performed.
Oh, Mom, that's gossip.
Every word is true.
I was at the DAR this afternoon
and heard all about it.
Mrs. Whitcomb lives
across the street from the Stampers...
...and she knows everything
that goes on in their house.
That's what happens to girls
who go wild and boy-crazy.
Well, congratulations, son.
- Congratulations, son.
- Good game, boy, the game.
Thank you.
Well, I'll, uh, run along upstairs and....
Dad.
Dad, I wanna have a talk with you.
I've had just about all the nonsense
I intend to take out of you, girl.
Now, you get out of here, young lady.
I'm gonna have a talk with my boy.
All right, son.
All right. Go ahead.
- Dad, I'm gonna marry Deanie.
- Whoa, now, son.
Now, listen, Dad.
You see, I don't really wanna go to Yale.
I'm not a very good student.
What do you mean
you're not a good student?
Wait a minute--
You can do anything
you set your mind to.
But, Dad, I'd like to go away to a good
agricultural college for a couple of years.
I'd really like to do that, Dad.
I could come back here...
...and I could take over your ranch
south of town.
- Ranching is no kind of life.
- I could marry Deanie.
I could take her off to college with me.
That's what I really want.
She'd be a big help to me, Dad.
I spent my whole life
trying to create...
...a place of importance
for you in this world.
Then you come home and tell me
you don't wanna go to college.
- You wanna marry some little girl.
- Dad, it's what I want that counts.
Son, a boy your age
doesn't even know what he wants.
After you've had a college education,
then you might change your mind.
A college education
will take me four years.
- Trust me.
- I do trust you, but I--
- Trust me this time, son.
- I trust you, Dad.
- I do trust you. But four years of wait--
- Bud, listen to me, now.
But, Dad.
Son, all I'm asking you to do
is to finish Yale.
Then if you still wanna marry
the little Loomis girl...
...you come back here
and you marry her, with my blessing.
I'll send you both off to Europe
for a honeymoon.
- Bud, please wait. Son.
- I just don't know if I can, Dad.
I feel like I'm going nuts sometimes.
I understand that.
Your old man understands, son.
What you need for the time being, Bud,
is a different kind of girl.
When I was a boy, son,
there was always two kinds of girls.
And us boys, we'd never even
mention them in the same breath...
...but every now and then, one of us
boys would sneak off with a girl.
And we'd get a little steam
out of our system.
Dad....
- No girl looks good to me except Deanie.
- Well, I know, son. I know.
- I love her, Dad.
- I know, son. I know.
- See, I don't wanna do that.
- I know.
Okay, I'll go to Yale.
But I want you know that
I'm gonna marry her a soon as I get out.
It's a promise.
- Well, I want you to remember that.
- It's a promise.
- It's a promise, son.
- Okay.
I'm gonna send you both
off to Europe on a honeymoon.
- It's a promise, my boy.
- Okay.
Bud, I'll wait for you.
I'll wait for you forever.
I'll do anything you want, Bud.
Yes, it's a time
of great prosperity for us all...
...and we must give thanks.
But let us not forget
Christ's warning to the multitude.
Lay not up treasures
for yourself on earth...
...where moth and rust doth corrupt...
...and where thieves
do break through and steal.
But lay up for yourself
treasures in heaven...
...where neither moth
nor rust doth corrupt...
...and where thieves
do not break through and steal.
For where your treasure is...
...there will your heart be also.
Fine sermon. Fine sermon.
Let us pray.
Take my advice, Del,
hang on to those stocks of yours.
As the comedian on the radio says,
"You ain't seen nothing yet."
We're hanging on, Ace.
We're hanging on.
Fine sermon, Reverend.
Fine sermon.
Wonderful passage.
Don't you light that cigarette
in front of all these church people.
Do you want me to be a hypocrite?
Alice, who'd have thought that one day
our kids would be, well...
...engaged, sort of?
I'm mighty proud
of my son's choice, Frieda.
I'm mighty proud of your boy too.
- Excuse us.
- I'll see you at dinner tonight.
- Don't forget, huh?
- All right.
Dad, I'm no spy.
Bud, all I'm asking you to do is keep
an eye on her while I'm in New York.
She likes you, son. She won't do
anything crazy when you're around.
Virginia.
Why, Virginia.
Ow.
Virginia, I told you,
your father has the key to that cabinet.
- And he's on the train to New York.
- That's him all over.
He keeps the cabinet locked...
...because he doesn't think
anybody should drink but him.
You may be shocking Glenn.
Virginia, after all,
we do have Prohibition, you know.
Maybe Glenn doesn't
approve of drinking.
Quick, Henry, the Flit.
Glenn, has your family
lived long in town?
- Um....
- They just moved here from Oklahoma.
Oh, I see.
Is your father engaged
in some business in town?
- Um....
- His father is looking for work...
...and Glenn works at the filling station
on the corner of Sycamore and Main.
Is there anything else
you'd like to know?
Ginny, I see no reason at all
for your bad nature.
Bud, you're not eating a thing.
I'm bored. Come on, let's go.
Ginny, there's a lovely dessert coming.
I don't want a lovely dessert. Glenn
and I are going for a ride. Come on.
- Virginia.
- Deanie and I will go with you and Glenn.
Bud.
Wake up.
Hey, Buddy boy, you're a Boy Scout,
run in and build us a nice hot fire.
My hair's a mess.
- Where?
- Here.
Glenn. Don't, Glenn.
Glenn, stop it. Stop it.
Everybody's wild about Mabel
She's the talk of the town
Mabel's willing and able
To show a guy around
She's a tease, she's a flirt
You better watch out or you'll get hurt
Oh, good, Buddy boy.
Now, how about a drink, hmm?
Oh, I forgot, Buddy boy's in training.
What about you, Deanie girl,
you want a drink, hmm?
Come on, Deanie.
Come on, have a little drink. Come on.
Or is Deanie girl in training too, huh?
Lay off, Ginny.
Oh, why don't you relax? You're just
standing around like a chaperon.
Is that what you came out here for,
just to chaperon Glenn and me?
Ain't he pretty, Deanie, huh?
My handsome filling-station attendant.
Fill me up, please. I'm empty.
- Come on, honey, let's go for a walk.
- All right.
Yeah, why don't you go
for a walk upstairs?
Ginny.
Why don't you quit trying to
pretend you're so pure and righteous?
If you weren't my sister--
If I weren't your sister,
you wouldn't do anything.
You never do anything
except what Dad tells you.
Isn't that right, Deanie?
You've been finding that out,
haven't you?
He just lets things torment him inside
and make him miserable...
...and he never does
anything about them.
He never does anything.
Bye.
All this is gonna be ours someday.
Why, it's the most wonderful
Christmas I've ever had.
Oh, isn't it beautiful? It's the most
beautiful thing I've ever seen.
I wonder what Bud paid for it.
Oh, Mom. I don't see why you always
have to think about what things cost.
If you wanna know the truth,
I wish it cost a lot less and was a ring.
- Don't, Mom.
- Four years, you're gonna be--
Oh, all right, all right.
I just wish that Bud Stamper
had a little more gumption.
Always drink plenty of milk, Deanie.
Still. Still. One, two. There.
Thank you for everything.
And one more, please.
I still don't see why
I couldn't have had a car.
Why should I buy you a car?
You've got your mother's coupé.
That coupé is a wreck.
What have you done
with your hair?
- I just put a henna rinse.
- You look like a circus clown.
Still. Still.
I'll get it.
One, two. There.
Thank God that's over.
- Hi, Ginny.
- Oh, Brian.
My parents are in there.
Oh, Brian.
- Perfume?
- Arpege.
It's my favorite kind.
I just have to slip on my dress.
Come meet the folks. Come on.
They're kind of dull, but you can
stand them for a few minutes.
Go on.
- Hello, I'm Ace Stamper.
- I'm Brian Stacey.
- What can I do for you?
- I'm just waiting for Ginny.
She may take forever.
Come on in. This is my son, Bud.
Come here, son.
Boy is captain of the football team.
You heard about him?
- Well, I don't get to many games.
- Yeah?
- Merry Christmas.
This is my wife, Mrs. Stamper.
Oh, won't you come in?
She's a tease, she's a flirt
You'd better watch out or you'll get hurt
- Ginny.
- Oh!
- Ginny, I wanna talk to you.
- Well, come on in.
Everybody's wild about Mabel
She's the talk of the town
Mabel's willing and able
To show a guy around
Ginny, I know who that guy is.
Ginny. That guy's a bootlegger.
Is he? Here, do me up.
Do you know he's a married man?
How do you know so much about him,
sweetie pie?
- You're not going out with him.
- Is that so?
- I'd like to see you stop me.
- This is Christmas.
You're gonna stay home
and be decent to your mother.
- Get out of my way. Get out of my way.
- You're not leaving here.
Bro-- Buddy.
Buddy.
If you wanna listen to Dad, go ahead.
One of these days, you'll find out.
You'll find out, and then God help you.
All right, calm down, everybody.
Come on now, just calm down.
All right, boys, give me a fanfare.
Give me a fanfare.
Hey, you people, shut up in there.
Give me some gin, baby.
All right, crowd around here.
Crowd around, everybody.
Bring this old New Year in right.
- This is for Joe.
- Oh, boy.
Come on in here.
Bring in the New Year. Come on in here.
Three, two, one. Happy New Year!
Yeah, Smokey. You look lovely, boy.
You're the prettiest baby here.
Shake that jelly. Hey, Daddy, Daddy.
Shake it, Daddy. Happy New Year.
Shake that jelly. Shake it, shake it.
Daddy, look at us. Daddy, look.
Come on, move aside.
Come on here, let me through there.
Hey there, Smokey boy,
let me ring your doorbell.
Happy New Year, Daddy.
Cut that out. You cut that out.
You behave yourself.
You behave yourself, you hear me?
Mr. Stamper,
the perfume is coming.
Yeah, yeah, perfume for all the ladies.
Line up, ladies, line up.
Get your perfume.
Come on, come on.
Get your perfume, all you ladies.
Hey.
Go on, you get in line too.
There's some for you too.
It's gonna be a great year for both of us.
- Dance with me, Dick.
- No thanks, Ginny.
Forget it.
Boy, oh, boy,
she's really plastered.
Hello, Bill.
She's disgraceful.
Well, it's all she can do to walk.
Why doesn't her father do something?
- What did she do?
- Hey.
Charley, will you dance with me?
Um, not right now, Ginny.
Oh, I didn't know you were married.
- Hey, look out.
- Hey.
Hey, what do you think
you're doing in here? Go outside.
Hey.
Joe. Happy New Year, Joe.
Go get your sister, son.
Take her on home.
- Hey, sis.
- Happy New Year.
Happy New Year. Hey, sis? Sis.
- What's happy about it?
- You wanna dance? Let's go.
- Joe?
You don't-- Where are you taking me?
- Where are you taking me?
- Let me just take you home now.
- No. No, I'm not going home.
- Can I do your dress up?
- No.
- Come on.
You know you're
all unsnapped here.
Go tell him I'm not going home.
You don't have to dance with me.
I like to dance with a good-looking girl.
Bull. If you weren't my brother,
you wouldn't even come near me.
You wouldn't come near me.
You're a nice boy, you're nice.
I know what you nice boys are like.
I know you only talk to me in the dark.
In the dark.
You talk to me then, don't you?
You talk to me then
in the dark automobiles, don't you?
You talk to me.
You're very familiar then, aren't you?
Get away from me.
Joe.
Joe, where have you been?
- Come on, Ginny.
- Your mother's watching, Joe.
Joe, Joe, Joe.
- Joe. Where's Joe?
- Here I am.
Joe.
- Let's go, Joe. Let's go.
- Where?
- Anywhere.
- Let's go.
Happy New Year!
Hey, come on.
Leave me alone.
I'm dizzy.
No.
Deanie, did you see where Arnold went?
- Get stood up, Kay?
- Looks like it.
- Bud, would you be an angel, huh?
- Oh, yeah.
- I'll love you for the rest of my life.
- I'll go look for him.
Hey.
Cut it out. It's his sister.
- Now, lay off, Bill.
- Cut it out, I tell you.
- She's his sister.
- He's gone mad.
- Lay low. It wasn't his fault.
- Stop, it hurts.
Stop this fight.
It wasn't his fault. No one's to blame.
- Come on.
- She's not worth it.
Let's go.
Well, she was asking for it.
- Come on. That's enough.
- Hit him.
That's enough.
Watch out, the car.
Stop it, stop it.
Charlie, Charlie, come on.
Come on, Charlie.
Come on, let's get out of here.
All right, all right. Come on, you--
- Come on.
- Bud?
Bud.
Bud? Come on inside a minute, okay?
Bud?
Do you wanna come
inside for a minute?
No. We've gotta stop all this kissing
and fooling around, Deanie.
Bud, tell me what's happened.
I just don't think that
we better see each other for a while.
But....
- Bud.
- I have to go. Goodbye.
We planned this play around you.
You're to be there when the ball is.
- What's the matter?
- I'm sorry.
- Sorry, my foot. You keep training?
- Yes, sir.
- Hours? Diet?
- Yes.
All right, let's try it again.
I said, let's try it again.
I want very much to say this.
I wanna give most of you
a high compliment on your term paper.
They're the best set of papers
I've ever received.
Thank you so much.
- So I want to say--
- Wait for me!
Isn't this wonderful?
- What did you get?
- An A, what do you think?
Bud.
Bud, just a minute.
- I got an A.
- We both got A's.
Bud.
Bud, there's something
I've got to tell you.
- Your term paper was not very good.
- Ha. Well, I guess so.
Just remember
you've got to do much better...
...if you're going to get into Yale
in the fall.
- Bud.
- Hi.
I miss you, Bud.
I just wanted to wish you luck
on the game.
Oh. Uh, thanks.
Come on, Bud.
Dr. Smiley.
- Doc?
- Yes, Bud.
- What happened?
- You tell me.
- Coach?
- What do you want?
- What is it?
- What's the matter?
He just had a fall.
- Coach. Coach--
- A hundred and four.
I'm gonna recommend the hospital.
There's a lot of pneumonia around.
- Pneumonia?
- My God.
Yes, I know.
Doc?
Look, I signed my name to this check.
You pulled my boy through
and I wanted to give you a bonus.
You just fill out the amount.
Five thousand, 10,000--
I'm doing everything
that can be done, Ace.
- Fill out the amount, doc.
- The boy is going to be all right.
- But if he isn't--
- What do you mean, if he isn't?
Ace, I'm not a very religious man,
but I know what every doctor knows.
You can't, uh....
You can't reckon with the will of God.
Just say whatever is in your heart,
Wilma Dean.
All I can think of is, "Dear God,
make him well, make him well."
Then that's your prayer.
But aren't there some words I should say
out of the Bible?
I can't think of any
that'd be better than your own.
Oh, please, God, make him well.
Make him well.
Well, Bud, another week or so,
you'll be feeling yourself again.
Then spring will be here.
You know what happens to a
young man's fancy in the springtime.
- You go with Del Loomis' girl, don't you?
- Yeah.
Mighty attractive girl.
She sure is.
- Doc.
- Yes.
- I'm pretty nuts about Deanie Loomis.
- Oh, I don't blame you.
I mean, I love her.
And she loves me.
But it's no fun to be in love.
I mean, it hurts.
Every time that we're together...
...I have to, uh, remember things.
You know what I mean?
Oh, yes.
And I just can't go back
to, uh, seeing her again.
Not like the way we were doing.
We'd go out every night...
...and I'd hold her and I'd kiss her.
And I'd just go home.
- I mean, a guy can go nuts that way.
- Ha, ha. Well, uh....
I don't know how to advise you, Bud.
Well....
My dad said...
...that I should get another kind of a girl.
Oh, ha, ha, no. No.
But when you don't really want
another girl....
No.
I don't know.
Well, come in again Friday, Bud.
I'll give you another shot of iron
and another sun-lamp treatment, hmm?
Okay, doc.
So long.
- Hi, Deanie.
- Hi, Toots.
And that was
the surest way to lose him.
What did you say?
- He's an animal.
- He is not.
- He is too.
- Yes, I met him.
- You don't know him.
- Who?
One, two, three.
- You're out.
- Am not.
Oh, yes, you are.
- I hurt my finger.
- Kiss it and make it better.
- Hi.
- Hi, Deanie.
- Morning.
What though the radiance
Which was once so bright
Is now forever taken from my sight
Though nothing can bring back the hour
Of splendor in the grass,
Of glory in the flower
We will grieve not, rather find
Strength in what remains behind
Now...
...what do you suppose the poet means
by these lines?
Deanie Loomis?
Oh, I'm sorry, Miss Metcalf, I, uh....
I didn't hear the question.
Well, I know it's spring, Deanie, but
I must ask you to pay more attention.
I'm sorry.
I quoted some lines
from Wordsworth's...
..."Ode on Intimations of Immortality,"
Deanie. Did you hear them?
I'm afraid not, Miss Metcalf.
Well then, I must ask you
to turn your text to Page 380.
Yes.
You read the lines to me.
Stand, please.
Though nothing can bring back the hour
Of splendor in the grass,
Of glory in the flower
We will grieve not, rather find
Strength in what remains behind
Perhaps you can tell me exactly what
the poet means by such expressions as:
"Splendor in the grass,"
and "glory in the flower."
Well....
I think it has some....
Yes?
Well, when we're young...
...we look at things very idealistically,
I guess.
And I think Wordsworth means...
...that when we grow up...
...that we have to
forget the ideals of youth...
...and find strength.
Miss Metcalf, may I please be ex--?
Shh, children!
I'll go see what's the matter.
- Well, hi, June. Hi.
- June, June, I wanna talk to you.
I just gave her a little sedative.
- I'm not sick.
- She'll be all right--
Now, Deanie, now lie down.
- I'm all right. Perfectly all right.
- Now, now, now.
- Stop that, now.
- I'm all right.
I'm all right.
I don't care if his father is making
my folks rich, I hate Bud Stamper.
You'd take a date with
him if he'd ask you.
I would not.
- Oh, you know you would.
- I absolutely would not.
Shh, here he comes.
Hi.
All right.
Bud, why aren't you
going out for track this year?
Got all that work to make up
from when I was sick.
You going to Yale?
Yeah, yeah, if my grades
are good enough.
Hey, Bud, how come
you're not dating Deanie anymore?
- I'm just not.
- I guess I'll just go to cow college.
I'm only a farmer and I know it.
Hot dog, now it's my chance.
Any objections?
I can't stop you.
Deanie. Come on, honey, supper's ready.
Deanie. Come on, honey.
Deanie, come on. Supper's getting cold.
Veal roast, mashed potatoes
and succotash for my girl.
Eat a good meal, Deanie.
Make you feel better.
Always drink plenty of milk, Deanie.
Deanie?
Eat your dinner.
Seventy-six and three-eighths.
What do you know about that, huh?
Seventy-six and three-eights.
Oh, Del. Did you hear that, Deanie?
We're rich. We're rich!
I'll bet the Stampers
are feeling good these days.
Honey, we're gonna send you to college.
We'll get a new car. That I promise you.
Saw young Stamper
driving down the street this afternoon.
Crowd of boys in the car.
Brand-new car his father got him.
Deanie, stop it.
Stop carrying on this way.
Mom, I can't eat. I can't study.
I can't even face my friends anymore.
I wanna die. I wanna die.
Del.
Do you feel better, dear?
Oh, yes.
Oh, yes. Yes.
There's nothing like a good soak, ha.
Deanie, tell me, what's been the matter
the past few days?
I'm sorry I've troubled you.
I didn't wanna worry you.
I didn't wanna worry anyone.
Is it all on account of--? Because of Bud?
Because he doesn't call
for you anymore?
I don't know.
I don't know, Mom.
I have a mind to call that boy
and tell him--
Don't you dare! Don't you dare, Mom!
- Don't you dare! Don't you dare!
- Deanie, I won't do it.
Mama, you do something like that...
...I'll do something desperate.
I will. I will, Mom. I will.
Deanie, how serious
did you and Bud become?
I mean-- Now, you know what I mean.
Deanie, had he...?
Had anything serious happened?
Did he...?
Did he spoil you?
Spoil? Ha, ha. Did he spoil me? No.
Deanie.
No! No, Mom! I'm not spoiled!
- I'm not spoiled, Mom.
- Deanie?
I'm just as fresh and I'm virginal
like the day I was born, Mom.
Stop it. Stop it.
I'm the virginal creature
who wouldn't think of being spoiled.
- Stop it, please. Del, Del.
- I've been a good little girl.
- Good little girl!
- What the matter?
I've done everything Daddy and
Mommy tell me. I've obeyed every word.
- I hate you! I hate you! I hate you!
- Del.
- What's wrong? People can hear all over.
- What are we going to do?
Leave me alone.
- Good grief, what are we gonna do?
- Give her some of that medicine.
Oh, Del, I hate to
give it to her so often.
I'm not spoiled.
- I'm not spoiled, Mama!
- What else can we do?
Deanie, open this door, dear.
Deanie, open the door.
What are you doing? Deanie?
Maybe we should take her to Wichita
like Doc Smiley suggested.
A psychiatrist? Oh, Del.
It'll take money,
but I'll sell those stocks if I have to.
Del, I can't believe
it's that serious.
She's bound to get over it
in a little time.
There's never been any mental trouble
in either of our families.
- Who's this?
- Probably one of her school friends.
How do you do, folks? My name's
Alan Tuttle. They call me Toots.
Yes. Yes, I've heard
Deanie speak of you.
How do you do?
I thought I'd drop in
and say hello to Deanie.
Hi, Deanie.
Hi, Toots.
How are you feeling, Deanie?
I feel all right.
Well, if you two young folks
will pardon us, we'll....
It's almost time for supper.
Very nice to have met you folks.
Yes.
What have you done to your hair?
Enjoyed meeting you too, Toots.
I've been meaning
to come over a long time, Deanie.
To see how you were getting along.
Did you see her hair?
Thanks, Toots.
Shh, I wanna hear what they're saying.
You look fine.
- She's out there in her robe.
- Call no attention to it.
- Thanks, Toots.
- Shh!
So I was wondering if maybe, uh....
Well, maybe you wouldn't like
to go to the dance.
Well, I....
I'd probably be an awful drip
at the dance, Toots.
Look, why don't you say you'll go, and
if anything happens in the meantime...
...you change your mind
or you don't feel like it...?
Huh?
She's a tease, she's a flirt
Everybody's wild about Mabel
She's the talk of the town
- Have a wonderful time.
- I'll take care of her.
- Oh, thank you.
- Toots.
- Good night, Deanie.
- Good night.
I'll leave the door open.
And, Deanie, don't stay out too late.
"Don't stay out too late."
Did you hear her?
She's been saying that to me
since I was knee-high.
I used to think it meant something,
but it doesn't. It doesn't mean a thing.
Hello, Deanie. Glad to see you.
- Hello, Toots.
- Hi, coach.
- Deanie.
You look just beautiful!
Look at your hair.
- Thanks. Oh, I cut my hair.
- You're here!
- You look gorgeous.
- Oh, Deanie.
He's here. And guess who with. Kay.
Hi, Deanie.
- Hi.
- Would you dance with me, Toots?
All right with you, Deanie?
Sure.
- Sure, go ahead.
- Come on.
- Hi.
- Well, how are you, Deanie?
All right, I guess. I don't know.
How are you?
All right, I guess.
So, what's...?
You like?
- Come on outside for a cigarette.
- Okay.
When did you start smoking?
Oh, the past few weeks.
I had to do something.
Mom had a fit,
but she doesn't say anything anymore.
Bud....
- I know why you quit coming by.
- Deanie, let's not talk about it.
I've gotta talk about it, Bud.
All I've done in the past couple months
is just sit home and think about it.
Hey, get out of there.
You said you weren't gonna see him
anymore and here you are in his car.
Deanie, I wanna tell you something.
Every night after dinner...
...I have to force myself from
going to the telephone and calling you.
Oh, Bud.
Deanie, I think about you
all the time, but--
Oh, Bud.
Where's your car?
Oh, come on.
Bud.
- Please, Bud. Please.
- Deanie, cut it out.
- Now, Bud.
- Deanie, you're a nice girl.
I'm not.
I'm not a nice girl.
Come on, cut it out.
I just can't go on like this anymore.
Come on, Deanie,
we're gonna go back inside.
No. No, I don't wanna go back inside.
Bud, I wanna stay here with you.
- I want you.
- This isn't the way it should be.
Why? Why not? Why not?
Why don't you, Bud? Why don't you?
Deanie, where's your pride?
- My pride? My pride?
- Deanie.
- I don't want my pride.
- Stop it.
Stop it, Deanie. Stop.
- Go on, go on. I haven't any pride.
- Deanie.
I haven't any pride!
Oh, God, Deanie,
what am I gonna do with you?
I don't care what you do.
I don't care what happens.
I haven't any pride.
I just wanna die.
Take me away from here.
It's okay, you'll be all right.
Come here.
I put some bread on to set.
We're gonna have some good
homemade bread for a couple of days.
- What are you thinking about, Del?
- Hmm, just worrying about our little girl.
Oh, she's all right now.
Why, she's at the dance and I'll bet you
she's having the time of her life.
Drink your milk.
Stop it.
Don't, Bud, don't.
Bud?
Deanie, come back here.
Where you going?
Deanie?
Deanie? Deanie, come back.
Stop it.
Oh, Bud.
- Bud.
- Deanie, come back here.
Deanie?
Hey, you can't go out there!
Hey, you, come back here!
Hey. Hey, you, come back here.
Hey, isn't that Deanie Loomis?
What's the matter with you?
Come here.
What's the matter with you? Come here.
Oh, Bud.
Hey, she dove in.
What's wrong with that girl?
Somebody better get her.
Billy, come on.
Go on in there after her.
Come on.
Get away. Leave me alone.
Bud.
She hasn't spoken a word of
sense since they brought her in here.
Stay close to her.
- Any word?
- No, not yet.
Not yet.
My baby, my baby. Why did she do it?
I don't wanna see you ever again.
- Mama, quit talking like that.
- I don't care.
He's the cause of all her trouble.
He's the cause.
- What did you do to her tonight?
- Now, Mama.
I want him to answer me.
Bud, she doesn't
mean what she's saying.
I do too.
- My little girl. I want my little girl.
- Mama, quit getting all worked up.
How can I help getting worked up
when my baby...?
My baby lies there fighting for her life.
Frieda, I'm sorry.
By George, Del,
I'm sorry to hear about this.
Son.
Is she all right?
They don't know
what's the matter yet, Dad.
Del.
I'm afraid your daughter's
in a very nervous condition.
I wanna see my baby.
Not now, Mrs. Loomis.
Perhaps tomorrow.
Have you thought about
what I suggested to you?
- Yes, I'm going through with it.
- Oh, Del.
I'm gonna sell those stocks and
send that girl off to Wichita...
...as soon as she's ready.
Good, I'll make the
arrangements for you.
All right.
Now, Mama, I think it's time
you and I were home in bed.
Doc, look, I'm gonna marry Deanie.
I don't care what he says, doc.
- Good night, Bud.
- Good night, Mr. Loomis.
I'm legal aged, I don't care what
he says. Doc, I'm gonna marry her.
Bud.
Nurse.
Bud, do you wanna help Deanie?
Then stay away from her.
- For how long?
- I don't know.
I don't know now. No one does.
Who's that?
- Who's there? Who's there?
- There's nobody, nobody.
Was somebody here?
Somebody was here.
You have another letter from your father.
I'm beginning to think
you wanna get thrown out of school.
Angelina.
Excuse me.
- Angelina.
- Uh-huh, uh-huh.
Hey, uh....
Angelina, do you think I could have
another one of these home brews?
Mister, you drink, you're gonna get sick.
Let me bring you some food.
Would you like something to eat?
My mama's making some pizza in
the kitchen. Would you like some pizza?
What is pizza?
You don't know what pizza is? Ha, ha.
Where are you from?
- I'm from Kansas.
- Kansas.
Where is that?
It's right in the middle of the U.S.A.
So that's where your home is.
Hmm.
Is it nice out there in Kansas?
Yup.
It's very friendly.
That's what it's like, it's friendly.
Everybody knows your name,
and they know who you are.
Why don't you go back?
You must have a sweetheart out there.
I did.
Come on out in the kitchen with me.
My mom will give you some pizza.
- Well, I--
- Come on. Sure.
- I'll have some pizza.
- Heh, heh. Come on.
- That's fine, you're up.
- Angelina?
- You all right?
- Angelina.
- Mama?
- Here.
No.
What?
- What?
- Are you all right, mister?
Sure you are.
Uh-huh.
- Hi.
Steady as she goes.
Sit on that bench. I'll be right with you.
All right?
No, that's for Mr. Mangolomino.
What do you think--?
What do you think about that?
Sort of squint your eyes a bit.
- What would Cézanne say to that?
- Well, that's swell, Deanie.
I never thought
I could do this well, really.
Looks better with one eye closed.
Oh, you. Ha-ha-ha.
I like metalwork though. You can get rid
of a lot of hostilities this way.
Watch.
Every time I pound,
I tell myself it's my old man.
My old man had his heart set
on my being a surgeon.
Well, not just a surgeon,
but the greatest surgeon who ever lived.
Well, so anyway,
I couldn't make that first cut.
That first cut into the flesh
of another man's body.
I shook. I couldn't keep
my hands steady, firm--
Oh, you can still be an M.D.
when you get out though.
- If I ever get out.
- Oh, Johnny, don't talk like that.
I'm kidding, I hope.
Deanie, your parents
are in the waiting room.
Mother and Dad are here?
Johnny, my folks are here. I haven't
seen them for about six months.
Not since I've been here.
Oh, Del, I hope these
people know what they're doing.
How much longer
are they gonna keep her here?
Here she comes.
Oh, my.
Mom, don't let Deanie see you
looking this way.
- My baby! My little baby.
- It's good to see you.
Oh, Daddy. Oh, it's so good to see you.
Oh, doesn't she look just fine, Del?
Oh, they can't tell me there's
anything wrong with my little baby.
Why, she's just as sound and normal
as the next one.
I brought our little girl a box of candy.
- Oh, thank you, Daddy.
- Come on, honey.
And all the girls in your old gang
wanted to tell you hello.
Oh, yes. Your father had to go
and tell everyone where you are.
- Oh, I'm not ashamed, Mom.
- Come on, sit down, sit down.
Well.
Now, let's see.
Um, Kay's gone off to
Mrs. Finch's school. Very elegant.
Oh, her folks are very wealthy now,
you know. Ha, ha.
And June, June calls about you
every week or so.
- I guess you know she married Bob?
- Oh, yes, we write once in a while.
And Carolyn and June
are off at the university.
Now, Carolyn pledged, um, Pi Phi.
And Hazel, um, pledged Kappa.
Which is better?
- I don't know.
- The university isn't far from here--
Mom.
Mama.
Maybe you'd like them to come
and see you some Saturday.
I don't think so, Mom.
Oh.
No, no, I guess not.
I guess it wouldn't be suitable.
But there's nothing the matter with you.
You just remember that.
You are perfectly all right.
Just as well off as Kay, or June,
or Hazel, or any of those girls.
- Mama.
- Yeah?
Maybe....
Deanie, would you like to have dinner
with us tonight down at the hotel?
I, uh....
Deanie's had a very trying day,
she's too tired.
Yes, I'm awfully--
We're not gonna see any more of you?
This? This is all we get to see of you?
Mom, I'm sorry.
We drove all the way up here
just to be with our baby.
Now they tell us
we can't be with her tonight.
You want what's best for your daughter,
don't you, Mrs. Loomis?
Yes.
Yes, I want what's best
for my daughter.
- We'll take our little girl out to dinner--
- I'm sorry.
--the next time we come up, Mama.
Mom kept calling me her baby.
And dad kept calling me his little girl.
Dr. Judd, don't they realize I'm me?
You're the one who's gotta change,
they can't.
I don't think I could ever
go back home again.
I don't think I could feel the same way
I used to feel about them.
You'll just have to
accept them as people.
With a lot of faults maybe,
but not as "Mama" and "Papa."
- As people?
- Hmm.
You know, we blame our parents
for everything these days.
You gotta remember
they had parents too.
I suppose.
You had a mama and a papa too.
Oh, yes, most assuredly.
That will be all, Deanie. You can go now.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Deanie?
Have you heard from that young man?
What was his name? Bud?
No.
No, we've, um, given up writing.
I guess he's probably away at school.
I don't know.
No one ever writes me
anything about him.
I guess they're afraid
that it would upset me.
Well, would it?
Well, maybe you'll feel
a little stronger about it in time.
I hope so.
I'll bet they've been practicing
some of that Freud on her too.
Oh, I've read about him.
All he's concerned about is sex.
And it's costing us every blessed penny
we made on our stocks.
If we could have held on to those
stocks, we would've made a fortune.
I don't think it's very polite
of you to turn on...
...the radio when I'm talking to you.
Stock prices crashed
today in the most disastrous trading...
...ever encountered
on the New York Stock Exchange.
Fourteen billion dollars was lost
in a nationwide attempt to unload.
"Sell out"?
What do you mean, sell out?
You're getting panicky
like everybody else.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Now, just don't get panicky, Jack.
Don't lose your courage.
Come in.
Hang on, Jack. Just hang on.
Just hang in there.
No, listen, I can't go on with this
right now, Jack.
- Sit down, friend, I'll be right with you.
- Okay.
I'm in New Haven.
Oh, my kid's in school up here.
Oh, hell, he's doing just fine. Flunking
every course, but otherwise fine.
No, he'll be all right.
I got an idea what's wrong with him.
Yeah, I'll be calling you.
- Well, what did you find out?
- You were right.
I knew it, who is she?
- She's a waitress.
- Waitress?
In a pizza place. It's all right here.
You want a drink?
- Bud, suppose you--
- He just hasn't been applying himself.
I know my boy. He could pass
any course you offer...
...flying colors, straight A's.
Thank you.
Suppose you tell us
what you think is the matter, Bud.
Have you really been interested
in your work here at Yale?
- Well--
- Interested?
What difference does that make?
I sent you up here to make
your grades and graduate.
Well, I'm sorry to disappoint you,
Dad, but--
Now, why don't we just
talk turkey, son?
Why don't you tell us
what's on your mind.
What's eating up
your time and energy?
There's a long-distance call
from New York for Mr. Stamper.
- Urgent, right this way, sir.
- All right, thank you.
Is there anything you'd rather be
doing now than going to school here?
To tell you the truth, Dean Pollard,
I never wanted to do a thing but ranch.
But Dad--
I've never held the belief
that everybody should go to college.
Well, maybe you could talk to him.
He isn't a very good listener,
really, is he?
I gotta get back to New York right away.
Bud, suppose you let me, uh,
talk to your father.
Oh, yeah, sure. Thank you.
I'll see you back in your room, son.
Dean Pollard,
what's the matter with people?
What do you mean?
I mean the whole town of New York
is jumping out of windows.
I mean, they're quitting.
And things are gonna get back to normal
in a couple of days.
- You really think so?
- I know so, I know so.
They got to, they've got to.
Now, about the boy, I'm gonna take
him to New York with me...
...and I'll have him back up here
Monday morning...
...ready to settle down and go to work.
I must say, Mr. Stamper...
...I do not feel that the boy
should remain in school here.
Please, don't give up on him.
Don't give up on him, Dean Pollard.
I had to go through something
like this with him once before.
He fall for some little girl
and then that's all he can think about.
- I don't think that's it--
- I think that's it, I think that's it!
I think I've known him a little bit longer
and a little bit better than you have.
I had to break up
something like this before...
...and I'm gonna have to
break it up again.
I'll have him Monday morning,
ready to go to work.
Kewpie dolls.
Would you like a kewpie doll
for your cutie-pie?
- Yeah, how much are they?
- Fifty dollars.
All right, you fish out 50 out of there
and you give me the rest back.
- Thank you.
- Oh, thank you.
- Bye.
They all look the same in this town.
The newlyweds.
Come on, stand up.
Give the little girl a hand.
She's earned it.
Hello, suckers.
I think I smell fresh money tonight.
I'm glad you didn't let a little thing
like the stock-market crash...
...keep you from coming out tonight.
Tonight as I was walking down
Park Avenue to get a taxi...
...I had to dodge the bodies
jumping out of the windows.
Ahh, but let's don't be morbid.
- Same all around?
- No more for me.
Yeah. Same all around. Same all around.
Lay one on me. Lay one on me.
- Hey, Dad, let's go.
- Wait, Bud, wait a minute, now.
I haven't gotten to the point
I'm trying to make.
I never have been able
to make this one point with you, son.
Bud, listen, I may not be around
too much longer and I--
- What are you talking about?
- Wait a minute.
Now, don't act so worried, I got no
intention of kicking off for a while.
What are you leading up to?
Bud, it may be that I haven't always
done the right thing by you, boy.
And I'm sorry.
Anything I might have taken away...
...I'd like to make it up to you.
Forget it, Dad.
Look up there.
Look up there on that stage.
Deanie.
Yeah, she does look
a little bit like Deanie.
Little, hell. Hell, a little.
Exactly the same damn thing.
Just as pretty, just as pretty.
You never been fair to me on that.
I did that for your own good.
How would you like
to be married to her now?
Did you ever think about that?
How would you like to be married
to Deanie and her in that institute?
Did you ever think about that?
How'd you like it?
How'd you like that,
her in that institution?
Oh, what the hell
difference does it make?
That's the same thing.
That's the same thing exactly.
And just as pretty, just as pretty.
You look up there at that, just as pretty.
You want that?
Do you want it, son?
If you want it, you can have it.
You can have it, boy. I'll get it for you.
You can have anything you want.
Anything you want, boy.
This world is your oyster.
You sit here, I'll show you.
You sit right there, I'll show you.
You sit there now and I'll show you.
Yeah?
- Yeah?
- Are you Bud?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Aren't you gonna invite me in?
I'm sorry, but I think
you must have got the wrong room.
Mr. Stamper?
Mr. Stamper.
- That's him.
- What do you wanna do with, uh...?
I'll take him home.
Well, I'll be home in a few hours.
First time in....
Two years and six months
almost to the day.
- How do you feel about going home?
- Like going to a foreign country.
Dr. Judd,
John has asked me to marry him.
And you waited until now to tell me?
- Well?
- Are you gonna accept?
- I don't know.
- Do you love John?
I think so.
It's different from the way
that I felt about Bud.
But I....
I love him.
Well, I see no reason why both of you
shouldn't have a very happy future.
John's back in Cincinnati now,
practicing medicine.
- Doing very well.
- Oh, I know.
I hear from him every day.
Oh.
My taxi.
- Well, I....
- Taxi's here.
Will you see Bud
when you're home?
I don't know.
Do you think you'll be happy
married to John...
...if you still don't know how you feel
about the other young man?
And when we face these fears,
they sometimes turn into nothing.
Deanie?
All right, Dr. Judd.
I'll see him.
I'll write to you.
Bye-bye.
I don't know why you couldn't have
married a boy from here.
You're not gonna be much company
for me living back east in Cincinnati.
What do you know
about this young man you're marrying?
After all, you met him in a mental
hospital. Are you sure he's all right?
- Well, I was in the hospital too.
- Well, with you it was different.
You were just run-down. That was
the only thing the matter with you.
Hmm....
- Is he a New-Dealer?
- I don't know.
I could cry, just cry,
when I think I'm gonna lose my little girl.
- How much did this cost?
- I don't know, Mother.
Deanie.
Did those doctors at the hospital say...
...your mother had raised you wrong
or something?
Did they blame your father...
...and me in any way?
I don't blame anyone, Mother.
I raised you the only way I knew how,
Deanie. The only way I knew how.
The way my mother raised me and
I suppose the way her mother raised her.
If I brought you up wrong, Deanie,
I don't think you should hate me.
Well, I know I used to hate
my mother at times...
...but I always believed
she was right about things.
Maybe she wasn't...
...but I loved her.
I love you, Mother.
I hope so, Deanie.
You know, it would be nice if children
could be born into this world...
...with an absolute guarantee...
...that they were going to have
just the right kind of bringing up...
...and all lead happy, normal lives.
But, well, I guess when we get born,
we just all have to take our chances.
- Mom?
- Hmm?
- Is he married?
- Who?
Oh.
Well, to tell you the truth, Deanie,
I don't really know.
Needn't be afraid of running into him.
He's living with his mother
down in Tulsa.
She joined her folks there,
after old Ace killed himself.
Oh, they say
she's poor as a church mouse.
And that girl Ginny?
Got killed in a car accident.
Oh, we all knew something like that
would happen, the way she carried on.
No, now the Stampers
are almost extinct in this town now.
You know their home
has been turned into a funeral parlor?
Deanie, Deanie.
Some of the old gang here
to see you, Deanie.
- I can't wait to see her.
- It seems simply ages.
How is she, Mr. Loomis?
She's fine.
Deanie. How are you?
June.
Hazel.
Come on, you go for a ride with us.
Give me two minutes
to wash the train off.
Okay.
Girls, just one thing.
Keep her away from Bud Stamper.
Mrs. Loomis,
she's forgotten about all that.
- No, no, she hasn't, have some fudge.
- Yeah, thank you.
The very first thing she did
was ask about him...
...and then she laid on the bed
and cried and cried.
Oh, I thought maybe the years away,
she'd forget about him but....
Now, I want you to promise me.
The doctors say
she's perfectly all right now...
...but there's no use in asking for
trouble. Keep her away from him.
Well, here's our girl.
Hazel, June.
I wanna see Bud now.
Now, honey, you just forget about him.
Gee, I'm not even sure
where he is now, Deanie.
I mean, well, no one ever sees him.
Do you know where he is, Hazel?
He's staying out
at his father's old ranch.
Deanie, it's
a long way out there.
I know,
I want to go there, please.
Clear out of there.
- Well....
- You want me to go looking for Bud?
Oh, Hazel, would you?
Bud?
He's around back.
- Oh, June.
- I know.
- Bud?
- Yeah?
- Oh, Hazel.
- Hi, Bud.
- Jeepers, you're a mess.
- Yeah, I been working.
We got about 40 head of cattle
and we're eating regular--
Bud, Deanie's out there in the car.
- Deanie?
- Yeah.
Oh, gee, I hate to see Deanie
when I'm so dirty.
She won't mind, Bud.
Uh, how is she?
She seems just fine.
Well, I'm glad.
Hi, Bud.
Long time no see.
- A long time.
- It's good to see you, Deanie.
Thanks, Bud.
Hey, you wanna meet my family?
Of course.
Come on.
She didn't even know he was married.
You're her best friend,
why didn't you tell her?
I just couldn't.
- Angie?
- Yeah?
- Angie.
Come on out here, honey.
I want you to meet somebody.
Hello.
Uh, Angelina, this Deanie.
An old friend of mine.
Oh. How do you do?
How do you do, Angelina?
Would you like to come in?
- Please.
- Well, I....
- Come on.
Hungry?
The house, it doesn't look like much.
- Maybe I can offer you some wine?
- Thanks, Angelina, but I really can't stay.
Oh. Uh, this is Bud, Jr.
The one without the feathers.
Oh, sure.
Hello, Bud, Jr. Hello.
Oh, what a fine boy you are.
So now we're expecting another child.
I hope it's a girl this time.
You're a fine boy.
Well, I have to go now.
You will come back again sometime?
- Will you come back for dinner?
- Thank you, Angelina.
I married Angie when I left New Haven.
You know, I didn't even finish
my first year in school there.
She's real nice.
She was wonderful to me
when things started to go wrong.
You're happy, Bud.
I guess so.
I don't ask myself that question
very often now.
How about you?
- I'm getting married next month.
- Are you, Deanie?
A boy from Cincinnati.
I think you might like him.
Gee, things work out awful funny
sometimes, don't they, Deanie?
Yes, they do.
Hope you're gonna be awful happy.
Well, like you, Bud, I don't think
too much about happiness either.
Aw, what's the point?
You gotta take what comes.
Yes.
Well....
Deanie?
I'm awful glad to see you again.
Thanks, Bud.
Goodbye.
Bye.
- June.
- So long, Bud.
Hello.
You girls will have to come out
again sometime.
- You might ask us.
- Oh, I will, I promise.
Angie and I got a little more money
coming in now...
...we'll have a big beer party.
She'll call you.
- It's a date.
- Great.
Goodbye.
When do we eat?
Deanie, honey,
do you think you still love him?
Though nothing can bring back the hour
Of splendor in the grass,
Of glory in the flower
We will grieve not, rather find
Strength in what remains behind
Subtitles by
SDI Media Group