Don't move.
Turn around.
Keep your hands wide.
You want something
from me, mister?
Sure came up quiet.
Got to give you credit.
My name's Tate.
Guess that don't mean
much to you,
or anyone else, huh?
This here is Pokey.
You fixing to meet somebody?
Meet somebody? Who?
Wouldn't mind if I did.
Wouldn't care who he was
or where he comes from
or what he does.
A man ought to always
mind his own business, I say.
Looks like you're the one
expecting company.
How long have you been here?
Been poking around these hills
three or four weeks now.
Got no calendar to know exact.
Got nothing to show
for it either.
If you're ready to talk some,
I'd appreciate
your putting that gun down.
You might get bee stung
or something
but I'd be just as dead.
Got some breakfast
coffee boiling.
- You want some?
- No.
Eh, tobacco?
This party you're asking
after...
Friend of yours?
He killed a marshal.
Kansas?
You've come a ways.
It ain't every peace officer
who'd do that.
I ain't seen Kansas
since before the war,
so I wouldn't know
you to look at.
My name's Tate, like I said.
Jesse Tate.
Howard Kemp.
You figure he's back
in these hills, Mr. Kemp?
I lost his trail
this side of the river.
- Did you see any sign?
- Hmm.
Ran across a dead fire
the other day.
- Where?
- Back in there.
Got no map to tell you sure.
Now, you can tell me
better than that.
Maybe. If we was going the same
way, but we ain't.
You got your job, mister,
and I got mine.
Helping you don't put
no money in my pocket.
- I got $20 here.
- $20!
$20. It's yours if you get
me on a fresh trail.
$20! Ah!
$10 now...
$10 now, $10 when we find him.
Start out by showing me
that dead fire.
Does this fellow know
you're after him?
He knows.
Then he might be waiting
behind some rock.
Waiting for us to ride up
in front of his gun.
He might.
It was still warm yesterday.
Horses moved out this way.
More than one, for sure.
This fellow got company?
Could be packing an extra horse.
But there might be two of them
waiting for us, huh?
That's why you held
the gun on me.
Come on, let's go. Come on.
Trail's as plain for you
as it is for me.
- Another fire.
- They ain't making much time.
Must be something
wrong with them.
- Looks like a horse fell there.
- Yeah.
- Well, it's no use guessing.
- Ahhh...
- Look out, rocks!
- Ride!
Well, I guess that's
the end of it.
Yeah, if it was
a natural slide.
Look out! Look out!
Well, you found him.
Uh, he's got to come
down sometime.
Yeah, but when?
A day, a week.
And the chance is
he sneaks down some night
and gets us.
We'll take turn on watch.
Having it out with this fellow
ain't my job, not for no $20.
You've got him,
but he got you too.
Unless there's another
way up there.
You're crazy!
You can't get up there!
Go up the trail
and get some cover
and take a shot at him
every once in a while,
and make him think
we're stuck down here.
Ain't we?
Come on.
Hold it!
- What's the trouble?
- Get down.
I heard some shooting
and came to look.
Who are you?
Oh, that's the way it is?
Lieutenant Roy Anderson,
sixth Cavalry.
Indian fighter extraordinary.
You're a long way
from an army post, lieutenant.
I quit playing soldier
last week.
Let's see your discharge.
I'm riding east, from Fort
Ellis. What's wrong with that?
Nothing, except the Bozeman
trail runs east from Ellis.
How come you're
this far off it?
Well, you see, there's some
bad-tempered Indians
along the Bozeman trail and...
seems this chief's daughter
fell into some trouble
with a handsome,
young army lieutenant, and...
Well, you know how it is.
The army never
did understand me.
Yeah.
Hey, how about these?
Alright, give him back his gun.
Come on.
Oh, you never did tell me
what the shooting was about.
I don't even know
who I'm talking to.
This here is Mr. Kemp.
My name is Tate, Jesse Tate.
You don't say?
We've got an outlaw killer
trapped up there
starting rockslides
every time we show our heads.
An outlaw killer
throwing rocks?
- That sounds real desperate.
- Come on.
Show him the picture, Mr. Kemp.
Come on, show me.
You followed him
all the way from Kansas?
He did. I joined up
with him this morning.
Sort of helping out.
Like a deputy.
Looks like you got
yourself a real
interesting problem
in tactics, sheriff.
Yeah. Come on up the trail.
Crazy, ain't it, Pokey,
what one man
will do to catch another?
Now, if it was gold up there,
instead of this outlaw,
I'd put my carcass to climbing
that cliff and never
think twice.
Hey, come on.
I thought you said
you were going some place?
Oh, don't mind me,
I won't get in the way.
I'll be right here
behind you, sheriff,
in case the bad man
sticks his head out.
Wonder if I can make it.
- Now, what do you want here?
- Just offering my help.
- Why?
- Why are you turning it down?
If I burn my hands,
I'll let you try it again.
Now, stand by with your gun.
I did as much for you.
Now, ain't that the way?
A man gets set for trouble
head-on,
and it sneaks up behind him
every time.
That's life.
Get up.
Open your gun belt
and let it fall.
No need to fuss there, soldier.
I've been out of cartridges
since Abilene.
You can see.
Now why don't you just
do what I say?
Hey, you two!
It's all over!
Get him, Ben!
Alright, Ben.
Tie him up!
Let me go, let me alone!
Let me alone!
Calm down, sweetheart,
we're not gonna hang you.
I ain't fighting you
no more, Howie.
- Not the three of you, I ain't.
- Who's she?
You remember old Frank Patch,
don't you, Howie?
This here is his daughter, Lina.
I remember an outlaw,
name of Patch,
lying dead in front
of a bank in Abilene.
I don't remember
any talk about kinfolk.
He was my father.
What's she doing
here with you?
I guess she don't know
nobody but me.
And I didn't figure on seeing
Kansas again.
Till now I didn't.
Alright, get up.
Come on, get up!
Here you are, Tate.
That settles us.
- I'm much obliged to you.
- Thanks.
Say, Mr. Kemp, now you've got
two of them to handle,
maybe you still have a mind
to hire up help.
This is my job, I'll do it.
Make you feel any better,
sheriff,
you can make me deputy,
official-like.
You ain't letting
on like you was
a sheriff or something,
are you, Howie?
Why, sure he is. Ain't he?
He told me he was
a peace officer.
I don't know
why you should do that.
No matter who gets me,
the reward still holds.
How's that?
Ain't you showed him
my picture, Howie?
I seen a paper saying
he was wanted,
nothing about no reward.
Maybe he ain't got a good copy
like I have.
- Is that what he showed you?
- How much?
Says $5,000. Why, you talk like
you knowed it all along.
Why else would a man
tear off the bottom of a poster?
I'm taking him back
and I'm gonna do it alone.
You didn't catch him alone.
You was goin' round and round
until you run into me.
You were hired to do a job
and you were paid for it.
You ain't gonna buy
my claim on this for no $20.
What about him?
He done the climbing, didn't he?
Could have gotten killed, too.
Tell you what,
I'll settle for a third.
How about you, Jesse?
Share and share alike?
That's the way it is.
Unless you're of
a mind to kill us all.
Looks like you got yourself
a couple of partners, Howie.
Ahh. Quit acting like we
was friends! You...
Maybe we sat down at the same
card game once or twice
but that don't mean
dirt to me now.
You shot a man in the back
and I'm taking you in
to hang for it.
It wasn't Ben
that killed that man.
It's him they're paying
the reward on.
- Now, where are your horses?
- Back at the rocks.
Lina's horse has got a bellyful
of disease. He can't travel.
He can't, huh? Alright,
come on, let's go. Come on.
Easy, boy, easy.
Easy there, boy.
Alright, watch him.
Easy, boy, easy.
He's really sick, mister,
that's why we held up here.
Must have took bad
water some place.
I rode him two days like this
when he should have
rested and throwed it off.
Easy, boy. Easy.
What are you gonna do, mister?
Oh, that horse is suffering,
he can't hardly breathe.
You've seen sicker horses
than this, ain't you, mister?
He's pretty bad, girlie.
No sense in shooting
a good horse
just to hang me a day sooner.
You keep out of this.
Besides, if we ain't
to the big river
before the rains,
it's another week downstream
to find a crossing.
Nobody's gonna touch my horse.
Nobody is.
Nobody is gonna touch my...
Come on, girlie, you don't
want to leave him
for some cat or bear
to rip open.
No, I'm not gonna go, no...
Let me.
Well, there's no reward
for killing my horse!
Ben, don't let them
kill my horse.
Don't let them kill my horse!
Listen to me! Listen to me!
That horse wouldn't have
lasted the night, anyway.
Forget about him. Start worrying
about me swinging from a rope.
- You want that?
- No.
I need time.
You understand, Lina?
Time. And you've
gotta help me.
I've already scratched open
a sore spot over that reward.
The longer we ride,
the more things that can happen.
That's the fight.
Are you listening?
Listen to me.
I heard you, Ben.
I heard you.
Alright, come on.
Move, you lop-eared
cactus-eater!
Quit dragging your feet.
Pokey don't like it
no more than you do.
Honey, first thing I'm gonna get
you out of that reward money
is the biggest steak in Kansas,
for that cheek.
Oh, you're not gonna be mad at
me all the way, are you?
Come on, I'll make it up to you.
What're you doing tonight?
You're having quite a time,
aren't you?
Ahh, come on, loosen up.
Spring is here.
It's gonna be a long,
lonely ride to Abilene.
And being as Jesse's too old,
I'll toss you for her.
Right now, she's probably
telling Ben
how to cut your throat.
You don't think that pretty
little thing would...
Hey, you two,
break it up there!
Here, try it with this.
Come on, don't be stubborn.
Press it against your face.
- Get away from me.
- Like it better this way?
Let me go, let me alone!
If she bothers you so much,
why don't you tie her up
and be done with her?
No bother.
I like to wrestle with her.
You're a big man
for beating up women, ain't you?
And you're no better.
Lina.
That jackass started a misery
in my back.
Can you do me?
Don't get them fired up
all the time.
Best thing on our side
is your pretty face.
They're men, honey,
and you ain't.
- Remember that.
- I'm not gonna...
I ain't asking you
to marry them.
The more they look at you, the
less they'll be seeing of me.
You sure got her trained, Ben.
Tell you, if I was
to have a daughter,
I wouldn't want her no different
than Lina here.
Except she shouldn't have
such sharp nails.
- Maybe not so much temper.
- Hold still!
Honey, you remember those
cigars I got put away?
I could do with one now.
Get two.
I don't smoke.
Any more at home like her?
She got no home,
that's the trouble.
Ma died in Paso a couple
of months ago
and she come up north
hunting her pa.
He was dead and planted
when she got here.
So, of course, you felt obliged
to look out for her.
Son, her pa was
my best friend.
Hey, Jesse! Why don't you get
a pan and do it right?
- What do you know about gold?
- Just what I heard.
Come on, let's get riding.
What's the crazy hurry?
We can camp here.
That's right, Howie,
a day more or less
won't change the price on me.
Of course, it might give one of
you boys time to think.
Plain arithmetic.
Money splits better two ways
instead of three.
Come on.
Hiyah! Hiyah! Hiyah!
Hiyah! Hiyah!
How can you breathe
that stinking rope?
Kills the taste
of your cooking, Jesse.
Nothing like a good woman
to stir a pot.
Nothing like a good woman.
I guess you've got
the years to know
better than any of us, Jesse.
Did you ever marry one of them?
Never had to,
with my good looks.
No sense in asking Roy
here about women.
He'd keep us up all night.
Well, right now,
I'm sort of in between.
Well, looks like we're
a herd of bachelors.
Even Kemp.
Never should have
marched off to war, Howie.
Should have stayed home
and married the girl.
Of course, it's none
of my business.
That's right, it's none
of your business.
Come on, let's get
this stuff cleaned up.
Alright, girlie,
grab a handful.
I'll do mine and Ben's.
You'll do what I tell you,
that's what you'll do.
Women.
I think I'll go along,
to protect her.
Sure works on me.
The way his eyes hang on her.
Fancy-talking Eastern boy.
Trouble is, talk's
just the beginning
with wild kids like that.
You watch.
When he's ready,
he'll reach out and take.
And who's to stop him?
Di... did you think
I was gonna jump you?
- That's right.
- No.
No, I was... just uncramping.
You look almost
sorry I didn't.
Yeah, killing me
in self-defense
is a lot better than
killing me for money.
Well, it's your choice, Ben.
A bullet right here on the trail
or a rope in Abilene.
Choosing the way to die,
what's the difference?
Choosing the way to live,
that's the hard part.
That's what's eating you,
ain't it, Howie?
There's nothing eating me!
Somebody was bound
to collect on you.
Maybe.
I calculated some
horse-thieving scum
would want the price on my hide,
but not you, Howie...
Now, why don't you shut up?
Not a man of your leanings.
Not a ranching man.
I don't deny you got
a dirty deal, but...
The things a gal
can do to a man.
Ohhh. Shut up!
Hold it up here!
Might save a day if we went
over instead of around.
A day might make
the difference.
Better take a look first
and find some kind of trail.
Wait, I got some glasses.
I knew you had your nuggets
hid somewhere under me.
I wouldn't be
putting up with you
if I had nuggets
to take back.
Let me get in there.
Funny you ain't had no luck
in this country.
A fellow I know
struck gold just north of here.
Half a mountain of it, almost.
- What fellow was that?
- A fellow I know.
Only thing, he had more trouble
getting it out of the ground
than he had finding it,
that's what I hear.
He don't know much.
Got them from an officer fellow.
Swapped him even
for a Paiute tomahawk.
It weren't really Paiute,
I made it myself.
I had you figured
for a horse trader.
Jesse!
Keep your eye on "em, Roy.
Mind if I get off
and stand a while?
Go ahead.
You can, too.
They gone up higher
to look ahead?
Well, if a man could do that
with his own life.
Maybe if I'd seen what was ahead
when I was younger,
I wouldn't be in this fix.
Ahh, of course I would.
Some of the things...
Nope.
Nope, I wouldn't have done
nothing no different.
Except for you, honey.
I wouldn't have
dragged you with me.
You didn't drag me, Ben.
I wish there was some way
to protect you from Howie.
He's gonna start on
you pretty soon.
Kemp?
I've seen him with women.
He'll look and think...
and then he'll
reach out and take.
And the way things are,
who's gonna stop him?
- Me.
- You better.
I'm the jealous type.
Ah! It's not
much of a trail.
I think we can make it
right through that pass.
At least the pay is good.
Give me those glasses.
What do you make of it?
Indians.
Two, four, six, seven, eight...
- About 12 of them.
- Are they wearing paint?
It's hard to tell.
Right up there.
Yeah, they're
just Blackfeet.
Nothing to worry about. Been no
trouble with them for years.
A little far south
for Blackfeet, aren't we?
- Hunting party, I guess.
- Uh-huh.
Hunting what?
Alright, mount up.
We're going over.
Oh yeah, and don't
get nervous if we see
a couple of Indians
coming up behind.
- Indians?
- Don't worry. Don't worry, now.
They're just Blackfeet.
Take it easy
on the trail up there.
Wait a minute.
What do you think you're doing?
You want to get us all scalped?
We got nothing they want.
Isn't that right, Jesse?
- Yup.
- Indians are Indians.
We can cover this trail
and finish them off
when they come through.
Why look for trouble?
What's the matter, lieutenant?
Alright, if you want to know,
they're after me.
They've been hunting me
ever since I left the fort.
Now that's something else again.
This chief's daughter
you was holding hands with,
was she willing?
Never mind the sermon.
We've got a fight on our hands.
This is your
fight, not ours.
You expect me
to take them alone?
They don't
just kill a man.
He's right. If them Indians
are out to revenge a squaw,
they'll make him holler first.
Do the same thing to us
if we're with him.
Maybe worse.
Alright, you better start riding
the skin off that horse of yours
if you want to stay
out ahead of them.
The reward cuts
bigger two ways, huh?
You're losing time.
Alright, now keep close
together. You ride next to Ben.
Come on.
Now just sit easy.
- Get behind that stump.
- Right.
Get down!
Anybody got a match?
You could have
got us all killed.
It worked, didn't it?
Did you think I was
gonna let those Indians
ride me into the ground?
Let them peel my hide
over a slow-burning fire?
Oh, no.
Not me... partners.
Come on, mount up.
You can't sit a horse
with a slug
in your leg, Howie.
You get on that burro.
Come on.
He's done a day's work.
Fix a fire.
Where are they?
Where'd they take her?
Let go now.
Get your hands off.
Get your hands off me.
I've got to find her.
I got to.
I got to... I got to find her.
- I've got to...
- He been like this long?
Not as bad.
What are you trying to do,
drown him?
Here, give me that handkerchief.
Mary, Mary, Mary...
Mary.
Don't worry.
The war won't last a year.
I'll be home before you know it.
No sense getting married,
and then having to say goodbye.
You understand that.
Sure, I understand.
Now, get some sleep.
You can manage, Mary. The boys
will take care of the stock.
When I get back, it'll be just
like we talked about last night.
You understand, Mary?
You remember what you said?
I remember.
I said, "I'll wait for you."
He got what was coming to him.
Half of Abilene knows about it.
I've heard of some big suckers
in my time but...
This ain't our affair.
You know what he done?
When he marched off
to preserve the Union
he signed over his ranch to this
gal, so she could work it legal.
Guess what?
Come back to find out
she'd sold it.
Used the money to run off
with another fellow.
It's nothing to laugh at.
No? Well, laugh at this then.
What am I supposed to do? Cry?
Feel sorry for him?
I got nothing against
these fellows.
They just happened along.
But him...
I never hurt him no wise,
and he starts out to hunt me
days, weeks, like an animal.
That's enough.
This ain't none of our business.
He wants his land back.
And I'll tell you something.
His end of the reward
ain't enough to buy it.
That's your business.
I think I'll make some coffee.
Then why did he make a deal
with us, to begin with?
Howie's a practical man.
He needed you fellas' help to
get through this rough country.
But the closer we get to Abilene
the more you've got to worry.
Give me my choice,
and I'll take hand-panning
in running water, naturally.
Especially when you're working
alone like I do.
Of course, when you get a strike
in high country
like here for instance...
your big problem
is getting the water
to where you're digging.
Yeah, that's the trouble
my friend had.
Ground full of gold
and no water to work it. Hey!
Now maybe you'll shut up.
I've been meaning to ask...
you talk like you've seen
this fellow's
mine with your own eyes.
I just heard.
Never hit it, huh, Jesse?
Nothing worth the mention.
Seems I've been looking
all my life.
All my life.
That's a long time to look
for something.
Maybe you've been looking
in the wrong places.
Fellow says, "There's gold in
the valley,” I go to the valley.
Fellow says, "Dig here,” I dig.
Fellow says, "There's a rush
on to the north,” I go north.
In '49, I run to California.
Still remember,
spent good money for maps.
Even made my own maps.
I've seen fellows
too drunk to walk
fall on their face
and find gold.
But never me.
Hey, Jesse!
Where's Roy?
He rode off before dawn.
Didn't say where.
That's enough shaving.
Give me that.
Drop it there.
Well, you slept yourself out.
Must be halfway to noon almost.
Why didn't somebody wake me?
What's everybody lying
around for?
That tells you, better than me.
You get him some breakfast.
You can change
the wrapping, girlie.
- Why me?
- Because I say so.
Don't fuss all the time!
Hold on, Jesse.
This girl's been up half
the night taking care of him.
She's wore out.
Never mind, Ben.
- Hey, I'll do it.
- Lay still.
- No, you don't have to.
- I'll do it.
- You sat up with me?
- Yeah.
- Why?
- Somebody had to.
You was raving,
so no one could sleep.
- Why should you care?
- I don't.
I'd have done it for a dog
if he was suffering.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
You said I was raving.
What about?
Nothing that made sense.
You thought I was your girl.
You kept calling me Mary.
You were really out
of your head.
We ain't nothing alike,
Mary and me.
At least, that's what Ben says.
Well, Ben's just like all
the rest of them.
- He never even met her.
- Well, he knows what she did.
What she did is her business.
She had no business
selling your ranch.
Alright, you're different.
You would have done
it different.
Let's let it go.
How do you mean I'm different?
I mean you got a man.
At least you stick to him.
- He's not my man.
- You're with him, ain't you?
- Not like you mean.
- Alright, forget it.
What are you doing
with Ben, anyway?
Did you expect to run
and hide forever?
Ben was taking me to California.
He was gonna start new.
Start new? At what?
Ranching, maybe.
He knows a lot about cattle.
Yeah, other people's cattle.
Did you ever think for a minute
that Ben had the temper
to settle on the land?
To clear it, to build on it?
To bring in the cattle and...
nurse them through the winter
and round up strays,
brand calves?
Start new? The only thing
Ben'll start is trouble.
He's wild, sure.
Like my father used to be.
But they didn't do
one of the ten things
that people blamed them for.
He's mean.
He was born mean...
Ben took me
for my father's sake
when there was no cause
for him to,
and he's treated me decent.
Well, that's more than he's done
for most people.
I've never seen him hurt no one,
except in a fair fight.
- Sure, I know, sure.
- And who are you to talk?
You didn't track him all this
way just "cause he's mean.
I never said I did.
There's a lot of outlaws riding
free with no one after them.
Ben could've killed a dozen men
and you wouldn't
have looked twice
if it wasn't for the reward.
Where have you been?
- How's the leg?
- Here you are.
Breakfast in bed.
What's this?
You better eat it
before we tell you.
I made a map of the trail ahead.
Here, take a look.
I know the way.
Hey, look.
Here's this pony-backed ridge
marked along this
stretch of trees.
You follow these mountains
right down to the big river
and we'll meet
on the other side.
Meet who?
Well, what he means,
all of you go on ahead
and I use this map
to catch up with you later.
That's right, isn't it?
It's the only smart way.
Riding alone,
he can make up time
it would take us days to cover.
And the rain's coming.
Well, Jesse, what do you think?
I'm thinking if something
goes wrong
and you don't meet up with us
I stand to gain from it
as much as Roy here.
That's a dirty idea.
I ain't much proud of it,
but it's the truth.
It won't be that way with me,
is all I can promise.
As soon as we get across, we
wait for you on the other side.
You got Jesse's word
on it, and mine.
Here, this is yours.
Come on, let's get the horses
ready. I'm riding with you.
What are you trying to do?
Kill yourself?
I ain't going to cheat you.
You know, your trouble
is you just
think of one thing at a time.
If this is his plan to get rid
of me, who's next?
Just think that over.
You better let Roy ride
drag. You ain't fit.
You know, Howie
I ain't been tied up like this
since I was knee high to spit.
The time pa sold
our place in Missouri
and started us out for Texas.
I didn't want to go,
so I run off.
He caught me, tied me up
and throwed me in the wagon.
That was a hard winter.
Ma caught the fever
and died on the way.
Pa didn't amount
to much after that.
Got gunned down in a saloon
before we ever saw Texas.
After that I...
met up with some
wild, young fellows.
You might say I come to no good.
Look out!
Come on, you buzzard bait, move.
- Is it time yet?
- Pretty near.
I can't sleep anyway.
Might be a cat poking around.
I'll go and see.
I better see
what's at the other end.
Now, this ain't bad.
We could all do with some of
Jesse's coffee.
Hey, Roy...
Wet cords are shrinking.
How about it?
I'm not going out
in this weather.
Easy there, girlie,
you'll have it all down on us.
It runs back about 30 yards.
Funnels down to another opening
about big enough for a cat
to crawl through. Or him.
Hey, Lina, honey...
this weather's creeping
into my bones.
Can you do me?
I wonder if you really need this
or if you just like
to be rubbed.
Same thing.
A man needs what he likes.
Poor old, Howie.
That bad leg's
just about got him wore out.
Might not be too sharp
on his watch tonight.
Shouldn't have to stand one,
the way he is.
Better for us.
This might be our chance.
He's coming around
on his feeling for you.
If you was to sit up
with him tonight
and tell him the things
that a man likes to know,
you know.
It'd only be a minute before I'd
be out of that hole in back.
- But if Kemp finds out...
- Finds out what?
I'll be long gone.
You're not gonna let me down,
are you, honey?
No, Ben,
- Only...
- Only what?
- He's got no feeling for me.
- No?
All he cares about
is the reward.
Well, you're right, honey.
You're better off out of it.
I guess my only hope is
that he'll drop off
at least long enough for me
to pick up a rock
and smash his head in.
I don't want to,
but time's running out.
I can help you, Ben.
The way you said.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
It'll be alright, honey.
It'll be alright.
Now, you get some coffee, huh?
What's the matter?
Nothing. Restless.
The stuff's been out
long enough.
It can't hurt. It's alright.
It's, uh, making music.
There's a sour one some place.
Roy's.
You know, at that,
it sounds better
than some fiddlers I've heard.
Is dancing hard to learn?
No, not the way I do it.
Do you like it?
Yeah, used to.
Sometimes I just like to sit
outside by a window
and listen to the music.
Like now.
Did you ever see
Mexican dancing?
What are you gonna do
when you get back to Abilene?
Help Ben if I can.
Don't you want anything
for yourself?
Used to think of going
to California.
Why California?
Some place new...
nobody caring who you are,
or where you come from.
A place you could belong to.
A house, maybe even neighbors.
I had neighbors, you know.
Tom Webster and his missus,
lived right across the river.
Had four sons, each one of them
skinnier than the other.
Always coming over
to lend a hand.
Didn't give you much chance
to get lonesome.
Although the house,
the house ain't much,
but it's just prime
cattle country.
And the fella
that owns the ranch now
he's willing to sell.
Maybe...
Maybe you'd like to take a look
at it after I buy it back.
With the money you get for Ben?
Oh, that's something else.
I'm talking to you now.
Be like stepping on a grave.
You know what I'm asking you?
I can't say how I feel,
the way things are.
Alright, get up.
Come on, come on, get up.
Come on. We're through
fooling with you.
- Quit that!
- "Dead or alive," it says.
Stop him!
Ben won't have a chance.
Chance at what? To kill us all?
Alright, if that's what you
want, I'll give him a chance.
There. Now, cut him loose.
Don't let him do it.
Cut him loose!
Alright, Ben.
It ain't a fair fight, Howie.
My hands ain't fit.
You're ready now, anytime.
Come on, draw.
I ain't got a prayer
against you, and you know it.
It's your first move.
If you're going
to murder me, Howie
don't try to make it look
like something else.
Come on, draw.
Kill him!
Alright.
Leave it be.
It's getting so I don't know
which way to point this no more.
How many chances does he get?
Is this part of your
deal with her?
- I didn't...
- No, no.
You didn't keep me busy
while he's making his break.
No, it just happened that way.
It just happened that way.
Well, this is no good.
You got any more shortcuts?
Well, there's no sense
stewing about it.
We got here late and that's it.
That's the time you cost us.
If you'd listened to me we cou...
Alright, I'll listen to you now
if you got any ideas
about how to get across here.
No, we can't get across that.
You gotta get downstream a ways.
- How far?
- Oh, four, five days.
If we make time.
We can swim it here,
so let's start now.
I'll take the point
if you're afraid.
At least I got the sense
to be afraid.
Besides, what about her?
She wouldn't last two minutes
in that current.
You want to go downstream?
Take her with you.
What if Ben gets washed away?
Then we got nothing.
I bow to your superior wisdom.
I promise you, Jesse, he'll get
across, one way or the other.
- Hey, wait a minute.
- Hey, you can't do that.
I'll try the river,
but not like this.
Yes, like this. Why not?
We'll go downstream
before we cross.
Now what are you worried about,
your girl?
Don't tell me you're worried
about him.
Why? It's no different
from the rope in Abilene.
You knew you were gonna
bring him back to die
when you started after him.
You know that now.
That hasn't changed.
He's not a man,
he's a sack of money.
That's why we're all here,
especially you.
Why don't you face up to it?
I don't suppose either
of you object
to stopping
the night here.
Ha! I didn't think so.
I...
Hey, Lina, honey
it's my back again.
Can you do me?
Let me do you this time.
Start fixing for a fire, girlie.
How do you like your rubbing?
Up and down or side to side?
Hey, you don't have to do that.
You better look after
your partners.
Partners, huh?
If I didn't need a grubstake
I'd have walked out
on this deal long ago.
It's too bad.
If you'd been lucky
like my friend...
And I've had about enough of
that, too.
You got no friend found gold
around here
you're talking about yourself.
I knowed I shouldn't have shot
off my mouth in front of you.
Quit playacting. You wanted me
to know it all along.
So, let's get at it.
You tell me where to dig
and I'll see that your gal
is provided for.
Don't try to horse-trade me,
Jesse.
I ain't gonna tell you where my
gold is, but I'll show you.
I knew that's what you been
scratching for all along.
Trouble is, I don't trust you
no more than I trust them.
Well, you don't have
to trust nobody.
Even if you don't fancy
my gold mine
you still got me
all to yourself.
Now, that's saying I trust you.
Say I tell you where my gold is,
you might still turn me in.
If I make a deal, I stick by it.
At least I wouldn't have any
partners to worry about.
- Except me.
- What do you mean, you?
If I did it, now just if,
it'd be an even swap.
You go loose,
and I get the gold mine.
Now, that ain't fair, Jesse
I got a right to some
of that gold.
Fair or no, its the only deal
I'd make.
And it's a poor deal no matter.
Same deal.
I'll trade you even up.
Your neck for that gold,
yes or no?
I ain't fixed for bargaining,
Jesse, you know that.
Come on then,
I got two horses ready.
I'll get Lina.
No, she ain't part of the deal.
She goes with me.
If I'm gonna be broke,
I ain't gonna be lonesome.
Get her up, then.
Remember, I'm watching you.
I'll tell you later. Come on.
Snake! Snake! Snake! Snake!
Where? Where?
Huh! Whoa! Ben, hey.
Fun's over.
Get down off that horse.
I said off, come on, move.
You alright, honey?
You got the gun.
What do you care?
You're alright.
Get moving.
I got it coming.
Do business with the devil
and you'll get it every time.
Ain't it the truth?
Get going. Lina, honey,
you take the horse.
Hold it, Jesse.
You better get going, Ben.
The other two will
be along any minute.
You mean, we better get going,
don't you, honey?
If it suits you,
I'll settle for going.
I don't fancy your friend
with a gun in his hand.
"Course, I don't suppose Ben
would be fool enough to shoot.
It'd be heard 20 mile or more.
Who's talking about shooting?
Leave him with the burro, Ben,
you don't need him. Please.
I'm just thinking that...
from up there,
a man could pick off anything
that moves in this clearing.
The only trouble is...
there's nothing
to stop a man.
Make him hold up for a while.
Ben, I got to talk a different
way now, I know that.
But that gold mine still ain't
gonna do you much good.
I'm thinking...
Thinking is your weak spot,
Jesse.
Here, Lina, hold the horses.
Leave the burro.
Ben! Ben! No!
You had no reason to kill him.
He couldn't hurt you none.
Leave him lay like that.
They'll come after you sure now.
That shot will bring them.
- And they'll finish you.
- I figure they'll come.
Now get those horses
on the other side of that rock.
Come on, do as I say,
before I have to knock
some sense into you.
Up here.
Get down.
Better not move around
too much up here.
Come on, you too.
I swear, he ain't half as
worried over it as you are.
Look at him.
Lying there peaceful in the sun.
He ain't never gonna
be hungry again.
Never want anything
he can't have.
That's more than we can say.
Hold still. Hold still.
You're gonna be still
from now on.
I ain't been harder on you
'cause I know you never
seen a man killed close up.
Well, that'll pass.
Day after tomorrow,
it'll be just
like a story you once heard.
You killed that man
in Abilene like Kemp said!
Just another gun I'll never have
to look into, you understand?
Pretty soon, Roy and your
friend Howie are gonna show up.
Then I'll get me some more
insurance against dying young.
Ben, we can get away.
California. We can go there.
You always said you'd
take me to California.
Might go to California.
Kemp didn't kill you when
he had the chance, remember?
You got to remember that.
I remember what suits me.
If you forget this,
I won't ever do anything
you don't want, I promise.
I won't talk, I won't
do anything wrong...
Of course, you won't, honey.
I decided how it was gonna be
with us when I took you in.
Boys must be having trouble
finding their way.
Ain't lost my touch.
Think I'll try for a pair.
Quiet now. Here they come.
That's better, Howie.
Stand together, boys.
Howie!
Lina's hurt bad.
Caught a ricochet.
She's bleeding something awful.
How about a truce
so I can fix her up?
What do you say, Howie?
Lina!
Lina, are you alright?
I didn't know what to do.
- Where is...
- Kemp!
Roy! Roy!
I got him! I got him!
Come in alone,
we'll pull him in after!
Stop it!
Ben's dead. Ain't that enough?
Look!
Look out! Let go of him!
Look out!
Cut him loose, Howie.
I'm taking him back.
This is what I came
after and now I got it.
No partners like I started.
He's gonna pay for my land.
Jesse, and Roy, and him...
They're dead! Finished!
Ben's not dead
if you take him back.
He'll never be dead for you.
I don't care anything
about that but money.
That's all I care about. That's
all I've ever cared about.
Roy, he called the turn.
He said, "Face up to it."
Alright, that's what I'm doing.
That's what I'm doing!
Maybe I don't fit your ideas
of me,
but that's the way I am.
Alright, if that's the way
you want it, I'll ride with you.
I'll ride with you all the way.
I'm taking him back.
I know. I'll marry you.
I'll go with you, I'll even
live on that land with you.
What else do you want from me?
Why?
Tell me why?
I'm taking him back, I swear it.
I'm gonna sell him for money.
You still want
to try California?
If you want.
That's it, then.
I'll fix some of Jesse's
coffee for you.