- Oh, George.
- Yes, sir?
Has he seen it?
Oh... Thank you.
Morning, J.P.
Morning.
I thought I sold everything
below 38th Street three years ago.
Well, that store is right on 38th
Street, J.P., so we kept it.
Neeley Department Store.
N, N, N, N...
Natural Foundry, Napex Corporation
National Radiator, yes,
Neeley Department Store.
You still own it.
This dummy doesn't look like me.
Maybe it's supposed
to be one of you.
There's a sign on the dummy
with your name on it.
Where?
M-E-R-R... That's
all you can see.
What's been done about this?!
We had a talk with the manager of the
department store. He fired the ring leader
and half a dozen of the employees
who participated in it.
Have this picture enlarged.
And everybody, even
watching it, fired. Out!
That's an excellent
suggestion, J.P.
I pay you a great deal to take care
of my interests and my privacy.
I want privacy.
I haven't had my photograph
in a newspaper in 20 years.
This is temporary, J.P.
Who could have gone to all the trouble of
finding out I own this piddly investment?
Our detective will ferret the whole
thing out, J.P., in no time.
What detective?
We have a man who's an expert.
If you care to speak with him...
He'll show you this is a simple little
disturbance that has no significance.
The Boston Tea Party was
a little disturbance.
I want to talk to this... detective.
Good day, gentlemen.
- Good day, J.P. - Goodbye.
- Good day, J.P. -  Good day, sir.
There's a detective here
for you to interview.
This way, sir.
Thank you.
Sit down.
- What's your name?
- Thomas Higgins.
What progress have
you made, Higgins?
I, uh, I've gotten a
job in the store.
Nobody in the whole store knows I'm a
detective except the Personnel Head.
Not even the General Manager.
I see.
I'm a salesman in the
Children's Shoe department.
That's the hotbed.
That whole fifth floor.
Will you have the graham
crackers individually
or shall I crumble
them in the bowl?
- Individually.
- Yes, sir.
- No. Crumble them for a change.
Tell me. How soon could you find out who
these employees are? The troublemakers?
Not more than two
or three weeks.
Why not two or three days?
Why, I've got to worm my way into
their confidence. Become one of them.
How do I know what they're going to
do in the next two or three weeks?
I'm not gonna hang from
every lamppost in the city
while you worm your way
into their confidence.
- It's a very difficult assignment.
- There's nothing difficult about it!
Fire anyone that's
even suspicious.
You don't have to be accurate.
Is there anybody you suspect yet?
Well, I... I haven't really started. I
thought I'd begin the day after tomorrow.
- What's that?
- My wife's having a baby in Philadelphia.
That's where I live. I thought
I'd go home tomorrow.
I don't think you ought to be separated
from your wife while you're having a baby.
I'll get someone else
for this assignment.
That's very considerate of
you, Mr. Merrick. My wife...
Nothing at all. I'll just keep this
card for the next fellow. Good day.
- Thank you for your kindness.
- Perfectly all right.
Go back to Poughkeepsie
and forget about it.
Poughkeepsie? Yes, sir.
Good day, sir.
George?
Yes, sir?
Come here.
I want you to tell me
the truth, George.
Yes, sir.
What would you like to see changed
in the world? In a business way?
- Well...
- Yes?
I have a few shares of steel stock. I
would be happy if it went up a little.
If anyone asks you, George.
You're not a typical working man.
No, sir.
Dr. Schindler made up your pepsin
into sticks of chewing gum, sir.
He thought you would
like the change.
You are to have one
every hour on the hour.
You will find them in your lower left
breast pocket. It's time for one now.
Look at their faces.
Moron. Sheep.
No wonder you can convince
them of anything.
How I'd like to hear one of
those troublemakers talking.
I'd show him.
- Mr. Merrick!
- Why not?
I'd like to see them operate.
- Your stomach.
- I'll be one of them.
Mix with them. Let
them talk to me.
Why, these idiots. I'd play
with them like a cat and mouse.
Oh my....
George, my name is...
Thomas Higgins.
Young lady, could you direct
me to the Section Manager?
He's right over there. See?
Standing at the little desk?
Thank you.
- There you are, madam.
- Thank you very much.
Thank you.
And what can I do for you, sir?
Oh, uh. I'm working here.
I'm a new salesman.
- You're Higgins?
- Mh-hm.
"Yes, sir."
Yes, sir.
Higgins...
Harrison...
In the intelligence test you took
this morning your rating was 66.
That's one point over the
lowest passing grade.
66?
There must be some mistake.
I answered all the questions.
You might have answered
some of them wrong.
That's possible, isn't it?
I said that's possible, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
Sir.
We never make mistakes, Higgins.
Neeley's is always right.
This is the lowest intelligence
rating in my department.
I hope you have other qualities
to compensate for it.
For your own sake.
Miss Jones?
Don't lean against my desk.
And remove your hat.
Please.
Miss Jones, I'm assigning Higgins
to Slippers. Show him his duties.
Welcome to the shoe
department, Mr. Higgins.
You come right along with me.
Now. This will be your counter, Mr. Higgins.
Bedroom, lounging, and house slippers.
You know, this is
really the best job.
No bending down for try-ons.
No running back and forth
for different models.
Everything's right here.
I wish I had this counter.
He doesn't think that I'm good
enough to sell shoes, is that it?
Now don't be silly.
This is just the same.
It's even better.
You have to be cleverer selling
slippers than you do shoes.
Don't forget people can always do without
slippers. They have to be convinced.
How could he tell I'm not as
good a salesman as the next one?
It's just your vanity that's hurt.
And you can sell shoes
when you relief for lunch.
Show him then what a
good salesman you are.
Your lunch hour will be from 12:00 to 1:00.
That's in 30 minutes.
I'm not going to eat lunch.
- You're not?
- I'm going to stay here selling slippers.
- I'm going to make a good impression.
- Why aren't you going to have lunch?
I'm not hungry. I never
have lunch anyway.
You go to lunch at 12:00 sharp.
No arguments.
You don't mind waiting
on me, do you?
What can I do for you, madam?
Mr. Higgins?
It's time for lunch. I'll
take over the counter.
I'm really not hungry.
Why do you argue so much? You go to lunch!
And hurry up about it.
- I don't know where to go.
- Well, you... um...
- Oh, Elizabeth?
- Yes?
Miss Ellis, this is Mr. Higgins.
- How do you do?
Elizabeth, will you show Mr. Higgins where
the employees' restaurant is, please?
I'd be glad to.
Did you sell anything?
One pair of men's
slippers, size 9, $1.98.
That's fine! Did you have
any trouble selling them?
- Oh no. No.
- Wonderful!
Be back in an hour, now.
- The restaurant's two flights up.
- Aren't you coming?
I always bring my own lunch and eat
in the park. It's pleasant in there.
I don't intend to eat at all. Would it
inconvenience you if I sat with you?
- Not at all. I'd love to have you.
- Thank you.
- Kind of stuffy in here.
- Yes, isn't it?
- Sure you won't have something?
- No, no, thanks. I never eat lunch.
You men worry more about
your figures than women do.
It's not my figure I worry about.
It's uh... I'm just not hungry.
Isn't it terrible about the store
not letting people organize?
I made these myself.
It's very rude of
you not to try one.
I wonder where they are
holding a meeting tonight?
Go on, eat it.
- What is it?
- Tuna fish popover.
- Tuna fish popover?
- It's my own invention.
Bite it.
- Oh, no, I couldn't. Really, I couldn't.
- Oh, please.
If I ask you to?
You haven't got a graham
cracker, have you?
Oh, a grown man eating graham crackers.
Why, there's no nourishment in that.
You eat that popover.
It won't bite you.
Won't it, though?
Tuna fish.
Like it?
I don't know yet.
- Is it good tuna fish?
- Costs 12 cents a tin.
- 12 cents!
- It's almost as good as you can buy.
- Almost?
- Go on, eat it.
- Tastes good.
- Thank you.
- Here, have another.
- No, no, thank you just the same.
Oh, one isn't enough to feed an infant.
Go on, take it.
How does a man exist without
a woman looking after him?
I could tell you were a single man.
You are single, aren't you?
Yes, I am.
What did you do before this?
What kind of work?
Oh, all kinds. You'd be surprised.
Were you out of work long
before you got this job?
- Hmm. Yes.
- How long did you work at your last place?
- Fifteen years.
- And how long before that?
Ten years.
Isn't that awful.
Mr. Hooper's coming.
- Hello, Mr. Hooper.
- Good afternoon, Mr. Hooper.
How do you do, Miss Ellis?
He usually sits here
for a few minutes.
Oh, I hope he's not angry.
Another popover!
You know, he ate
almost all my lunch.
He was famished!
Oh. I gave him 50 cents.
He probably needed it so badly he
didn't want to spend it for lunch.
Oh dear.
- Don't look up. A shopper is coming.
- What?
A store shopper, they pretend they're
customers. But they're only testing you.
Be careful how you act.
Oh, uh, may I help you, madam?
Oh, that's all right, this
gentleman will wait on me.
Yes, ma'am.
What can I do for you, madam?
Do you sell slippers here?
Yes, ma'am, we do.
These are slippers. That's
what we call them, slippers.
They don't look very good.
Oh but they are. I wear
a pair of these myself.
Woolies. Keep your
feet nice and warm.
- Real sheep wool.
- Aren't they a little too warm for summer?
We never had any complaint
from the sheep. Ha-ha.
I'll think about it.
I hope you didn't mind my inconveniencing
you without buying anything.
Of course not, madam.
I'm only here to serve you.
- Are you chewing gum?
- No, ma'am.
I'm a store shopper.
Open your mouth.
- Did you swallow that gum?
- No, ma'am, I wasn't chewing any gum.
Well, see that you
don't in the future.
And don't lean on the counter.
Yes, ma'am.
Well, you didn't do so badly.
Say, what are you doing?
Keep a diary?
It's a kind of a diary.
A Doomsday Book.
What's a Doomsday Book?
It contains the names of a lot of people
who are going to meet their doom.
I don't get it.
Employees! Listen, employees!
Here I am! Right here!
Gather round, please! All the employees
of the Neeley's Department Store.
I have a message for you!
They have fired some
of us for organizing!
But we haven't given up!
We are still at it!
Call the detectives!
Don't be afraid!
Come to our meeting!
If enough of us stick together,
they won't be able to stop it!
Nobody listen to him!
Everybody stop him!
I repeat, come to our meeting!
Get him out!
Get him out of here. This is one time
you can't throw me out, gentlemen.
- And I haven't any key.
- Take him away!
Saw me out!
It will only take about four hours.
And while you're sawing,
I'll give a little speech.
Don't be afraid! Come to our meeting!
In union there is strength!
We gotta fight together.
We gotta think... Hey!
Right is on our side!
And don't be afraid!
We got the situation
well in hand!
They can't stop us now!
I tell you they can't stop us...
Fellow employees.
And I call you fellow employees
because that is what we all are
from the smallest stock clerk to me myself
though I carry the title
of General Manager.
There was a disturbance
on the 5th floor today.
A shocking un-American
invasion of private property.
Nothing more or less than trespassing.
A criminal offense.
There are still some troublemakers
employed in this store
we have not as yet ferreted out.
But we shall.
And if employees are found
cooperating with these traitors
in our one big happy family
I can tell you now, they
will be not only discharged
but blackballed from working in any
department store in this city.
Now, may I wish you all
a very good evening.
Good night, fellow employees.
- Are you doing anything tonight?
- Eh? No. Not especially.
Come with me.
Good night.
- What've you got in there?
- Me, you idiot?
Don't get excited, Pop,
thought it was a package.
Come on, come on.
Good night.
- Does it hurt much?
- A little.
I can't understand how you've
never eaten in an Automat before.
I never thought of it.
I could sue them getting my
finger caught like that.
Well, I don't know. I've
been eating there for years.
I never heard of anybody getting
their fingers caught before.
Say, tell me the truth.
Was the manager right?
Did you try to get that blueberry
pie without putting in a nickel?
You, too?
I tell you, I did put in a nickel.
But I went to get coffee and somebody
must have sneaked the pie out.
It was their responsibility to
get me another piece of pie.
And I'd have gotten it too
if you hadn't interfered.
Honey!
Joe, did they do anything
to you? Did they hurt you?
Never laid a hand on me.
I dared 'em to.
I was so afraid that they'd
do something to you.
- Well, uh, who's this?
- He started in the store this morning.
- Oh, welcome, brother!
- Mr. Higgins, this is Joe O'Brien.
He hung up the dummy of
John P. Merrick.
Made the front page of
the Times, that's all.
- Did you see it?
- Yes, I saw it. This is quite a pleasure.
Likewise. Come on.
We're just about ready to start.
Come on.
I knew you'd join us. I could
tell that the minute I saw you.
All right, everybody.
I, uh, see that some of you
are here for the first time
and you'd probably like
to know more about us.
We are not professional agitators.
I myself started six years
ago at the Neeley store
as a packing boy
and worked up to Assistant
Section Manager.
Now, our quarrel is simple.
We're given a small raise every year.
Thanks.
At the end of 10 or 15 years, when our
salary is higher than a new employ's
we're let out.
Now, this is a regular practice
at the store, mind you.
It's probably good bookkeeping, but
I think that it's pretty unfair.
We're entitled to some
security in exchange
for a quarter of a lifetime
of loyalty to one employer.
Uhm, may I interrupt, please?
I've attended many of these meetings
but I've never spoken before.
I'd like to show you a practical case
of what we're fighting for, if I may.
Certainly, Mary.
Step up here.
This is Miss Jones of Children's Shoes.
Mr. Higgins, would you
step up here, please?
Mr. Higgins!
Step up here, will you, please?
This is Thomas Higgins.
How old are you, Mr. Higgins?
Fifty-five.
Now, don't be nervous, Tom.
He's 55. Now, that's
not so very old.
Look at him, he's bright,
alert, has all his faculties.
Can you honestly expect to be
in better condition at his age?
I hardly think so.
This then is the picture
of you... and me
at 55 years of age.
Now, I'm gonna tell you
the rest of that picture.
He came to work this morning
in Children's Shoes
without the few cents in his
pocket he needed to buy lunch.
And that isn't all.
I gave him 50 cents. You
know what he did with it?
He kept it because he
needed even that 50 cents
more than he needed food.
Maybe for medicine.
Maybe for a place to sleep tonight,
I don't know. I didn't ask him.
I felt too ashamed for him.
Do you want to know
how he got his lunch?
From another employee.
Sharing the few crusts she brought
which were hardly enough for herself.
Fifty-five years old
and nothing to eat.
By what kind fate he got a
job today I'll never know.
And how long will
the store keep him?
And what will become of him
when they let him out?
And he will be let out,
he has been before.
He worked 15 years. 15 long loyal
years, and they let him go.
Before that, he had
a job for 10 years.
Twenty-five years for
only two employers.
Surely this man must have
been capable of holding a job.
And yet, now.
White-haired
friendless, he faces
another employer.
Who will use him.
And when he's through with
him, he'll throw him aside
for a younger man.
Leaving him insecure,
friendless, homeless
with no-one to turn to except
charity and the poorhouse.
Please, take your seat.
- You were wonderful.
- I didn't do anything.
All right, everybody.
If you don't think that we're right
now, nothing will ever convince you.
Are you with us or aren't you?
- We sure are, Joe.
- We're with you, Joe.
What do you think their complaint is?
They are getting too much money.
That's what it is, actually.
I knew they were crackpots.
Why don't they make themselves so
indispensable the store can't fire them?
Oh, no. That's too hard. Heh.
I'm glad I saw this.
I found out who some of them are.
The first day, too.
Not all of them. But just give
me another couple of days.
Heh. The idiots.
Making me one of them.
I'll show them who hangs who.
Shall I crumble them, sir?
Graham crackers, take it away.
And let me tell you another thing.
If I'm not sick by tonight or
tomorrow at the latest
my fancy Dr. Schindler from Vienna
will wish he was back in Vienna.
Yes, sir.
And I want a lunch prepared for
me tomorrow to take along.
In a shoe box.
Yes, sir.
I want tuna fish popovers.
Tuna fish popovers?!
- Tuna fish popovers?
- You heard me.
I wonder... I wonder if the chef
can make tuna fish popovers?
Then get one who does.
If certain people can make
them on a little gas stove
then that idiot downstairs ought to be
able to make them in that whole restaurant.
Yes, sir.
I didn't do so well selling
things today.
- It's just a matter of luck.
- Yes, sir.
What I want you to do
is to get a little girl
and bring her to the shoe department
tomorrow at exactly ten after twelve.
Is there anything
I can do for you, sir?
I thought... I thought I would buy
some shoes for my little girl.
Shoes for the little girl. Yes, sir.
Certainly, sir.
- Won't you be seated?
- Yes, sir. I mean certainly.
He'll bungle it.
No, he's pretty good, Mr. Hooper.
I've been watching him.
I want you to buy a
dozen pair of shoes.
Eleven? I think that's too many.
They'll get suspicious.
- You think so?
- Yes, sir.
All right, then a half dozen.
No less.
No, sir, half a dozen.
One and a half.
Thank you.
This is your chance.
Now, don't be nervous.
I'm not nervous. Stop
talking about it.
- What size do you want?
- One and a half.
- Here. Now ,don't be nervous.
- For heaven's sake.
Is this the hardest
shoe to sell?
What's the hardest shoe to
get rid of in the whole stock?
- The hardest?
- Yes.
Well, we have some high-tops that
haven't moved for years.
- 25 cents bonus for each pair you sell.
- Fine. These are the ones I want.
Don't you think you'd
better start on these?
How many of those
you got in stock?
- Five.
- That's too bad. I could've sold six.
I wish you'd just try to sell the ordinary
shoes. You're making trouble for yourself.
Now. Here we are.
- Just slip your foot in.
- I don't like that.
- Come, come, now.
- Put your foot in the shoe, Sally.
I don't want to,
I don't like it.
- Put your foot in.
- I don't like it!
Where'd you get this brat?
She belongs to the upstairs maid.
If she don't stop squirming, there's
going to be another upstairs maid.
- Stop squirming, dear.
- I don't like it! I don't like it!
Na, na, na!
I knew he didn't have the
personality for shoes.
- Stop squirming, dear.
- I don't like it! I don't like it!
Na, na, na, na, na...
- I don't like it!
- Grab hold of her, grab hold of her.
Well, well, well.
How are we coming along?
Fine!
Mr. Higgins. We're not
shoeing a horse, you know?
Look. Look what I've
got for the little lady.
You're quite sure that
you want this type of shoe?
Yes, sir. This is the
type that I want.
Hmm. All five pairs.
I've been looking for this model.
They are very hard to find.
There's someone at your slipper counter.
I'll take care of this customer.
I've got these shoes sold.
There's someone at
your slipper counter.
He's not a regular
shoe salesman.
I'm the Section Manager but
I'm going to wait on you myself.
Thank you.
There's someone at
your slipper counter.
Will you take them with you,
sir, or shall I send them?
- Are you taking these shoes, sir?
- Yes, sir. Wrap them up, please.
Now, young lady, your own shoe.
Don't you feel badly?
He'll get his just desserts
one of these days.
I'd like to be as certain of
the hereafter, Miss Jones.
And don't lose confidence in yourself.
You could've sold them just as well.
He only butted in 'cause he
wanted to get the bonus.
I don't remember when I've ever disliked
anyone as heartily as I do him.
And I've disliked quite a
few people in my time.
To their misfortune.
You just forget all about it.
I'm an elephant, Miss Jones.
A veritable elephant.
I never forget a good deed
done me... or an ill one.
I consider myself a
kind of divine justice.
Other people in this world
have to forget things.
I do not.
Now, don't talk like
you're out of your mind.
And don't be blasphemous about
divine justice. I don't like that.
I came over here to ask you
something very important.
What is it?
Well, Elizabeth
asked me to ask you
if you'd like to take her to Coney
Island tomorrow with Joe and me.
Oh, it's Dutch treat.
And you have to let her
know right away because...
well, Mr. Hooper's
asked her out.
- Has he ever taken her out before?
- Oh, lots of times.
- Does she like him?
- Well, uh....
You know how it is, a girl has
to go out with someone.
He keeps asking her
and asking her.
Oh, I'd like to go, certainly.
I'll tell her.
Um, and there's something else.
Now, I don't want you to
say anything to Mr. Hooper
about the sale he
took away from you.
There's no use antagonizing him,
'cause after all, he can let you out.
He can, eh?
Now, promise me you won't
say anything to her.
- Promise me?
- Oh, all right. I won't say anything.
Do you know what would
be very clever?
If you'd go over and thank
him for helping you out.
Thank him?
You want to keep
this job, don't you?
You're in no position
to be independent.
Now go on over. Go on.
Go on.
Mr. Hooper.
Yes?
Well, uh. I wanted to
say, about that sale.
- You've got quite a way with children.
- Well...
They certainly take to you
like a duck to water.
Hot water.
Well, I probably couldn't have
handled it as well as you...
As well as me? You couldn't handle
it at all. I made that sale.
Oh, I don't know. I have a hunch
those shoes are coming back.
- My sales never come back.
- Want to bet?
Certainly. How much?
- Make it easy on yourself.
- How much can you afford?
Oh, I can manage to scrape
something together.
Would ten dollars be too much?
- Make it twenty?
- I'd be lucky if I get the ten.
I'll say so.
If you want to bet any more,
I'll give you odds.
Ten dollars. Just get back
to your slipper counter.
What do you think I was wig-wagging
at you for? Playing Boy Scout?
I... I didn't understand, sir.
I kept indicating for you
not to buy anything.
That was simple enough.
But you had given me such definite
instructions to buy the shoes, sir.
I...
There's kind of a picnic tomorrow.
Everybody?s bringing something.
I said I'd bring a
bottle of wine.
They don't think I will
because I haven't the money.
- Well, to the wine cellar.
- Yes, sir.
I haven't been down
here in 15 years.
No, sir, you bought most of
these before prohibition.
What's the best bottle of
wine in the whole place?
The best? I would
say this is, sir.
Roman?e-Conti 1903.
It's good, eh?
There were only 24 bottles
in the world originally.
You bought 12 and the royal
family have the other 12.
Take the label off the bottle.
I don't want them to be suspicious.
- Label off the bottle?
- Yes.
Yes, sir.
Very interesting, George,
my little experiment.
I'm glad you are
enjoying yourself, sir.
I watch the little ants scurry around
and I know each and every one is
going to get his just desserts.
I am sure they are.
That Joe, Mary's fellow...
Bad. An evil influence
on the girl.
Kind of Svengali corrupting
her whole viewpoint.
- Yes, sir.
- I'm going to break that up tomorrow.
I'll talk her out of that.
And then there's Hooper.
A petty tyrant.
Well, he's going
to get his reward.
Then there's Elizabeth...
- Well, come on, up with you.
- Yes, sir.
Oh dear, I knew I forgot
something. The pickles!
Hey, you little guttersnipe! Why
don't you look where you're going?
Do you understand Italian?
I understand that. He-he.
Say, would it be too much to ask you
two millionaires to lend a hand here?
Woman's place in the world
is to tend the male.
Not this woman and not this male.
Here, open it.
Why don't we try my wine?
Oh, I've never been
interested in domestic wine.
This isn't exactly domestic.
Oh, Tom, you shouldn't have
spent your money for this.
Oh well. You only live once.
Skol!
- But I don't know what it means.
- Ha-ha.
Well?
You like it, don't you?
Yeah. Well, I tell you Tom,
it's not really bad, it's...
Tom, did you spend more
than 50 cents for this?
- 50 cents for...
- Oh, Tom, they saw you coming.
Who saw me coming? You mean
you don't like this wine?
Say, I got a good
mind to return it
and make them give
you your money back.
- Oh, the nerve of some people.
- Gee whiz.
Now wait a minute. You're not
giving this wine a fair chance.
Hey, I got an idea.
Just a second.
Look here.
We'll open this and put some
of this in it. See?
Put some of this in.
No, come on, it'll
help kill the taste.
Well, skol again.
- No.
- It's no use.
No. Guess you can't save it.
It's a shame, really.
Too bad we had to
ruin a bottle of pop.
Isn't it?
Pour it out, Tom. It
might make you sick.
I am sick.
Wine experts!
Now, here's a bottle of wine
that's really a bottle of wine.
This was made by our
iceman's grandfather.
Same as he used to do
in the old country.
He puts the grapes in the
bathtub and he jumps on 'em.
I saw him do it.
Ah! Real jumped-on grapes, huh?
Why didn't he take
his socks off?
I knew you'd like it.
Well, I'm going for a swim.
See you all in a minute.
- Ha-ha!
- Ouch!
Now, don't show off
and swim way out!
We'll be watching you!
Say, maybe the Pregbury man will
have some extra pickles he'll sell.
I'll be back in a minute.
Don't worry.
Nothing will happen to him.
Ah. He's a pretty good swimmer.
He's pretty good at everything.
- You wouldn't be prejudiced?
- Maybe.
Is it possible you're reading
virtues into him that don't exist?
Don't you like him?
What makes you say that?
Well, I was watching you on the subway and
thought that you were making faces at him.
My feet were hurting me.
But you're not really
crazy about him.
Well, that depends upon how
much you're in love with him.
And I don't think
you're any judge.
Who's a better one?
Any outsider.
Me, for instance.
Now, look around us.
There's a couple over there.
They think they were
made for each other.
He's biting her ear.
Now she's biting his ear.
Very touching.
I think so.
They've found each
other, haven't they?
Out of this whole wide world, these two
were lucky enough to come together.
But don't you think if
she hadn't met him
there wouldn't be somebody
else biting her ear now?
And don't you think he wouldn't
be at some other girl's ear?
Probably ten feet away?
Maybe. But that doesn't
prove anything.
Scientists can write all the books they
like about love being a trap of nature.
I remember reading that.
That it's biology and the chemistry
inside a woman that fools her.
But all the scientists are going
to convince are other scientists
not women in love.
I don't say Joe is the greatest
thing that ever lived.
I probably wouldn't
love him if he was.
I'd just want to look at him.
But you see, I'm not the greatest
girl in the world, either.
Two people look at each other
and they see something
way deep inside
that nobody else can.
And that's it.
I wouldn't be surprised if
the greatest love affair
in the world was between a
Chinaman wearing a pigtail
and a girl who's missing
two front teeth
if you could measure it.
If they feel it, they feel it.
- Do you?
- Not the way you see in the movies.
Or hear in those
songs, you know...
about the touch of your
hand, you set me on fire.
I guess I'm not the
combustible type.
But when I'm with him
I don't know if it's the
advertised 7th heaven.
We get along just average, I guess.
Little arguing...
Even maybe being a little bored
now and then if we admit it.
But yet if I knew I'd
never see him again...
Yes?
I've never even thought of
what it would be like
not to see him anymore.
I guess that's the test of it.
If I thought
I'd never see him again
I don't think I'd care
if I lived or died.
Look! I found some pretzels.
They're homemade. The Pregbury
man's wife makes them.
- From her own recipe.
- Don't they look delicious?
Gangway!
Oh boy! Pretzels!
Oh, Joe! No!
Don't you dare! You'll
spoil your lunch!
Joe! No!
Joe! Spit it out!
Spit it out, Joe!
I beg your pardon.
I was wondering if I could find out
whether my clothes are in this bathhouse?
- Did you take them off in here?
- Well, I don't exactly remember.
Where's your locker key?
That's got our name on it.
I shared the locker with a young
friend of mine, he has the key.
But unfortunately I can't find him
or any of the people I came with.
- I've been walking about for hours.
- Does this look like the place?
I rented this suit. Can you
tell me if it's yours?
Not ours. That's a
pretty cheap suit.
Not yours.
Thank you.
Ain't ours.
Thanks.
It don't belong to us.
How many bathhouses are
there around here?
- A couple of hundred.
- A couple of hundred?
Thanks.
Young man.
Yes, sir?
I've got a big bargain for you.
How would you like to give me
a dollar or two for this gold watch?
You mean, uh, you want to
leave it for security?
No, I don't think I'll
be down here again.
- I'll let you have it for a dollar.
- A dollar?
That's all. It's a
very fine watch.
Solid gold. Here,
take a look at it.
Yes. Mh-hm.
Uh, would you mind if I showed this
to the boss? I'll only be a second.
I only want a dollar for it.
This is a pretty good
watch for a dollar, Pop.
- You got any more?
- For heaven's sake!
No need to get excited.
There's been a lot of stuff
stolen from lockers around here
and we're just checking up.
Well, I assure you that
watch is not stolen.
It's an awful good watch
to go for a buck.
Officer, I've lost the
friends I came with.
I can't find my bathhouse
and I've been walking around for hours
trying to trace this rented suit.
I want to sell the watch
so I can telephone my home
and have my car and
chauffeur come for me.
- Oh, you have a car and chauffeur?
- Yes, I have.
- And you rent a bathing suit?
- No, my ...
- Where did you get this watch?
- Well, if you want to know...
The Governor gave it
to me on my birthday.
The Governor?
My boss works for him.
Now, what do you say we go
down and pay him a little visit?
- You know, kind of friendly-like.
- You let go my arm!
Now, now. Be a good boy, Pop.
Come on.
- Come on.
- Take your hand off of me.
...pretty monotonous. And I'm getting good
and sick of seeing your ugly little face.
You're not even a good pickpocket. When are
you going to get sense enough to quit?
- Take him away. Marv.
- Yes, sir. Come on.
He was trying to sell this watch
to a clerk in a drugstore for a dollar.
When I questioned him about it, he said he
wanted the money to call his chauffeur.
And beside that he told me that he
got the watch from the Governor.
I thought that
sounded suspicious.
Suspicious enough for me...
I would advise you two simple
guardians of law and order
for the sake of your
own future security
to be very careful of any
decision you make concerning me.
- How was that again?
- Tom!
Tom, we've been looking
everywhere for you!
Joe's running up and down the boardwalk
and Elizabeth's gone to the hospital.
- What happened to you?
- I got lost.
My! Well thank heaven
you're all in one piece.
- Thanks for finding him, officer.
- That's all right, miss.
You can call your
chauffeur from here.
Here.
What chauffeur?
The chauffeur that you
were going to call.
- Me?
- Certainly you.
I haven't got any chauffeur.
Wasn't he trying to get money
to call his chauffeur?
That's what he told me.
Say, what's going on here?
I don't know what
he's talking about.
Oh, you must be mistaking
him for somebody else.
Say, what do you two
do for a living?
We work, of course.
Where?
Don't list the store.
We'll get fired.
Hey, stop that!
Where do you work?
At the Automat.
What do you do?
I have charge of blueberry pies.
I put them in those little boxes.
And what do you do?
I, uh... I help him. I...
I snap the boxes shut.
There's something
fishy going on here.
My feet hurt. Can't we continue
this while we're seated?
You know, you ought to
be ashamed of yourself.
Supposing someone treated
your father like this.
Is he your father?
Yes.
Girlie, I catch you in more lies
than you can shake a stick at.
If he's your father, why did you call
him Tom when you came in here?
I always call him Tom.
My goodness!
Is there a law against calling
your own father by his first name?
Come with me, miss.
Where were you born?
- In New York.
- Shhh, keep your voice down.
What street?
Uh, 121st street.
What street was she born on?
Look at me!
72nd street?
They're the ones that have been selling
this hot stuff all right. I'll bet on it.
How much do you want to bet?
Mary! Where did
you disappear to?
I got lost, and I
couldn't find...
Quiet, everybody, quiet.
I'm telling you two that anything
you say may be used against you.
- So, uh, use your own judgment.
- What happened?
Joe, you better go home.
We'll met you later.
Quiet, you!
How well do you know these two?
Well, I know them well enough to
know they haven't done anything.
Where do they work?
- Uh... Mary, stop that!
- Come on!
- The Neeley Department Store.
- Ah-haa!
Ah-haa! Some detective!
Are they, uh, father
and daughter?
Uh... yes... no, they're not!
What are you...
Joe, please don't say anything more.
I don't want to have to tell you
to keep quiet again, girlie.
How about using a more
civil tone, officer?
- Who, me?
- Yes, you.
- Have they charged you with anything?
- No.
Then you don't have to stay here.
Come on out.
Hey, stay right here!
Look, you can't hold people here unless
you've got a charge preferred against them!
I can fix that.
Was he dressed like
that in the drugstore?
Yes, sir.
Violating a city ordinance, wearing a
bathing suit on the boardwalk.
How do you like
that for a charge?
A great many other people
were wearing bathing suits.
Well, are you satisfied, or would
you like to see another charge?
- You just try it.
- Really?
Did he come along peaceful
or did he pull on your arm?
- He made quite a protest.
- He did, eh? OK.
Resisting an officer. Would you
like to see another charge?
- I'd like it fine!
- Say!
- Trespassing.
- Suits me.
- Soliciting funds.
- Keep on.
- Peddling without a license.
- Ha-ha, you're not frightening me.
Stop! He's frightening me.
And we'll throw in a little case of
vagrancy. How does that suit you?
That's just dandy.
- A vagrant. Me?
- We haven't even started on you yet.
Young man, what do you think
you're accomplishing?
I'm giving him enough
rope to hang himself.
You're giving me enough rope? I've
got a little surprise for you, too.
I'm charging you with
obstructing justice.
- Fine.
- And contempt of police authority.
Fine.
And suspicion of inciting
a group to riot.
Fine.
What's the matter? Your imagination
running out of charges?
Are you an idiot?
Who do you think this man is?
This man is a servant of the people,
that's all. And a darn poor one at that.
I don't work for him,
he works for me.
How do you like that?
Let him put me in jail. I'll holler
my head off. This is a free country.
You let a guy say you were spitting
on the sidewalk when you weren't
and the next thing he'll do
is tear up the Constitution.
Say, are you crazy?
Yes, I'm a little crazy.
But that happens to me my
particular kind of patriotism
I don't care how small the right is
you're trying to take away from me.
I'll fight for it.
The Boston Tea Party was
started over one penny.
This is big enough for me.
Well, put me in jail.
Don't tell me what to do.
I'm running this place.
Go on! Lock me up!
You've got enough charges.
I'll lock you up when
I'm good and ready.
OK, take your time.
We, the People of the United States,
in order to form a more perfect union
establish justice, ensure
domestic tranquility
provide for the common
defense, promo...
Don't look so startled, sergeant.
In case you didn't recognize it
that's the beginning
of our Constitution.
I'll recite it for you.
Where was I? Oh, yes...
Provide for the common defense...
There he is. If he thinks he's
right, he won't give into anybody.
- Isn't it wonderful?
- It isn't very practical.
No, he isn't. But
he's wonderful!
I also know some of the
Declaration of Independence.
I might get a couple of the words
wrong, but you'll get the general idea.
When, in the course of human events,
it becomes necessary to...
- I don't like this.
- Neither do I.
When they start reciting the
Constitution, look out.
We had a nut like this downtown once.
It was awful.
- What can one fellow like him do?
- It's not him, but it gets in the papers.
That somebody sends down a big lawyer, then
you ought to see what happens in court.
- You'd think it was a big murder trial.
- What? For a little thing like this?
The way they mix it up? Turns out
that Abraham Lincoln's on trial.
- Lincoln?
- Trial downtown took over two weeks.
Two weeks? My vacation
starts Wednesday.
Oh, but you'll spend it
listening to Abraham Lincoln.
In a nice hot courtroom.
My wife would skin me alive.
One of them reporters will be here any
minute now. You know what'll happen then.
Yeah.
Quiet!
A lucky thing for you that
I feel charitable today.
I'm gonna to suspend charges
on both of you. Go on.
Oh, no you don't. Wait a minute!
You're not going to
get off that easy!
I'm not going to get off?
We don't want any suspended
charges hanging over our heads.
- What do you want? An apology?
- Well, what's wrong with that?
You humiliated this man.
You dragged him in here barefooted,
questioned him like a criminal
and you think an
apology's too much?
Boys! Throw him out!
I'm not going to move one step until those
charges are not suspended, but dropped.
All right, they're dropped.
And I apologize.
Now get out of here!
I didn't that you'd have
the grace to apologize.
Even in that tone
it's appreciated.
And stay out of this precinct,
or I'll have you arrested.
Go on about your business.
Next time you bring a thing like that in
here, I'll throw you right into the ocean.
Yes, sir. I mean no, sir.
Lincoln!
Say, we'd better get you dressed.
You two try to cool off on the sand.
Joe?
What's that for?
Because you're wonderful.
Some wonderful.
Come on.
It's getting pretty late. We
better wake 'em up and go home.
Oh, let's let 'em sleep a while longer.
They must be awfully tired.
You know, he didn't
like you very much.
But I think he changed his opinion in
the police station. I was watching him.
Whether that old goat likes me or not,
it certainly doesn't change my life.
Did you watch what
he's been eating?
He acts like a guy that just
discovered his stomach.
I don't think a goat could
put that stuff away.
You know, you're making
him a responsibility.
I want him to marry Elizabeth.
- Oh.
- Why shouldn't they get married?
- Well, why should they?
- Because she loves him.
- How do you know?
- I can tell.
It'd be wonderful for him.
He must be very lonely.
It doesn't make any difference how many
people you talk to during the day.
If you haven't got someone that
really cares for you
you're all alone.
You're one person
against the world
unless you have someone.
Then it's only half as hard.
At least you're two against the world.
So you both starve, instead
of starving alone.
Joe... Don't let
yourself get depressed.
It's all over, Mary.
We've lost.
What do you mean, we've lost?
400 employees out
of a possible 2500.
How can you blame them?
Black list, store detectives.
I don't see how we got the 400.
- Maybe if you gave it more time, Joe.
- Time? We had a year already.
So we'd have a 100 more, they'd
walk out like sheep to the slaughter.
People like this who starve quietly
wishing they hadn't joined.
Oh, it's doomed,
Mary, I know it.
Got the poor suckers into working,
at least keep their jobs.
Joe, if you could only
reach all of them.
Yeah, if, if, sure.
If the store would only ask 'em all to go out
to Bryant Park and let me speak to them.
Mary, I want to talk to you.
I meant to do it when I brought you
home, but now's as good a time as any.
I can't get a job in New York.
Mary, I... I can't see you anymore.
For a while.
What do you mean?
Well, I... I can't. I
can't take up your time.
Is that what you call our
relationship? Taking up my time?
I haven't got the right to take up your
time, that's what I'm trying to tell you.
Well, I think that you might
ask my opinion about that.
What are your plans, Joe? What do
you want to do? Go out of town?
I'll go with you, that's not
such a terrible thing to ask.
- Oh, Mary you'd...
- But I'd love to if you want me.
Oh, I wish you'd marry
me, just like it is.
- I'm not afraid.
- Marriage?
You're not afraid. No,
women are never afraid.
How long do you think you'd be in
love with me, living off your salary?
That's nothing to be ashamed
of, if you can't help it.
Not to you, but it is to me.
I bought me a $5 wallet for my birthday
and left the sales slip in so I could
trade it in for the money.
Oh, who are we fooling? The next
step will be giving me the money.
A quarter at a time, for lunch,
for carfare, for cigarettes...
I can't be in love under
those conditions.
I... I don't want to marry you.
Honey, I...
I shouldn't have done that. I didn't
have any right to ask you to marry me.
I don't own you, you know,
even though I do act like it.
We've got to look
at it sensibly.
Maybe, it'll still turn out
all right in some way.
But I... I couldn't go away
obligating you to wait for me.
That's very considerate
of you, at least.
Maybe I hope you'll wait for me.
But you're young and attractive,
you got a whole life ahead of you.
Go out and meet people,
have a good time.
It's certainly coming to you.
Who knows? You might get
interested in somebody wonderful.
Yeah. That's what someone
was telling me recently.
That's what nature does, let you
get interested in other people.
It's a kind of protection.
Well...
Then I don't promise to wait for
you, if that'll make you happy.
What do you intend to do, Joe?
Uh, why, the government's taking
young fellas for construction work.
Down in Panama. I'd have a
trade by the time I get back.
You only have to stay a little while.
Two or three years, I think.
Two or three years?
Why, I... I thought you meant
you'd only be gone a few months.
Why, you're nothing but a coward.
That's what you are.
For all your bravery in police
stations you can't even face life.
Half the world's
starving to death
and you're afraid to get married because
you might not be able to get a job.
It's not me I'm worrying about.
I'm not going to get locked up in a hall
bedroom watching you iron my shirts
and nobody's going to make me.
Nobody's going to
make you do anything.
- Go on to Panama, go any place you like...
- Oh, Mary, now...
Right now you can go on home.
Go on, unless you're
afraid of the dark.
Better keep it.
It's going to turn
out all right.
I've got a seventh sense.
- You mean a sixth sense.
- I mean a seventh sense.
I've got a sixth sense
and a seventh sense.
It's going to turn
out all right.
You really shouldn't drink.
It isn't good for you.
Three glasses of beer. You
can't get drunk on that.
- You are.
- Oh...
- Elizabeth?
- Yes, Tom?
- I want you to tell me something.
- What is it?
Didn't Hooper ask you out today?
- Yes, he did.
- Well, why did you go with me instead?
- You really want to know?
- Certainly.
- You won't laugh at me?
- Of course not.
Well, Mr. Hooper is the...
Well, he's the executive type
and you're sort of helpless and
need someone to look after you.
- He's the executive and I'm...
- Now, don't be offended.
People can't tell on themselves.
That's the type you are.
Oh, for heaven's sake!
I don't like the executive type.
What you can see in
him is beyond me.
Well, he asked me to marry him
during the clearance sale.
- Did you even consider it?
- To be honest, I did.
Well, why didn't you?
I didn't know whether I loved him. Maybe
I'd be marrying him for his money.
- Has he got money?
- Oh, he makes $55 a week.
Fifty-five dollars?
I don't see how a woman can
marry a man with money.
She'd always feel that maybe... maybe
she'd married him not for what he was
but for what he has.
There'd always be that
doubt between them.
- Oh, my...
- Don't you feel well?
Elizabeth?
I wonder if you'd care
for the real me.
I think I know the real you.
I may not be exactly as I
appear on the surface.
Well, no-one's really perfect.
I'm not.
What do you mean,
on the surface?
- Are you married or something?
- No, no, no, no...
- Then what is it?
- Well, I, uh...
I've got a very weak stomach.
You put your stomach
in my hands.
Oh, our station! Good night, Mary.
It was lovely.
See you tomorrow, Mary.
Good night.
Hello.
Hello!
Dorothy, I'm sorry to get
you out of bed so late
but this is very...
This is very important.
Do you still go with that fellow that
works in the personnel department?
Yes, I do.
Well, give me his telephone number.
I have to speak to him tonight.
It's for you, Sam.
Yeah?
Uh, Sam, Sam, listen...
We're in terrible trouble. Meet me at
the employees' entrance right now?
Now?
You mean this late?
Yes, now!
As long as there's a
chance we can win
I'm going to stick.
Yes, dear.
They locked me out of my room.
Can I sleep on your roof?
Yes, dear.
What's the matter
with you, honey?
Mary!
Mary, I'm back.
Don't take it so hard.
I'm going to stay here.
Yes, dear.
Good night, Joe.
Good night, honey.
I won't see you for breakfast.
I'm starting out real early.
- Well, you can have breakfast.
- Mh-hm. Good night.
Remember the list
with the 400 names?
Mh-hm.
Where do you think it is?
Down on the sand at Coney.
It's in Higgins' pocket. And
he's a spy for the store.
What?
Who? Who? Higgins?
And there's no mistake.
And he's got all those names?
All those poor people.
And it's my fault.
Where does he live? I'll get
that list back tonight.
I don't know.
Tomorrow. You get him in
the stock room. I'll get that list.
How are you going to
get in the store?
Don't worry how I get in the store.
You get him in the stockroom, see?
And I'll join you.
And I'll get that list if I have
to hit him over the head.
Will you please sign, Mr. Hooper?
Our friend Higgins seems to be
a little late this morning.
Probably drinking last night.
Oh, he only had three beers.
- You were with him yesterday?
- I... We...
Mary and Joe
No, just Tom and I.
Mr. Higgins and I went to the beach.
He asked me before
you did, really.
That's perfectly all right.
- Ah, who have we here?
- Good morning, Elizabeth.
Good morning, Mr. Higgins. Tom.
- We're a little late this morning, aren't we?
- Oh, did you come late, too?
You are a little
late this morning.
- Yes, I am.
- And why, may I ask?
Because I overslept.
I was tired.
- Well, that's a novel excuse.
- Well, it's true.
- I don't like your tone of voice.
- I don't like yours, either.
Who do you think
you're talking to?
Just another employee
in the store. That's all.
And a darn poor one at that.
Do you know what's going to happen
to you? You're going to be fired.
- I'm going to be fired?
- Yes.
Let me tell you something. You're going
to be fired. How do you like that?
Five pairs of these high-tops
come back in the exchange.
Ha! Give me my 10 dollars.
- Bring them in here.
- Hey, where's my money?
- You shouldn't have done that, Tom.
- Why not?
I'm entitled to common courtesy.
- It doesn't work that way.
- The trouble with you people is
you have no faith in employers.
Well, where's my sales book?
I'm worried about him.
Elizabeth, you know, you've...
you've lead a very sheltered life.
Now, men aren't exactly
what they seem to be.
Some men are wonderful.
Other men are beasts, like...
Well, like other men.
Oh, honey. Joe will come back.
It isn't Joe.
I'm talking about a
particular party.
Who thinks nothing of toying
with the heart of a good woman.
How'd you like what
I said to Hooper?
You were very brave
but foolhardy.
Mr. Higgins, would you be kind enough
to assist me in the stockroom?
- Is it necessary?
- Most necessary.
Well, what happens?
Uh... there's been a lot
of trouble in here.
Uh... there should be a right shoe and a
left shoe in every one of these boxes
and lately, there's been a
right shoe with a right shoe
when there ought to be a
right shoe with a left shoe.
What's that again?
Uh, look, you just open every box
and see that there's a right shoe
and a left shoe in it.
I'll be right back.
Mr. Higgins!
Mr. Higgins.
Tom!
Tom! Tom, say something.
Say something. Oh dear.
- Is this Higgins?
- Yes.
- Are you Jones?
- He's drunk.
- He is not!
Come on, you two. The General
Manager wants to see you. Up.
Where am I?
- Where are you taking me?
- To the General Manager's office.
Is that how he makes people
go to his office? Oh!
You must feel pretty good,
Mr. Higgins.
You'll probably get a raise after
they fire all of these poor people.
You Benedict Arnold
in sheep's clothing.
I'll show you who's a Benedict
Arnold in sheep's clothing!
You watch!
Is this the way you discharge
your responsibility?
Can't you understand that dealing
with people the way you do
is the reason for this
civil war around here?
I've worked with these people.
They have rights.
What do you suggest? I suggest
that you get a different job
if you can't get the confidence of your
employees. You bumble-witted idiot!
Tom... Tom, this is wonderful
what you're doing.
And you'll never regret it.
Let them fire you.
As long as there's a breath in my
body you'll never go hungry.
Calling me names
isn't the solution.
I'd like nothing better than to get
the confidence of my employees.
But who can I talk to? Who
represents enough of these people?
Would you consider 400 enough?
Yes, I would.
There's our representative.
Where are your 400 names?
There's the catch.
He wants the names.
See? My hands are tied.
- This isn't a trick, is it?
- Do I look like I'm lying to you?
- No. You don't.
- Mary, you can't.
If there's a right way, this is it.
We're not being fair to him.
If we want him to trust
us, we gotta trust him.
Well, I'm against it.
I'm taking a big
chance too, Joe.
I... If this doesn't go, I lose you.
All right, honey.
Well, Tom, have you got the list you
picked up on the beach last night?
- Yes, I have.
- Give it to Mr. Allison, please.
It's going to be terrible if you
fool these two young people.
You old fool. How dare you come into
my office and talk to me like you did?
I can outwit morons like you every day
of the week and twice on Sundays.
Which is why I sit behind the desk
while you stand in front of it.
Why, you!
Hooper, get that paper!
Keep your hands off of her!
- Harley, McGinnis, come in!
- Ahh!
You idiots! Both of
you, I discharge you!
Eat it! Eat it!
Give me that paper!
Give me that!
Stop it! Stop it, I
say, you idiots!
Stop it! Oh!
Stop it! Stop it, I say!
Why, you mashing brute!
Give me that paper!
Stop it, I say!
How dare you?
I'll have you discharged!
Every one of you!
Now, you simpleton. I'll
show you who can outwit who.
Who're you going to fire now?
You give me the name of
everybody on that list
or I'll fire the entire
5th floor for starter.
That's not fair. Many people on the
5th floor know nothing about this.
Every name or else they all go.
Every one of them.
Get out of my way!
Discharge slips. For
everyone on the 5th floor.
- Yes, sir.
- How dare you? What do you mean?!
- Hold that door! Get it open!
- Help me, Tom!
Stop that! Take it out!
Employees! Listen
to me, everybody!
Come out to Bryant Park!
Don't be afraid! Everybody together!
If we all walk out now, we got 'em licked!
Come out to Bryant Park.
Drop what you're doing and
come out to Bryant Park!
If we all get together now,
they can't stop us!
Here we go! Everybody out!
Leave what you're doing!
Don't just stand there!
Move! Go on, walk!
Everybody together!
Come out to Bryant
Park, don't be afraid!
If we all walk out at once,
we got 'em licked!
Come out to Bryant Park!
Shhh! Picket...
Picketing your house.
George. I'm worried.
Elizabeth won't marry me.
A man with money.
Maybe, in your case,
she will make an exception.
- Do you think so?
- Maybe.
- No.
No, it's against her principles.
She'll have to know sometime.
Right now!
- Don't get excited, J.P.
- We'll call the police.
Nobody's going to call anybody.
I'm going to send for the ringleaders
and have it out right now.
- You wait in there.
- Excellent idea. We'll handle them.
- How do I get out the back way?
- This way, sir.
Get my hat.
Tommy, you son-of-a-gun!
There he is!
Tom, where have you been?
Mary! Here he is!
We got a surprise for you.
- You've got a surprise for me?
- Yup, look.
We decided that nobody was to have
the honor of carrying this but you.
- Come on, folks, we have to keep moving.
- Wait!
They're waiting inside there
to meet with us.
What?!
Tom, how did you arrange it?
It wasn't hard.
Oh, Tom, that's wonderful!
Come on, in we go!
This is it, folks!
Get rid of that old fool.
Elizabeth!
You do like me, don't you?
Of course I do, Tom.
Just the way you are.
Oh, my.
You sit here.
Well, let's begin.
That's right, let's begin.
- Suits me.
- We're ready.
You know you're not in a very
good bargaining position.
Maybe not, but the
store's closed.
We can open it again!
And very easily!
Let's not raise our voices.
Yeah, that's right.
Uh, I don't know very
much about business, but
from a woman's viewpoint, there
are moral issues involved here.
Miss, we are not concerned
with moral issues.
- Why aren't we?
- Because we aren't!
Moral issues are
pretty important.
Oh. I see your point of view.
Uh, could I have a word?
This may sound foolish, but
in my opinion, one of the things that
ought to be corrected in this store is
Go on!
Well, there ought to be somebody in
the store's pet shop on Sunday.
All those canaries there
without water the whole day.
Canaries?
That's the most idiotic
thing I've ever heard!
Talking about canaries at a time
like this! That's purely idiotic!
There's nothing
idiotic about it!
Certainly! There's nothing
- There are moral issues involved.
- How can you say a thing like that?
Excuse me.
Madam, have you gone mad?
- Get your hands off him!
- Let go of Mr. Merrick!
Let go of Mr. Higgins!
- Are you hurt, Mr. Merrick?
- Are you all right, Mr. Merrick?
Elizabeth, money isn't everything.
You could learn to love me.
Mary, you see my side of it.
Say something!
Joe!
Hey, that's my wife
you've got there.
This one's yours.
Ignore him.
We're having a swell time,
Mr. Merrick.
Glad you are, Mr... Mr. Feldspar.
Men's Clothing, 3rd floor.
Lovely dress, Mary.
Our debutante model, $27.75.
You remember Mrs. Craig, Lingerie, 5th
floor? Mr. Martin, Hardware, basement?
- Mr. Merrick.
- How do you do?
Do you remember everybody's
name in the store?
Almost everybody.
- Oh, aren't they having a wonderful time?
- Yeah.
- He's all right!
- Who's all right?
Merrick's all right!
Gee, this is wonderful!
I can't believe we're
really going to Honolulu.