Of course.
I've just spoken to them.
- And do they know what happened?
- No more than you read there.
- And what speed?
- The fastest yet achieved anywhere on Earth.
"Disintegrated... Wreckage lies
scattered over a mile-wide area. "
It looks as if it really
had exploded in the air.
- But they must know more than this.
- They don't. There's nothing left to tell.
- They may have hit something.
- Aye, he hit something all right.
He hit the speed of sound.
Well, it looks as if I might
have been wrong after all.
Cos you can't get through this thing. That
was a great aircraft, flown by a great pilot.
- Yes, I know.
- Well...
Do we go on?
Well, that's for you to decide, isn't it?
Yes, I suppose it is.
I wanted to know how you feel about it.
Could we get a full report on all this
and could I look at it? It might help us.
Oh, and if you're sending a wire,
you might put my name on it too.
He was a good bloke, old Geoffrey.
I'd better say it at once. I'm going
on with this sound-barrier business.
Why, Tony?
It's difficult to explain. I... just
feel it's got to be done, that's all.
By you?
Yes, by me.
Was... he married?
Yes, I believe he was.
Is there anything I can say
that will stop you, Tony?
No, Sue. Nothing.
Don't you see, I... I
can't let the show down now.
Let the show down? Is there no thought
in your mind of letting me down, or him?
- Oh, Sue.
- If only I could understand, Tony.
But I can't, you see.
I can only see a great wall in the sky
strong enough to smash an aircraft to pieces.
And beyond it, nothing.
Nothing at all.
I'm sorry, Sue.
Darling...
I promised to speak to Dad and ask him whether
I mightn't give up this job, but after...
Well, after this, how could I?
Don't you see what he'd
have felt about me if I had?
I've heard those words before, Tony.
Christopher said them to me
the night before he was killed.
He was scared too Father
might think he was a coward.
Oh, it isn't that.
I just don't want him to think I'm ratting on
a job because someone else got killed doing it.
- Where are you going?
- I can't face him tonight.
Oh, darling.
Leave me alone.
Oh, Sue is not feeling very
well. She's not coming down.
Oh.
Sorry.
You know, when I first started flying,
some people, religious people,
thought what we were doing was wrong.
They thought it was breaking a law of nature.
Sounds funny now, of
course, but they used to say,
"If God had meant us to fly,
he'd have given us wings. "
Now, this sound barrier...
people might feel again that God had
put it there for his own good purpose.
That it can't be broken.
That it would be wrong to try.
Now, I wouldn't blame anyone
who believed that. I...
I wouldn't blame them at all.
- Do you believe that, Tony?
- No, Dad.
If I believe anything,
it's the exact opposite.
Oh, if only I were 30 years younger.
Well, sorry about Sue. We'll
get Factor to send her up a tray.
Let's go in, shall we?
Mummy, somebody at the door.
Yes, dear, I know.
Oh, Sally, don't play on the
stairs, dear. I've told you before.
- Hello, Jess. Am I disturbing you?
- No, of course not. Do come in.
I was shopping and I thought I'd drop in.
- Hello, Bobby.
- I made this.
Oh, isn't that lovely.
Jess, I wanted to speak to
Philip rather urgently. Is he in?
No, but he'll be back quite
soon, I expect. Let's go in here.
Oh, I do think you've done this charmingly.
You know this is the house
I'd set my heart on, don't you?
Why did you want this when you've got
that big house almost to yourselves?
I just did.
Here he is and I haven't got
the pie in the oven. Excuse me.
- Hello, darling.
- Hello, sweetie.
- Look who's here again. Isn't that nice?
- Oh.
I'm just getting lunch.
- Hello.
- Hello. I was passing and I thought...
Well, it was a nice thought.
Come on, come and sit down.
- How was the flight?
- Wonderful. Tony was kind about my flying too.
- No regrets, then?
- None at all.
Why does everyone I'm fond
of have to be a test pilot?
Why can't they sit in offices
like the rest of humanity?
The rest of humanity doesn't
know what it's missing.
When Tony's flying these days...
I try to go to the cinema.
You can't hear the sound so clearly in there.
Philip...
How does Jess feel about all this?
Oh, I think she accepts it
just as a job like any other.
I wish I were like Jess. I'm
not very brave, I'm afraid.
When's he testing the
Prometheus at full speed?
I don't know.
You do, I think. But perhaps
it's best you shouldn't tell.
- What's he doing at this minute?
- He's up for half an hour on a routine test.
- Will you stay for lunch?
- Oh, won't that be difficult for Jess?
- Has she enough?
- She'll manage somehow.
Susan, you mustn't worry, you know.
There's no better pilot in this country.
Philip, I believe to have courage,
one must also have understanding.
If only I could understand
the purpose of it all.
You know, I don't think that sort
of understanding comes from up here.
Only from here.
Jess, lay on another place, will
you? Susan's staying for lunch.
- Well?
- Tomorrow at 3:00.
- What, the full test?
- Yeah.
That's good work, Will.
She's still nose-heavy over Mach 9.0.
- Well, give up the test if you're worried.
- Of course I'm worried! Wouldn't you be?
Tony says it's not serious.
He can correct easily.
He doesn't want to wait any longer. Nor do I.
- You need a rest, Will.
- Of course I need a rest!
I've needed a rest for over 35 years.
- Give me a drink.
- You know where to find it.
- Where is Tony now?
- He's over with the new test pilot.
That boy's a good flyer, by the
way. Tony says he's better than him.
That's not true. No one's better than Tony.
Tony hasn't got it up here.
That's what a pilot needs
nowadays. Brains and imagination.
- Isn't that what they've always needed?
- Maybe. Well, here's hoping.
- Well, what is it, Dad?
- A galaxy in Andromeda.
- And how far away is that?
- Oh, about 700,000 light years.
You mean that what I am seeing now is the
way this galaxy looked 700,000 years ago?
That's right.
Hm.
- I'm looking at the past, then, aren't I?
- In a manner of speaking.
Is there a way of looking into the future?
- Yes.
- How?
Through that telescope. What you see there is
the past, the present and the future, all in one.
The process of continuous creation.
Stars die, stars are born.
No beginning, no end.
Yes, you can see into the
future out there, all right.
- Nice hobby you've got here.
- Passes the time.
- Well, good night.
- Tony?
- You hardly knew Christopher, did you?
- Well, just that one night.
Susan blames me for his death, doesn't she?
Oh, that you needn't answer. I know she does.
I just wondered if you blame me too.
You can tell me the truth, I can take it.
Do you, Tony?
No.
Hm. Well, good night, Tony boy.
Happy landings for tomorrow.
Piece of cake.
Oh, sorry, darling. I
didn't mean to wake you.
- You're very late, Tony.
- I've been gassing with the old man.
Are you flying tomorrow?
Just the usual bumble around.
- What time?
- Three o'clock.
- I'll see that film at the Palace.
- Mm.
It's a good one, I hear.
- Darling?
- Mm-hm?
Do you mind if we call him John?
I think I do.
- Good night.
- Good night, my love.
- Pity.
- What?
- That I didn't meet you ten years ago.
- Why?
I'd have had ten years longer
of being married to you.
- Good night.
Tony?
Oh, Tony.
Crash crew, this is Control,
testing. How do you hear me?
Roger. Stand by in crash
position on runway 2-0.
- Good afternoon.
- Hello.
Ridgefield Tower from Glass
Jar 1-0. Clear for take-off?
1-0. Clear to go.
Roger.
Ridgefield Tower, this is Glass Jar 1-0.
I'm going up to 40,000 and dive her first
at a Mach number of about 0.95 or 0.96.
- Roger, 1-0. - Coming
in over the airfield now.
1-0 to Tower. Flying level. 30,000 feet.
Conditions pretty near perfect.
Visibility unlimited.
I'm going up another ten to 40,000.
40,000, straight and level.
Outside air temperature, 50 below.
Revs 12.5, ASl 380 knots.
OK, here we go.
0.90.
No buffeting, trim correct, increasing speed.
Nine four.
Nine five.
Buffeting, nose-heavy, trimming back.
Port wing dropping. Air
brakes open. Throttling back.
OK. At that speed, nothing serious.
Behaviour normal, apart from nosing down.
Right, I'm going up to 40,000
feet again for the full go.
Hello, Tony, this is Will. Did you correct
that nose-heavy trim before opening air brakes?
All right, Will, you old hen. Everything
you said would happen did happen.
All in order, don't fuss.
What about your nose-heavy
trim? Did you correct?
Of course I corrected. I told you
I was climbing again, didn't I?
OK, 40,000. Straight and level.
All set.
Hang on a minute.
Here we go. This is it.
Nine-five.
Buffeting. Nose heavy.
Trimming back.
Nine-six.
Nine-seven.
Nine-eight.
25,000. Very nose-heavy.
Air brakes open.
The controls don't respond! I can't hold her!
Nine-nine!
- Still no response!
- Bail out.
It's coming up to Mach One!
Bail out. Bail out.
Tony!
Crash, square able 7.
Get back!
- Why did you come here?
- I wanted to.
I wanted to.
Halt!
Here, you'd better sit down.
- Is... Is Father here?
- No.
He was here for an hour
or more, but he's gone now.
Oh, Will.
I don't know what to say to you,
Susie, love. I don't know what to say.
I can't go on, of course. I've had
my fill of designing aeroplanes.
Still I don't know where it
went wrong. I can't fathom it.
Oh, I suppose I've got too old.
What are you going to do?
I don't know. I... hadn't thought.
- I must go somewhere, I think.
- No, Susie love, please, don't.
I'm thinking of JR. I know how things are
between you, but don't leave him alone now.
Not for a bit, anyway.
I must go now, Will.
Please don't blame yourself.
Tony knew... he was up against
something he couldn't beat.
Come on, I'd better take you home.
All set.
Hang on a minute.
Here we go. This is it.
Nine-five.
Buffeting. Nose-heavy.
Trimming back.
Nine-six.
Nine-seven.
Nine-eight.
Down to 25,000. Very nose-heavy.
Air brakes open.
The controls don't respond. I can't hold her!
Nine nine!
Still no response.
- Bail out.
- Coming up to Mach One!
Bail out. Bail out!
- Sue.
- Jess.
Get Dr Peyton, Philip.
Come along, we'll go upstairs.
- It is a boy, isn't it?
- Yes.
Oh, it's Tony.
- Name this child.
- John Anthony.
John Anthony, I baptise you
in the name of the Father,
and of the Son,
and of the Holy Ghost, amen.
Now, smile, please.
He's here. The car's outside.
Oh dear, I hoped he wouldn't.
Oh, don't panic, Jess.
Ah, how do you do?
- Well, hello, Sue.
- Hello, Father.
Hello, young fella.
- Did you christen him Tony?
- No, John.
It was what Tony wanted.
Hm. He's a fine baby.
Yes, isn't he?
- Oh, Sir John, can I tempt you to this?
- Oh, thank you. It's a charming house you have.
Glad you like it, Sir John.
I haven't had a chance yet
of congratulating you, Father.
Mm. Quite a surprise.
- I hear the new airliner's is a great success.
- Mm. We hope so.
Now, here's a small present for... John.
Thank you.
The Chinaman, he says, "Me no likey
plitty lady. Me likey plitty drinky. "
- Hello, Will.
- Hello, JR.
Delighted to see you looking better.
- How was Bognor?
- Oh, very restful, very quiet.
- I'm glad you're back.
- I'm not back.
Oh.
Well, when you're at Bognor, you might
have a look at this. I'd like your views.
- Byfield's work?
- Yes.
- What's his idea in that?
- To increase stability.
The way I see it, JR, a good aircraft has... It's
got to have something sort of... inevitable about it.
Now, look. This thing could be changed
a hundred different ways. For example...
Do you know what you are,
JR? You're a vile seducer.
Oh, by the way, I hear you've
made a... new Prometheus.
- What's the idea?
- It's too good an aircraft to lose, Will.
It's the best that came out
of England since the war.
- No. It failed, JR.
- It wasn't the aircraft that failed, Will.
Now, you come and see me on Monday.
Well, this may not be the time to tell you,
but I've been watching your work very closely,
and now Makepeace is leaving us, I've
decided to promote you to chief test pilot.
- Oh, thank you, Sir John.
- In the firm, I'm still known as JR.
- Take up the new Prometheus tomorrow.
- Yes, JR.
Take her up every day for the next few weeks.
No specific tests, just get used to her.
- Right.
- Goodbye and thank you. A charming party.
Oh, and Peel? Not above Mach
9.0, until further orders.
- Philip?
- I think so.
Hello, darling.
Come on. Up we get.
- Has John been good?
- Yes. He doesn't seem to mind the noise at all.
- Jess?
- Mm-hm?
You've both been very good to me here. I don't
think you'll ever realise how grateful I am.
Why this all of a sudden?
I think I've got that flat in London.
Oh dear, I'm sorry. We
shall both miss you terribly.
I shall miss you.
Couldn't you find something
a little nearer here?
I don't want him to grow up in
the shadow of his grandfather.
Come on, darling.
- Why not stick the nose on the tail?
- I'll stick your nose on your tail.
- Will?
- What?
Is it possible that at the speed
of sound, the controls are reversed?
At the speed of sound,
Philip, anything's possible.
Why?
During the war once, I put a
Spitfire into a flat-out dive.
No particular reason,
just youthful high spirits.
I think now that I hit the sound barrier.
I remember that the more I pulled on
the stick, the harder the nose went down.
- The same thing happened today.
- You're not meant to do a high Mach number!
I know, but I did.
Both times, I felt that if I'd had the guts to
put the stick forward instead of pulling it back,
I could have pulled out
without having to lose speed.
What do you think?
There's nothing in the books to suggest for
one second anything so Edgar Allan Poe-ish.
Rather depends on the
books, doesn't it, Will?
There were books once that
said the Earth was flat.
Yes?
Oh. He's here.
It's JR, for you.
Hello?
Peel here, JR.
Yes?
What, now?
Well, yes, of course.
What have I done? He sounded grim as blazes.
Here's Daddy.
- I'm sorry I'm late, darling.
- We had to start, darling.
I had to see the old man.
- You've got it, then?
- I've got what?
- Well, the rise, of course.
- Oh, blast it. I forgot to ask him.
- You forgot to ask him?
- Yes. I'm sorry darling.
Oh, really! What a husband.
All right. Bobby, go
out and play on the lawn.
- That's it, you come with me. Nice flight, dear?
- Yes, thanks. Wonderful.
I've got something hot for you in the oven.
What does he want?
- You won't tell Jess, will you?
- No.
To take the Prometheus up and reproduce
the conditions under which Tony crashed.
Could I have the bread, please?
Thanks.
- At the same speed?
- Well, faster, if possible.
When?
I shall take her up this
afternoon for a high Mach number,
and if that's all right, full crack tomorrow.
Are you going to do it?
Look, I don't have to, you know. This
was merely a suggestion, not an order.
Hm.
That's the situation, Sue.
I don't have to, but I must.
- Why must you?
- Well...
It's a bit hard to explain. I only know that
if I don't accept your father's suggestion,
I should never want to fly again.
And as flying, I've now found
out, is my life, well, I...
- There we are, darling. I hope it's still all right.
- It looks lovely.
- Fancy you forgetting to ask for the rise.
- Don't worry. I don't think he'll... object now.
- Is it safe to buy the coats for the children?
- Mm.
Oh, good. Now they'll look smarter
than those stuck-up Harrison kids.
A complaint from one of our most
important customers in Mexico
has revealed to me a possible defect in
the Marlborough Mark 3 engine mounting...
Ah. Oh, Will.
What's the test scheduled
for the Prometheus tomorrow?
- The details are on the sheet.
- There's one quite important detail that isn't.
- At what Mach number is my machine to fly?
- Mach One.
Wasn't Tony enough for you?
We learnt a lot from Tony's crash.
Just enough to know that to fly
at the speed of sound is death.
- Haven't you had enough of that?
- No.
Ever heard of pilotless aircraft?
This problem can't be solved
with pilotless aircraft.
Not in years, anyway.
Well, what are a few
years one way or another?
Important to me. I may
not have so many of them.
Hm. Trying for a peerage now, huh?
You'd better get out, Will.
I'm sorry for you, JR. I don't know
what devil it is that's eating you up.
And it can't make life any too happy for you.
Cable to Mexico City. Your letter received,
and will receive our attention. Stop.
Oh. Good evening, Sue.
Good evening, Father.
Well, you don't often give me the
pleasure of seeing you these days.
- How's my grandson?
- He's very well.
Good.
- Father?
- Yes?
- Are you going on with this test tomorrow?
- What's that to do with you?
Did Philip tell you what
happened to him this afternoon?
Yes. I've just been reading his report.
For a good ten seconds, he
was completely out of control.
What are his chances if
that happens tomorrow?
Well, it might not happen tomorrow.
Please put off the test, Father.
No.
You're prepared to let
Philip go the way of Tony?
Well, we don't know the way of Tony.
That's Philip's job tomorrow,
to find out how Tony was killed.
And Tony was finding out how
Geoffrey de Havilland was killed,
and another pilot will find
out how Philip was killed.
And each time, we'll learn a bit more.
So that one day, Ridgefields will build an
airliner that'll go to New York in three hours.
Two.
So a few people who can afford it will
spend an occasional weekend in New York,
and Ridgefields shares will go up and up.
My dear Susan, what kind
of man do you think I am?
I don't know. I... really don't know.
What sort of a man with... two deaths on his
conscience could risk burdening it with a third?
A man whose passionate worship is for a
pile of bricks and mortar called Ridgefields?
My dear Susan, if you were to tell
me that only by giving up Ridgefields
could I find out what happens to
an aircraft at the speed of sound,
I'd say, "All right, Susan,
my girl, it's a deal. "
- I don't believe that.
- That's because you can't understand it!
You make imaginary sacrifices for yourself, but
it's other people's lives you really sacrifice.
You think I felt nothing at Tony's death?
What else can I think, when a few hours after
his death I find you listening to his voice?
Our ways are different in so many things, I
expect our ways of grieving are different too.
Well, I don't suppose
you've any more to say to me.
Yes, I have, Father.
- I'm taking John to live in London.
- Oh. Indeed?
You know why I'm taking your
grandson away from you, don't you?
You want me to think of
you as a man with a vision.
Well, that vision has killed
both my husband and my brother.
And while I'm alive, it's
not going to kill my son too.
There are evil visions as well
as good ones, you know, Father.
That's why I'm taking my baby away.
Thanks, Windy.
- Tell them I'll be out in two minutes, will you?
- OK.
You sent for me, Father.
Well, thank you for coming.
I've... I've got something to say.
1-4 to Tower. Climbing now.
JPTseems a bit high, but
other pressures normal.
Checking. Will call again later.
Erm, before you go off, I... I wanted to
know what school you've got John down for.
Is that all you wanted to say?
No. Good schools are not two
a penny. You've got to think.
But surely there's plenty of time.
I'm climbing to 40,000 feet.
Weather conditions ideal.
I'm going to make my first
run level at full throttle.
I'm still climbing.
- Susan...
- Yes, Father?
Levelling out now. 40,000.
All right. I'm all set.
Starting run now.
Increasing speed.
Revs twelve-five.
Mach 0.88.
0.89. Slight buffeting.
0.90. Getting nose-heavy now. Correcting.
Throttling back.
Run completed.
- I'm sorry, I must go.
- No, don't go! Stay and talk.
Don't leave me alone.
1-4 to Tower.
Still at 40,000. At that speed,
she was quite controllable.
There was a slight port wing
drop, but nothing serious.
Didn't have to use trim,
I corrected on the stick.
JPTnow normal.
Well, what were we talking about? It, erm...
- It was about schools, wasn't it?
- Yes.
Right. Second run.
This time we'll try a dive.
35 degrees.
Here we go again. Starting dive... now.
Maximum revs.
0.91.
Slight buffeting.
0.92.
She's pitching a bit. Still buffeting.
0.93. Nose very heavy now.
Trimming back.
Port wing dropping. Correcting.
0.94. Still under control.
Nine-five.
Nose still going down.
Air brakes open, throttling back.
Second run completed.
Can a vision be evil, Sue? Can it? Can it?
I shouldn't have said that.
It's a terrible thing to make a man
doubt everything he's ever lived for.
If I've killed them both for nothing.
Well, it can't be true, can it? Can it?
Ridgefield Tower, this is 1-4. 40,000 again.
All right. Third and last, steepest
possible, dive. Full throttle.
Here we go.
Nine-four.
Nine-five.
Buffeting.
Nine-six.
Nine-seven.
Nine-eight.
Out of control.
25,000 feet.
Air brakes on, throttling back.
Pulling out of dive.
Ridgefield Tower, this is 1-4.
Nose heavy again. I couldn't trim out,
I had to use the air brakes to pull out.
All right. Clear to land now. Runway 3-0.
1-4, negative. I've got an idea I
want to try out. I'm going up again.
Ridgefield Tower, this is 1-4.
40,000 feet.
I think I can beat this nose-heavy
business by reversing the controls.
Anyway, I'm going to try.
I won't be a moment.
All right, here we go.
Increasing speed.
Nine-four.
Nine-five.
Buffeting.
Nine-six.
Nine-seven.
Nine-eight.
She's out of control.
Nine-nine!
Mach One!
I'm putting the stick forward.
She's coming up!
Throttling back.
It's sticking.
I did it! I did it!
1-4 to Tower.
On fourth run, Mach meter showed 1...
.. point 01.
Corrected nose-heavy trim
by putting the stick forward.
Have you got that? Stick forward.
I'm landing now.
He's got through.
It's all right. He's got through.
You'll...
You'll do me a favour, will you?
Of course.
You don't tell anyone what happened
in this office this afternoon.
Do you think I would?
I say. A chap called Sound just looked in.
He's absolutely livid with you, old boy. He
says he's going to bump his speed up next time.
Oh good, I've found you in.
- Hello darling. I...
- Look at this.
- We've got to make up our mind now.
- Look, darling...
Do you think the colour's too much? Cos they've
got a sort of beigey colour with stripes, and I...
Well, it seemed a bit dull to me, but...
Look, darling, pay attention.
This is very important.
- Is it all right?
- Yes, I'm sorry, darling. Yes, it's fine.
Good, that's lovely. I'll
be able to get back in time.
Well, bye-bye, darling. See you at home.
Hm.
I thought I heard a car. I
wondered if it could be you.
He has the look of Tony.
His eyes.
- What's that?
- It's the moon.
I never knew it could look so unfriendly.
It's an unfriendly universe.
Do you believe that?
Unfriendly only because it's
unconscious of our existence. 12
- That's a depressing conception.
- Doesn't depress me.
In our fight with the universe,
it gives us the advantage.
Must it always be a fight?
Well, I think it must. It wasn't for nothing
we were given so many weapons to fight with.
- Such as?
- Imagination, for one thing.
Which some people call vision, don't they?
Yes, some people do.
And I suppose another weapon is courage.
- Daddy, why didn't you tell me?
- Tell you what?
How alone you must have been.
Even Will had more imagination than...
I am sorry.
You've no need to be.
- I must put John to bed.
- Yes.
- He's no right to be up as late as this.
- And you mustn't keep your car waiting.
The car's gone, Father.
We've come home.
Hm.