Watch out, Axel!
Gonna be blowing "fireballs"
after tonight.
Fucking-A!
Not bad!
Steve, now you're going to the army,
how about giving me my 20 bucks back?
Alright, Mike!
Take care buddy!
See ya fellas!
You know about the happy Roman?
He was "glad-he-ate-her!"
Let's go!
Where's Stan?
Stan, Let's go!
Take it easy, don't get your
ass shot off! Take care!
Take care of yourself! Good luck!
Kill a few for me too!
Axel, there's Stan!
Stanley, you asshole!
It's no use!
Come on, you're beautiful enough!
You're still an ugly bastard!
Good luck in the army, Mike!
Get the hell outta here!
Look at that!
What the hell is that?
Where?
Holy shit! You know what that is?
Those are sun dogs.
What does it mean?
A blessing on the hunter
sent by the Great Wolf.
What are you talking about?
It's an old Indian thing.
You're full of shit!
Would I shit you about
something like that?
You know, there's times nobody
but a doctor can understand you.
That's an omen. We could have one
fucking good hunting trip tonight.
I don't know where the hell
you come up with the shit!
Wait a minute!
You thinking of going
deer hunting tonight?
Not tonight!
I'm getting married tonight and
you guys are going deer hunting?
First we'll get you legal and
tuck you in bed with Angela.
You're fucking nuts!
Life is over!
You're getting married,
we're crazy!
It's all right.
It's all right, we'll
be right with you.
Am I right?
Right!
Come on!
Come on! I'm buying the
first round this morning.
Steven, any help you need tonight,
feel free to call on me.
Sometimes your humor ain't funny!
Willing fingers!
Extra lips!
Great!
- You're a regular poet, Axel!
- I couldn't agree with you more.
I do!
Oh, my God!
I still do not believe this!
My own boy with a strange girl!
And not so thin,
if you understand my meaning.
The next thing is,
he goes to Vietnam.
I do not understand, Father.
I understand nothing anymore!
Nothing!
Why?
Can you explain?
Can anyone explain?
Pass on the inside.
You'd never do it!
Shut up! I'm trying
to concentrate!
- It's your caddy against my truck.
- It ain't your lucky day!
Axel, you owe him a window!
Mighty!
Mighty Mike!
Here's your truck back.
I hope I didn't break it, Axel!
That was a million to one
shot against a sure thing.
There's no such thing.
Did you see that?
How you doing?
Don't take anybody's money!
Don't take my money, take his!
What do you want to drink?
A "Kessler" and a "Rolling Rock!"
And give my friends down
here my warm regards.
I got a 100 bucks says that the "Eagles"
never cross the 50 in the next half ...
and the "Steelers" win by 20.
I've got an extra 20 that says the
"Eagles" quarterback wears a dress.
Drinks are on the house!
Joe, maybe we could
use some more flags.
Is that all right?
Up a bit, I would say.
No, down!
Oh, the beautiful cake!
You have a beautiful cake!
I haven't forgotten about you!
I have one for you, too.
Go to fucking hell!
I'll give every car in
the town a flat tire!
Goddammit!
I'll do it!
I fucking mean what I say, girl!
Come on!
All around ... Like a sea!
Ocean of flat tires!
Fucking bitch!
All bitches!
I hate 'em!
Daddy, no! It's me!
Give 'em all flat tires.
It is great!
It's my shot, right?
Come on,
wipe off the table!
This is it.
This is really it.
I mean ...
here I go!
There's no sense
getting too relaxed.
You faggot!
Bum!
Jesus Christ!
How can you do this
to your own mother,
who prays for you all her life?
How can you be so
cruel and unfeeling?
You marry this girl,
you leave her ...
with me and you go with
these bums to the Vietnam.
It's one flight!
It's one flight upstairs!
When I come home ... One flight!
I love Angela.
And she loves me.
Wear a scarf today!
You don't wear a
scarf with a tuxedo.
I'm not wearing a
- You trying to look like a prince?
- What d'ya mean "trying?"
You should've done that a long
time ago, that way it would've set.
I know.
- Then why didn't you do it?
- Because I forgot.
Steven's getting married in
a few hours. I don't know why ...
we're talking of hunting
one last time.
The whole thing is crazy!
I'll tell you one thing.
If I found out my life had to
end up in the mountains,
it'd be all right.
But it has to be in your mind.
What?
One shot?
Two is pussy.
I don't think about
one shot anymore.
You have to think about it.
A deer has to be taken
with one shot.
I tell people that.
They don't listen.
Do you think about Vietnam?
Yeah.
I don't know, I guess
I'm thinking about the deer,
going to 'Nam ...
I like the trees.
The way they are in the
mountains, all different ...
The way the trees are.
Sound like some asshole, right?
You're the only guy
that I'd go hunting with.
I like a guy with movement and speed.
I ain't gonna hunt with no assholes.
Who's an asshole?
Who do you think is an asshole?
They're all a bunch of assholes!
I love 'em, they're great guys,
but without you I hunt alone.
Seriously, I do.
You're a fucking nut!
Know what Mike? You're a
maniac. A control freak.
I just don't like surprises.
- Damn thing won't open!
- Give it a kick!
Not like that!
See that?
Fucking-A!
Axel, now I know why you're not
kicking for the "Steelers."
I love Mike's car.
Some cars, they just sit.
You never know with a car like this
where it's going to take you.
It makes me feel safe.
Axel is humping Mike's
"Coupe de Ville!"
Get out of there!
Get up! What are you doing?
Sit up! Don't ...
Here, put this on,
you must have it on.
Crummy tuxedo!
It's been stuck a million
times. Where did you get it?
You're not funny!
- I'm beautiful!
- No you're not!
Thanks, Amy.
Axel, come on!
Beautiful!
Linda, what's the matter?
I was gonna pick you up!
What's the matter?
He ...
I wanna ask you something!
Wait a minute, goddam it!
What the hell is that on your face?
Nicky, you and Michael, you're
going away in a couple of days.
I was just wondering if
I could use this place to stay?
Sure!
I'd want to pay you both.
- And I was thinking ...
- What are you talking about?
I would want to pay you.
Kochatka, it's me!
How long have you known me for?
What?
I don't know.
Have you, Steven,
a firm intention ...
to take unto yourself
as wife, Angela?
I do.
You have not promised yourself
to any other bride?
I have not.
Have you, Angela,
the firm intention ...
to take unto yourself
as husband, Steven?
I have.
You have not promised
yourself to any other man?
I have not.
Blessed is the kingdom of
the Father and of the Son ...
and of the Holy Spirit,
now and ever ...
unto ages and ages.
For a buck, you get a shooter,
and a cigar, and a dance
with the beautiful bride.
Fucking-A!
Quiet, please! Please!
Thank you! I have a very important
announcement to make. The owner ...
The owner of the white Chevy
Impala, would you please move it,
it's blocking the driveway ...
Ladies and Gentlemen, Angela and
Steven would like to welcome you ...
and introduce you to their bridal
party, especially Michael and Nick,
who are going to Vietnam with Steven
to proudly serve their country.
You dance with me!
Monday is the day!
Monday!
You nut, you want me to dance?
You know I'd be going with you
guys if it wasn't for my knee?
I'm not the greatest
dancer in the world.
- You're okay.
- No, I am not.
You're very fancy.
Do you want a beer or something?
A beer?
Okay, sure.
What kind do you like?
What?
I don't know,
I don't care, any kind.
I'll get you a "Rolling Rock."
It's the best beer around.
A "Rolling Rock?"
I'll be right back.
Do you wanna come ...?
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Jerry, two "Rolling Rocks"
and give me a "Kessler."
It's okay. It's a wedding.
You're supposed to
let go and have fun.
You like Nick a lot, eh?
Put me down! What are you doing?
Axel, no! Put me down!
What are you doing?
I wanna kiss you!
Stop!
Stop! Or I'll stab you!
Do you want to fuck or fight?
I'd like to dance with the
lady, if you don't mind.
Have you known him long?
Know what the son of
a bitch is doing?
He's got his hand on her ass!
It's only a wedding, Stanley.
What do you mean? The guy is ...
Look! He did it again!
I'm going to get my
gun out of my coat.
Go! Get it!
I'll give him a kick up his ass!
- Stan is crazy.
- What's happened?
He's crazy.
A Green Beret!
Jerry, give the man a drink!
Give him a drink.
Don't cause any problems!
I just want to talk to him.
We're going over there!
Sir, Mike Vronsky.
Nick, and this is
the groom, Steven.
I'm the best man.
We're going airborne!
I hope they send us where
the bullets are flying.
Right!
Fuck it!
Fuck it? What did he say?
Fuck it! That's right!
What's it like over there?
Can you tell us anything?
Fuck it!
Okay, fuck it.
Fuck him!
Fuck who?
Who the hell is he?
No idea!
Looks like a fucking hillbilly.
Give him another drink, Jerry!
Hey, fuck it!
Will you marry me?
You would?
What I mean is when
we get back from ...
I mean, when we get back.
I don't know what the hell I mean!
What goes through your mind
comes out of your mouth.
Angela and Steven!
If you don't spill a drop, it's good
luck for the rest of your life.
Don't worry about what
Stan says. Forget that!
He's got a big mouth!
I never really did it with Angela.
Great! That's great!
It's my last one true secret.
That's nothing,
just forget about it.
What am I gonna do
when she has a baby?
Leave it all to
Angela, hang loose.
Be happy!
See you Monday on the train.
Drive carefully!
You didn't know that
about Angela, eh?
- It's bullshit!
- Yeah?
- I happen to know it's true.
- You're full of bullshit!
You want a bet? Put your
money where your mouth is!
Fuck you!
Grow up!
Alright!
Michael, what are you doing?
What the hell are you doing?
What are you doing?
Come back here!
What is he doing?
Come back!
I've got to talk to ya!
Shit!
I must be out of my fucking mind!
I must be out of my ...
Everything's going so fast, man!
Think we all will come back?
From 'Nam?
You know something?
The whole thing,
it's right here.
I love this fucking place.
I know that sounds crazy,
but if anything happens ...
don't leave me over there.
Just don't leave me.
You've got to promise me that.
No, man, you've got to
promise, definitely.
You've got it!
Promise?
That sounds like shit.
It is the "Screaming
Eagles Airborne" song.
"Screaming Assholes!"
I can't remember the
rest of the words.
Get scared!
Don't push!
It's fucking cold!
36 beers!
What?
Right, I'll go 'round already!
Did you ever piss and take a
drink of beer at the same time?
I barely got a chance
to shake it off.
Wait! You fuck ...
Bastards!
Sons of bitches!
You guys going my way?
That's not funny!
Don't fuck around now!
Come on, don't fuck around!
Don't fuck around!
Let me out!
This is not it!
Somehow they changed it.
Like this happens every year!
You're full of shit, Stanley!
Who did you say's full of shit?
You, you're always full of shit!
I'm starving.
Eat that!
How come I never see you eating?
I like to starve,
keeps the fear up.
It ain't natural. Come on, John!
That's mine!
- You really want it that bad?
- Right!
Give me a "Twinkie," Mike.
What are you guys,
a bunch of cripples?
- That's mustard!
- What?
You put mustard on your "Twinkie!"
You're talking like a traffic cop!
Unbelievable!
Give me a beer, Mike!
I can't believe you guys!
What am I doing with you?
This is not it!
They changed it somehow!
You couldn't find your
own ass with two hands!
Fucking-A!
We forgot to toast
Steven and Angela.
What?
- Don't, I've got things in my mouth!
- I can't take you guys anywhere!
What are you doing?
Get your hands off the bread!
You can dress them up, but
you can't take them anywhere.
What the fuck are you doing?
That was mine, you assholes!
Fucking assholes! You can't ...
Fucking-A!
You've got a terrific vocabulary!
Hey, where's the gear!
Gimme my bag!
It's getting cold, eh?
Hey, Mike. You got any
extra thermal socks?
Got any extra thermal socks?
Come on, I got 'em.
Where the hell's my boots?
Anybody seen my boots?
Somebody took my boots!
I bought 'em special.
Alright!
Alright, guys!
I want my boots back!
I've got a boot,
right up your ass!
Mike, let me borrow
your extra pair?
No, Stan.
No?
- What do you mean, no?
- Just what I said: No! No means no!
You're some fucking friend.
- You know that?
- You've gotta learn, Stanley.
- Here, you've got your head up your ass!
- Maybe he likes the view up there!
Every time he comes up, he's got
no knife, no jacket, and no boots!
All he's got is that stupid gun
he carries around, like John Wayne.
That ain't gonna help you.
What the hell?
Give him the boots!
I ain't giving him
no boots, no more.
You're a fucking bastard!
See this? This is this!
This ain't something
else! This is this!
From now on, you're on your own.
I fixed you up a million times.
I fixed him up a million times.
I don't know how many times!
And nothing ever happened.
Your trouble is
nobody knows what
you're talking about.
"This is this!" What the hell's
that supposed to mean?
Is that some faggot
sounding bullshit?
Shut up, will'ya?
You're outta line!
Watch out with that gun.
You know what I think?
I think you're a fucking faggot!
Come on, you guys!
Last week he could have had the
new waitress at the "Bowladrome"
and look what he fucking did?
Nothing! That's what!
Shut up, Stan!
Shut up! Take Michael's goddam boots
and shut up, otherwise I'm going home!
OK, I'm going home right now!
Get off my stuff!
What the hell you doing?
Hey, Stosh ...
I said no.
Where you gonna shoot me?
Here!
What's the matter with you?
Bums! Go home!
Un-fucking-believable!
Christ, I don't believe it!
Jesus Christ!
Stevie, take it easy!
Stevie, calm down!
Think of something else!
Pull yourself together!
We don't belong here.
Stevie, it's gonna be okay! Okay!
- I'm loose.
- It's gonna be okay.
- I'm okay.
- Okay, take it easy.
It's okay!
Take it easy, Stevie!
Come on!
I'm okay.
Keep calm. Press hard. Okay!
Okay, press hard!
I'm here!
Go ahead, that's it!
Shake it out!
Think of something else, of home!
Think of home!
Think of Angela.
Come on!
You're gonna have to kill my ass.
You've got to do it! You don't,
they'll throw you in the pit ...
and you'll die.
You can do it!
You can do it, Stevie!
Look in my eyes.
Stevie? Stevie, look at me!
Do it!
Alright, show 'em you got balls!
Fuck you, you ...
Go ahead, shoot me!
Come on!
Go ahead! Go ahead, Stevie!
Show 'em you got balls.
Go ahead!
Hey, kid!
Kid!
Look at me, Stevie, you did it!
You showed these bastards!
Don't worry, kid!
You did it.
Stevie, don't worry!
Help!
Oh, God!
Michael, there are rats in here!
Motherfucker!
Nicky, listen!
It's up to us now.
It's me and you.
What about Steven?
Forget him!
- Forget him?
- He ain't gonna make it.
Who do you think you are? God?
Look at him. He's in a daze.
He ain't coming to life in a dream!
- What are you saying?
- I'm saying, forget him.
Get it through your head, or
you and me are both gone too.
- We've gotta play with
more bullets. │- What?
More bullets.
I've gotta get more
bullets in the gun.
- What? │- We've gotta
play with more bullets.
With more bullets in the gun?
How many more bullets?
Three.
So that means we've got
to play each other.
More bullets against each
other? What are you crazy?
It's the only way!
I'll pick the moment.
When I start shooting you
go for the nearest gun ...
and zap the fuckers.
I'm not ready for this.
You gotta listen to me! You want
to stay down here and die?
It's up to you,
now it's up to you!
No!
Him against me!
Get away!
Me and him! Me against him!
Come on!
These fuckers! Go ahead, Nicky!
It's gonna be all right!
Go ahead, Nicky!
I do three bullets, three!
Three! We do three, ya?
One, two, three! Three!
Three!
Three.
Don't worry!
5 minutes we're gonna
be outta here!
Now we've got ourselves a game. You
and me. Now we've got a real game!
Ok, you want a game! Alright.
Go ahead!
No more. No, no more!
I'm gonna will us outta here!
Put an empty chamber in that gun!
- Goddam it! │- It's gonna
be all right! Go ahead!
Shoot, Nicky!
No, Nicky!
You goddam ...
You're gonna die, you
motherfucker! You're gonna die!
Go ahead, Nicky! Just do it!
Do it!
Go ahead!
You made it!
Alright, we're gonna show 'em.
That's good!
Alright.
Come on!
Nicky!
Get me up!
Stevie, come on!
We're gonna go for a swim.
We're foreign here in
the jungle, Michael.
Just get out of here, see!
There's rats in these waters.
Hold on.
I wanna go home!
What is that?
What's that sound, Michael?
I've hit some rocks.
I've hit some rocks, my legs ...
My legs!
Come on!
My legs, I hit some rocks.
My arm!
I can't feel my legs!
Alright, come on!
Are you Nikanor Chevotarevich?
Can you understand me, Nikanor?
Yes, that is me.
Are you sure?
Chevotarevich, is
that a Russian name?
No!
It's American.
Right, let me see your name tag.
Is this yours?
It's his.
What are your parent's names?
Lou ...
And my mother's name is ...
Eva.
What are your parents'
dates of birth?
Get him out of here.
Excuse me.
Hello?
I'm calling the United States.
Clairton, Pennsylvania.
Clairton, C-L-A ...
I-R-T-O-N.
Pennsylvania, right.
Never mind!
Nothing! No, never mind!
Back off, Jack!
Back off!
How are you?
I'll show you. Come upstairs.
It's not like this with the
girls back home. It's ok.
I give you a special.
Make you crazy.
No, I don't want that.
Come on inside!
OK, what you like to call me?
What would you like to call me?
Linda, just like home.
No! Thanks!
Call me Linda!
Hey, look!
Elephants!
I've got to get the elephants.
No!
I can't stay in a room
with a kid crying!
- Come on!
- No!
Why don't you pay
me first? Fuck you!
You seem disturbed.
People inside doing it for money?
Sometimes a great deal of money.
I can't play this
kind of game myself ...
but I'm always ...
how do you say ...
looking out for those things
quite different, quite rare.
Champagne?
No.
Don't say no.
When a man says no to champagne,
he says no to life.
You saw this before?
Up North.
Oh yes, of course!
Gotta go.
But you must come in!
I insist!
What is there to be afraid of
that is war? War is a joke.
- A silly thing!
- I'm going home, Ace.
Naturellement I pay
my players. Cash.
American.
However, should you prefer
German Marks or Swiss Francs,
that, of course,
could be arranged.
I can arrange everything.
You've got the wrong guy, Ace.
- But you must come in.
- Don't do that!
But I insist!
If you are really brave and lucky,
I can make you very, very rich.
Wow, would you look at that!
- Just keep going!
- You said Logan Street.
- The trailer is right there!
- Just keep going!
Wait 'til Michael gets here!
This is it! This is Michael!
Stay right there!
I'll go and get him.
- Everybody ...
- Stay here!
Three cheers for the
red white and blue!
- That cab ain't stopping.
- What's going on?
What happened?
I thought it was him.
His plane could be late!
Take it easy, Axel, you're
driving everyone nuts!
You okay?
I know Nick'll be back soon.
I know Nick, he'll
be coming back, too.
- Right, Axel?
- Fuckin-A!
- Go straight on down to the highway!
- It's your bread, man!
It's open!
You look beautiful.
Let me take your coat.
Everybody was here,
you missed them!
They are going to be so mad when
they find out they missed you.
Welcome home!
I was hoping ...
I was hoping somehow maybe
you had Nick with you.
No.
Did you hear anything on Nick?
Nothing. He is AWOL,
that's all we know.
He'll be back.
He never wrote to me.
He never called me.
Maybe you were out.
Yeah, maybe.
So, how are you, anyway?
Fine. How are you?
Me? I'm okay, I'm fine.
I go along.
Still working at the market ...
There's a million things to do.
You sure, you're all right?
What about your wounds?
There is nothing.
Just the usual
complications that's all.
But we heard ...
That's not true, lots
of guys go through it.
I made Nick that sweater.
I couldn't remember
the exact size.
I think he is about
the same size as you.
No, too big.
Well, I could fix
that though. I mean ...
one thing about wool:
It's really a cinch ...
to fix.
Christ!
It's okay!
It's okay.
- How's your job?
- Great! Fine!
Once or twice we almost had to
close. I've gotta go to work now.
You've got to go now? Would you
mind if I walked you to work?
Mikey, you're so ...
weird!
You're always such a gentleman.
It's cold out there.
I'm not used to it.
I'm so glad you're alive.
I'm so happy!
I really don't know what I feel.
Linda, I just wanted to say
how sorry I am about Nick.
I know how much you loved him and
I know it will never be the same.
I just wanted to tell you that.
Maybe ...
Maybe, you don't want
to talk about it.
How's it going, Hot Lips?
A new kid.
A real tough guy.
It's okay.
Come in with me and say hello.
Please, just say hello.
They want to see how you're
doing. Just a second, okay?
Hey, look who's here!
It's Michael!
Michael, I read a lot
about you in the paper.
Doesn't he look terrific, Janie?
Hi, Michael! Beautiful, you look!
You look good Michael! Welcome back.
Wait a minute! Look
at all the medals!
Helen, come on!
We really won over
there, Mike? We won.
I have to go to work now.
Good to see you.
See you, Michael.
Come see us, Michael.
Can I see you later?
- After work?
- Where? At home?
- One beer at John's.
- What?
I'll buy you a beer.
Alright, just one.
Hey, look at this.
Mikey, how you doing?
Where was you?
- Where was you?
- Where was I?
We had everything all
there, the beer,
am I right, Axel?
I got there too late.
You've got a moustache.
Looks pretty good.
- Cute!
- It looks ...
Come on, we're going to John's.
So how you guy's been?
Hanging in there.
How does it feel to be shot?
It don't ...
It don't hurt, if that's
what you want to know.
How things been? Been okay?
Same old thing.
Nothing has changed.
I'm getting more ass than a toilet seat
and Axel is getting fatter than ever.
Show him that gun.
Take it easy!
That little pussy
thing. Look at that!
What's that for?
- The same thing the other one
was for. │- And what was that for?
- He's a warrior.
- Forget it!
Let's go have a drink!
Come on in the back! Come on!
What's going on?
Stosh, get the glasses
out of the sink.
- The dirty one's?
- Yeah, use them.
Holy shit!
Did you win the war by yourself?
With no help from you.
Here we go!
To you, Mike!
Fucking-A!
Wait! To Nick and Steve!
To Nick and Steve!
You look great!
How's Angela?
Not so good.
- Worse since she talked to him.
- Talked to who?
Steven? I didn't know he was back.
You didn't know he's back?
I didn't know he's
back. Is he back?
You ...
Where is he?
Okay, Hey, come on John!
Where is he? Just answer me.
I don't know where.
I don't know where he is.
Angela wouldn't tell us.
She wouldn't talk to anybody.
Is that true?
I heard Steven was
alive. Where is he?
Where is Steven?
Just tell me where he is.
Angela, where is Steven?
Where is he?
Please!
You gotta tell me, where is he?
Where is he?
Take care!
I'm in here!
What are you doing?
Nothing. I just got my
gear, I was going to go.
What?
- I was going to go.
- Don't go!
I have all this food.
I'll make you a nice dinner.
I can't.
Why don't we go to bed?
Can't we just comfort each other?
I can't. Not here!
I've got to get outta here.
I'm sorry. I've just
got to get out. I ...
I don't know,
I feel a lot of distance. I feel
far away. I'll see you later.
It feels kinda weird
going to a motel.
You know what I mean, Michael?
I gotta put my can down for this.
Michael, it's on the house.
No, thanks.
Thanks, buddy!
- How you feeling?
- Fine.
You okay?
You sure?
- What do you think of her?
- I don't know.
Come on, on the level.
I don't know.
Is she beautiful?
- Truth?
- Yeah!
No!
No.
- Do you think she's
intelligent? │- No.
Neither do I!
I don't think she's
intelligent either.
- What the hell do you see in her?
- I don't know. That's what I'm asking.
Do you think she's good in bed?
Why don't you ask her?
Where is that fucking ball?
What's he doing?
- What's up?
- The ball ...
Get the jack out of the car!
Watch your elbow!
- Alright?
- Fucking-A!
What you guys want to do now?
We're going hunting, right?
Who asked you?
I'm asking Mike. He's going.
He's going.
But no women.
Just like old times, am I right?
- Just like old times!
- Fucking-A!
You kidding me, Axel?
40 times we could've had it!
If I had been where you are.
Go get him, Axel!
Fuck you!
How sweet it is!
Fucking-A!
Jesus Christ! What was that?
Hey, John! Hey, Axel! I got one!
Hey, fellas, I got mine!
What is that stupid
gun doing up here?
In case.
In case? In case of what?
In case you stumble on your girlfriend
sucking on a forest ranger's cock?
Say that one more time!
Say it!
You're so full of shit,
you're going to float away.
- Try me? Say it!
- You're gonna float away!
- Take it easy, Mike!
- What was that for?
Did you think it was loaded?
Give me it!
You want to play games?
I'll play you games!
How do you feel now? Huh?
Big shot!
Linda's in back.
- How was the hunting?
- Fine, thanks.
What's the matter?
I don't know.
Nothing. I don't know.
It's got to be something.
I got the car outside.
Well, that's okay.
Are you sure?
It's okay. Just leave me alone.
Really.
We'll get you home.
I think I'll go with him. Thanks.
You okay?
You ever think life
would turn out like this?
No.
We have a Bingo!
"Johnny Come Lately!"
Where are you, Johnny?
There you are!
B 15, I 16,
N 33, G 16.
We have a winner!
Get out of my road!
I can't see myself smoking.
The next number is I 16.
I wish I was sweet sixteen.
I 18, then you become a man.
Let's go, men! G 60!
And help those boys who
can't help themselves.
Will you dance with me? G 47!
I'm still satisfied
with what I've got.
The wonderful life I've lived.
Think it over, buddy boys,
and I'll give you O 6.
Steven, there's a call for you.
Maybe it's from Angela.
- Hello.
- Stevie, it's me, Mike.
How's things?
I'm okay. Never mind
me. How about you?
Great.
What's that noise?
What?
Wheelchairs!
When are you getting out?
I'm going to stay here a while.
- What for?
- The place is great!
It's like a resort.
I mean they've got
basketball, bowling ...
What?
Princess Grace came to
see us the other day.
I've got to go, Mike.
Curfew, man!
Mike? Hey, how are you?
We made it!
That's it!
I don't want to go home!
- I know.
- Good!
Good! Really!
You look good!
You do any hunting?
- Yeah, I did hunting.
- Did you get one?
You didn't get a deer?
No!
I was tracking this beautiful
buck but it slipped away.
- Angela didn't send you?
- Angela?
- She didn't send you?
- No.
Good. I've got
something to show you.
- What?
- I've got something here.
Come here. Something
I gotta show you.
Angela keeps sending me socks.
But it's not socks
I gotta show you.
This comes every month from
Saigon. I don't understand.
That place is gonna
fall any day now.
That's Nicky's.
Nick's alive?
What do you say?
How do you know?
That place is going to
get caught in a shit storm.
Where's a guy like Nick
get money like this?
Cards maybe.
Listen, Steven, I'm
going to take you home.
Aw shit! You promised me!
I don't fit! Look!
- I'm going to take you home!
- Shit man, look!
You promised me! I don't fit!
I'm sorry! You do as
your heart tells you, man.
- Anybody wants one?
- No, Sergeant, we're running late.
Make way!
Where are you going?
Come with me.
Remember me?
Do you remember me?
Do you remember Nick?
Where is he?
I don't know.
Really, I don't know.
He disappeared a long time ago.
- Hold on a minute.
- What are you looking for?
Nothing to see here!
See that?
- What do you want?
- I want a game.
That's for you.
It is too dangerous now.
These times are too dangerous ...
Do you think I'm afraid of you?
I want to play the American.
I'll match him. Highest stakes!
How do I know, you
know where he is?
Because I know, that's all.
But I have to take
you by the river.
Only because I feel
comfortable with a white suit.
Here we are! If you'd
like to change your mind ...
Wait here!
He say we have to
pay for go inside.
- How much?
- 1,000 dollars.
Tell him I'm coming up.
The American is inside. You have to give
him 500 dollars for this information.
- Where is Nick?
- I don't know.
- Where is he?
- I have to ask the boss.
Are you all right?
Nick, it's me!
What are you doing?
Nicolas, what's the matter?
Get away!
Do you know it's me? Mike.
Tell me: It's Mike.
- Tell me, it's Mike.
- It's Mike.
Mike who?
- Mike who?
- Mike who? I don't know.
I came 12,000 miles to get you.
Don't do that to me!
Fucking don't do it!
What's the matter with you?
Don't you recognize me?
Nicky, I love you. You're my
friend. What are you doing?
Don't do this to me, you fucking ...
Did you hear what I said?
Let me in the fucking game!
How much?
How much? Here's how much!
Here, you can count it!
Why not?
- I don't want the money.
- You don't want it? Take it!
Tell him!
We don't have much time.
Don't do it!
This what you want?
I love you.
Come on Nicky. Come home!
Just come home. Home!
Talk to me.
Wait! What did you do to your arms?
Remember all the different trees?
Remember that?
The mountains ...
Remember all that?
- One shot?
- One shot!
Nicky, Nicky, don't!
No!
This seems to be the last chapter
in the history of America in Vietnam.
It's also been the largest movement
of people in the history of America.
Hillary Brown, "ABC News" on board
the aircraft-carrier "USS Hancock" ...
in the South China sea.
I'll get these tables.
Axel, bring those
2 tables over here.
Everybody make yourselves at home,
the coffee is already made.
- Cups! I'll get them.
- I'll help you with that.
I'll help, too.
There's too many cups.
- How does everybody want their eggs?
- How about just scrambled?
Toast!
Careful, that's hot!
Hey, Axel, how about some beer?
I'll get started on the eggs.
- I'll help you.
- No, sit down!
Pour the coffee!
It's been such a gray day.
To Nick!