- Travers?
- That's right.
Bert Connolly. Glad to meet you.
- Did you have a nice trip down?
- Fair.
- I've fixed for you to stay with us.
- Oh...
I don't think that's a very good idea.
- Well, whatever you say.
- Well, let's push off, shall we?
As far as everybody else is concerned,
we meet for the first time tomorrow.
No, I just thought she was
a long time in the bathroom,
so I went in and there she was being sick.
So, I asked her, "What's up?"
- Morning, Tom.
- Hello, Jack.
- You know, just asked her...
- How about practice today, Tom? Any go?
Yeah, all right, fine.
Tell the boys.
There aren't that many ways of saying it.
I just said,
"Don't tell me you're in the club again,"
and that set her off.
Oh, dear! The old Italian stuff
started hitting the fan,
- and she's yelling at me, "Yes, she is!"
- Yeah, those Italians can't half hand it out.
- All right, Tom?
- Hi, Freddie.
- Don't feel like it this morning?
- No.
Hello, Doris, how goes it?
What's the matter?
Saving it up for Christmas?
There again, I was only asking.
You know... is it too late? That's all.
And bang, she starts all over again!
Ooh, look at that
seventeen jewel movement!
She reckons she's nine weeks over.
What would that make it?
May? Yeah, end of May.
Would be,
I don't even get the tax rebate.
- You're really in trouble, boy.
- Wouldn't you be worried?
Yeah, I'd be worried, I'd be doing me nut -
I'm not married.
See you in a minute.
Hey!
- Concerns you, you know?
- Really? Jolly good!
- What's ol' Gladys doing then?
- Yeah, whatcha doing, Gladys?
Don't call me Gladys!
Hey, Chuck,
you gonna have a basin of this?
Have a giggle, eh?
Nah... what for?
What for?
You can read, can't you?
Yeah, bleedin' union man, ain't you?
Nah... he's Salvation Army.
Ol' Eddie... "Salvation Army"!
- Come on, let's have a giggle, eh?
- Any tarts out there?
- Yeah, that's right, sit with the tarts, eh?
- Watch it. Davis.
So? We're entitled to study
union notices, ain't we?
Yeah, well now, brothers,
I hope you'll all be willing to support...
All right, let's get to work!
Only keeping up with current affairs,
Mr Davis.
Yeah, you wanna keep up with haircuts -
do you more good.
You'll get that lot caught in a lathe
one of these days.
I'll be Yul Brynner then, won't I?
Ol' Eddie! Yul Brynner!
Mr Connolly!
My fault. My fault.
- You all right?
- Yes.
Stupid of me.
Don't know what I was doing.
- You'd better go and see Sister.
- No, I don't want to make a fuss.
No, it's not a question of fuss.
You go and see Sister.
You might have shock later on.
You report as per regulations
and you got the company for damages.
Should be guard rails
on all these machines!
I've been saying so for ages!
I should get along and see Sister.
- I was coming to tell you about...
- I'll see to him. Get off.
I do feel a bit faint,
as a matter of fact.
Silly thing to happen!
My name's Connolly.
All right, boys, the show's over!
Start it up, Ted!
Are you familiar with these?
Well, you have a look around.
I'll be back with you in a minute.
What was all that about?
Your old tabby got herself caught up
in one of them VMBs.
- She all right?
- I sent her off to see Sister.
Um...
Well, she's gone for the day then.
Could have lost an arm, you know.
Should be guard rails fixed.
Well, get them out of store then.
They're all down there rusting up.
It's the blokes who take the things off,
not me.
It's the law,
and it should be enforced.
Look, Bert, don't tell me the law.
The men take the guards off cos it's
too much trouble to work round them.
You want them back,
I'll put them back.
How about that new bod -
is he any good?
Well, if you mean
"can we use him", yes.
Right. Well, start him then.
I did it, boy, I finally did it.
You know the one in the pay office
I've been working on for weeks?
She just said yes for next Sunday.
Let me see, I'm gonna have to do
a bit of switching around.
Yeah... gonna be a day of rest
for someone.
You know, I really flogged myself
to death over that little darling,
opening doors,
carrying the tray in the canteen...
Joe... look, do you mind?
Some other time.
What's the matter?
Oh, yeah. Sorry.
Still, er... could be worse, couldn't it?
I mean, the way I look at it,
you got two kids,
you might as well have three.
Not worried about me, are you?
I can move out if you like. You know,
be sorry to go and all that, but...
Well, if you need the extra room,
don't worry about that.
Mate, it isn't due tomorrow.
Anna!
Anna?
Oh. Just wondered where you were.
Everything all right?
- Where are the kids?
- They went next door.
You all right?
Yes, fine. Thanks.
I'm sorry about this morning.
Sorry I yelled at you.
Mum and Dad weren't over here
this afternoon, were they?
Yes, they came for tea.
I knew something had upset you.
What did they want?
You tell them you were expecting?
- I told your mother.
- What did she say?
Well... didn't say much.
Not about the baby anyway.
All she talked about was
that you're just like your father.
That must have really cheered you up.
What's wrong with the telly?
The kids had it on?
No. Not that I know of.
Something special you wanted to see?
Yeah, big football game.
- Eat this while it's hot.
- Dead cert it had to go wrong.
What?
I said dead cert it had to go wrong -
finished paying for it last week.
- It's got sauce on it.
- If it's the tube, I'll kick the front in. Oh!
Brian! Cathy!
Time you were in bed.
- No, not yet, Mum!
- No, now! Come on!
They've been terrible today.
Would be tonight.
Always is when you want to
watch something good.
Brian, what are you doing now?
Nothing, Mum.
Cathy won't come out of the lav.
I shan't tell either of you again.
Come upstairs.
Brian locked me in the lav.
No, I didn't.
Can I have something to eat?
- Yes, he did.
- Oh, will you please be quiet!
And you shan't have any more tonight.
Can I have a bit of
bread and butter, Dad?
- What is he, hungry or something?
- He had a bigger plate than you.
- Please!
- Go on, then, just one.
Now she'll want one.
Well, they're growing, aren't they?
- Do you want one, too?
- Please.
Here you are then.
One each, that's all.
I said no.
Been playing a game with Ronnie.
Yeah, smashing game
called "sex maniacs".
Called what?
Old Ron thought of it all by himself.
- Can we have some jam, Mum?
- Come on, it's bedtime.
Did you hear what he said?
Daddy, when I came home from school
and I turned the telly on, it went bang...
Cathy, will you please go upstairs
and get ready for bed!
- Can we play with old Ron tomorrow?
- Well, we'll see.
Thought of that game all by himself.
Cathy, let's go round
to old Ron's tomorrow, eh?
I'll give him "old Ron" -
I'll have a sharp word with his father.
They don't know what it means.
Our two might not.
I'm not so sure about old Ron.
I don't know... kids!
They drive you up the wall.
What is it, love?
You are pleased about the baby,
are you?
I mean, when you get used to the idea,
you will be pleased.
Of course I will.
Sometimes I don't know you at all.
I don't know what you're thinking.
I don't mind now,
but I couldn't bear it
if you weren't pleased at all, not ever.
I'm pleased now.
Promise I am.
I know it was... it was a shock.
I don't mind you pretending now,
as long as you don't pretend all the time.
Look, I'm not pretending.
Annie. Annie, look at me.
Do I look as if I'm pretending?
- No.
- No, of course I'm not.
Look, I'll tell you what was wrong
with me this morning.
It came as a bit of a shock, right?
I wasn't prepared for it, you know,
and... Monday morning and that and...
well, we'll have to buy all the gear again,
won't we?
Now it's happened
we want to do it properly.
That's all.
I thought perhaps we might get
out of here this year,
maybe put the down payment on a car.
But they'll still be selling Fords next year,
and we've stuck this dump since we were
married, so a bit longer isn't gonna kill us.
What's it feel like - boy or a girl?
It just feels like a baby.
They can tell now, you know.
Tell by the heartbeat rate.
You're so funny sometimes.
You don't know how funny you are.
You just sit here and think about that
while I get you a cup of tea.
D'you want to know, darling?
Hey, Marilyn, I'm talking to you.
What are you looking at, Grandad?
You better get inside.
The first house's started,
you'll miss the big picture.
Stupid old git!
Where are you going, Ed?
Going down the park?
Staring at us, he gotta watch it!
Ol' Mick said he'd be down the park
with a couple of scrubbers.
Brian!
Well, this is D-Day, isn't it?
Too right, boy!
Starting the countdown.
Come on, Daddy! Daddy!
OK.
- Hope you count better than I did.
- Yeah.
- Who are you giving it to today?
- Nobody you know.
Who's he trying to kid?
It's that new tart in the pay office.
Ol' Mick had a go -
she don't wanna know.
Mmh... what do you want to do then?
How do you mean?
Well, we can't just lie here all day,
not talking or nothing.
I don't mind talking.
Well, you know what I mean.
Look, what do you think
I'm gonna do to you?
Tear your clothes off,
throw you in the bushes or something?
What, do you think I'm after
the old News of the World stakes?
I mean, I know I've been out
with girls before,
but it doesn't make me Jack the Ripper,
does it?
I don't know
what you're thinking -
haven't said nothing
since we've been here.
I mean, we could have saved the petrol,
stayed home and gone to church
or something - really lived it up.
Well... it's not as though
I forced you to come, is it?
Only asked you in front of
about fifty other people.
I mean, it was real intimate.
I don't know...
Shall I tell you something?
Yeah, surprise me.
You're married with three children.
You try too hard.
What do you mean, "try too hard"?
Listen, if I was trying hard,
I'd get somewhere, wouldn't I?
Believe me, I'm not trying,
I just don't like teases.
Who's teasing you?
Well, don't let's go into all that.
Seriously, what's the matter?
- You really want to know?
- Yeah.
Well, from what I hear you've been out
with everything on two legs
wearing lipstick and over age, and you've
got a couple of them in the family way,
and you didn't do anything about it.
I was told the first day I took the job
that you were the one to watch out for.
I saw you coming before you saw me,
and when I saw you I didn't care
what you'd done or what I'd heard
because you looked nice
and I thought I'd like to go out with you
if you asked me, and you did ask me.
And I still feel that way,
but it doesn't mean I'm going to be like all
the rest, or you'll get it the first time,
because I want something more than that.
If you can't give it to me,
you'd better know right away
so as we don't waste each other's time.
I see.
Yes, I see.
Well, that just about wraps it up then,
doesn't it?
Coming?
Bread and dripping, mate.
Bread and scrape, we used to call it.
That's all we had for years,
brought up on it.
My old man led the hunger march
down to London.
That was a time to be alive, believe me.
The workers was really together then.
Oh, yes, yes.
Erm... about this next meeting.
Can't have any slip-ups.
Not bad grub here, is it?
Aren't you eating yours?
Oh, sorry, can't have any what?
I mean, if necessary
you'll have to rig it.
Rig it? What, the meeting?
How do you mean?
I didn't mean "rig it" exactly,
that's just a figure of speech.
The point is, the rest of them
look to you for guidance.
- They can't think for themselves.
- No, that's true.
So, you've got to give them that guidance.
Put it to 'em in a way they can understand,
but it's no good telling them everything.
Only confuses people.
Yeah. Yes, I see.
Meeting lunch time!
- Meeting lunch time.
- What about?
If you spent a little less time
on the football pitch, you'd know.
I want everybody there.
Shut the door, will you?
I gather you're not satisfied with
the management's answer this morning.
I can't discuss union business.
No, of course not.
Just that I'm an interested party.
- Wanted to find out the facts.
- Well, you read the demands we put in.
Yeah, that's right, I did.
Course I did.
Well, let's forget about those for a moment
and talk about the real facts.
You trying to be funny?
You know me, Bert,
I never have time to be funny.
I just want to know what it's all about.
I've told you, I can't discuss
confidential union matters.
All right, well, I'll discuss them for you.
I'm not a funny man,
but I can spot a joke when I see one.
You're not contemplating coming out
cos there's no toilet paper in the bogs.
That was one of the things, wasn't it?
"Inadequate sanitary arrangements".
Look, Bert, I didn't get this job
by knocking you chaps over the head.
I worked out there once, remember?
I used to knock off the soap myself.
At least you've got toilet seats now -
in my day we didn't even have toilets.
- That was your day.
- I know what your real beef is, Bert.
You want a closed shop, don't you?
Well, maybe you're right,
but this isn't the way to go about it.
It's not that sort of factory.
Nobody's getting hurt.
Martindale's not carving you up
like some we could think of.
Everybody gets a fair whack.
If you want it all well and good,
come out and say so -
don't hide behind a smoke screen.
You'll get a closed shop all right.
You'll close the place down for good.
- I'm not prepared to discuss it.
- You're not prepared to discuss it, no.
Well, that's that then, innit?
And I'm busy.
Nice turnout.
What are you going to vote for, Gladys?
- Why don't you drop that "Gladys"?
- I'm asking you what you're gonna vote.
I don't know.
What's it all about then?
Are you in favour of mixed marriages
between the Scots and the English?
They're not voting on that!
'Ere, Eddie,
we get paid if we come out?
- Nah, unofficial.
- Waste of time then, innit?
Come on then,
what are you waiting for?
Come on!
Brothers... brothers! Brothers!
At the last meeting,
a decision was taken
to elect a works committee
to represent you in dealings
with the management.
That decision was taken
in a democratic fashion
by the majority of brothers present.
I'd like to read you the official minutes
of that meeting.
That Connolly again?
How's he suddenly sprung to the fore?
Doesn't know his arse from his elbow.
Here, finish the bottle.
Beats me why you let him get organised.
- We've managed here for thirty years.
- Yeah.
- Times have changed, you know.
They've changed this much -
I'm paying more tax
and losing business hand over fist.
Lost four orders to Germany
already this year.
Well, we've got to help them get back
on their feet - after all, they lost the war.
Don't be so bloody clever.
This beer's flat, too.
- How serious is that?
- Depends how you look at it.
Well, I mean, what's he really after?
Closed shop?
Yeah, that's about it.
Well, he can forget that.
Only one union worth bothering about,
that's the hard work union -
of which I'm a founder member.
That crew down there'll
never get organised.
And since the management has chosen
to disregard our main demands,
we must take stronger action.
What sort of action?
I therefore call upon Brother Matthews
to put the resolution to you.
Mr Chairman, brothers,
the works committee move...
Propose!
We propose the resolution that if after
a period of 24 hours from noon today
our demands are not met,
we withdraw our labour from the factory
until such time as they are.
- Order, please! Order! Order!
- Mr Chairman!
Order!
Who will second the resolution?
- Thank you, brother!
- Mr Chairman!
Shut up, give him a chance.
Quiet, everybody, please!
Have you got something to say,
Brother Arkwright?
- Yes, I have.
- Right, go ahead.
You all know me here...
Who are you?
Sit down, Crippen!
I'm a working man, and that's more
than I can say of some people.
Ooh, sit down!
I've been through a few strikes,
I mean real, big strikes,
and I'm telling you,
you won't go far
unless you have right on your side.
- Point of order, brother chair.
- Yes, point of order.
Point of bloody nonsense!
I'm a union man,
and I don't stomach any messing about.
If you want to strike,
strike with the union behind you.
Just a minute,
we're all union men, you know!
Well, start trying to behave like it!
Never mind your big speeches!
- Tell us what we live on while we're out.
- What we live on?
- You heard me!
- You heard him!
In reply...
In reply to Brother Arkwright's
probably sincere,
but I promise you misguided remarks,
all I can say is that in disputes of
this kind sacrifices have to be made.
Answer the question!
Now, if there are no further questions,
I call upon you to vote by a show of hands
for the adoption of this resolution.
Those in favour...
- What are you doing, Eddie?
- Ah, what's the odds, put your hands up.
Come on, you haven't got
a family to support, you're laughing.
Not officially, anyway.
Well, this is an unofficial strike.
- Hundred and seven.
- That's right.
Those against...
Come on, hurry it up now.
Thirty-nine.
The voting was as follows -
those in favour, 107,
those against, 39,
majority in favour, 68.
The resolution is carried and will be
put before the management this afternoon.
I declare the meeting closed.
Good thing the wives
don't come out on strike -
you'd really feel it then.
Do you have to do what they say?
- Yeah, if they decide it, you know...
- No, you don't, not necessarily.
- Of course you do.
- Why? Don't see it.
Well, you can't run a factory on your own,
can you?
Who's talking about "on your own"?
Watch out.
Quite a few of us don't want to come out.
Yeah, all right, but I mean, you're still
bound to be in a minority, aren't you?
Still, as I say,
I couldn't care less about any of it.
All that "brother" lark -
they can stick that.
No, the best thing is not to vote either way,
let them get on with it.
I mean, they will anyway,
so what's the odds?
You coming down the pub?
No, a few of us are getting together
down at old Billy's for a bit of a chat.
All right, see you then.
- Good night, Joe.
- So long.
Ta-ta.
He's marvellous, isn't he?
Just marvellous.
As long as he gets his beer and oats,
he don't wanna know.
I don't mind you -
I don't know about both of you.
- Were you as bad as he is?
- When?
You know, before we got married.
Why do you always
have to come back to that?
- What you don't know...
- ...doesn't hurt me, I know.
- Were you?
- Oh, yeah, worse.
And I started early -
I wore a muzzle till I was 14.
- A muzzle? What's that?
- Shh... not in front of the child, please.
What do you think about it,
you layabout, eh?
- He don't care.
- How do you know it's a he?
Ah, "she", then.
It's all right for old Joe -
he can afford to lose the money.
- What are you talking about?
- This strike business.
I wouldn't mind if it was
about something serious, but...
the whole thing's a storm in a teacup.
I'm sorry, but the answer's no.
Now, that's not a final no, it's just that
he's not prepared to meet all your terms.
- Now, just before you jump right into it...
- I'm not prepared to discuss it, Mr Davis.
We've had their answer,
now they can have ours.
All right! All right, that's it!
Ah, well, the dreaded veto.
Coming?
Come on, you lot!
Come on.
Come on, boys, let's get moving.
What can I do for you, Bill?
Well, we've had a bit of a talk together,
and we've been wondering.
Supposing there are some of us
who still want to work,
how would it stand like?
Well, as far as I'm concerned,
this walkout hasn't got the union backing.
The gates'll be open for anyone
who wants to come in.
The rest is your lookout.
Where do you think you're going?
You wanna watch it,
you'll get carved up.
Get all their names!
- I'm talking to you, mate.
- I'm talking to you.
- Is this all of you, Billy?
- Yes, sir.
All right.
Well, you'd better get on
with routine maintenance.
I've managed to scrape up
a skeleton canteen staff,
so you'll get your dinners all right today.
I don't know about tomorrow though,
so you'd better bring your own
if you're going to keep this up.
Yes, well,
they were dead keen to see us.
- What's up?
- All right, Stirling Moss, that's your lot.
- Watch it, son.
- Ol' Eddie! Stirling Moss!
What's your place playing at?
I was on to them last night -
they shouldn't have sent you.
First I've heard.
What's going on then?
Labour withdrawal.
This place is black.
- Black, Charlie? They didn't tell us.
- No.
Well, pass it around when you get back.
- All right, Charlie?
- I'm easy. Get home early for once.
OK.
I know what I'd do.
Barrett! Come here!
I said, "come here".
Had the police on to me this morning.
- So?
- So, I'm warning you.
I want this strike to stay clean,
you understand?
When I need your help, I'll ask,
so just watch it.
Otherwise next time
I'll tell the coppers where to look.
Be too bad, won't it?
Who sent for the police, Billy?
Getting scared?
- What do you think then, Billy?
- I think we should turn it in.
I don't mind about myself, but my missus
is getting too old for this sort of caper.
Didn't sleep all night.
They did another couple of windows,
you know?
It's been an eye-opener to me,
I'll tell you that much.
Yeah, I agree.
Not getting anywhere, are we?
What do you think, Tom?
Well, I'm going with
whatever you lot decide.
They missed my windows cos we're on the
first floor. Bleedin' landlady got my brick.
We all agreed then?
Well, the management
didn't want to know either.
Turn it in, eh?
Best really, ain't it?
Goes hard with me,
I don't mind telling you.
I mean, I'll have a scrap in the open
with anybody,
but I've had it with this one.
Been an eye-opener to me,
a real eye-opener.
Thought you might have done
something about it - been home all day.
I never had it on.
Why don't you call the man in?
Can't afford to.
I'm out of work too now.
Mrs Curtis, you there?
- What's the old cow want?
- I'll go and see.
Mrs Curtis!
Tell her she'll have to wait for our rent
next week, that'll shut her up.
Ah, there you are.
Someone to see you.
- Who is it, Mrs Jackson?
- I don't know. Pressed the wrong bell.
- It's me, Mrs Curtis. Bert Connolly.
- Going to the door all night!
- Did you want to see Tom?
- If I might.
Please come up.
Sorry about the bell.
- Bert Connolly.
- Here?
Come in, Mr Connolly.
I'm afraid the place is a bit of a mess.
That's all right, I'm used to it.
Would you like some tea?
Oh, er... be very nice,
but only if you're making it.
Hello, Joe. Hello, Tom.
Bert.
Come to see how the rich live?
- What's the matter, the tube?
- No, the guarantee went.
Let's have a look.
I'm pretty good at fixing these things.
Ta.
Ah! Here's your trouble.
Try it now.
Enjoying the rest, Joe?
- Makes a change, don't it?
- We could do with you on the picket line.
Ah! There you are!
Yeah, still not perfect though, is it?
Thanks anyway.
- Well, now. What can I do for you?
- Well, it seems you've already done it.
Old Billy tells me you've decided
to back us all up at last.
Well, we've decided to stay away
from work, yeah. That's right.
Seems a pity you didn't do that from
the beginning, like our brother Joe here.
Yeah. Pity all round, innit?
Now, look, Tom, you know as well as I do
you got to go along with the majority.
That's the democratic way.
And personally speaking,
I was very hurt
to see you step out of line
with them others.
Still, that's all over now.
We won't bring that up again.
What we've got to do now
is to show a united front.
You made a mistake,
you've been big enough to admit it.
I mean, I'd be the last person in the world
to hold that against you.
I wouldn't come round here
and threaten you or anything like that.
No, I'm glad about that.
But I don't mind telling you,
I've had a bit of trouble with some of the
boys down there. They don't like scabbing.
Some of them were talking about
getting quite rough.
- It went a bit further than talking, didn't it?
- How do you mean?
- They set fire to any good cars lately?
- Oh, I don't know anything about that.
No, maybe not.
But I'd just like to make one point.
I got a couple of kids in there, fast asleep.
They were in there when Mother Jackson
got a brick through her window.
That wasn't meant for her,
that was meant for me!
- It could have come in there!
- I tell you, I don't know nothing about that.
No, well, I'll put it in another way, Bert.
You didn't get a brick
through your window, did you?
- What does that prove?
- I'm just telling you...
Anyone interferes with my wife and kids,
and I'll start chucking a few bricks around.
So, don't come it.
Nobody's coming it, Tom,
now, don't get excited.
I'm not getting excited.
Only, this is my home, not the factory,
so don't you nor anybody else forget it.
I joined your bloody strike, so you won,
so what else do you wanna say?
I'm not saying anything,
one way or another.
What you want to remember in future,
you or any other blackleg,
is that you won't always get off this easy.
We goy ways, mate, we got ways.
- And I don't just mean broken windows.
- You got what?
- Let's leave it at that.
- No. You got ways of what?
- I'm just telling you for your own...
- What are you telling me?
Don't give me that lip, mate, not here.
I pay the rent here.
You're very generous with your advice
these days, aren't you?
- Tom!
- Real generous!
- Tom, please!
- Keep out of it, Annie! Just keep out of it!
Come round here, laying down the law.
Well, it so happens you're not the law,
Mr God-Almighty-Connolly, mate.
And I decide whether I go back or not.
Not because you tell me,
because I decide, see?
So, you can stick your advice!
It don't mean a thing to me.
Doesn't it?
We'll see about that.
I'll have that some other time, Mrs Curtis.
Good night!
- Come in here, telling me...
- What started all this?
Nothing! Don't ask questions.
You don't understand.
I know what I've heard.
I'm not deaf.
- Joe, what do you think?
- Oh, he don't think any bloody thing!
You keep your big, idle trap shut,
don't you, Joe?
One of these days,
you're gonna sit so hard on that fence,
you're gonna split yourself
right up the middle!
I'll tell you what you gotta face up to,
all of you.
I'll tell you the facts of life.
You can't have it both ways.
- Mind if I help myself, Charlie?
- No, no, no, go on.
No good breezing up here
on your expense accounts
and then behaving like a lot of shocked
parsons at a dirty postcard convention.
You don't get offered
a government contract every day,
not on this sort of level.
It's the biggest deal
we've ever had a smell of.
And we can't even consider it
until the men are back again.
So, to get them back
you got to make concessions.
Now,
what do the concessions amount to?
Extra safety precautions,
a few new toilets,
and a face-saver
on the closed-shop angle.
That'll get the machines running again.
Once they're back and back on overtime,
you won't hear any more.
You mean, you hope
Now, listen.
I know men, believe me.
So, make up your minds.
You want that contract,
you gotta water your beer.
This is the Pakistan contract,
isn't it?
Look, Alfie, why don't you
get into your Bentley
and power-steer yourself back to London -
it's past your bedtime.
Pakistan!
We finished that job last Christmas!
Oh well, I vote we take this other thing,
whatever it is.
Who do you think you are?
He'll have to be taught a lesson.
But a mean a real lesson.
That Curtis on his own?
What's his game?
No idea!
No. Funny fellow.
My wife's never forgiven him
for marrying that Italian girl.
What's her name? Anna.
We brought her over, you know -
best girl we ever had.
No... he's a funny fellow.
I don't like lone wolves on either side.
Oh, ta.
I don't know what Curtis is out to prove,
but he could've saved himself the trouble.
- They'll all be back shortly.
- Oh?
I thought that would shake you.
- Here, I'm not alight.
- Sorry.
I've prepared a statement here
for you to give to Connolly.
You'll see what I'm getting at.
Yes, yes, changes the whole set-up.
Oh, sure, Martindale knows
which side his bread's buttered.
Exactly, ICBM, the magic letters.
How will who take it?
Oh, I can handle Connolly.
He's still fighting the general strike.
Yes, amateur night.
Well, that's it then.
I'll get them to go back, then we can
get them out again at the right moment.
You bet. Yeah.
Hello? Yes, speaking.
Oh, is that you, Phil?
I was going to get on to you.
What do you think about Martindale's
offer? He can stick that, can't he?
Accept? Yes, but...
Oh, I see.
You've been on to London, have you?
Yeah, but it's not like them
to take it all that easy, is it?
No, but, you see, London take the view
that we've done very...
well, that you've done
very nicely so far, and...
Yeah... yeah, told me to tell you.
And even though these concessions
don't amount to much,
it means that Martindale's seen the light.
That's it.
They'll have to listen to you now.
Oh, the sooner the better,
I should think.
Call a meeting for tomorrow night.
Oh, and by the way,
I've had an idea about Curtis.
- Bit naughty, wasn't it?
- What, Curtis?
- Yeah.
- Suppose so.
- Still, nothing we can do about it now.
- No.
Pint of bitter, Bertie.
- Do you mind?
- Take it easy!
- You over there!
- No!
Set the alarm for the morning.
Pint of bitter.
Yeah, we're going back.
Come on, luv!
- You're a friend of Curtis, ain't you?
- That's right.
Better give him the message.
- What message?
- Wait a minute!
Hey!
Hey, you lot!
Hey, got your boots?
- Well, she said I was the first.
- She said what?
Don't give me that!
We've all been there.
Over here!
Come on, let's have some.
- Do you hear someone speak, Gladys?
- No, never heard nothing.
Never mind the jokes.
Come on!
All right, put some down there.
Down where?
Oh, down there!
What are you playing at, Gladys?
You're a bit obstructive this morning.
Naughty girl!
Over here, Bill!
You're late!
Am I?
Now, don't tell me
I've given you too much.
You need it now you're expecting again.
Joe was telling me
everybody was glad to be back today.
Was he?
Mm-hmm.
I bet old Martindale was pleased, too.
I know I was.
I was out shopping today,
and you should have heard
what the wives were saying.
You're very quiet tonight.
Am I?
It's been a quiet day.
Come on, have another.
- No, thanks, not when you're driving.
- What are you talking about?
- Could I have a word with you, Joe?
- Yeah, have a drink.
Er... you know, a word with you.
Oh, all right.
Mind your nylons.
- 'Ere! Don't run away!
- What, in these shoes?
Well, what's up?
Well, we were talking about Tom.
- Oh, yeah?
- You know him better than anybody.
Well, you room with him, I mean, so...
Well, we were talking about
the football side of it.
Yeah, we've missed a couple of matches
already, you know, with being out and that.
Yeah, that's right. Well, the point is,
who's gonna run it now if Tom doesn't?
Well, there's no "if", is there?
I mean...
Can't ignore a bloke all day for scabbing
and kick a ball round with him after hours.
- There's no "if".
- No, that's right.
- I mean, we got to sort it out somehow.
- Look, do you mind if I butt in?
Look, Joe. Let's be honest, eh?
I mean, you're like me.
I don't care what a man does,
you know, religion and that -
I've got some very good friends,
they're Jews and that...
And politics, you know, but...
well, this is a special sort of situation.
- Yeah, and another thing...
- Look... mind if I put what I wanna say?
Look, Joe, I know Tom,
and I agree with him in some ways, but...
well, we got the team to think of,
and the season's underway, and...
well, somebody ought to talk to him.
I'm only saying this
for the good of the team, mind.
You want me to tell him, do you?
- Well, not tell him exactly...
- Yeah, tell him!
- What are you doing out of bed, boy?
- My heart's stopped.
Has it? Well, you've done verywell
to get this far then, haven't you? Hmm?
You've done the trick, anyway -
it's started again.
You must have shook it up,
like your watch.
Go on, back to bed.
Quick, quick, quick.
Sleep well.
- What is it?
- Brian having a bad dream.
Don't think it'll make
any difference to them, do you?
You don't know what kids pick up.
Seen the doctor yet, by the way?
Oh, there's plenty of time for that.
What else happened today?
That's about it.
They're just not talking to me.
Didn't Joe talk to you?
No.
You mean to say...
- Who decides these things anyway?
- What?
- Who decides...
- Well, the men decide.
- What men?
- Just the men, all of them.
You mean to tell me that
they decide to treat you like...
Doesn't anybody get up
and say how stupid this is?
I wasn't at the meeting,
so I don't know what was said.
Who thought of it?
That's what I want to know.
The committee, I suppose,
Connolly and that lot.
- You mean the union?
- No, not the union.
They're not the whole union.
I'm the union as much as they are.
- Who decides then? Somebody must...
- Look, Annie, I don't know!
I don't know who thought of it
or who decided it or anything. All I...
I'm sorry I shouted.
All I know is they're not talking to me.
Nobody's talking,
not even old Billy Arkwright.
- What are they scared of?
- I don't know. They're just scared.
Doesn't do to step out of line these days.
We're all so equal, we're nothing.
Huh!
Remember that case in the paper?
Remember? I read it out to you.
- Railwayman, wasn't it?
- Oh, yes.
I though then...
I wonder what it's like.
Well, now we know.
Do... do they do it for a time,
or what happens?
Well, I don't remember that case exactly,
but I...
I think they kept it up for quite a while.
How long? A week or two?
Uh... a bit longer, I think.
I think they kept it up for quite a bit.
Anna gone to bed?
Yeah.
I haven't done mine this week.
Fag?
Yeah, ta.
I'm sorry about all this.
What are you sorry about?
Talking about you or me?
Well, you of course!
Look, I... I know
what you must be thinking. Well...
I don't like trouble, see?
I mean, I wasn't at the meeting.
I didn't vote or anything like that.
But you know how it is -
they... they get at you.
Well, you can't go against all of them.
Yeah, I noticed that myself.
Well, there you are!
I mean, where's it all got you?
The point is,
you've got to live with them,
so what's the use sticking your neck out
all the time?
I mean, I don't wanna go into
the rights and wrongs of it all, but...
once it happens, you know,
you're better to fall in with them.
I mean,
they're all a bunch of twits anyway.
Yeah, I'm sorry, Joe,
I'm still not quite there -
best that you
should fall in with them or me?
Well... well, both.
I mean, I don't get anything out of it -
been feeling lousy ever since it happened.
Well, you can stop feeling lousy
on my account.
I'm glad you finally talked about it,
anyway.
Yeah, well, I was asked...
Oh, you were asked?
Well, not exactly, but...
well, some of the what-you-call-it, the...
the football team, they wanted to...
You see, they're a bit worried
about the fixtures and that.
In what way?
Well, apparently... I mean,
you know more about it than I do,
but a couple of the matches
had to be scrubbed, didn't they? And...
Well, the team's got a bit anxious
or something.
I see. And?
Well, the reason they picked me to tell you
is cos I live here, I suppose.
Tell me what?
They want you to take a back seat.
Joe's been telling me some news,
haven't you, Joe?
Really?
Did he make sure
all the doors were locked first?
You never know, do you, Joe -
somebody might be spying on you.
They might find out that you've
actually spoken to Tom Curtis.
All right, all right...
No, it's not all right.
It's not all right at all!
He can't have it both ways,
and if you won't tell him, I will!
He can't talk to you at work,
he can't talk to you here.
- He had something to tell me.
- Yes, like "how are you" or "goodbye".
Leave it, Annie.
This is between Joe and me.
No, it's not. This is my house, too, and
I've had all I can take from Mr Wallace.
- Look, you'll wake the kids!
- I'll wake Mr Joe bloody Wallace, too!
Look, this is a home, not a morgue.
People talk in homes.
They speak to each other.
They say "good morning"
and "good night".
They don't treat their friends like they have
some sort of a disease or something.
What was so special
he had to tell you tonight
he couldn't have told you this morning?
What was so special, huh?
Look, you'd better look at me!
You went out of this house this morning,
you couldn't even bring yourself
to say hello to me, let alone my husband.
Well, I want to tell you something.
I don't work at your rotten factory,
and I don't belong to your little committees
and your little unions.
And nobody's gonna send me
to Coventry!
I don't want you here anymore.
I don't want you near me or my children!
I don't want you here
in this house anymore!
- Now, look, Annie, shut up, will you?
- You know something?
I feel sorry for you.
You can't even think for yourself.
Look, Annie, stop it!
I'm sorry, Joe.
Yes, you're sorry. You're sorry.
You deserve your friends!
Yeah, that's all I needed today.
Well, look, maybe I'd better clear out -
be best for everybody.
Mr Curtis?
My name's Ball, I'm from the A rgus.
Oh yeah?
Sorry to spring at you so early,
but I wanted to be sure of catching you.
Er... about this business
over at the factory-
I understand you've been sent to Coventry
over some difference with
the works committee, is that correct?
Something like that, yeah.
You didn't come out on strike,
did you, Mr Curtis?
- No.
- Why was that then?
I had personal reasons.
You didn't agree with the strike,
in other words. Can I say that?
No, I didn't agree.
You thought it was all rather unnecessary,
shall we say?
That's fine.
Erm... one other thing -
how do you feel now?
- In what way?
- Well, I mean, about your workmates.
Well, it's difficult to say.
I don't understand it, really,
be different if the union had fined me.
I see. You feel that
you've been persecuted
- Well, I wouldn't say persecuted...
- Don't you think it's unfair?
Well, yes, I... I do, really.
Same thing, really, isn't it?
Right, well, thank you, Mr Curtis,
you've been very helpful.
Hope I haven't made you too late.
- Who was that?
- Some bloke from the A rgus.
- What did he want?
- Wanted to know what I felt about it.
- What did you tell him?
- Told him the truth.
"The truth according to Tom Curtis
"is that he has been... been..."
Let me see that!
- "...has been victimised..."
- Yeah, that's right.
"...by those responsible
"for an unnecessary and unreasonable
withdrawal of labour
"which did not have union backing."
- He's begging for it, isn't he?
- Yeah.
Read the rest.
Read further down, about old Martindale.
He had something to say.
Bit unfortunate?
It's a bloody sight worse than that!
They got on to me last night.
I told them it was off the record.
- Well, what do you want me to do?
- What do I want you to do?
Kill it! Get after Connolly
and get it sorted out.
If you have to, get rid of Curtis.
I don't care... but kill it!
Yeah, all right, the old man's upset.
Everybody's upset.
Well, they've got a right to be.
Let's not talk about rights, shall we?
Let's keep the conversation clean.
I just want to make sure
that this thing doesn't go any further.
Well, that's easy enough - sack Curtis!
Couldn't you just as easily
stop this Coventry business?
You've had your fun. Call it a day now,
and the papers got nothing to write about.
- What do you mean, "fun"?
- What I say.
What do you call it? Justice?
All right, justice then, I don't care.
Call it what you like, but finish it.
I can't finish it.
It's not my decision.
- I'm only a spokesman for the men.
- Don't give me that guff, Bert.
You're slipping these days, you know,
you're treating me like an equal.
You can stop it.
Well, maybe I could have
stopped it before, but not now.
The men didn't like that article.
What is it?
A few words in a local rag.
It'll end up on a nail in the toilet,
or somebody'll make a fire with it.
What are they all
getting so excited about?
They took it very personally.
Well, do me a favour, use your influence.
Tell 'em not to take it personally.
- I don't care...
- I took it personally, too!
It practically mentioned me by name.
I don't like that.
Don't tell me you're getting a lawyer.
Curtis is a blackleg,
and I don't want him here.
Well, let me tell you something.
You don't run this factory yet,
and while I'm works manager,
I decide who gets the push.
And it's gonna take more than
a few paragraphs in the A rgus
to make me give Curtis his cards.
And I'll tell you something else
you can take personally.
I don't like what you're doing.
You'd better get that lawyer -
you might need him one day!
I'll remember you said that, Davis.
"Mr Davis" while you're still talking to me!
Well, they look happy enough.
What are their names?
Brian and Cathy... Catherine.
Nice-looking kids.
Do you mind if we borrow this for a while?
We'll let you have it back safely.
Get you some copies made.
Tell me, Mrs Curtis,
you're not English, are you?
- No, Italian.
- Italian, huh?
And what's your Christian name?
I might as well have that, too.
- Anna.
- Not Gina.
It's a nice name. It suits you.
I knew a girl called Anna once.
Excuse me asking, but somebody told me
you are in fact expecting another edition.
Is that right?
- Yes.
- Well, congratulations.
- What's all this for?
- Oh, thank you.
Well, it's just that a lot of people
are interested in your story,
that's why they sent me all this way.
We like to get the woman's angle.
- You're not gonna write anything bad?
- What's that?
You're not gonna write anything bad?
What's for breakfast?
Why don't they sack him?
Why don't you sack me then?
If Mr Martindale feels so strongly about it,
why doesn't he sack me?
Don't think he hasn't thought of it!
We're not gonna sack you.
That'd really give the papers
something to write about.
All he wants you to do is apologise to
the works committee, finish it, kill it dead.
Would you apologise?
- We're not talking about me.
- No, but I'm asking you.
I don't know what I'd do.
I wouldn't have got myself where you are in
the first place. But I'll tell you this much:
I'd think of a way to finish it,
and I'd finish it soon.
Soon? What's the use of "soon"?
We've got to finish it now!
We're committed, you know that.
I've signed the contract.
But they've got a get-out clause, and
they'll use it if we have any more trouble.
They can't afford delays.
- I still think it'll blow over.
- You said that last time.
I mean, what are we gonna do?
You say you can't sack him,
he won't apologise, they won't back down,
and we're right in the bloody middle.
And I'm not going to lose business
because of one man. Life's too short!
And what's your opinion?
- What about?
- Can you stand back, please?
You're one of the men
who sent Tom Curtis to Coventry.
In a way, yeah.
Are you proud of this evidence of solidarity
among the men who work here,
or ae you ashamed of what
a lot of people regard as a cruel act?
Am I...
Look, you'd better ask somebody else.
Nothing to do with me.
You three work here, do you?
- No, we're the owners.
- Ol' Eddie!
Let me ask "old Eddie",
what do you expect to achieve
by sending this man to Coventry?
Or is there any pleasure in inflicting this
punishment on one of your work mates?
Yeah, I'll tell you what I expect to achieve.
I think he deserves it.
Do you think he deserves it?
Well, um... like he says, um...
Curtis asked for it.
As I understand it,
this was an unofficial strike,
so Curtis was quite within his rights
in refusing to come out.
No, I don't think so.
You'd make no distinction between
an official and an unofficial strike?
- No.
- You'd always come out?
- Yeah, when they tell us to.
- When who tells you to?
Er... the men and that.
What men? Would you come out
if he told you?
I never told him.
But you were at the meeting
at which it was decided
to send Tom Curtis to Coventry?
- Yeah, I was there, yeah.
- Did you vote to do that?
Yeah, I put my hand up, yeah.
Did you know what putting your hand up
would mean to Tom Curtis?
Do you always vote when you don't know
what you're voting for?
Well, if he doesn't know,
let me ask you.
What makes you decide
how you're going to vote?
Well, er... it depends, don't it,
what they're gonna give us.
'To find out what action the employer
is taking in this explosive situation,
'I've come to talk with
the managing director
'of the Martindale Engineering Company.'
- Listen to this one!
- Oh, blast!
'An ugly and frightening weapon
'has been used
in this small industrial town.
'The weapon of silence.
'Melsham today is troubled and confused,
and tempers are short.
'In the past few weeks,
it has known violence,
'and you may have felt, as I have,
'that the whole town is tense and braced
for yet another outbreak of this violence
'that nobody quite understands.
'And at the centre of it all, Tom Curtis.
'The man against whom
this weapon has been used.
'The man who's been sent to Coventry.
'There are two ways of looking at Curtis,
it seems to me.
'As an obstinate and foolish
and selfish man
'who has let down his mates and who fully
deserves the punishment that he's getting.
'Or as a brave, honest,
and thinking man,
'unjustly tormented by the men
who work alongside him,
'most of whom don't know or care
what the row is about,
'but follow like sheep
'the one or two men
who are full of malice and spite.
'But whoever's to blame,
there's something ugly in the air.
'And so, from Melsham,
a town where there is hatred in silence,
'back to the Tonight studio in London.
'Good night.'
- What were you gonna say?
- I was gonna read you this. Where is it?
Oh, yes, yes.
"A position could always be found for you
in our Brisbane works."
- Where?
- Brisbane. Australia, isn't it?
Erm... a man named Fraser -
he owns a factory out there.
"I am sure you and your family
would find a new and full life out here.
"The cause of personal liberty's one
that has always been close to my heart."
- Nice letter, isn't it?
- Yeah, if you want to live in Australia.
Well, I mean,
it was nice of him to offer.
I can't believe it,
all these people writing to us.
Some of the people
stop me in the street, too.
Oh, I mean to tell you -
you know Mr Booth at the grocer's?
He slipped in a bottle of lemon squash
for the children and didn't charge me.
Probably made a mistake.
No, he meant it,
I know he meant it.
Well, of course
they're not all on our side, so...
What am I gonna do, Annie?
What am I gonna do?
What do they want from me?
I suppose they want you to
give up and get out.
Is that what you want, too?
Tear everything up a second time
and start all over again?
No, I don't want that.
I mean, I don't know.
I only want what you want, I suppose.
Here you are, darling, catch.
- Where is Brian?
- What?
Don't say "what".
- Why isn't Brian with you?
- Don't know!
- Who's slamming about?
- Come on. Come on, quickly.
- Sorry Mrs Jackson, just the wind.
- I know who it was all right.
I told never to slam it before.
- Where's Brian?
- I told you!
Wasn't he waiting for you, Cathy?
Look at me. Wasn't Brian
waiting for you at the gate?
No.
- Well, did you wait for him?
- He didn't wait for me.
Oh, Cathy. Cathy, look at me,
I'm talking to you.
Did you ask any of the other boys
if they saw him?
No.
Well, you know you're supposed
to wait for each other.
How could I wait for him
when he wasn't waiting for me?
All right, you start your tea.
I'm going to the corner.
Now, there's one cake each,
and I shan't be long. You'll be all right.
You can have some biscuits,
but just one cake, all right?
All right?
I shan't be long.
Brian! Brian?
Brian?
How is he now?
I had to put him in our bedroom
because of Cathy.
I couldn't get it off, Tom.
I mean, I got most of it off with that
stuff we have in the kitchen, but...
- It was just like tar.
- He say who did it?
Huh? Oh, some boys, some bigger boys,
in the next class.
I carried him all the way home.
You shouldn't have done that.
- Where are you going?
- I'm going to see him.
- Oh, please don't.
- What do you mean? I gotta see him.
Brian?
He's asleep, Tom.
Let him sleep.
You asleep, boy?
It all right, boy, it's Dad.
You aren't asleep, are you?
Why won't you talk to me?
Because you're a dirty scab!
Shut up!
Shut up, will you?
You don't have to worry about
not talking to me.
I don't want you to talk to me,
do you hear?
But you stay away from my family.
Just stay away from us!
Get stuffed, short-arse!
And you lot,
you didn't ought to talk to nobody,
cos you got nothing to say!
You're nothing!
We don't need any of you!
We don't need you.
- You going to the dance on Friday night?
- No.
Mr Curtis?
Mr Curtis, you all right?
- Feeling all right?
- I'm fine.
- Thought you looked a bit...
- I'm fine, fine...
Joe?
- What's happened now?
- What about?
- What's wrong with Tom Curtis?
- Nothing that concerns you.
- Oh, yes, it does.
- Do you mind?
I'm asking you a question!
What happened?
Now, look, I'm tired of
people getting on my back.
He brought it on himself.
What do you expect me to do?
Everyone goes on like if it was my fault.
Well, I didn't start it.
I didn't have nothing to do with it.
I just mind my own business,
so why don't you do the same?
Well, you couldn't have an opinion
to save your life.
You're the big I am. I don't know
why I ever bothered about you.
You're just like the rest - gutless!
You haven't got the brains
to stick up for anything.
One man, that's all it needs.
One man!
Is it all right to talk?
Good.
First thing,
you got any instructions for me?
Right. Now, listen.
The reason I asked you to ring is,
something happened here today.
No. No, concerning Curtis. Yeah.
And it occurred to me
that if the time's ripe all round,
we've got it ready-made up here.
We use Curtis to get them out again.
That will screw up this whole contract.
Sure... about seven factories
all dependent on Martindale's.
Oh, it'll work a treat, you'll see.
Curtis really played
right into my hands today.
Connolly!
Connolly! Up here a minute!
- What's happening?
- What's happening about what?
These production returns.
No. 2 shift in 4 Bay -
they retired or something?
No, they're working to rule.
Since when?
Decision was taken
by the works committee.
We're operating a full overtime ban
until the management get rid of Curtis.
Oh, so we're back on that one again,
are we?
What are you frightened of?
You afraid Curtis might win in the end?
- No, we're not worried about that.
- Aren't you?
Well, I'll give you a little thought
to take away with you.
Once you start sacking people
because they don't agree with you,
or because you don't like the way
they part their hair,
once you establish that little precedent,
you might give other people ideas.
It might just occur to me that you're not
my cup of tea, for instance.
There's no telling where it might end.
- Quite a few people might get sacked.
- Are you threatening me?
Take it any way you like.
Now, just get out, will you?
He said there'd be
quite a few people sacked.
What's up?
- Don't know yet?
- Gonna close down.
Who says?
You heard. Davis told ol' Connolly.
It's victimisation, you know?
Yeah... what is?
They're gonna make an example.
Sack a few.
That's what I was told.
I didn't hear about that.
Sack 'em?
That's what somebody told me.
I want to speak to the Union Secretary.
Well, who is there?
Has he got any authority?
I don't want the office boy.
I told you to sort this out.
But no.
You said it would blow over.
Well, things don't blow over anymore.
Should have sacked Curtis the moment
this Coventry business started.
- Well, that's a matter of opinion, isn't it?
- What?
Hello?
Yes, yes, of course it's urgent.
It's more than urgent, I'm afraid.
They're coming out.
Yes, speaking.
Who's that? Thompson?
I'm sorry to pull you out of the meeting,
but we've got a wildcat.
I want a union representative
up here right away.
What do you think you will do then?
I don't know.
I prayed for us this evening.
I didn't go to your mother's as I said.
I... I went to mass.
I thought perhaps it might help.
You see,
I don't mind if we go away at all.
I mean, Australia, anywhere...
Somebody told me Australia's very nice.
Nice people, and it's hot.
Almost like home.
We could go home, of course.
Yeah, that's right.
- This isn't really home for you, is it?
- I didn't mean that.
No, I know.
I've really messed everything up,
haven't I?
And I don't even know why.
But I've got to decide something.
I've just got to, otherwise I'll...
I don't even know how I got into it.
You got into it because you thought
that was the right thing.
Yeah.
Well, I hope that is why, because if
it isn't, we may as well clear out.
We may as well...
I mean, if people can't be different,
if they take that away from you,
there's no point to any of it,
no point in bringing up kids or anything.
Just no point at all.
The funny thing is,
I can see both sides.
They must think they're doing right, too.
That strike you as funny?
No... not so funny.
Tom, wait!
Tom?
Don't go.
Please, God, don't go.
- Come on...
- You're gonna get it!
Get back! Come on!
Mr Curtis! Mr Curtis!
You're still not striking. Why not?
Nobody told me there was a strike.
Joe, can I talk to you for a minute?
- Yeah, pull up a chair.
- I've got to talk to you.
- All right.
- Don't mind me!
- It's Tom Curtis. He's been hurt.
- What do you mean, "hurt"?
I don't know the details.
I was working late and the police phoned.
They just said an accident,
wanted his address.
- Where is he now?
- Up at the hospital, I think.
All right, come on.
In the waiting room, over there.
Thanks.
Hello, Anna.
Hello, Joe.
I, er... I heard the news.
That girl I used to go with,
don't think you ever met her, nice girl, Pat,
she told me.
You... you all right?
Just worried about leaving the kids
with Mrs Jackson.
Oh, well, I could ask Pat to go round
and stay with them for a bit, if you like.
She's outside.
Erm... how is he?
They don't know yet, Joe.
Well, they never tell you much, do they?
I mean, even if everything's all right
they seem to like to keep it to themselves.
Expect they have to keep to the rules
or something.
You sure you're all right?
They... got any idea what happened?
He was knocked down by a car,
they think.
- They think they might have to operate.
- Oh!
Well, don't worry.
No, that's... that's a silly thing to say.
Of course you worry, but...
Well, they can do wonderful things
these days,
and you know Tom, he's pretty tough.
Well...
I'll go and tell Pat.
Then I could come back
and stay with you.
That is, if you want me to.
Thank you, Joe.
I'd like you to stay.
Excuse me.
Mrs Curtis?
Sister would like to see you.
- How is my husband?
- Oh, he came through it verywell.
Sister will tell you about it.
You, er... you all right now?
Yes, you don't have to wait
any longer, Joe.
We'll take care of her.
Oh, er... you didn't see
a patient called Curtis, did you, Doctor?
- He was in a car accident.
- I saw him when he came, yes.
Was he bad?
- You the driver?
- No, just a friend.
Well, he's not too good.
Had to lose an eye, I'm afraid.
Come on, Perce,
what about the old rosy then?
Cor, dear, what a night!
- What have you this time?
- Attempted suicide. All over the place.
They never do a good job with a gun.
Bloke here asking about his pal
in that car crash you brought in earlier.
Hit and run, the police reckon.
No witnesses either.
Never is with them bastards.
He was still conscious when we got there,
but couldn't tell the police nothing though.
All he was concerned with was Gladys.
Who's that, his wife?
- Gladys?
- Yes, kept talking about her.
No, it's not his wife.
- His wife's name is Anna.
- Oh!
Well, I never mentioned it to nobody.
Nurse?
- Is that you, Nurse?
- Yes.
It's all right, Mr Curtis.
Could you do something for me?
Don't...
Don't let my wife know.
Mustn't worry...
Not now.
Having a baby...
Brothers, please!
Brothers, please,
I call upon you to give a fair hearing
to Brother Sid Thompson, Chairman...
Brothers, please hold it in the back.
Please, please!
Chairman to the union's
negotiating committee.
Brothers!
Brothers, I have come specially here
to urge you to return to work...
...and I am confident that between us
we have found an acceptable formula.
Acceptable to who?
- Seen Eddie Barrett?
- No, not this morning.
Acceptable to who?
Go back to work!
It's in your own interests.
Hey, Gladys, come here!
I want to talk to you.
- What about?
- About Tom Curtis.
Get knotted!
Uh... wasn't me!
I didn't do nothing!
I only kept a lookout!
It was Eddie done it!
Right. Well, you stay there
if you know what's good for you.
I'm gonna make sure of you, Barrett,
before the police get you.
What police?
Who are you trying to kid?
You done Tom Curtis last night,
didn't you?
You nuts or something?
You touch me, and I'll carve you!
Is that what you used on Tom Curtis?
I know nothing about Tom Curtis.
You keep away from me!
I warned you, you keep away from me,
you mad bleeder! Ow!
Ow!
- Ow!
- Now!
What don't you know about Tom Curtis?
The only way to tackle this problem
is on an official union basis.
That's what I'm here for,
and that's what I'm prepared
to stay here for.
You are all engaged
on work of national importance.
What about the blokes
who've been sacked, eh?
You keep saying that.
Nobody has been sacked!
You can't show me a man
who's been sacked!
Who do you think you are?
The management have categorically
stated that there have been no sackings.
Go on, get him down!
There have been wrongs on both sides.
I think we'd better break this up.
Would you say there's been
outside interference in this strike?
- Yes, definitely!
- Come on now, break it up!
Mr Thompson, can I quote you?
Yes, quote me.
What do you know about it,
you ponce?
You see the sort of chap
I'm fighting for?
Brothers!
Brothers, I'm very proud...
very proud indeed...
- Dan, over here!
- ...a response to our call for unity.
Stand back, please. Excuse me.
Hello. Could I have a word with you?
What's your name?
- Joe Wallace.
- And you both work at Martindale's?
- Yeah, sort of.
- What happened to him?
He beat someone up last night.
- Who?
- Tom Curtis.
- Curtis?
- The bloke who was sent to Coventry?
- And our answer must be...
- Mind your backs, please.
...that no machinery
to deal with victimisation...
Get him off there!
Let me have that mic!
- Nobody wants to listen!
- They'd better listen, and you had too!
All right! Quiet for a moment!
Quiet! Here's someone you all know.
Will you shut up and listen!
They're not gonna listen to me.
You tell them!
You tell them what you told me!
I've got some news about Tom Curtis.
I said, I've got some news
about Tom Curtis,
and you're gonna hear it!
He had an accident last night.
At least that's what some people
would like everyone to think.
Only... only I know different.
I... I've just come from the hospital.
Well, he's lying up there now
in the hospital
where he's lost an eye.
And...
And I can tell you how he lost it.
Somebody kicked him in the face.
That's how he lost it.
So...
I don't know...
whatever we think he did to us,
I reckon he's paid for it.
And the reason he's paid for it is...
because we let it happen.
We sort of just stood by
and let it happen.
Well, I let it happen
the same as the rest of you.
All I know is...
I feel I've done something dirty.