(GAVEL BANGING)
AUCTIONEER: Yes, ladies and gentlemen,
we are in luck today here in Los Angeles.
Through the years,
the Bullwinkle Galleries...
have brought up for auction...
many collections of the personal effects
of your famous movie stars.
But today, today is indeed
a red-letter day.
The personal effects of Tony Hunter!
Lot 94.
Ladies and gentlemen,
let's start out with Lot 94.
Some of the potpourri
of Mr. Hunter's own personal costumes...
that he used in his famous
dancing-singing pictures.
Remember this?
Perhaps the most famous top hat...
and stick of our generation.
Yes, the one he used
in Swinging Down to Panama...
and all his other famous pictures.
Let's start with $5. Do I hear $5?
It's worth a lot more.
All right. Let's start with 2.
Well? Fifty cents?
Anything?
Just one more for the road.
About 20 minutes to New York.
Bottoms up.
- So you're from California?
- That's right. Sunny Cal.
- Sunny Cal?
- Yeah. Sunny Cal.
Say, you're from Sunny Cal. I bet
you know a lot of movie stars out there.
I got to confess.
I'm just like you and me.
- Only get to see them in the movies.
- Ha, ha.
But I read about them.
I know all about them.
Boy, I'd sure like to meet
that Ava Gardner.
- You're a little late. She's married.
- Yeah.
- You know this one?
- MAN 1: Who's that?
- MAN 2: Tony Hunter.
- Oh, him. The singing-dancing fella.
My wife used to go see all his pictures.
Almost broke up our home.
"Tony Hunter! Tony Hunter!"
He was good 12 or 15 years ago...
but the columnists out there
say he's through.
TONY: Through? He's washed up.
Hasn't made a picture in three years.
- Did you say something, mister?
- I said I agreed with you.
That Tony Hunter's a has-been.
- Got a match?
- Yeah.
I wouldn't go to see him
if they gave away $5 bills with the ticket.
(MAN 2 CHUCKLES)
Yeah.
We should be pulling...
The funny thing about what you're saying,
boys, is that it's absolutely true.
Here. Have an exploding cigar.
- This the last of the bags, Mr. Hunter?
- Yeah.
Say, porter, um, could you see that
they get put in a taxi...
- ...and taken up to the, uh, Plaza Hotel?
- Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
Everybody's getting off, sir.
If you don't mind,
I'll just sit for a minute or two.
You couldn't just, uh, make up my berth
for the night here, could you?
No, sir. I couldn't do that.
(HUMMING)
There's a mob of reporters
and photographers out there.
Yep. There must be some big shot aboard.
Maybe the president.
No, too many for that.
Probably a movie star.
(CHATTERING)
- TONY: Hi, fellas.
- Tony Hunter! Hello, Mr. Hunter!
Thanks for the red-carpet bit.
I didn't expect it.
- MAN 1: What brings you to New York?
- Just fooling around.
- Between pictures, Tony?
- In a manner of speaking.
Didn't I read something in Variety
about you going into a show?
Lily and Les Marton had something
planned for me. I haven't decided yet.
I haven't been on the stage in a long time.
And you get into a different medium.
- What it actually is...
- MAN 2: Here she is!
- MAN 1: Excuse me, Mr. Hunter.
- See you later.
MAN 2: Hi, Miss Gardner.
MAN 3: Miss Gardner, hold it, please?
Smile pretty. Thanks.
- MAN 2: How long you going to be in town?
- I have no definite plans.
Tony! I had no idea
you were on the train.
This is a surprise.
You going to be here long?
- Perhaps a week or two...
- Excuse me, Miss Gardner.
Could the boys get one more shot of you
coming out the door?
Honestly, isn't all this stuff
an awful bore?
- Good to see you, Tony.
- It's nice to see you.
MAN 2: By the door, please, Miss Gardner.
Once more! Here we go! Thank you.
MAN 3: Miss Gardner, my paper would like
to do a Sunday feature on you.
Those poor movie stars.
People just won't let them alone, will they?
No. I don't know how they stand it.
(SINGING) I'll go my way by myself
Like walking under the clouds
I'll go my way by myself
All alone in a crowd
I'll try to apply myself
And teach my heart how to sing
I'll go my way by myself
Like a bird on the wing
I'll face the unknown
I'll build a world of my own
No one knows better than I, myself
I'm by myself alone
(TONY HUMMING)
(MAN SHOUTING)
LESTER:
Tony Hunter! There's Tony Hunter!
(SINGING) Rah-rah, Tony, Tony Hunter
Sis-boom-bah, yay
Did you kids paint
those signs just for me?
That's cute. Piggy.
Let's get rid of this stuff.
This is the biggest surprise I've had.
- Mister, can I have your autograph?
- You certainly can, gal, come here!
That's my wife. Let go.
Don't worry.
I'll get around to you in a minute.
- Who's he?
- Never saw him before in my life.
- Hello, piggy!
- Hello, yourself, you two-headed creep!
Why didn't you say when you were coming?
We had to ask your agent.
- Why didn't you send us a wire?
- I wanted to sneak in quietly.
Believe me, I didn't have any trouble.
I want to see if you've changed in a year.
No, Les, you haven't changed a bit.
You look desperately ill, as usual.
- What'd you have to say that for?
- Just kidding.
I've been feeling terrible all day.
Kind of faint, lightheaded,
a lot of pressure here, queasy inside...
- ...my pulse...
- You look great.
As for you, that New York pallor
is like a breath of fresh air.
You're too pretty to be a successful writer
and much too pretty to be married to that.
That's the prettiest compliment
I've had all day!
Come on, you two-headed lovebirds,
there's work to be done!
- Now I have here a script of a show!
- Les, you didn't bring it.
It's great. It's the best thing
we've ever written.
Take it, boy. Smell it!
You can tell it's good.
There's a great part in it for you,
nice little parts for us.
Wait. This boy must be starving.
Let's take him to Sardi's.
(HORN HONKING)
Only two blocks more, then Sardi's.
- Shall we tell him, Lil, the big surprise?
- You tell him, Les.
Who do you think
is going to do the show?
Only the greatest director-producer
in town, Jeffrey Cordova.
- Who?
- Jeff Cordova.
We're meeting him tonight, backstage,
right after the show.
- What did you say his name was?
- Jeffrey Cordova!
You're not serious.
I don't think he ever heard
of this fella.
What's the matter? Don't you
get newspapers back in California?
This genius directed Man
in a Mousetrap...
The Lost Nymph, and did them both
while starring in Oedipus Rex.
He's got three hits running,
and he's starring in one of them.
Only one?
This fella's fabulous, phenomenal,
fantastic! He can do anything.
- Has he ever directed a musical?
- Oh...
What's the difference?
He can do anything.
He's theater.
He's a new kind of theater man, Tony.
The theater's changed.
Lots of things have changed.
They certainly have.
What's happened to 42nd Street?
I just can't get over it.
I just can't understand it.
This used to be the great theater street
of the town. The New Amsterdam.
I had one of my biggest successes there.
Ran a year and a half.
Noel Coward and Gertie were here in
Private Lives in the Selwyn.
Strictly carriage trade,
nothing but the finest.
First show I ever did was at the Eltinge,
and I don't believe that's here anymore.
- Oh! Oh! Oh!
- What's the matter?
- LESTER: I think he broke my leg.
- Can you put your weight on it?
- LESTER: I'll try.
- I'm sorry! I didn't mean it.
- Okay, forget it.
- Let's get him a cab.
Taxi!
(WHISTLES)
Here, let me carry you.
My dear man, it's entirely my fault
and I apologize.
Here's for your trouble.
- Ow! Ow! Ow!
- Lean on me.
- I can stand anything but pain.
- You'll be all right.
It's swelling. I'm getting a hematoma.
The blood is spurting out.
I want some cold compresses!
Not hot, but cold.
Listen, you go over to Sardi's.
I'll see you later.
Driver, take them on over.
Order me a steak.
I'll see you in a few minutes.
Excuse me.
I'm just a little bit fuzzy.
Wasn't this formerly the Eltinge theater?
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
What are you doing in there?
(BELLS DINGING)
(SINGING) When you feel as low
As the bottom of a well
And can't get out of the mood
Do something to perk yourself up
And change your attitude
Give a tug to your tie
Put a crease in your pants
But if you really want to feel fine
Give your shoes a shine
When there's a shine on your shoes
There's a melody in your heart
With a singable happy feeling
A wonderful way to start
To face the world every day
With the deedle-dum-dee-dah-dah
A little melody that is making
The worrying world go by
When you walk down the street
With the happy-go-lucky beat
You'll find a lot in what I'm repeating
When there's a shine on your shoes
There's a melody in your heart
What a wonderful way to start the day
Now there's a shine that you get
In the barbershop
There's a shine that you get
In the Pullman car
In the pool room
There's a shine that you get
In the school room
(TAP DANCING)
But it doesn't matter where you get it
It'll do a lot of good if you let it
A little bit of polish will abolish
What's bothering you
When there's a shine on your shoes
Melody in your heart
Singable happy feeling
Wonderful!
Got a shine on my shoes
Shiny shoes! Shiny shoes!
I got a shine shoes
Shiny shoes! Shiny shoes! Shiny shoes!
Shine, shine, shine, shine on my shoes
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
I got a shine on my shoes
Got a shoeshine
(BELL DINGS)
(CARNIVAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(IN NORMAL VOICE) Yeah! Hooray!
ENSEMBLE (SINGING): In such a time, indeed
You must reap doubly
With a twofold pain
JEFF (AS OEDIPUS): Kind friend,
you alone are faithful to me.
Blind though I am...
I know that you are here,
and your voice is known to me.
(DRUM BEATING)
ENSEMBLE (SINGING): Oh, man of dark deed
How did you find the heart to blind yourself
But deliver to all?
Apollo, friends! Apollo!
Come near me.
Lay your hand upon a wretched man.
Do not fear.
My plague can touch no one but me.
Seize me and drive me out!
Send me, for God's sake,
to some distant spot!
Conceal me! Kill me!
This guy is going to direct a musical?
This guy can do anything.
ENSEMBLE (SINGING): Therefore plan
For to death shall watch life's hand
And can't all happy till thee pass
The earth away
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
Sweetie, we start on the left foot!
Always the left!
The whole exit depends upon...
Lily, darling! How are you?
Lester, how am I doing?
- Jeff, this is Tony...
- Excuse me.
Underneath it all, very simple.
Isn't he wonderful?
Listen. Order me
a corned-beef sandwich, will you?
Lean, now, no fat, no gristle.
And a cream soda and a pickle.
- Mr. Cordova wants a...
- Stay right here. It's all right.
That maniac. Honestly! Say, Hal?
- Yes, Miss Marton.
- The maestro wants his, uh...
I know. The corned beef.
It's in his dressing room already.
Hal, this is Mr. Hunter.
- This is Hal Benton, Jeff's manager.
- Nice to meet you.
- I'm a great admirer of yours.
- Thank you.
- When did you get in town?
- I got off the train a couple of hours ago.
- Wasn't that curtain slower tonight?
- It was my fault. I'm sorry.
No, don't change it. Keep it that way.
It's wonderful. Doubles the applause.
- This is Tony Hunter.
- JEFF: How do you do?
Sorry, kids. Be with you soon as
I get out of this sackcloth and ashes...
Max, what happened to that amber spot?
It was way off.
Must have more light on me there.
Don't let us keep it a secret
I'm in the show.
- Excuse me.
- Hello, sweetheart.
- You look wonderful.
- Thank you.
Hal, call a full dialogue rehearsal, will you?
Friday, for the full company.
Sloppy diction. The original was in Greek,
but this is in English.
Don't let us keep it a secret it's in English.
I want to catch the matinee tomorrow...
- ...of Man in a Mousetrap.
- Can't do. We got a drama lecture...
Never mind. We'll work it out somehow.
Jeff, this is Tony Hunter.
Yeah, I know. We just met.
Mr. Hunter.
- I beg your pardon.
- I'm glad to know you.
So happy to meet you.
You have no idea
how delighted I am to see you.
- Delighted and thrilled.
- Thank you.
We need our theater greats right here.
So when Lily and Lester said they were
doing a show with Tony Hunter...
that's all I had to know.
I'm dropping every other project,
and there are plenty, believe me.
That's wonderful, Mr. Cordova,
but all this... The classics...
- Do you really want to do a musical?
- Musical, musical!
I'm sick of these artificial barriers
between the musical and the drama.
In my mind, there is no difference
between the magic rhythms...
of Bill Shakespeare's immortal verse
and the magic rhythms...
of Bill Robinson's immortal feet.
Hal, write that down.
I'll use it at Princeton.
It's already down.
You used it last week.
I tell you, if it moves you,
if it stimulates you...
if it entertains you, it's theater.
When the right combination gets together
and it spells theater...
I got to be right in there
up to my armpits.
That's higher than usual.
Now, that's what I wanted
Tony to hear you say.
I tried to tell him how you feel, but I knew
that you could say it so beautifully.
Lily, you splendid animal.
Take your hands off my wife
and let's get down to business.
Now I have here a script.
It's great. It's ready to roll.
Jeff, I want you to take this home.
I want you to read it tonight...
But before I do,
give me a rough idea of the plot.
- LESTER: Now?
- Throw it at me for a quick impression.
- TONY: I'm dying to hear it.
- LILY: You tell it.
- You do it so much better.
- Lester, honestly.
- Please, Lily, tell them.
With Tony in mind, we naturally
visualize a light and intimate show.
We want to give him a chance to play
a charming guy, with just enough plot...
to make him do lots
of gay and varied numbers.
He's a writer and illustrator
of children's books...
but to get in the real dough...
on the side,
he writes lurid murder mysteries...
full of violence and buckets of blood.
The success of these
makes him feel he's sort of...
sold his soul to the devil,
but he keeps on doing it.
There's lots of comedy implications
with his friends, played by us.
- With his girl.
- I love this. Terrific possibilities.
And some of the best numbers
we've ever written!
Children's playground, a reform school,
12 showgirls playing softball!
- And a number about a murder mystery!
- You two are the end.
- Tony, I'm so glad!
- Some of the best lines we've written.
What do you think, Jeff?
Kids, you're geniuses.
The whole thing
is a brilliantly imaginative idea.
Why, Jeff!
You've hit on something
that's not only great as a musical...
but valid in terms of today,
of modern life.
Jeff, I'm so glad!
Of course, these modern thrillers,
he's got to keep turning them out.
They make him fame, money. He's caught.
It's a funny situation.
Of course! It's brilliant,
contemporary, perceptive.
This story's a modern version of Faust.
- Faust?
- You're kidding, Jeff.
I guess I didn't tell it right.
I didn't bring out the point.
But you did bring out the point admirably.
You used the phrase:
"He sells his soul to the devil."
Now, that's the line you have to follow
straight through.
Just like Faust,
this man is tempted by the devil...
and his compromise, his sellout,
must end in eternal damnation.
That'll leave them laughing.
Kids, you've got a choice here
between a nice little musical comedy...
and a modern musical morality play...
with meaning and stature!
- But we don't want to write Faust.
- You're taking me too literally.
I want to do your story. I love it!
But I want to angle it
to bring out the analogy...
between the Faust legend
and this man's story.
Won't this make it heavy?
Is this a box-office idea?
Is Faust box-office?
Listen, Faust by Christopher Marlowe,
Faust by Goethe, Faust by Gounod...
Faust by Hector Berlioz.
I tell you, anyone who's touched this
legend has turned it into a gold mine.
It's got to be a smash.
It could still have all the fun in it,
couldn't it?
- Yeah, and some stature thrown in.
- Now, kids, I'm happy about this.
- Really happy.
- So are we, Jeff.
This publisher you mentioned...
obviously, he could be
the counterpart of the devil.
Evil personified!
Leading all mankind
into the paths of temptation!
- LILY: But nobody could play it like you.
- Nobody's going to.
LESTER:
You mean you're going to play it?
The part of the girl... Somebody fresh.
Somebody with fire, charm, grace, beauty.
Gabrielle Gerard.
- Gerard? She's a ballet dancer.
- She doesn't want to do a show.
- She turns them all down.
- Nobody ever turns me down.
Do you really think you could get her?
What a cast!
Tony Hunter, Jeff Cordova,
Gabrielle Gerard! Tony! Isn't this exciting?
Yeah.
Now, look, this is going to be
a sort of modern Faust story.
I play the Faust character. You play
the Devil. It'll have stature, importance.
- I have to dance with this ballet dancer?
- She's wonderful.
It'll be great.
It'll be great for somebody.
I'll pick up my marbles and go home.
Fellas, bless you and good luck,
but this just ain't for me.
I know what I can do,
and I'm sticking to it.
That's the trouble. You've stuck to it,
and you're stuck with it.
- What?
- JEFF: Nobody admires you more than I.
I've seen every show
and every movie you've ever done...
but let's face some brutal facts.
Times have changed, Tony.
You haven't changed with them.
- You've gone stale.
- Then you certainly don't need me.
Yes, we do!
Because you can be greater
than you ever were!
We are going to make you explode
on the theater scene like a skyrocket!
Not just the old trademark,
with the top hat, tie, and tails...
but a great artist
at the peak of his powers.
The new Tony Hunter. Tony Hunter, 1953!
- But can I do it?
- It's a challenge to all of us...
but that's what the theater's about:
a challenge.
Whatever I am,
whether it's a new me or an old me...
remember, I'm still just an entertainer.
What do you think I am?
What do you think they are?
What do you think the theater is?
It's all entertainment!
Believe me, there is no difference
between the magic rhythms...
- ...of Bill Robinson's immortal feet...
- You said that before.
All right, what did Bill Robinson do?
He danced on the stairs, didn't he?
Now I happen to play Oedipus the king
on the same stairs.
What's the difference?
We're all theater.
Show me the greatest tragic actor...
or the lowest red-nosed comic
in burlesque...
and I'll show you an entertainer.
We're all...
(SCREAMS)
LILY: Jeff, are you all right?
(SINGING)
Everything that happens in life
Can happen in a show
You can make 'em laugh
You can make 'em cry
Anything, anything can go
The clown with his pants falling down
Or the dance that's a dream of romance
Or the scene where the villain is mean
That's entertainment
(SINGING)
The lights on the lady in tights
Or the bride with the guy on the side
Or the ball where she gives him her all
(IN UNISON) That's entertainment!
The plot can be hot
Simply teeming with sex
A gay divorcée who is after her ex
(SINGING) It could be Oedipus Rex
Where a chap kills his father
And causes a lot of bother
The clerk who is thrown out of work
By the boss who was thrown for a loss
By the skirt who is doing him dirt
(IN UNISON) The world is a stage
The stage is a world of entertainment
That's entertainment!
LILY (IN NORMAL VOICE): All right!
SINGING (IN UNISON):
That's entertainment!
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH IN SQUEAKY VOICE)
LESTER (IN NORMAL VOICE):
Look what I can do.
It's still me!
SINGING (IN UNISON):
The doubt while the jury is out
Or the thrill when
they're reading the will
Or the chase for the man with the face
That's entertainment!
The dame who is known as the flame
Of the king of an underworld ring
He's an ape who won't let her escape
That's entertainment!
It might be a fight
Like you see on the screen
A swain getting slain
For the love of a queen
Some great Shakespearean scene
Where a ghost and a prince meet
And everyone ends in mincemeat
The gag may be waving that flag
That began with a Mr. Cohan
Hip hooray, the American way
The world is a stage
The stage is a world of entertainment
- You gone yet, Hal?
- HAL: I'm in here, Jeff, on the phone.
Drama desk? Hello, Mike. It's Hal.
You know that item Mr. Cordova sent you
about signing Gabrielle Gerard...
for the Marton show?
There's been a mistake.
I wonder if there's still time to kill it.
- Yeah. I'd appreciate it. Thanks, kid.
- Why did you do that?
To save you from making an idiot
of yourself in print.
- You know you can't get Gerard.
- Why?
Because Paul Byrd won't let her
do a show. He's a tough customer.
He's not only her choreographer,
he's also her boyfriend.
She doesn't make a move without him.
(DOORBELL BUZZES)
That will be Paul Byrd now.
- It's 3 in the morning.
- Let him in, Hal, will you?
- HAL: Hello, Paul.
- Where are they?
He's in there.
JEFF: Hello, Paul.
- Where is he?
- Who?
- Oscar Hammerstein.
- Home in bed, I hope, at this hour.
- Who is it? Dick Rodgers?
- What are you talking about?
Didn't you say the greatest producer
of musicals today...
was here and wanted to see me?
- That's me. I'm doing a musical.
- Did you get me out of bed...
I see what this is all about.
You needn't go any further because
the answer is no on Gabrielle Gerard.
Gabrielle... Paul, I don't follow you.
Gabrielle is not going to do a show.
She's too important to ballet.
This has nothing to do with Gabrielle.
Paul, I want you to do the choreography
for the greatest musical in years.
Oh. Oh.
- I'm sorry...
- That's why I wakened you, Paul.
I'm so keyed up I just can't sleep.
You know how brilliant the Martons are.
This time, they've excelled themselves.
This show is a choreographer's dream,
and only you can do it.
- I wouldn't say that.
- No time for false modesty.
You're the greatest, and we know it.
This is just your meat.
A great classic theme.
The story of Faust in a modern setting.
Say, that sounds interesting.
I've never been so excited
about a project in my life.
Now, there's Tony Hunter, myself,
a great score by the Martons.
Wonderful. My brain's beginning
to churn already.
Good. Now we must comb the country
for a wonderful singer for the girl.
Singer? Jeff, don't you think we ought
to stress the dancing in that role?
No, Paul.
This girl has to be a virtuoso performer,
with fire, charm, beauty...
a great lady with a gamine quality.
You know no dancer can give you that.
Wait. Of course I wouldn't let her do it,
but Gabrielle has all that and more.
Gabrielle? Paul,
I feel a little embarrassed.
I think she's charming,
within her limitations. Charming.
She's a great artist, and you know it.
- Sorry. I know how fond of her you are.
- That has nothing to do with it!
She can be one of the greatest
stars in the theater.
Everybody's been trying to get her.
For the right vehicle,
something light and fluffy.
Light and fluffy? Now, see here, Jeff.
I'm not gonna do this show
unless Gabrielle Gerard plays that part!
Now, Paul, this throws a little
monkey wrench into things, doesn't it?
Never mind.
You and I will work together sometime...
Wait. At least do this. You come
and see her in the ballet tomorrow.
- Bring Hunter, bring the Martons.
- No. Impossible.
I have a performance.
But I'll gladly send the Martons.
We can get together afterwards and talk.
Mind you, I'm promising nothing.
Good night, sweetie.
(HUMMING)
HAL: Drama desk?
Mike. Hal again.
Better print that item after all.
And, Mike, after this, if Mr. Cordova tells
you he's casting Tallulah...
for Little Eva, believe him.
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING CLASSICAL MUSIC)
Well?
She's fabulous, sensational,
loveliest thing I've ever seen.
A little tall, isn't she?
Stage illusion.
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
So you didn't care for it much?
The girl's fantastic, beautiful...
but I can't dance with her.
Stop worrying!
It isn't that I don't appreciate
what she does.
I tell you, I know she's magnificent.
That's what scares me.
But I haven't done ballet
since I was a kid. I'd look silly.
Hello, Lil. You look wonderful.
Put your things over there.
Hello, Mr. Hunter. How are you?
- Hello, Les. Glad to see you.
- How are you?
What is this?
The annual fur trappers' convention?
- The boss is inside with big money.
- His backers?
- They're raising money for the show.
- What show, ours?
- Sure.
- He hasn't read the script yet.
- I better go back...
- Sorry, Mr. Marton.
You disturb the water, you scare the fish.
They're biting tonight.
- What's he telling them?
- Whatever it is, it's going over big.
- Come on, Lil.
- Please don't go in yet.
Wait here.
He's saving you for the finale.
(DOORBELL BUZZES)
Excuse me.
- Lester, isn't this wonderful?
- Yeah.
- This is going to be great, Tony.
- Why?
Cordova. The dough for the show.
No problems.
How many times did we have to audition
the last time?
- Fifty.
- A hundred, maybe more.
Jeff might raise the backing tonight.
We'll be ready to rehearse in three weeks.
- Hello, Hal.
- Hello, Paul. How are you?
How nice to see you. Come right in.
Hal, this is Miss Gerard. Mr. Benton.
How do you do?
Jeff's inside with the backers.
Why don't you wait in the library?
- Excuse me.
- Thanks.
Paul.
Let's wait in here a minute, huh?
Now, wait a second. I'm not ready yet.
There's a lot to be cleared up first.
This girl Gerard,
it's not just her dancing.
On top of everything, she's too tall for me.
This girl is a giantess.
She's not too tall for you.
I know this girl.
She comes up to here,
maybe 2 inches shorter.
You know I'm the perfect height for you.
Now look...
turn around. Measure. Look.
You see? Isn't that fine?
Listen. Gabrielle Gerard in her
stocking feet is at the most 3-feet tall.
Now relax. I'm going to find you a drink,
and you can stop worrying about her.
Jeff only wants her in the show
because she's the best.
We all gotta go along
with him too, Tony.
In the show, one guy's got to be
at the helm...
and in Jeff, we got someone
we can trust to...
it is the Devil, come to claim the soul
of the modern Faust man.
With flapping wings
and grinning evil eyes...
he points the way
to the yawning pits of Hades.
Hallelujah.
- I'm embarrassed.
- Don't be childish.
I'm sure Tony Hunter doesn't want me
in this show.
- What makes you say that?
- Did he come backstage to see me...
after the performance?
He knew he was going to meet you here.
- I'm just a ballet dancer...
- You're a famous leading ballerina.
What does he want with me?
He's a famous movie and stage actor.
He's practically a historical character
by now.
Dancing with him is like dancing
with a statue of General Grant.
Now look, Gaby.
You know, this is a Cordova show.
It's an important step for you.
I'm going to do the choreography,
so there's nothing for you to worry about.
But I still think he doesn't want me
in the show.
Your nose is shiny.
- Where's the, uh?
- Maybe this is it.
He passes by all the writhing souls
in torment paying for their deadly sins.
Gluttony, avarice...
It must be upstairs.
Lester, what have we got ourselves into?
The story he's telling them has nothing
to do with the story we wrote.
This will mean months of rewriting.
He expects us to go into rehearsal
in three weeks?
Brimstone and flames. Save me.
(JEFF SCREAMING)
Corrupter of children.
Purveyor of evil. Dungeon...
bubbling cauldrons.
Fiery furnaces of doom.
(SCREAMING)
- You're...
- And you're... How do you do?
How do you do? It's certainly a...
- We've been waiting for you in there.
- We just got here.
We just got here ourselves,
about five minutes ago.
A little early, I guess.
Mr. Cordova's busy.
Yes, I know,
and I rushed so to get here.
- I'm a mess.
- No. You look wonderful.
- Will you have a cigarette?
- No, thanks. I don't smoke.
- Never?
- I don't think a dancer should smoke.
I see.
- Is anything wrong?
- No.
- Pretty shoes.
- Thank you.
You always wear high heels?
No. Not always. Sometimes toe shoes.
Toe shoes.
I'm afraid I've been awfully rude.
I haven't told you how wonderful
you were tonight.
Thank you.
I'm a great admirer of yours too.
- I didn't think you'd ever even heard of me.
- Heard of you?
I used to see all your pictures
when I was a little girl.
I'm still a fan. I recently went to see
a revival of them at the museum.
Museum?
"Step right this way,
ladies and gentlemen.
"Egyptian mummies, extinct reptiles...
and Tony Hunter,
the grand old man of the dance."
I didn't mean...
I want you to know that I can still
thread a needle without my eyeglasses...
and still occasionally do
a soft-shoe shuffle.
Nothing balletic, of course.
You're not a ballet devotee, are you?
Yes. I was going to the ballet
before you were born.
I saw Pavlova, Karsavina,
all the real ballet greats.
You don't see dancing
like that nowadays. I'm sorry.
That's okay. I don't expect you
to class me with Pavlova.
In fact, if she were around...
I doubt if she'd be good enough
to dance with you.
You'd probably insist
on an audition first.
I sure would.
I'd audition my own grandmother.
Then why don't you audition mine?
She'd be just about right for you.
- I'm terribly sorry.
- No, you're not.
- No, I'm not.
- Neither am I.
Good.
- Paul, I'm leaving.
- What's the matter, darling?
I can't work with that man.
He's impossible.
We just got here. It'll look funny...
The whole thing is off.
This girl is a monster.
I have definitely had it.
(ALL SHOUTING)
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
the brains, the talent, the artists.
Wonderful. Aren't they wonderful?
(ALL CHATTERING)
You have no idea
how well things are going.
It's really wonderful.
Ladies and gentlemen.
I want you all to meet
the happy little group...
that's responsible for the show...
that everyone will be clamoring
to get seats for next season.
The celebrated choreographer Paul Byrd.
The authors you know:
Lily and Lester Marton.
Take a bow, Lily.
And, ladies and gentlemen...
my star, Tony Hunter.
A name, a talent.
Mr. Show Business himself.
And, ladies and gentlemen,
his new leading lady.
That glamorous, delightful dancer
from the magical world of ballet.
Mr. Hunter's own personal choice,
Gabrielle Gerard.
I think, gentlemen, you will agree
your investment is safe, yes?
Now let's relax
and have a drink, shall we?
My dear, how do you authors
ever think of these brilliant ideas?
That damnation scene.
Did you ever in your life hear...
My boy. I had the pleasure
of backing your last show too.
Jeffrey. How about?
There it is, folks. The work light.
Only an electric bulb, perhaps,
but for the next four weeks...
that will be our sun,
our moon, our stars.
These four walls will be our universe,
our private world.
We enter with nothing but a dream,
but when we leave...
we'll have a show.
In between, there will be enthusiasms,
frustrations, hot tempers...
ha, ha, cold coffee.
Some of us will fight,
some fall in love...
but all of us will work and adore it...
because all of us are inspired
by the same thing.
The night that curtain goes up,
it will go up on a smash hit.
And believe me, kids...
there's nothing in the world
as soothing...
as a smash hit.
(INAUDIBLE)
What do you think this is,
summer stock or something?
(INAUDIBLE)
Go!
That's it. That's wonderful.
Why didn't you do it before?
Good, men.
Honey, would you try
that cross, please, again for me?
"The same kind of opportunistic snake
that he is."
"You got me wrong.
I'm a self-made snake.
"Listen, baby, we all live by the jungle:
Eat or be eaten.
"I just realized that I like to eat,
and to eat caviar whenever possible.
"Anything wrong with that?"
"Anything wrong with that?" A bad line.
What we need is some quick image,
like "spreading ideals on a cracker."
You all like that? "Ever try
spreading ideals on a cracker?"
Let me hear it, Tony.
Did you ever try spreading ideals
on a cracker?
- Jeff. I don't...
- Honey, just try that cross again for me.
"The same kind of opportunistic snake
that he is."
"You got me wrong.
I'm a self-made snake.
"Listen, baby. We all live
by the law of the jungle..."
- Excuse me, Tony.
- "...eat or be eaten."
Pardon me, folks.
You know about icebergs, don't you?
One-eighth above the surface,
seven-eighths below. That's you.
You're giving me only that one-eighth.
I'm greedy. I want more.
All eight-eighths. Now let it rip, Tony.
Give it too much. Go way over.
Come along. The whole eight-eighths!
Okay, Gaby. Same place.
"The same kind of opportunistic snake
that he is."
You got me wrong. I'm a self-made snake!
Listen, baby. We all live by
the law of the jungle: Eat or be eaten!
And I realized that I like to eat,
and eat caviar whenever possible.
Did you ever try spreading ideals
on a cracker?
Good boy, Tony.
That's it. Eight-eighths.
- Sorry. Butterfingers.
- No. It's not your fault, Tony.
It's an awkward pattern.
I have a better idea.
You hold your position right here,
and Jimmy...
suppose you pick up Gaby like that,
and put her down...
right here next to Tony?
Now you see, Tony...
I'd like to practice it with her
two or three times.
I think I could handle it.
Do you mind if he tries it with Barbara?
These are new toe shoes.
They're killing me.
Sure. You go ahead and rest.
Barbara, come here. Try it.
I think this is what's throwing you off.
If you hold your balance so, like this,
then grab her here by the...
Paul, I think we're making
a mistake here.
I think we're wasting Tony
in this scene.
He's got the first-act finale right
after this. The damnation scene.
I don't want to dissipate
his impact in that.
Now, why not let him exit into the house
and watch it from his balcony?
- How'd that be?
- Wonderful idea.
See what that would do?
Save your sock for the finale.
Much better that way.
PAUL: Let's go back
to the beginning positions. Gaby.
Boys, get around up here,
and the girls, yes.
You were down here in the line
like that. Not too close.
This group's down here, you're up there.
- Let's try it this way.
- No!
Let's not try it this way
or any other way.
I have had enough. I've had
three weeks of these lovely rehearsals...
three weeks of Chinese torture.
I don't know what you're trying to do...
except make me look like
a complete fool. A clumsy idiot.
I've tried. For three weeks, I've tried.
I've taken everything.
I've watched my part being changed,
my numbers being cut out day after day...
and I haven't said a word.
Got to be cooperative,
think of the good of the show.
Let's get this straight:
I am not Nijinsky.
I am not Marlon Brando.
I am Mrs. Hunter's little boy, Tony,
song-and-dance man.
I'm supposed to have entertained
millions of people in my time.
And I am not entertained by
this little ballerina's snide insinuations...
that I am a no-talent hoofer.
I am sick of her superior smirk.
I'm sick of her.
I'm sick of Faust. I am sick of this show.
Never mind saying it!
Tony Hunter, 1953.
I hereby declare my independence.
Tony Hunter, 1776.
Bless you.
(CHATTERING)
- Lester, where are you going?
- I don't know. I was...
What's happening to us? Let's try
to keep our heads. It's only a show.
I know. I'm sorry, baby.
So am I. Let's try
to be sensible about it.
- Do you think we should try to find Tony?
- I don't know. What do you think?
- Maybe we should.
- But Jeff said not to.
And, of course,
you mustn't disobey teacher.
Right or wrong,
someone has got to be at the helm.
But to you, he's 100 percent right
every time.
If you say one more word to me
about Jeff's hypnotic influence on me...
- ...I'll scream.
- He's got you so bulldozed...
(SCREAMS)
Someone's liable
to think we're quarreling.
We're not quarreling.
We're in complete agreement.
- We hate each other.
- Unh!
Joe, tell Mrs.
Marton I've gone to Tahiti...
to paint.
(DOORBELL BUZZES)
- Hello, Mr. Hunter.
- You must have the wrong apartment.
No. I came to see you.
May I come in a minute?
Please.
I, uh, was just about to slip
into my bed of nails.
Oh.
I'm terribly sorry.
That's all right. You couldn't have done it
if I hadn't softened it up for you.
- What?
- Nothing.
- Cigarette?
- No, thanks.
That's right. Dancers shouldn't smoke.
- You mind if I do?
- Yes. I mean, it's all right.
Thanks.
How lovely.
I've never seen such wonderful prints
in a hotel.
They don't belong to the hotel yet.
They're mine, and they're originals.
Oh.
Don't let that throw you.
I don't know any more about art than I do
about dancing. I'm just a Hollywood actor.
I call my agent and say,
"I've got a wall to cover.
"Send me over 20 feet's worth
of paintings in assorted colors."
That's a very early Degas, isn't it?
"1877."
Yeah. I swiped it from his desk
in school. Was he sore.
What can I do for you?
I know. You demand an apology.
Okay, let's cut it short. I apologize.
No, don't do that.
I'm supposed to apologize to you.
- Oh...
- I mean...
I see, the fellows got together,
stuck a gun in your back...
No, it was all my idea.
I just wanted to tell you that...
All right. It was Paul's idea.
Why do I let him push me around?
What do I want to apologize
to you for anyway?
You've been mean to me.
You didn't want me in the show
in the first place.
What?
And you think
I'm a dime-a-dozen ballet dancer.
No.
And this whole thing's making me
a nervous wreck and no show is worth it.
I wouldn't apologize to you
in a million years.
Now, don't do that. Please, just
calm down. Now take it easy. Look.
I thought I was the only nervous wreck
around here...
and all this time
you've been behaving...
I've behaved horribly to you,
and I know it.
I'm not used to behaving horribly.
It's a big strain.
You just misunderstood me, that's all.
I think you're terrific.
I think everything in the show
is probably terrific, except me.
I've been scared to death of you...
and scared to death
of every last kid in the chorus.
Don't be nice to me.
It just makes me seem twice as ugly.
I'd say you were more plain than ugly...
- ...but at least you've got talent.
- Thanks.
Now look, Gaby. It's just plain silly...
that we have never sat down
and talked this out.
We are the only animals given
the greatest means of communication...
human speech.
- And all we do is snarl at each other.
- I know.
We're from two different worlds,
two eras...
but yet we're supposed
to dance together, work together.
No one consulted us...
but we're the only things that matter
in this whole thing.
Not those geniuses out there,
telling us what to do.
You're right.
We have to do the performing.
We're the ones
that have to get up on that stage...
- ...and make idiots out of ourselves.
- Tony, is that what's going to happen?
No. Of course not.
Things are going to be fine.
I have a feeling that everything
is going to be much better from now on.
Yes, I know, but...
Can you and I really dance together?
I don't know.
Let's find out.
- Taxi, sir?
- Yes, please.
- El Morocco, please.
- No.
Stork? Waldorf?
No. I'm not dressed.
I just came from rehearsal.
- I can't go to any of those places.
- You look fine to me.
- Never mind. Thanks.
- Thank you.
- Where to, sir?
- Leave it to the horse.
(LAUGHING)
Look, trees.
Yes, I remember now, dimly. Trees.
And isn't that called grass?
And, look, there's the sky.
This has all been here...
the whole time we have been shut up
in our little sweatbox of the arts.
Really? Amazing.
Do you know what those are
on those benches? People.
Happy people.
Would you believe it?
They don't even care...
whether we have a damnation scene
in our show or not.
Neither do I.
(BAND PLAYING SLOW JAZZ MUSIC)
You can't get it into the elevators.
And you take this one here,
and it won't fit the finale.
- How are we doing?
- It's a disaster.
We're in terrible trouble.
We just can't open in three days.
I told you from the beginning,
you are overloading the show.
You can't get all this scenery
in the theater.
- Why isn't this hung?
- We've been hanging all night.
You've got more scenery in this show...
than there is in
Yellowstone National Park.
Never mind. Get your blueprints.
We'll go have a conference.
Everything will work out all right.
Hold it. I scored for brass,
and all I hear is flute.
I don't want so many long bows.
Lester, I gotta cut 16 bars
out of that dance.
Sixteen bars! Hey, Lil.
All right, I'll make the cut.
Page to page.
Would you ask Lily
if she approves the cut?
- Lil, how about this cut?
- It's fine.
Okay, Lester. Let's give it to her.
This'll sound like hash. I better
put some chords in for transition.
Wait, just a minute.
Sublime, time, dime, slime...
You can't hear Tony
in Lovelier Than You.
- I'm already holding down the orchestra.
- Maybe the key's too low.
Ask Lester if Tony
can take it a key higher.
About Lovelier Than You,
Les, a key higher?
Don't you see I'm trying to make a cut?
The key's perfect.
- But Lily said you'd make the change.
- The key is...
Everyone on their toes
for the transformation scene.
- We're not ready.
- JEFF: Perfectly all right. Next.
Watch it.
I'll cue you for the transition music.
Isn't it great? Herman.
Everybody ready back there?
We got to have more time
to make the change.
- I've got to have 16 more men.
- I got elevators...
Do the best you can.
All right, everybody. This is it.
Men in the elevators,
watch the signal lights for your cues.
Switchboards. Stand by to come down
your number one batten on cue.
Girls on stairs, take your positions,
but don't be frightened.
Men in armor, light your chandeliers.
All right, make this great, everybody.
Don't forget, it's the first-act finale.
Are you guys all right in there?
Now, watch your cue.
Light change.
Revolve.
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING)
This is going to be beautiful.
It will be a memorable moment.
Memorable.
Ah, yes.
This is real theater.
Everything's smooth as silk.
No, Herman, that doesn't go up,
it goes down. Take it down.
What is this? Herman!
I don't think
you've got your cues right!
No, stop!
That one doesn't go down, it goes up.
Take it up.
(FABRIC RIPPING)
For heaven's sake,
look at your cue sheet.
Take it up. No, not me.
Herman, this cable has fouled.
(ALL SHOUTING)
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
Calm down. Don't let us lose our heads.
This is a setback,
but that's what we come out of town for.
We'll never make it work.
Of course it will. You boys get together,
think of something brilliant.
You can't put Gaby on that thing.
It's dangerous. I won't allow it.
It's all right. After all, we expected
to strike a snag or two.
Get the full company in the lounge
for dialogue rehearsal...
while they're clearing the stage.
We can't afford to waste a moment.
(TONY CHUCKLES)
Here. I'm sorry. I forgot.
That help?
All right?
If you've quite finished,
let's try this.
We're going to get the stage soon.
You don't know it yet.
Paul, I'm afraid Gaby's kind of beat.
Nobody's had any sleep for two nights.
Can't you let her rest a while?
If you don't mind, Tony,
I've worked with her for many years.
I happen to know her a good deal
better than you do.
All right, Gaby. Come on.
Madame, may I have this dance?
Cut the clowning. It's not going to seem
so funny tomorrow night.
All right, Adam.
(PIANO PLAYING)
Okay, Paul, they're ready
for you on-stage. Come on.
JEFF: This is the big moment.
Hal, come on. Take it over there.
Tony, Gaby, this is it.
I want it to be outstanding.
It must be beautiful, fabulous,
warm, and fiery.
Your cue is, "Dance, fools, dance!"
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING "YOU
AND THE NIGHT AND THE MUSIC")
CHORUS (SINGING):
You and the night and the music
Fill me with flaming desire
(GABRIELLE SCREAMS)
Setting my being completely
On fire, fire, fire
You and the night and the music
(PEOPLE COUGHING)
Thrill me but will we
Be one
(GABRIELLE COUGHING)
After the night and the music
Are done?
Until the pale light
Of dawning and daylight
Our hearts will be throbbing guitars
Hal, it seems to be a little too much,
doesn't it?
Yes.
Are we really supposed
to open tomorrow night?
(LAUGHING)
"Dance, fools, dance!"
Hello, there! It's a big night.
Everybody is here from New York.
Simply everybody.
Do you hear that, my dear?
Everybody from New York is here.
Come on. Don't want you
to miss the overture.
Think we should get ready, boys?
No, we can finish this hand.
Nobody's made a pep talk yet.
Pep talk?
Yeah. I never seen an opening night yet
without some guy...
gets all the poor actors together
and makes them a long speech:
"They should be brilliant."
HAL:
On-stage, please. Everybody on-stage.
Mr. Cordova wants to say a few words.
Come on, girls. Hurry up. Let's go.
Step right along.
Company, a final word.
You've all been just wonderful.
Thanks for your cooperation.
Tonight, we're about to perform
before an audience in a theater.
It's not only a temple of the arts,
but a place of business.
And I feel we have here a venture
that is successful on both counts.
Nothing to be nervous about.
We've got to keep our wits and do a show.
There will be rough spots,
but we'll smooth them out.
Remember, that's what
we came out of town for.
Up to now, I've been giving you
orders as director...
but when next you see me,
I shall be just as one of you...
an eager ham, anxious to make good.
Actors, let's go.
All right, people.
Get ready for the tableau, girls.
Finish your make-up.
Come on, girls. Let's go.
I'm so glad you folks could come.
And don't forget the big party
at the hotel after the show.
The whole cast will be there.
You'll meet them all.
Of course, I have to go backstage
to congratulate them afterwards.
(LAUGHING)
I'll see you all at the party.
All New York is here.
Big party at the hotel after the show.
I'll look for you. Big party, big show.
Come on, now.
We don't want to miss a thing.
Now, don't forget the party.
Evelyn, big party at the hotel
after the show.
I'll look for you.
Champagne's on me.
(BELL TOLLING)
Shall I drive you to the hotel, sir,
to the party?
No. Drive me to the station.
Maybe I can still make the 11:40
back to New York.
Yes, sir.
- Good evening.
- I was looking for The Band Wagon party.
This is it, sir.
(PLAYING UPBEAT MUSIC)
(SPEAKING IN FRENCH)
This way, please.
- Are you leaving, sir?
- Yes. Good night.
We must do this more often.
Oh, give me something
To remember you by
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
When you are far away from me
Some little something
MAN: It's all Annie's fault.
I should have listened to my mother.
She told me only to be in hit shows.
(ALL LAUGH)
Hi, I don't want to barge in.
I just want to tell you all
how great I think you are.
I didn't get a chance
to know you very well.
- I'm sorry I messed up the show for you.
- Wait a minute, come on in, have a drink.
- I don't want to crash the party.
- Give Mr. Hunter a drink.
- What do you say, Scotch, rye, or beer?
- Beer's fine.
- One beer, coming up.
- Want some pizza pie?
How about a sandwich?
We've got ham and deviled egg.
I've had enough of both for one night.
(ALL LAUGH)
Far away
Me, oh, my
Only yesterday
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
There we were, the whole act,
the 10 Tapping Troubadours.
The 10 Tapping Troubadours?
Yeah, believe it or not...
we were stranded in Pittsburgh
with $3 between us...
crammed into one room
the size of that closet.
Gaby, come on in.
We're having a good old-fashioned wake.
I've been looking all over for you.
Where is Paul?
He's at a very exclusive wake
with Jeff and the Martons.
Can I get you a drink, Gaby?
How about a beer?
How about some popcorn?
Tony!
(WHISTLES)
TONY: Lily, Lester, come on in.
Are you sure? Don't you remember?
We wrote that thing.
This is a wonderful party. Come on in.
Who's going to go out and get the beer?
Okay, Sis, you're elected.
Tony, watch this!
(PLAYING PIANO)
More beer!
LESTER:
I'll never forget. You blew a gasket.
You were really gone. Come on.
(ALL SHOUTING)
Come on, Tony. Come on, get with it.
(SINGING) How I love the glass of beer
(SINGING) More beer
- Beer goes very good with beer
- More beer
When I'm drinking beer I'm thinking
"Ach, life is dear"
But there's someone I love
Even more than beer
I love Louisa
Louisa loves me
When we rode on the merry-go-round
I kissed Louisa
And then Louisa
Louisa kissed me
We were so happy
So happy and free
Ach! Ach! But she's a
Beautiful Louisa
SINGING (IN GERMAN ACCENT):
Ach! When I choose 'em
I never want to lose 'em
ALL (SINGING): Someday Louisa
Louisa will be
More als just a Fräulein to me
- Frenchmen love a glass of wine
- More beer
- The English think the whiskey's fine
But when I comb off all the foam off
I drink a toast
To the Germans and the Mädchen
I love most
(SINGING IN GERMAN)
Ach! Ach! But she's a
Beautiful Louisa
Ach! When I choose 'em
I never want to lose 'em
Ach! Ach! But she's a
Beautiful Louisa
Ach! When I choose 'em
I never want to lose 'em
Someday Louisa
Louisa will be
More than just a Fräulein to me
More beer!
(ALL LAUGHING)
Gosh, with all this raw talent around,
why can't us kids get together...
and put on ourselves a show?
Maybe we can find ourselves
a barn or something, and maybe...
I could stand anything but failure.
- Where's the telephone?
- In there.
Give me Jeff Cordova's room, please.
Hello, Jeff. This is Tony.
Now, don't say anything. Just listen.
I'm here with all the kids,
and we've come to a decision.
We're not closing this show, if you
can call it a show. We're going on.
We're going to keep it on the road
and redo it from top to bottom.
It won't be a modern version of Faust...
Pilgrim's Progress, or the Book of Job
in swing time.
It'll be our show,
the show we started out to do...
the book the Martons wrote,
with the songs you threw out.
It'll have laughs and entertainment.
You remember entertainment?
Look, we'd love
to have you with us, Jeff.
But if you're not,
it won't make any difference.
We're going ahead just the same.
We're going to put this thing across,
aren't we, kids?
All right. What do you say?
WOMAN (OVER PHONE): Hello? Nobody here.
This is the chambermaid,
but if you want...
- ...I'll leave a message for Mr. Cordova.
- Thank you, madam.
He isn't in.
Jeff, did you hear what I said?
Tony, I've learned one thing
in the theater, and it's this:
one man has to be at the helm,
the rest take orders.
I believe in what you said. I got
carried away in the wrong direction.
You've got to be the boss, Tony.
I think you can pull this off brilliantly...
and I'd like to be a part of it.
Jeff, you're all right.
I must tell you one thing.
There isn't any money.
Colonel Todd and the backers
have stolen away into the night.
- We've got backers.
- Who?
A bunch of painters.
A fellow named Degas from...
- You wouldn't sell your paintings.
- Sure, they love the theater.
I figure we need five or six weeks on tour
to do what we have to do with this show.
- Jeff, would you help us with bookings?
- Of course.
Hal, have you got paper and pencil?
We can send a telegram.
(ALL CHATTERING)
- HAL: Washington? Washington's open.
- TONY: And Boston.
Boston's very good.
Can we go to Philadelphia, Detroit,
then come on back to New York?
- Paul, aren't you excited?
- Yeah. It's wonderful.
I wish them a lot of luck.
- This kind of leaves us out.
- Why?
With Tony doing the dances,
it's not going to be my kind of show.
Yours, either.
I don't want you to do it.
I wouldn't think of leaving
the show, Paul.
- I've worked too hard on your career to...
- It's my career, and I want to stay.
I'm taking the 9:00 train
tomorrow morning for New York.
I expect you to be there.
Have a nice trip, Paul.
JEFF: Dancers, singers, the sketches.
TONY: Listen, kids, it's going
to mean rehearsing every day...
all day, right up to curtain time.
We're going to put in new numbers,
and learn them as fast as we can...
and we're going
to yank out all that junk.
(ALL LAUGH)
We've got our schedule all worked out,
and it looks pretty good now.
Philadelphia, Boston, Pittsburgh...
Washington, Baltimore...
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING)
(SINGING)
I see a new sun up in a new sky
And my whole horizon
Has reached a new high
Yesterday my heart sang a blue song
But today hear it hum a cheery new song
I dreamed a new dream
I saw a new face
And I'm spreading sunshine
All over the place
With a new point of view
Here's what greets my eye
- New love
- ENSEMBLE (SINGING): New love
- New luck
- New sun
- And there's a new sun
In the sky
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING)
(SINGING)
I guess I'll have to change my plan
I should've realized
There'd be another man
I overlooked that point completely
Until the big affair began
Before I knew where I was at
I found myself up on the shelf
And that was that
I tried to reach the moon
But when I got there
All that I could get was the air
My feet are back upon the ground
I've lost the one girl I found
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING)
(SINGING) Get goin', Louisiana hayride
Get goin', we all is ready
Start somethin', Louisiana hayride
No use for callin' the roll
Oh, I like that sport
Sittin' in the hay
Lovin' it away, oh, oh
For the time is short
Crack your little whip
Get your little ship to go
Start somethin', Louisiana hayride
No foolin', we all is happy
Get goin', Louisiana hayride
No use for callin' the roll
- Jasmine Washington
- I is here
- Sweet Pea Oglethorpe
- Jonquil Jezebel
- Here
- Lemon Verbena
- I is here
Mo and Freddy
Lily and Lettie
We is here
We all here
- Zeke and Lemuel, Hiram and Samuel
- We is here, we all here
- Primrose Paradise
- I am here
- Daisy Dandelion
- I is here
We all here
Can't you see?
If you is really ready
And you're goin' steady
Get goin', Louisiana hay
Louisiana hayride
Start something, Louisiana hay
And no use to call, no use to call
- It's no use
- No use to bother to call the roll
Get goin', get goin'
I like that sport, sittin' in the hay
Lovin' it away, ow, ow
The time is short, crack your little whip
Get your little ship
- Get your little ship
- Get your little ship to go
Get goin'
Louisiana hayride
Clear the way
Watch out, kindly step aside
Get goin'
Louisiana hayride
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
The scene's only about two minutes.
You won't have time to make the change.
TONY: I know it's a rough deal,
but we won't make New York if we don't.
- As much rehearsal time as possible.
- Better call them at 10:00.
Don't forget, everybody.
Rehearsal, 10:00 on the dot, Baltimore.
That case is important.
Tell you what we'll do, when we start.
Say, who's the pretty girl?
Why, this couldn't be
the mousy little Miss Gerard.
You've been with the firm for years.
I've never seen you with glasses on.
Say, you are beautiful.
How are you, Gaby?
- I'm all right. Thanks.
- TONY: Good.
Oh!
I'm sorry.
- You must be tired.
- Yes, I am, a little.
- Bet you are too.
- A little.
Lester, look, I've got a problem
with these two numbers.
The murder mystery has a jazz beat
and I don't want it to...
- Anyone heard from Paul Byrd?
- No, I haven't heard.
As a matter of fact, nobody has.
At least they haven't mentioned it.
- Wasn't he going to...
- What a rat.
Rat? Lester, wait a second.
He's a wonderful guy,
wonderful and talented.
He's written... Listen, don't sell him short.
That boy has got a lot...
He may be a little young, yes.
He needs a little more experience.
- Just give him a few more years.
- Yeah.
Probably when he settles down
and gets married.
- You think he'll make a good husband?
- And how. Great.
He'll make a great husband. Sure.
Listen, this kid is solid.
He knows all...
It isn't gonna be easy. No.
Marriage and the theater and two careers.
Problems. It isn't all skittles.
- It's no bed of...
- Is that why you never got married?
Who, me? You know,
I'm the kind of fella...
You got the right slant.
You're pretty happy as you are.
I like to kick around
and have a lot of laughs.
Lester, I'm very much in love
with this girl.
It's ridiculous, I know, things being
as they are, but there it is.
Look, Tony, uh,
I don't know what the chances are...
but wait till we get to New York,
and see how you stand.
Personally, I think the girl's crazy
about you...
but what you can see in a beautiful,
young and talented girl is beyond me.
(TONY CHUCKLES)
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING)
(SINGING)
Three little unexpected children
Simultaneously the doctor brought us
And you can see that
We'll be three forever and A
E, I, O, You wouldn't know how agonizing
Being triple can be
Each one is individually the victim
Of the clinical day
E, I, O, Every summer we go away
To Baden-Baden-Baden
Every winter we come back home
To Walla Walla Walla
We do everything alike
We look alike
We dress alike
We walk alike
We talk alike
And what is more
We hate each other very much
We hate our folks
We're sick of jokes
On what an art it is to tell us apart
- If one of us gets the measles
- Another one gets the measles
Then all of us gets the measles
And mumps and croup
How I wish I had a gun
A wittle gun
It would be fun to shoot the other two
And be only one!
Mrs. Wifflepoofer loves
To talk to Mrs. Hildendorfer
Of the fatal natal day
She had her silly Willy
Mrs. Hassencooper loves to talk
To Mrs. Goldenwasser
Of her major operation
When she had her twins
But when Mother comes along
She silences the others
She accomplished something
That is very rare in mothers
MGM has got a Leo
But Mama has got a trio
She is proud
But says three is a crowd
We do everything alike
We look alike, we dress alike
We walk alike, we talk alike
And what is more
We hate each other very much
We hate our folks
We're sick of jokes
On what an art it is to tell us apart
We eat the same kind of vittles
We drink the same kind of bottles
We sit in the same kind of highchair
Highchair, highchair
Oh, I wish I had a gun, a wittle gun
It would be fun to shoot the other two
And be only one
(HORN HONKS)
- It's raining cats and dogs.
- A rainy opening is good luck...
when it rains on opening night.
Good luck, Tony.
Sweetie, I just want to say that no matter
what happens tonight, it's been...
I know. It's been that for me too.
If this turns out to be a hit,
you'll get sick of the sight of me...
six nights a week, two matinees.
No escape.
Course, if it isn't,
you won't have to see me at all.
Gaby, I've been wanting
to ask you something.
It's been... I felt there's been
an obstacle between us.
I wanted to... Is Paul coming tonight?
- Why, I think so.
- I see.
What I wanted to ask...
Perhaps, I better not.
I wish you wouldn't, Tony.
- Tony, good luck tonight.
- Good luck, Gaby.
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING)
GABRIELLE (SINGING):
I see a new sun up in a new sky
- TONY (SINGING): If one of us gets the measles
- JEFF (SINGING): Another one gets the measles
ALL (SINGING):
Then all of us gets the measles
LILY (SINGING):
Get goin', Louisiana hayride
Get goin', we all is ready
(PLAYING JAZZ MUSIC)
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(GUNFIRE)
TONY: The city was asleep.
The joints were closed.
The rats, the hoods,
and the killers were in their holes.
I hate killers.
My name is Rod Riley. I'm a detective.
(TRUMPET PLAYING)
Somewhere in a furnished room...
some guy was practicing on a horn.
It was a lonesome sound.
It crawled on my spine.
I had just finished a tough case.
I was ready to hit the sack.
(ORCHESTRA PLAYS SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
I can smell trouble a mile off,
and this poor kid was in trouble.
Big trouble.
She's scared,
scared as a turkey in November.
There was nothing left of the guy,
nothing at all, except...
a rag, a bone, and a hank of hair.
The guy had been trying
to tell me something, but what?
So that's the way
they wanted to play. All right.
Somewhere in the city there was
a killer and that was bad.
Bad for the killer,
because I shoot hard.
And I hate hard.
I was playing a hunch.
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING ROMANTIC MUSIC)
She came at me in sections.
More curves than a scenic railway.
She was bad, she was dangerous.
I wouldn't trust her any farther
than I could throw her.
She was selling hard,
but I wasn't buying.
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING OMINOUS MUSIC)
This had to be Mr. Big.
Get him and you get them all.
(PANTING)
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING SOFT JAZZ MUSIC)
There was something about this kid
that made you want to protect her for life.
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING DRAMATIC MUSIC)
That bullet was meant for me.
Maybe this was a long shot,
but I've seen some funny ones pay off.
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING UPBEAT MUSIC)
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING MYSTERIOUS MUSIC)
I was beginning to see daylight.
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
These mugs were smart,
but they made one mistake.
They got me mad.
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING UPBEAT MUSIC)
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING SEDUCTIVE MUSIC)
All the pieces fitted together.
I knew how the crime had been done.
The high note on the trumpet
had shattered the glass.
(TRUMPET PLAYING)
The glass with the nitroglycerin.
Now I knew who the killer was,
but it didn't matter anymore.
Killers have to die.
Another page in the casebook
of Rod Riley was finished.
The city was asleep.
The joints were closed.
The rats, the hoods,
and the killers were in their holes.
I felt good, but something was missing.
She was bad, she was dangerous.
I wouldn't trust her any farther
than I could throw her.
But she was my kind of woman.
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING UPBEAT MUSIC)
(SHOE THUDS)
- Who's that? Somebody come in?
- No one, Mr. Hunter.
- You sure? Did you look out in the hall?
- Not a soul, Mr. Hunter.
I can't understand it.
Are you sure this show's a hit?
A very big hit, Mr. Hunter.
Congratulations.
It certainly doesn't feel like one.
I didn't expect them to pull my carriage
through the streets or hurl flowers at me...
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
- Hal, come on, boy. Have a drink.
- No, thanks.
- Got any notes for the cast for tomorrow?
- No.
- Good night.
- Say, look.
Doesn't anybody come backstage anymore
on opening nights?
No. It's considered old-fashioned.
Have a good night's rest, Tony.
Did Gaby go out with Paul?
Gaby? I don't know. I guess so.
Good night, Tony.
Bobby, you know what I'm going to do?
I'm going out to the biggest nightclub
I can find.
I'm going to get a glass of champagne
and celebrate.
Fine idea, sir.
(TONY HUMMING)
(SINGING) I'll go my way by myself
All alone in a crowd
I'll try to apply myself
And teach my heart how to sing
I'll go my way by myself
Like a bird on the wing
I'll face the unknown
I'll build a world of my own
ALL (SINGING): He's a jolly good fellow
He's a jolly good fellow
That nobody can deny
For he's a jolly good fellow
Tony, the whole company got together.
We all chipped in,
and we bought you... nothing.
So we have nothing to give you...
but our gratitude, our admiration...
and our love.
The show's a hit, but we all feel...
no matter what might've happened to it,
it was wonderful knowing you...
working with you.
Maybe some of us didn't see eye to eye
with you at the beginning.
Maybe we thought
we wouldn't work out together...
but we have.
Yes, there were obstacles between us...
but we've kissed them good-bye.
We've come to love you, Tony.
We belong together.
The show's going to run a long time.
As far as I'm concerned,
it's going to run forever.
- Tony.
- May we say something?
(SINGING) A show that is really a show
Sends you out with a kind of a glow
And you say as you go on your way
"That's entertainment!"
(SINGING) A song that is winging along
Or a dance with a touch of romance
Is the art that appeals to the heart
That's entertainment!
(SINGING) Admit we're a hit
And we'll go on from there
We played a charade
That was lighter than air
A good old-fashioned affair
As we sing this finale
We hope it was up your alley
No death like you get in Macbeth
No ordeal like the end of Camille
This good-bye brings a tear to the eye
The world is a stage
The stage is a world
Of entertainment
(English - US - SDH)