A hundred years ago,
Africa was a vast, dark unknown.
Only a few explorers and missionaries...
the ivory hunters
and the infamous slave raiders...
risked their lives
on its blood-soaked trails.
Gleaming tusks were the prize...
and sweating slaves
sold by their own kings and chiefs
in the ceaseless tribal wars...
or seized by slavers.
The lion and the leopard hunted savagely
among the huge herds of game.
And man, lacking the will
to understand other men...
became like the beasts.
And their way of life was his.
Bring up the rear.
I've got a feeling about this safari.
We're going to make a killing.
Well, let's hope so.
I've been thinking.
After this,
I'd like to go into the slave trade.
Very lucrative.
Very, very lucrative.
Should go well with ivory.
Want to become a partner?
No, thanks.
Uh, this is my last time out.
After this, I'm settling on my farm.
Suit yourself, laddie,
but you're missing a big chance.
Ah, well, that happens.
No, you don't want that.
They're friendly.
Let's keep it that way.
What's he saying?
Where's that interpreter?
Oh, we don't need him.
I happen to know this dialect.
- What do they want?
- Well, it's the usual thing. Gifts for their chief.
No. Stay there.
I'm not giving them anything.
What the hell for?
Who says they own this land?
They've been here for generations.
Long enough to call it their own.
Anyway, it's customary,
and it's wise.
Let's get this understood.
I'm financing this safari, and I'm -
And I'm managing it.
That was the agreement.
Now, don't let's argue in front of them.
You can manage it.
But you're not giving my money away.
I paid for those goods
to be traded for ivory...
not to be given as handouts to every...
beggar who turns up on a jungle path.
Listen to me.
It's not worth it.
For a few trinkets, they'll let us alone. Otherwise,
they can give us a bad time. It's not worth it.
It's the principle of it. You give it to one,
and they'll come from miles around.
I know these chaps.
I've dealt with them before.
You're not the only one.
Let's get moving.
Don't be a bloody fool!
You're endangering the whole safari.
Get out of my way!
Did you see that brain shot
I made on that big bull?
Running too.
Let everybody eat
after they've cleaned one tusk.
Right, sir.
At an angle.
I got 14 of them. Not bad, huh?
- How many did you get?
- We're not in a contest.
Eleven.
That's how many, laddie.
Eleven to my 14.
All of mine were carrying ivory.
What is that supposed to mean?
That mine weren't?
Exactly. Five of them
weren't worth the gunpowder.
What the hell!
So I shot some of them for sport.
Have another drink.
Not for me.
I think we've both had enough.
We've got quite a few miles
to cover today.
Look, friend.
You're managing the safari, not me.
I'll have another.
Will you shut up!
Stop them over there!
Hey! Hey, you bastards!
Hey, you devils! Hey!
Hey, you devils! Burn! Burn!
Burn! Burn, you devils!
Burn! Burn! Burn, you devils!
Oh, my God.
Hmm?
Mmm. Mmm, mmm.
Mmm. Yum-yum.
Ah?
Aha!
- Zavoudi.
- Huh?
Zavoudi.
Zavoudi?
Ah, zavoudi.
Well, that's very, uh, zava -
- Zavoudi.
Well.
Here.
This is for my little singer.
Zavoudi.
Oh. You want to go home.
Uh -
Mm-hmm.
I hope you'll be all right.
Here. I have a present for you.
Zavoudi.
Zavoudi. Hmm?
Number One Company.