Carobs. Carobs. I harvested them
and now you're eating them.
Feel the perfume! Three for
half a lira.
- Give me for half a lira.
- And to me.
You either eat these,
or eat nothing.
Come on, you can buy them without a
ration.
Carobs! Eat! We've gotten
worse than swines.
Let me breath! I need air!
Make way for the Holy Virgin!
Would you want to leave the Holy Virgin
under bombs, on her celebration day?
- Make way!
- There's no place!
What have we done wrong to God?
Must he send all of them here?
Don Mario, I've counted it. With this one,
we've had 122 bombardments.
You're attracting them. If only they'd
fly throw their bombs on Rome.
No, not on Roma, my son's there.
Better they bombard here.
No loss if we die.
You can't decide that. There can't be
any personal issues.
- Silence. - Listen to me.
Oh man, what's with this silence?
In order to spare the nation
from further disasters...
...the Italian Government has asked
general Eisenhower, Commander in Chief
...of the allied Anglo-American
forces for a truce...
The war is over!
No more war!
No more hunger! It's over!
No more bombs!
- Can this be true?
- This is all crazy!
The Holy Virgin has spared us,
on her celebration day.
Nunziatina, we can get married now!
- Have you lost something? - Arturo,
you can get out, war is over!
Look where she had hidden her son!
Yes, I wouldn't give him to them
for this beautiful war!
Come at daddy.
Easy, handsome. Take him slowly
to light.
- Open your eyes slowly.
- Help him out.
Come out, my son.
My soul! My little one!
Mother's soul!
Now no one's going to take you away
from my arms.
"Chiattona", don't worry, I'll
even kiss you!
- Me?! But I'm old!
- Today I find you all beautiful!
I can shave at last!
I must get drunk!
Rejoice, soldiers,
we have lost the war!
Open up! Mail for the 3rd
anti-aircraft squad.
With all this you worry about the mail?
Take a hike!
Hey, you want it? I'll give it to you!
What are you doing?
I don't know! What do you intend doing?
Here's chaos!
- Capitain, what are we to do?
- I've got orders not
to give orders anymore!
- If no one gives orders...
- Don't bother me, take care of yourselves!
- War is over, isn't it?
- Yes. Only morons fought.
The king of morons tells you this!
- Thief! - I raised the chicken in the
barracks. - Then enjoy.
What noise (casino) you're making
at the brothel (casino)!
Women, today all for free!
You don't have to pay!
Poor whores, always locked up!
Even they're taking a little fresh air.
- What beauty! - Raise the flag!
We haven't won the war!
- Even those that lost it, won the war!
- Even the whores!
What are you doing, beauty? You're sad?
- I'm happy.
- Why?
- And what will you do now?
- Nothing, like before.
But still I'm happy, for all this
soldiers who can go home now.
Scram, stinking German!
Don't come here anymore!
Hitler kaput. War kaput. Hurray!
Fritz, go fritz yourself!
- Don't forget me!
- Careful, potato.
Hey, "your war,
my war, all finished"!
- Do you take me for your girl?
- Let's go!
- Where shall I take you?
- Home. All Germans go back in Germany.
- In Germany by bike?!
- Yes! All's over! Peace!
Hurry up, take him away! Sooner they go,
better it is! Go!
A lira haven't I got,
but love it is my lot!
Let's go!
Hitler kaput. War kaput.
Happy?
Of course, my husband will be back!
He's a soldier too.
- All's over!
- Hurray!
What are you doing?
Pitrella, let's go.
Down.
What shall we do now?
Lieutenant, why are you looking at me?
Then, Lieutenant?
Pitrella doesn't say anything?
- There's nothing else to do.
- Come, let's throw everything, us also.
- Everyone returns home.
- Happy you, living in Naples!
- But will the Lieutenant let us?
- The officers are gentlemen!
This sailor pays for the hostile acts
against the Germans.
This should be a warning:
if other irresponsibles will dare,
...now they'll know what sanctions
they're exposed to.
Mario, come here.
And now, kneel everyone,
says the Captain.
You must kneel, you from the first row.
Everyone must be able to see.
The people from Naples
can only approve...
...and that's why, says the Captain,
applaud!
He's filming you for the 'Newsreel'.
I'm telling it for your own good:
Applaud!
If not, these one will take you
on also!
You mustn't cry.
You mustn't cry!
Attention, colonel Scholl
has assumed starting today...
...the absolute command, with full powers,
of the city of Naples.
Civilian and military Italian authorities
will obey his orders.
Starting today, State of Siege
is proclaimed...
...and curfew will be in place
from 21:00 to 06:00 in the morning.
Everyone possessing arms must
turn them in at the police stations...
...under death penalty.
These are the orders from the Fuhrer's
General Staff Command.
Attention, for military reasons,
all inhabitants of the buildings...
...along the coast line,
up to 300 meters from the sea...
...must immediately evacuate their
dwellings.
Who will be found in the prohibited zone
will be punished...
...according to German military laws.
- Let us through!
- Clear the way!
- Give me your handbag.
How are you feeling?
- Better.
I feel better.
Put everything in the tub.
Wait, the canary!
We almost forgot the canary.
You take it, mother! What are you doing?
I'm sorry, have you seen my husband?
Umberto! Where can he be?
He's driving me mad. Umberto!
Where the hell have you hidden?
- Umberto! Umberto! - Hey, even I am
a mother and have a son!
- Excuse me. - There are moments when he
gets me down, this child!
Let's go, children. Stay close to me,
or you'll get lost.
- Where's Assuntina? - I don't know,
mother, she was with you. - My God!
Excuse me, have you seen a child
with braids?
Assuntina!
Criminal! If I don't find Assuntina
on the spot... Go look for her!
Assuntina, come on!
- Mother!
- Mother, she's there!
- Assuntina!
- She's here, ma'am!
Here she is.
Take her.
Mommy's here. Don't cry.
Stay close to me, have you understood?
You, count.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5: We're all here.
Ready, we're leaving!
- Where are we going?
- I don't know, where the feet will take us.
Let's do what everyone else does.
Mamma mia! Come, let's go.
Drop this spoon.
- Donna Concetta, eat something.
- No, thank you.
A little beans, if not what will you
feed the baby with?
Why are you pressing her? With all this
turmoil, she has no appetite!
I have to go. I must see who can
take me in with the other four.
Please, remember you said you
were the oldest.
What did you tell papa?
That you'll take his place.
Give me a kiss.
- Grab my skirt. Stay close to me.
- Mother, where are we going?
I don't know. We'll find someone to take
us in. We'll try.
Come, on. Eat, eat.
What kind of beans are these?
Red or early?
- Early!
- Ah.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7. You've only
eaten two beans?!
Eat, kid! Now you're starting? Eat!
- For a kid early beans are heavy in
the evening. - It's day. - Ah.
Come on, eat. Come on.
- Come and listen.
- Wait mother.
- Do you have sons? - Yes, why?
- Don't take them outside.
The Germans want to catch all the males
and take them to Germany.
Orders for forced recruitment...
...for all men born between 1910-1925.
- Who told you?
- Doesn't matter. It's how I tell you.
- I'll go warn Pasqualino.
- What are you waiting for? Run!
Vittoria! - What?
- Don't let the men out!
Carmela, Nunziatina, listen carefully,
they want to take the men away!
Donna Rosina.
They want to take away our sons.
Spread the word around.
Little one, hide your papa!
Tell your husband too!
Run in the square and shout it!
Women, hide the men!
The Germans want to take the men away!
Salvatore.
Salvatore. Come here.
Quickly.
- Where are you going? - I'm running away,
I'm afraid.
Who, you? Go back home and hide.
Do it for my sake.
Why? You care about me?
You often think at me?
You can't have these thoughts anymore,
now you've got a husband and children.
Damn, this key! I never find when
I look for it.
- If I knock, the baby will awake.
- Maria!
- Disaster. Maria, come! The baby's crying!
- Coming!
If you are a man, shouldn't stick
these manifesto.
These things they should do it themselves,
with their own hands.
Salvatore, don't raise your voice.
They understand Italian.
- You shouldn't stick them.
- But you don't know the Germans.
What is he trying to prove? It's here
he wants to play the dare devil?
- That one's trying to get in trouble.
- Or get us in trouble.
How nice it is to play the hero!
But don't you think at all the people
that could get caught in this?
The hero! Don't make me laugh!
He's a delinquent, he's in the Camorra.
Close the window.
A big deal they'll get with me!
Paternity: ---. Profession: ---.
Come on, Salvatore.
All!
- They want to count all Neapolitans.
- Good day.
Present!
Brother, do you have a potato for us?
If I had one, would I give it to you?!
But the Almighty could spare a thought
even for us!
What's a potato for the Almighty?
You don't know how it's like leaving
your children in different houses!
What are you doing, fool? Down!
We're in the middle of the street!
Radio London, Colonel Stevens
speaking. Good evening
Good evening to you.
Not one Neapolitan has come forward
force the forced labour.
American troops have reached
Torre Annunziata.
My God, Torre Annunziata!
Half an hour by train!
Yes, but those ones go by foot,
and they don't run!
- Friend, the game!
- Come in. - If I may.
Yesterday, in the Sanità district,
a woman was killed.
Holy Virgin! A few steps away!
But how come he knows it,
him being in London?
Neapolitans, defend...
What precision! They seem to go
by a time table!
Jesus and Mary! Are you not Don Giovanni?
The Blessed Virgin has granted her grace!
Your husband is back.
Giovanni!
Giovanni! You've come back!
- Don't cry anymore.
- And you, why are you crying?
Don't hold me so tight,
or I'll faint.
I've got wounds and I hurt all over.
I had forgotten how a bed was made.
Let me sleep first.
Come here, handsome.
You can't imagine what it means.
I haven't slept for 100 hours.
You are clean now, you can kiss him
as much as you want.
- Come to daddy.
- It's daddy, go.
Come to daddy. What does it mean?
That's how you're celebrating your daddy?
It's the beard!
Do you want to shave it off?
Do you want me to look for a razor blade?
And I'll look for something to eat too.
Come, handsome. It's not that I'm bad.
I'd like to stay and look at you
until tomorrow...
...but my eyes are shutting down.
How tired I am!
Have patience...
Let me go! What have we done?
Who are you looking for? It's not we!
Where are you taking me? I'm a veteran!
I was in the war!
One moment, let me take my pants.
Gaetano, what are you doing, getting out?
No! Gaetano.
The proclamation doesn't concern me!
The registry says I was born on the
2nd of January 1905...
...but in fact I was born on the
25th of December 1904!
Cavalier Gennari, who has held me at my
baptism can confirm it.
Heil Hitler. Heil Mussolini.
I've always been a fascist!
- I swear! - Arnaldo! - You tell them
I'm a fascist! - Arnaldo!
Arnaldo, I want to go with you.
Where are you taking him?
Arnaldo, you're mine.
I'm also a fascist! But how do you
say "fascist" in German?
The proclamation doesn't concern me!
What are these manners?
Where do you think you are?
- How is Assuntina?
- I've told you already, she's fine.
- But don't let her see you, or
she'll start crying. - You're right.
You've wisen up. War maked you grow-up,
isn't it?
Easy. Eat it here, if not, if they see it,
they'll take it away.
But you don't want some?
Taste a little.
Only to see if they are good.
If you'd only know where I've found them!
Here.
Now it's better I go.
Mother, when will we
live together again?
Here, give it to Assuntina.
Please, don't eat it.
Ma'am, tell my mother:
Colletta Teresa.
- Where are they taking us now?
- To play foot.
Have you seen my son?
He's name is Mario. He has auburn hair.
He's tall and skinny. Has auburn hair.
His name is Mario.
- That manifesto is only a lie.
- You're wrong!
- Let it be known we're still alive.
He's skinny! - But what can I do?
- What are these manners? - Good day,
ingegnere. - Good day, avvocato.
Where are they taking you? To Germany?
Colletta Teresa.
Give us back our men!
The Blessed Virgin be with you.
Let's go!
Stop!
Wait!
Damn it, I thought we were the only ones
having this idea!
- They all want to go to Sorrento.
- The Americans must be there already.
I don't care if the Americans have come...
...I want to know if my son has been born.
- Let's find another boat. - Where will
you find another madman to take you?
- We must find him.
- The Germans! The Germans!
The taxi! Curse your souls, what are
you doing? Are you mad?
You had to shoot right here? Go make
war somewhere else.
Right in my taxi?!
Do you want to go away,
once and for all?
Jesus, he's dead!
Enough. Enough, wait.
He's dead. Give me a hand.
- Oh, Blessed Mary. - Easy. Be careful.
- Let's put him on the roof.
- Come here, help me.
- Let's take the other one.
Easy, easy.
For these innocent souls...
Come on, let's get down!
Go, taxi.
Neapolitans, show yourselves. See what the
Germans have done.
Take this, Giovanni!
- Neapolitans, show yourselves.
- Give it to me.
- Neapolitans, open your windows,
get out. - We must revenge them
See what the
Germans have done.
We must revenge our poor brothers.
Get out, get out!
They've died for you.
Long live Naples.
Death to the Germans
Neapolitans, these dead are calling
for you, they're here for you.
Neapolitans, don't hide!
Get down.
Wait, I'll go with you.
Let's save Naples. Neapolitans, don't
play smart.
You're mad! What got into your heads?
The other one has torn clothes.
I have good ones...
What does it matter now?
Anastasio's dead.
Doctor! Doctor!
Doctor! Let me see him
Let me go!
No, it's not him.
Thank you, Holy Virgin.
Who knows whose poor mother
he was the son.
- Have you tried finding her?
- He had no documents.
Let me through.
- What is it?
There's a rumour going on there's a
young man dead who's unknown.
Good riddance. It's been three days since
I was looking for that swine.
Oh, Jesus! He has such an angel's face!
What were their sins to have
died so young?
This war was almost over!
Jesus! Jesus!
How could this happen?
This morning you were alive,
and I won't see you again.
Treacherous son, why have you left me?
- Why? - Ma'am, you want to take him
away during curfew?
That's what his father wants.
Arturo, daddy's coming now
and all three of us will go home.
Did you hear, Arturo?
Did you hear your mother?
Excuse me. Please.
- Who were you afraid for? - I've got three
brothers, three despairs.
We are looking for them and we
are worried.
War, always the war.
And dead laughing in your face.
Allow me.
- We must take him away like this.
- What do you mean? - On our arms.
- I haven't found a cart.
- Do you need help? - Yes, thank you.
Wait. Easy, easy.
Easy, don't hurt my son.
My son! Wait. Where's the handkerchief?
I'm sorry. My handsome...
- Do you want me to accompany you?
- No, thank you very much.
I'll take him, easy, easy.
Have you seen how beautiful is my son?
You should have pity on me, I feel he's
more pleased to be at his home.
Wait, I'll help you.
What a procession! This night, despite
the curfew, half of Naples comes.
Woe on her who recognizes him!
- Is that the house?
- It's the only lit door.
- What happened? - Don't you know?
Two boys have died.
In a shoot out with the Germans!
There even were 5-6 armed Christians.
Mamma mia! Germans?
I've said Christians. Like us!
Imagine if every Neapolitan would take
upon himself to kill a German.
It's like how they say:
"If everyone puts down a lira...".
They say it, but don't do it.
- Pitrella, are you sure this is the
place? - I think so.
Ah, there's something written down here.
- Here! A little backwards.
- Give me a hand.
- Who is it?
- Silence. - The Lieutenant!
Isn't it here that we've hidden the arms?
What are you waiting for? Come on,
keep digging.
I'm sorry, maybe you wanted to say it.
Do you have a riffle for me?
You had a revolver. Look for it.
Everyone takes his stuff.
Come, write.
"People of Naples..." No.
"People of Vommero, the hour of the
insurrection has come."
"Let's fight the Germans,
let's save our loved ones..."
"...from deportation and death."
Professor, these are beautiful words,
but what are we when facing the Germans?
- They have guns, tanks!
- Yes, sure.
- Where were we? - It lacks the signature.
- Ah, the signature.
With what right should I sign it?
Who am I?
- What do you mean?
You're the Commander!
- Yes, a Commander full of shit!
Five soldiers have been killed. Execute
50 hostages. Colonel Scholl's orders.
We'll need a machine-gun.
It's the only way to deter attacks.
Is it clear?
Bring the Italians here, the firing
squad will take position on the field.
What do they want now?
They can't leave me alone.
The Americans are at Capri,
at Ischia, and are going away?
- Where can I do a little something.
- Go there! Who's watching you?
- I'm ashamed!
- Go!
- Wanna' make a game?
- No!
Hey, you want to play?
Please, I'm so tired,
I haven't slept in 100 hours.
It almost makes me cry. That's where
they had to take me? Close to my house!
- I've got a wife and child!
- Try calling for them. - Better not.
Want to play a hand to make time go by?
No, thanks, I'll do a solitaire.
What are they doing?
No! Not like this, damn it
Give it to me. Like this.
You take this.
- Professor! - What? - This gentleman
wants to speak to you.
- What does he want? Who sent him?
- I've read your proclamation.
Captain, nobody called you, soldiers, in.
This are the arms you have thrown
when running away.
- Where have you been until now?
- In Yugoslavia, in Albania, in Russia!
Certainly not to please me, and always
stoopping in front of the Germans!
I'm a fascist!
Holy Virgin, they want to kill us!
They want to kill us like
we were animals!
- Stay close to me. - Yes.
- Stay close. Give me your hand.
Shoot! Don't stop! They must think
there are a lot of us!
Maybe we'll save them! Shoot!
Go on shooting, I'm going down.
You two, come with me!
- Go way!
- We won't move from here.
It's ours that are inside.
Professor, stop!
Stop! Professor!
Soldiers!
German soldiers!
- Move! - Move!
- Come!
- Are we stopping here or what?
- No, we go forward!
No, here!
Those go to Vommero!
Why do you shoot here? Go make
war at your houses!
Don't you say anything? Go shoot wherever
you want, but not here.
You must go away, we want to be left
alone. I'm telling you.
- Leave, before the Germans come.
- That's why we're here!
- You must leave immediately!
- The Germans!
Totò! How come? You had gone out
to buy bread!
You can't make war next to your wife!
I can't live without you, I have to be
at your side. Do you love, Totò?
- Don't stick to me!
- Totò, you always exaggerate!
- With the marble?
- Yes, with the marble!
What are you doing, moron? Not my bed!
Take something else!
We've stopped them.
We've made it.
I'm hungry!
Thief! He has full sacks of flower.
It's useless threatening, you'll
find nothing inside!
Baking has been stopped!
I don't have flower! I don't have anything!
We want to see. If they don't give,
we'll take it!
- Excuse me. - Doctor, I was looking for
you. I have a tooth that's killing me.
Cicillo, I must try and get some bread!
I've shot the Germans,
I can also shoot you!
Pull my tooth out! Doctor!
Cicillo. Is it true you have shot?
Him no, but them yes.
- Them who? - Salvatore and some
50 more people.
- Where?
- Above the districts.
The Germans!
Comrades, here, help me!
Cicillo! Wait for me!
Come on, Maria, run!
Go away! Take this woman away,
they'll be shooting here soon!
- The cartridges. - Stay here.
- Find cartridges.
Where did you take this red marked
cartridges from?!
The Germans. Give me cartridges. What
are you doing? Give me the cartridges!
- I don't think they're good. - Yes,
they are, I took them from barracks!
Let's go!
Attack! We're not afraid!
We're not afraid.
Maria, go away.
Christ! These are blanks!
- These are blanks, boys! Run!
- These are blanks! Open! Open!
Francesco.
Cicillo, you heard?
Comei! Run!
What are you doing here? I told you to
go away! Runaway, Maria.
Please, get out of here!
Salvatore, I didn't think I'd
find you.
- What do you want? - Nothing. - It's
sheer madness. Go back home!
It's madness! All this people
shooting and dying!
- You mustn't die. - Go back home.
Why have you come?
No. Salvatore, you mustn't die,
understand?
I've just seen one of your friends die.
- What friend?
- Cicillo.
I've seen him die with my own eyes.
Assassins, you must die too.
Swines, you must die.
- Look at the second floor.
- That window. - Ah, yes!
- Take a gun, run!
- Let's go, the guns!
- Come on, let's show them who we are.
- And who are we?
We are all sons of the "androcchia"!
Take the guns and be careful,
'cause they're shooting!
- Give us Ajello.
Ajello, we've come to take you.
Come on, let's get out!
Ajello!
Ajello, wait! Ajello!
Stop! We'll shoot!
Thank God there's no law,
no police...
...and that bombs are falling,
otherwise you'd have never gotten out.
But be careful, 'cause sooner or later
you'll be back here!
I won't go before you.
And who's going out with me,
stays with me.
Yes, well done! Play the hero,
do the camorrista!
I know you well, and what you're
capable of!
Steal, rape, kill,
you're always ready for it.
Ajello, you've still got time.
What's this shit!
Talk, talk... Let's go
Where are we going? Sack the city?
Who shall we make cry?
We must go to war!
And show who we are.
- Who's this one?
- I don't know. Where do you come from?
- From Margellina.
- Margellina, wanna come or not?
- Wanna get lost?
- Get lost, I don't want to see you anymore!
- Why, what are you doing?
Mister, please, where's the war?
I don't know, it's a moving war:
now's here, then is there.
Let's go!
They are getting out!
Forward. Ready.
Please, go away!
There's nothing to see. Please,
don't stay here!
Don't shoot! Listen to me!
The major says that if you don't surrender
they'll shoot the hostages.
They'd shoot innocents.
What have we done to you?
We're all innocents here,
and we're making war!
- Tell your Nazi friend...
- What friend?
Those are bastards! But even you,
try to understand!
There's no need to surrender
just go one by one.
Tell him to give up, he and all his men.
The Neapolitans inside make war
as we do on the outside.
Arnaldo!
Arnaldo! Oh, my God! Arnaldo!
What have they done to you, my love?
They've killed him!
A truck's coming out. There are some
of ours to.
Professor, they're ready to get out,
with hostages covering them.
Captain, the Germans are getting
out with a truck.
They're hiding behind ours.
- Shoot all the same.
- No, no don't shoot. - Let me go!
- There are our loved ones in there.
- If you shoot, we'll get in front.
Shoot the tires!
Shoot! Shoot!
Vicenzo, what have they done to you?
The Captain is an assassin!
Stop shooting.
- Why do I get only half a biscuit?
- You're smaller, and less hungry.
- The kid woke up!
- All to the war!
Don't you drink? We only had one hour
of water, and where were you?
- I was at war!
- And these, where are you taking them?
- We are the army Giovanni
Ajello! - And who's this Ajello?
Keep your hands down!
These are our prisoners.
Alright, they're yours, but can I
kick them in the butt?
But only one.
Let it go, they are prisoners of war.
Enough! Leave them alone!
Let's get back at t he queue.
- Move it, get back in the line.
- I was first.
- I'll say who's first and who's not.
- When's water coming?
Soon. Tomorrow, or after tomorrow,
the latest.
I've killed him.
Holy Virgin I've killed him!
Who'd have thought that today I'll
have killed a man?
I've never killed a fly, and now I've
killed a German.
How many Neapolitans will have to die!
A hundred, they say. Don't cry.
For 100 dead Neapolitans,
we want 1000 Germans dead.
Christ, shouldn't we move?
We've been pulling it for 4 hours!
I'm dying, I can't make it anymore.
- Push! - Come on! - Push!
- Come, lazy! - Pull!
What are you doing, walking around at
this hour with this gun?
They're shooting at you!
Where are you taking it?
- Salutami "a soreta"!
- Incredible!
- Forward, with all our strength!
- What strength?
- Come here.
- Who's in charge?
- The Lieutenant. - After, when we'll
shoot. Now, I'm giving orders.
You pull here, you push here
and you there!
Pull! Pull! Let's go!
Pull! Pull!
Who knows if these are thunders
or bombs.
Make me laugh. Complaining about the
filth.
They have only to call the sweepers
and they'll take everything away.
For shelled house you need
more than a broom.
I like you. Do you have kids?
- No. - It's a sin. You must.
- Are you joking? With a beautiful
girl like her...! - Professor!
The lady is not my wife. She' married
to an honourable person!
With an accountant's degree and
a knight's cross on his chest.
Don't torment yourself.
Think only that we're together and that
if it wasn't for this mess...
Ah, I got it. Then, we should
thank the Germans?
Please, make way.
Let us through.
We got Germans, open!
Will you open or what?
- We got Germans.
- And we're also hungry.
Let's put them in a safe place, boys.
We're going in now, but then we'll go out!
Come on, get in! It's fine inside.
- They're safe in my cell.
- Yours?! Have you bought it?
Let's pretend it's mine.
Mine and the warden's.
Because only him and me don't ever
had any house!
You give it to them.
I have a house and from the bog
you can see the sea.
Fine nostalgia to have when
we're eating!
- You have even taken this kid.
- He's name is Cazzillo.
- Where's your home?
- In Margellina.
- It's a nice house and from the bog...
- Another pants shitter.
Always in mother's lap.
Now I'm all alone. There's no one
at home. Not even mother.
- These are the last potatoes.
- And tomorrow?
We're leaving! We have a war to make!
It's worse for you,
hidden inside here.
Forward, shoot, courage!
The grenades. Quickly, bring the
grenades!
- Cazzillo, come with us!
- No, he's staying here, at shelter!
No, not like this!
Pull the tab.
Not like this! Ajello!
- What are we doing now?
- Take the stretcher.
We must take him to the hospital.
Careful, don't hurt him.
- Let's hurry! - Yes!
- Put a hand under the head.
What's with this handkerchief?
Let's do like the Red Cross,
they'll let us through like this.
Stop! Dead can wait.
What dead? We're still alive.
Help me. Easy, easy...
I can't take you all!
But where should we go?
Don't you get there's no place?
Doctor, this the warden,
he must be treated!
- There. Still here?
- You have no heart!
Isn't this one a German? - Yes,
look at his boots. - A soldier.
- What's he doin' here? - With all the
young men dying in the street!
- Doctor! - There are not enough beds
even for the Italians!
- Who knows how many has he killed!
- Enough! - What's happened?
Doctor, we're all Christians,
you must save him also.
- That's why we're losing the war!
- We're not making it to kill.
Ajello. Stop.
Listen. You've been in war,
are you satisfied?
Now go back to the institute,
there at least you'll be safe.
And maybe you'll even find some potatoes.
Why are you worrying?! Don't think about it,
try to get well.
I have to tell you something, especially
to you, who are the oldest.
Take him to his mother.
Cazzillo, let them be, they're rogues.
You're too small. Have you seen how
easy it is to die?
Let them be. Do you promise me that?
Make way, kids.
Warden, don't worry, we'll come see you.
- Yes, when you'll be better.
- You'll come visit you, warden!
- Who knows where he's hiding.
Have you seen a child? - No.
This high. I've been looking for
him since yesterday.
- I'm sorry.
- This way.
Cazzillo, move it!
- Have you seen a child? He's name is
Pasqualino. - No, I'm sorry.
I've been all around Naples.
Do you know who children are?
Everyone a pain in the heart.
What days have these been!
How many were there?
Three? I don't know night for
day anymore.
What are you doing?
They're not coming from there!
Stop!
Go back the other way!
- No, we must go forward!
- Who told you so?
Logic did!
We must block the passageway!
Wherever they go, we shoot them!
- Help him up.
- Thanks.
- Where are the Germans coming from?
- From there!
They surely aren't afraid
to get down!
Silence, keep quiet!
Who's the imbecile who told you
the Germans are coming from there?
The tanks are coming
from the back!
The gun's here!
What are you waiting for?
Fire.
You must fix the cannon! You, come here!
Stay covered, or we'll die before
shooting. Take cover.
Come on, charge it!
If the baby's born,
they'll be able to tell it:
..."When you were born there were more
cannon shots than a royal baby."
Sorry, gentlemen,
is this the war?
Have you seen a boy here?
He's name is Ajello.
I don't know! What are you doing
with that machine-gun? Give it to me!
- No, it's mine! I found it!
Give to me! - Go!
- What are you doing here?
- Go away!
- Run! Help us!
- Run and help us!
Go!
- Don't bother with me.
Leave me here. - Let's put Jim here
Easy.
After, when all will be over, do me
a favour.
But after, when it's all over.
Take me to Sorrento.
Because my son is born.
Don't think about it.
I'll be back soon.
Follow me!
- Will you give me my riffle back?
- This is nowhere you should be!
- I've already been at war!
- Who, you?! Are you leaving or not?
- I've fought with Ajello's army, I swear!
- Enough!
Don't shoot, it's a kid.
Stop.
No, please! Don't shoot,
stop! Don't shoot.
- They've killed him. - How can you
do such a thing?
Let's burn everything.
We're all giants.
Now, we're all giants.
What do you want to do?
It's only us!
Let's go!
- Who are you? - Fighters defending
the city of Naples.
- Who is the moron that shot?
- Masullo, from Bagnoli. Come!
- What do you want?
- Let me see you!
- What are you doing with the Germans?
- The officer is our hostage.
Who gave you the car?
Why are you still in uniform?
- Do you know we could kill you?
- Let it be!
You want to know where we're coming from?
From Vommero.
With this officer we're trying to obtain
the surrender of the Germans...
...and the liberation of the
Naples hostages.
- How do we know you're telling the truth?
- I! And you... Go.
- You're responsible for every lost minute!
- I?
You can go, but the German
hostage stays here!
- I'll go with you.
- It's better like this
The pistol!
Take it, Maria.
Captain, if the Germans harm you,
we'll kill this one!
Let's go! Hurry up!
I can only deal with an official,
not with him.
It's one of those bandits
that have fallen in our back.
These bandits have owned their dignity
by fighting.
That's why he's making the conditions.
Come, your turn to speak.
I?! And what should I say?
Make him understand we don't like wars.
It's enough they go away...
All in all, they must leave!
Are you married, German?
Do you love your wife?
Yes, I've got a wife and children.
Two.
12 and 8 years.
- What names!
- It's not their names, it's their age.
I'd like to know if he thinks
about his wife.
Did you understand?
You miss your children.
If you never missed them.
What was it?
Silence.
- Ours?
- No! - Yes-- No!
- Tanks!
- The Germans!
- The Germans are leaving!
- Look they've surrendered!
Yes, the Germans are running!
We've made it!
Look, ours are seeing them by,
they're taking them out of Naples!
- Remember Naples!
- Don't come here again!
Well done! Take them far away!
Go away!
Come, let's make them go.
- We'll let them live this time!
Go! - Make way!
- Take it, railway man.
- It's alright. Let's go, Maria.
- CAPITANO! - Ma tu lo conosci!
Come si chiama?
I think he never told us his name.
I don't know, he was the Captain.
Don't cry.
Carmine, come here.
I can't leave you for one moment.
- Here, ma'am.
- Honey! My baby!
Stay close to me, yes?