( ♪ Man singing in African language )
( ♪ Drums beating )
(Narrator) 'A hundred years ago,
Africa was a vast, dark unknown.
'Only a few explorers and missionaries,
'the ivory hunters
and the infamous slave raiders
'risked their lives on its
blood-soaked trails.
'Gleaming tusks were the prize
and sweating slaves,
'sold by their own kings and chiefs
in the ceaseless tribal wars,
'or seized by slavers.
'The lion and the leopard hunted
savagely among the huge herds of game.
'And man, lacking
the will to understand other men,
'became like the beasts,
and their way of life was his.'
(Birds squawking)
( ♪ Men singing in African language )
(Man) Bring up the rear!
(Crickets chirping)
( ♪ Men chanting )
(Flies buzzing)
(Bird squawking)
I've got a feeling about this safari.
We're going to make a killing.
Well, let's hope so.
I've been thinking.
After this, I'd like to go
into the slave trade.
(Chuckles)
Very lucrative. Very, very lucrative.
Should go well with ivory.
Want to become a partner?
No, thanks.
This is my last time out. After
this, I'm settling on my farm.
(Shouts in native language)
Suit yourself, laddie,
but you're missing a big chance.
Ah, well, that happens.
(Shouts in native language)
(Native language)
( ♪ African singing )
You don't want that, they're friendly.
Let's keep it that way.
(Native language)
What's he saying?
Where's that interpreter?
We don't need him. I happen
to know this dialect.
(Native language)
- What do they want?
- Oh, the usual thing. Gifts for their chief.
(Native language)
No, stay there! I'm not
giving them anything.
What the hell for? Who
says they own this land?
They've been here for generations.
Long enough to call it their own.
Anyway, it's customary and wise.
Let's get this understood. I'm
financing this safari and I'm...
And I'm managing it.
That was the agreement.
Now, don't let's argue in front of them.
You can manage it, but you're
not giving my money away.
I paid for those goods
to be traded for ivory,
not to be given as handouts to every beggar
who turns up on a jungle path.
Listen to me, it's not worth it. For
a few trinkets, they'll let us alone.
Otherwise, they can give us a bad time.
It's not worth it.
It's the principle of it! You give it
to one, and they'll come from miles around.
I know these chaps,
I've dealt with them before.
You're not the only one.
Let's get moving.
Don't be a bloody fool! You're
endangering the whole safari.
Get out of my way!
(Native language)
(Animal screeches)
(Trumpeting)
- (Gunshot)
- (Wailing)
(Trumpeting)
(Gunshot)
(Gunshots)
(Trumpeting)
(Fusillade of gunshots)
(Vultures squawk)
Did you see that brain shot
I made on that big bull?
Ha-ha! Running, too!
Let everybody eat
after they've cleaned one tusk.
Right, sir.
At an angle!
I got fourteen of them. Not bad, huh?
- How many did you get?
- We're not in a contest.
Eleven.
That's how many, laddie.
Eleven to my fourteen.
All of mine were carrying ivory.
What is that supposed to mean?
That mine weren't?
Exactly. Five of them weren't
worth the gunpowder.
What the hell?
So I shot some of them for sport.
(Chuckles)
Have another drink.
Not for me. I think
we've both had enough.
We've got quite a few miles
to cover today.
Look, friend, you're
managing the safari, not me.
- I'll have another.
- (Animals squawking)
♪ Drink to me only... ♪
- Will you shut up?
- (Distant animal calls)
(Squawking and screeching)
(Various animal calls)
(Whistles)
(War cries)
(Gunshots)
Stop them over there!
(Shouting and whistling)
(Women ululating)
(Native language)
(Cheering)
(Drums beating)
(Whispering)
(Cheers)
(Drumming stops)
(Native language)
(Cheering)
(Crowd grows quiet)
(Cheering and beating drums)
(Native language)
(Speaks native language and chuckles)
(Cheering)
(Crowd grows quiet)
(Drums beating)
(Laughing and jeering)
(Horns blowing)
(Shouting and horns blowing)
(Women ululating)
(Drums beating)
(Man screams)
(Crowd gasps)
(Crowd cheers)
(Whistling and cheering)
(All cheer)
(Speaks native language)
(Men jeering and shouting)
(Panting)
(Groans)
(Agonised screams)
(Panting and groaning)
(Insects buzzing)
(Squawking)
(Bird squawks)
(Native language)
(Agonised scream)
(Sighs heavily)
(Grunting)
(Snarling)
(Screeching and growling)
(Leopard growls softly)
(Squawking)
(Excited chattering)
( ♪ Singing in native language )
(Animals screeching)
(Growling softly)
(Growls)
( ♪ Chanting in native language )
(Speaking native language)
(Elephants trumpeting)
(Gasps and shouts)
(Sneezes)
(Native language)
(Growling)
(Distant drums beating)
(Hollow beat)
(Shouting and cheering)
(Whooping)
(Distant whooping)
(Whistling)
(Groans)
(Agonised groans)
(Grunting)
(Weeping)
(Shouting in native language)
(Whooping war cries)
(Whooping cries)
(Shouts)
(Screaming)
(Laughing)
(Raucous laughter)
Hey! Hey, you bastards!
Hey, you devils! Hey!
(Laughing)
Hey, you devils! Burn! Burn!
Burn! Burn, you devils!
Burn, burn! Burn, you devils!
( ♪ Whistling )
(Elephant trumpeting)
(Laboured breathing)
(Mosquito buzzing)
Oh, my God.
(Sighs heavily)
(Birds chirping)
(Groans)
(Stomach gurgles)
(Gurgling)
(Grunts)
(Groans)
(Coughing and retching)
(Roars)
(Men speaking native language)
(Angry shouting)
(Groans)
(Shouts in native language)
(Snake rattles)
(Hissing)
(Cawing)
(Roars)
(Vulture shrieking)
(Grunts)
(Screeching)
(Screams)
(Groans)
(Groaning)
(Burps)
(Gasps)
(Laughs)
(Heavy breathing)
(Speaking native language)
(Angry shouting)
( ♪ People singing in distance )
( ♪ Singing and clapping )
(Speaks native language)
(Animal bleating)
(Grunts)
(Goats bleating)
(Gun cocking)
(Shouting in foreign language)
(Gunshots)
(Screaming)
(Shouting and screaming)
(Screams)
(Baby cries)
(Bawling)
(Rustling)
(Fire crackling)
(Screaming and shouting)
(Men shouting)
(Whispers)
(Grunts)
(Groans)
(Men shouting)
(Water rushing)
( ♪ Singing lament )
(Crying)
(Retches)
(Coughing)
( ♪ Singing in native language )
(Exclaims in native language)
(Speaks Swahili)
(Speaks Sesotho)
(Speaks Zulu)
(Speaks native language)
(Laughing)
(Sniffing) Hmm?
(Native language)
Mmm. Mmm, mmm.
Mmm. Yum-yum.
Ah?
A-ha!
- Zavoudi.
- Huh?
Zavoudi.
Zavoudi?
Ah, zavoudi.
( ♪ Girl sings in native language )
(Hissing)
( ♪ Singing continues )
(Screeching and hissing)
(Man) ♪ Oh, how I love thee
♪ Ha, ha, ha! You and me
♪ Little brown jug, how I love thee
♪ Ho, ho, ho! You and me
♪ Ha, ha, ha! You and me
♪ Little brown jug, how I love thee
♪ La, la, la, la, la! In-de-man-zooma
♪ La, la, la, la, la! In-dia-marenga
( ♪ Girl mimics song )
♪ Little brown jug, hoo-hi-la-di!
♪ Ho, ho, ho! Yu-na-mi
♪ Little brown jug, hu-hi-la-di!
(Laughs)
Well, that's very... uh, zav...
Zavoudi!
Zavoudi! Ha-ha!
Well...
Here. This is for my little singer.
♪ Yo, ho, ho! You and me
♪ Little brown jug, how I love thee
♪ Ho, ho, ho! You and me
♪ Little brown jug, how I love thee...
( ♪ Hums melody )
Zavoudi.
Oh, you want to go home.
Uh...
Mm-hm. I hope you'll be all right.
Here, I have a present for you.
Zavoudi.
Zavoudi!
(Sighs heavily)
(Men shouting)
(Whooping)
(Bird shrieks)
(Groans)
(Gunshots)
(Fusillade of gunshots)
(Screams)
(Distant shouting)
(Officer) Number One Company!
( ♪ Bugler plays fanfare )
(Speaks in native language)
( ♪ African singing )