♪ Fairy tales can come true ♪
♪ It can happen to you ♪
♪ If you're young at heart ♪
♪ For it's hard you will find ♪
♪ To be narrow of mind ♪
♪ If you're young at heart ♪
♪ You can go to extremes ♪
♪ With impossible schemes ♪
♪ You can laugh ♪
♪ When your dreams
fall apart at the seams ♪
♪ And life gets more exciting
with each passing day ♪
♪ And love is either
in your heart ♪
♪ Or on its way ♪
♪ Don't you know ♪
♪ That it's worth
every treasure on earth ♪
♪ To be young at head? ♪
♪ For as rich as you are ♪
♪ It's much better by far ♪
♪ To be young at heart ♪
♪ And if you should survive
to a hundred and five ♪
♪ Look at all you'll derive
out of being alive ♪
♪ And here is the best part ♪
♪ You have a head start ♪
♪ If you are among
the very young at heart ♪
♪ And if you should survive ♪
♪ To a hundred and five ♪
♪ Look at all you'll derive
out of being alive ♪
♪ And here is the best part ♪
♪ You have a head start ♪
♪ If you are among
the very young... ♪
♪ At heart ♪
Hiya, Howard.
Allie! Sheez.
How are you?
What are you doing here?
Why didn't you tell me you were coming?
I just thought I'd drop in on you.
God, that's so funny
because, you know...
I was just thinking about you the
other day. I saw your show on TV.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah, what I had to do
to get to these clowns
to turn off the ball game.
This is Alfred Miller. He's my friend.
He's a big TV writer.
This is Margo, the big waitress.
How are you?
Pleased to meet you.
Listen, I thought maybe
before the dinner rush,
we could take a walk, play a
little chess or something.
Sure. Marg?
Can you take over the register?
Sure, Howard.
I mean, unless you're too busy.
For you? Are you kidding?
It's good to see you.
Yeah, you too.
Hey, Howard.
Yeah?
What's the price on the
Kid Gavilan-Basilio fight?
It's eight-to-five, Gavilan.
I'll take Basilio, five times.
Okay, you got it.
You never change.
It's your move.
Howard, I can't work anymore.
Yeah? What, like writer's block?
No.
Well, what?
You're not sick, are you?
I'm blacklisted.
Yeah, all right,
but you feel okay?
I feel terrible.
But you're healthy?
I mean, besides your ulcer?
Howard, they won't buy my scripts.
I'm on a blacklist. Do you
know what that means?
It's a list of names.
The studios have them,
the networks, the ad agencies.
You're on the list, you're
marked. You don't work.
So, what difference does
it make if I'm healthy?
Well, you know,
it makes a difference.
So, what are you blacklisted for?
I'm a communist sympathizer.
Well, you always were.
Well, it's not so popular anymore.
Hey, how many times
have I told you?
Take care of number one.
So, all right, who can you sue?
Nobody.
Nobody admits there's a blacklist.
I mean, they just say,
"Your script's not good enough."
"You're not right for the assignment."
You know, that kind of thing.
Hey, I know some people.
They're not exactly
"people," but for $50,
they'll break a few legs, and
you're not bothered anymore.
That's not what I need.
What, you need money?
I happen to know a stock, believe
it or not, which is low right now,
but it's going through the roof.
I need another name.
Yeah, I can see that.
Um... Rappaport.
Al... Alfred Rappa...
Arnold Rappaport.
Pseudonyms don't work. They know
we're all changing our names.
I need a real person, Howard.
Oh...
Of course.
Someone, uh, they can
believe and I can trust.
Naturally.
Now, listen... I wouldn't
ask you to do this...
Who would you ask?
I'd be insulted.
Well, nobody would know
about it, just you and me.
When do we start? Well,
just wait a minute.
You'd better find out
what you're getting into.
You want to put my name
on your scripts.
It's not that simple.
I write the scripts.
I send them in under your name.
They buy the scripts, right?
It's perfect.
Then they're going to want
to meet the writer.
So?
So you're going to have to go
in there, really be the writer.
So I'll be the writer. What's the big
deal? I can do it, and I want to do it.
I'm your friend. You're in trouble.
What's a friend for?
Well, these days, you can get
in trouble being friends.
Life is risk.
I'm going to pay you
for this, Howard.
What do you mean, "pay"? What
is that, a friend takes money?
10% from each script,
and no arguments.
You can use the money.
You're always in hock,
and I'd be paying that much
to an agent anyway.
Ten percent?
Off the top.
Well, how much
do you get for a script?
Um, $750, $1000.
It depends on the show.
Go home and write.
Your troubles are over.
What are you pulling here? Huh? You
owe me for three winners already.
What am I? Some kind of charity?
Don't get excited. Your money's coming.
You book bets, you lose,
you pay off.
What? You don't trust me?
You know...
Hey, don't get me mad
on you, you hear, Howard?
We've been doing business a long
time, so don't get me mad on you.
I don't understand you.
What do you do with your salary?
Flush it down the toilet?
No, I had a tip on a stock.
It looked good, so I plunged.
To who do you come to stocks?
Why don't you ask me?
I'm familiar with the market.
Ask me before you flush your
salary down the toilet.
All right, next time, I'll ask you.
Howard, Howard... what's
it going to be with you?
Mama and Papa would turn
in their graves.
I haven't found myself yet, you know,
but it's all going to change, Myer.
You were always the smart one.
Did I get the lessons?
You could've gone to college.
Instead, you're a bum.
How much this time?
Uh... $600.
You said on the phone 400.
Yeah, I know.
Four gets me even, then I'm blank.
I'm keeping strict accounts.
You said four, you get four.
Enough is enough.
I'm at the end of my rope, Howard.
I got a business.
You know what it costs now
to feed one lousy mink?
You know what a cutter gets today?
Yeah, thanks, thanks for...
If you were realizing your potential,
I'd say, "Fine, that's an investment."
I'm working on it, Myer.
At that cockamamie job you got? You call
that a job? With a head like yours?
I think you're going to be surprised.
I'm serious. The well is running dry.
Sink or swim.
$500.
The winner, number three, Mr. Turf
ridden by William Boland.
3-60 and 2-90.
The place horse,
number six, Stepchild
The show horse, number 70,
Easy Whirl.
Belmont Park
are a service of WTRM.
Each race...
Loews Sheraton.
Well, who wants him?
Who? Florence Barrett?
What do you look like?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah. This is... That's right.
This is Howard Prince, the writer.
No kidding. Did you?
Yeah, you liked it?
Sure. No, I can meet...
When... afternoons are fine.
You know, I use the evenings to
write because there's less noise.
Okay, great. Tuesday's perfect.
Right. Ciao.
Yes, Old Gold,
the cigarette with
nearly 200 years
of tobacco know-how.
Uh, Florence Barrett?
The one with the hair.
I won't tell him, Phil. You're the
producer. Do your own dirty work.
All Hecky has to do
is go talk to the man.
Why should he? Who is this creep anyway?
Just because he worked for the FBI?
Where does he come off
clearing anyone?
Where does anyone come off?
It's for Hecky's own good.
What's good about it?
I'm against the whole rotten...
I'm against it too.
Then do something.
I don't run the network.
Can I help you?
I'm Howard Prince.
Who?
You're Howard Prince? Hello.
I'm Florence Barrett.
I'm so glad you could come. Phil,
this is Howard Prince, the writer.
Phil Sussman, our producer.
How do you do?
Sorry, I didn't connect
the name. Howard Prince.
That's a hell of a script you wrote.
Where've you been hiding?
We looked you up: no credits, no nothing,
out of the blue, just like that.
Well, I just took up writing
a short while ago.
Well, that's one hell of a script.
You got more?
Are you kidding?
Howard Prince, I'd like you to meet Steve
Parks, who plays the lead in the show.
It's a marvelous script.
Thank you very much.
And Hecky Brown...
Who plays with himself.
who plays the narrator.
Howie! Howie Prince!
They let you out, finally.
Darling, darling...
Darling, I've waited for you.
I was faithful to you.
It's been so long.
You know each other?
Never saw this man
before in my life.
Seriously, Mr. Prince,
a first-class script.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you very much.
We don't have too
much time, Mr. Prince.
That's why I asked you
to come right away.
We wanted to meet you...
Your script's a little long, Howard.
Four-and-a-half minutes.
I'd like to suggest
cutting the kitchen scene. I don't
know how you feel about that...
I think it's a mistake.
To me, the awkward scene
is the one in the police station.
Don't you think?
Yeah, maybe. Maybe not.
You know, it depends
on your definition of awkward.
Well, the police station at
least has some violence.
I'm not saying eliminate it. I
just think it can be trimmed.
What do you think, Mr. Prince?
What?
Yeah.
"Yeah," what?
You know, I think that, um...
I think that what...
There's a lot of facets here, you know,
and it's... I don't want to just answer
right off the top of my head,
you know,
because I don't think that would be
fair to you or fair to the show.
Howard, I know it's not fun to cut your
script, but television is television.
You decide and you cut.
I'm not the kind of producer
who disembowels a writer's script.
I believe in the written word.
Absolutely.
I need it tomorrow morning.
But you be happy with it.
I really liked your script a lot.
Oh, yeah? Thank you very much.
Most of the stuff I read...
I mean, yours had substance.
It was about people.
Well, I feel if you're going
to write about human beings,
that, uh, you may as
well make them people.
Freedom Information Service.
Who's calling? One moment, please.
Mr. Hampton from the network.
Hennessy.
Yes, Tom.
Yes, of course.
Uh, first name: Howard.
You got an address on him?
Social Security number?
I'll check him right out.
No, it's no trouble at all, Tom.
That's what you're paying me for.
Yes, as a matter of fact,
he's right here right now.
I'm sure we'll work something out.
I'll get back to you as soon
as I know anything about Prince.
You too, Tom.
Carry on.
Sorry, Mr. Brown.
Hecky. Everybody calls me Hecky.
I'm a household name.
I can't guarantee you
anything, you understand,
but if you tell me the truth,
I might be able to help.
I'll tell you the truth.
I'll do anything.
The question is, Mr. Brown,
what have you done?
Nothing. I'm an actor.
Nothing?
Six years ago, I marched
in the May Day parade.
I bought a subscription
for the Daily Worker,
but I never read it, not one word. Right
from the mailbox to the garbage can.
I was only trying to get laid. This girl,
this communist girl, she had a big ass...
I am not interested in
your sex life, Mr. Brown.
Hecky. I was just telling you
that girl was the reason.
Was she also the reason you signed
a petition for Loyalist Spain?
Did I do that?
And Russian war relief?
We were on the same side,
weren't we?
That girl with the big ass,
she was the reason. Honestly.
Would you say, then,
that you were duped?
Tell me what it means
and I'll say it.
You want it in writing?
Tell me what to write.
It has to come from you, Mr. Brown.
Hecky.
From your heart.
It has no value otherwise.
It'll come. Don't worry.
I'm an actor.
What do I know about politics?
My whole life has been acting.
People from all over the
country write me letters.
Write me a letter, Mr. Brown,
in your own words.
How you were duped, how
you feel about it now.
I'm against it 100%.
Whoever else you remember
was in that parade.
Who asked you to sign
those petitions.
It was such a long time ago.
Try to remember.
Sincerity is the key, Mr. Brown.
Anyone can make a mistake.
The man who repents sincerely...
I repent sincerely.
Write me the letter, Mr. Brown.
I'll see what I can do.
And I didn't even get laid.
Now, stand by, everybody.
We have 30 seconds to air.
Can I see opening shots, please?
Camera one.
Fine. Two's good.
Three, frame up, please.
Tilt up.
That's it. It looks good.
Watch your boom.
All right, stand by
to dim the lights...
And, uh, okay...
Dim them down.
Looks nice.
Ten...
nine... eight... seven...
six... five... four...
three... two... one.
And fade up on three.
This is my station, Grand Central,
where a million stories
start and finish.
And Hecky the Hackie
knows them all.
Tonight, have I got
a story for you.
Remember last week you laughed a lot?
Well, tonight, you may cry a little.
See for yourself on Grand Central.
Me?
I'll go make up with my cab.
See you later.
♪ A-doo doo, dee dee dee... ♪
Joey.
Joey?
Pop...
Pa, it's only $4000.
Why, it's almost nothing.
I can pay you back
in a couple of years.
Looks nice.
And ready to go in.
Right in... Tight close-up.
Stand by to go to black.
30 seconds to credit.
Studio 12.
Yes.
Thank you. I thought so too.
It was terrific. Thank you.
Who was it?
Studio 12.
God.
Hello.
Well, thank you.
Yes, thank you very much.
Um, yes, I'll tell everybody.
Well, I think we got a winner.
Studio 12.
Hey, Howard Prince!
Bravo! Bravo!
Bravo!
I usually don't drink wine at lunch.
It makes me sleepy.
Yeah? So why don't you
just take a nap after?
I have to work.
Well, then, you know, I think...
I think we should go out
on a Sunday night.
I think it'd be better.
But you don't like Sunday,
so what about Saturday?
What about Friday? Regular night?
Howard, I really ought to
tell you. I'm involved.
I don't understand.
What is that, are you married?
No, but involved.
So what?
I mean, you telling me
that you're one of those
"one guy at a time" people?
Yeah? Okay.
Here's what I say to you...
we go out, don't bring him along.
Right?
Okay, so what does he do?
What, is he a writer?
What, a musician? What?
Stockbroker.
A stockbroker?
Well, that's interesting.
You know...
He's very nice.
Yeah, I was not knocking it, you know,
because you do what you can do.
You know, I... I got to ask you.
Did you see my new script?
Marvelous.
It's even better than the last one.
Well, you should see the next one.
It's very exciting for me to
watch a new talent emerging.
May I ask you a personal question?
Sure, feel free.
Why did you start writing so late?
Well... Because,
in order to write...
Excuse me. You got to get
experience, and you got to live,
and life is experience... So I had
to, you know, get that experience.
Well, here in the city?
You do come from here, don't you?
Yeah, I come from here, but
I bummed around a lot.
I was a boxer and a seaman, and all
that stuff you got to be to write.
What, you don't believe me?
Well, should I?
No, but I did bum around a lot.
What about you?
Not a lot.
No, I didn't mean it that way,
you know.
Where are you from?
Connecticut.
That's... That's very ritzy.
It's very proper, anyway...
I was very well-bred.
We're the kind of family where the
biggest sin was to raise your voice.
Oh, yeah? In my family, the
biggest sin was to buy retail.
Well, do you guys laugh a lot?
Who?
You know, you and the stockbroker.
Yes.
Thank you.
The character of the girl
in your script...
You write about women so well,
with such understanding.
Hey, uh...
This is all a la carte.
So, what about tomorrow night?
I'd have to tell him.
I don't know if I'm ready for that.
Come on. So you go out with me
once, and then you'll know better.
What? What are you laughing at?
You're so unexpected.
Well, I didn't expect you, either.
You call yourself a writer?
Modern American writing started
with Huckleberry Finn, dummy.
It did?
Hemingway said that.
How about Hemingway?
You're low on the moderns... Faulkner,
Sherwood Anderson, Fitzgerald.
All right, give me... give me
two Hemingways and a Faulkner.
Faulkner. Hemingway, Heming...
There we are.
The Russians...
Brothers Karamazov
No more Dostoyevsky?
What else you got?
Diary of a Writer.
Oh, yeah?
I can use that.
Remember, Howard, you
got to pay for these.
No credit.
Don't worry.
Listen, Danny,
I got hit very hard last week.
Long shots come in like relatives.
Well... Well, soon.
Soon is soon.
Tomorrow, the day after.
Wha... Danny,
what are you mad about?
It's a promise. Trust me.
Come on, Myer.
Jesus, I'm still an unknown.
What am I talking about? Five thousand,
probably. You're making as much as I am.
That's how much you know.
Where's taxes and agents?
I got to buy books and paper...
Money goes through you like Epsom salts.
You're a sick individual.
I'll pay you back.
I just sold another script.
Don't play me for a sucker, Howard.
A man earns and he still borrows?
First you pay back what you owe.
My dad's in the study.
You want a drink?
Me? No, thanks.
You look tired.
Yeah, this was a tough one.
Shit, they're all tough.
But it turned out good, I think.
Yeah? You really work hard, don't you?
It's a terrible thing, that blacklist.
You know, you having to work like this.
I always work like this.
To work.
I was thinking, there must be a lot
of writers who are blacklisted.
So how do they get along?
Why?
I don't know.
You know, it must be hard.
Yeah, it's hard.
You know, it's funny.
I got them so snowed.
I mean, two writers
wouldn't be any harder than one.
Oh, yeah? You think not?
What do you have to know?
It's a cinch.
Why not three?
Yeah, even three.
10% each.
Well, I don't know.
I could do three for 25%.
Well, I wouldn't want you
to feel cheated.
All right, make it 10% each.
Oh. What's the matter?
You don't think that's fair?
Oh, no, I think it's a bargain.
Hey, I got the time.
You know writers who need help.
I'm willing to help.
Oh, cut the crap, Howard.
Why? I'm running around every
place. I got to take taxis.
You know, I got to
keep up appearances.
You want the money.
Come on, I'm offering a deal.
What, are you
some kind of romantic?
You know, that's the trouble with leftos.
You got a thing about money.
You want the deal?
I want it, but I know you.
You're going to take off and
fly right up your own ass.
I'm willing to help.
Take advantage.
All I can say, Howard, is thanks.
Yeah, it's no trouble.
I'm a Communist, Howard. I want you
to know that right off the bat.
The Committee asked me,
I took the Fifth.
It's none of their business,
but I'm telling you.
It's none of my business.
Well, I think you should know
who you're fronting for.
I don't have to know.
They're trying to sell
the Cold War, Howard.
They're using the blacklist
against anyone who won't buy.
Herb, he doesn't need a lecture.
I'll send you some pamphlets.
I'll break your arm. Leave him alone.
He knows who he's mixed up with.
Who's mixed up?
What Herb means is we're not blacklisted
because we're kind to dumb animals
or because somebody lied
about us or made a mistake.
I know, you're out of work.
That's all I have to know.
What about taxes? That's
going to be a problem.
You need a deductible?
Take my advice... natural gas.
Yeah? I heard cattle.
Cattle is also good.
Filet of sole. Vegetable cutlet.
Mushroom omelet.
Protose steak.
Eat in good health.
All right, the network pays him,
he pays us, less the 10%, right?
Then we just pay all
the taxes that we owe.
Nothing illegal. No tricks. Everybody
declares exactly what he earned.
What's he paying us for? He's
got to put something down.
We're his collaborators.
If anyone reads the returns,
connects him with us...
Can't we protect him better?
The IRS isn't going to care as
long as the right tax is paid.
The FBI will, and they've
been looking at tax returns.
Only in political cases.
He's not political.
You guys kill me.
They're beating your brains out,
and you're worried about taxes?
We're worried about you.
Don't worry about me, okay?
Just write the script.
I'll take care of my end.
Five pounds, sweetheart.
Have a nice day.
Cash?
Three hundred?
Howard, have an orange.
Thanks, Uncle Howard.
Thank you, Uncle Howard.
Thank you, Howard.
But I'm Harry Stone, the actor.
The other Harry Stone, the
director, he's the one you want.
I'm blacklisted because
they think I'm him.
I understand.
I never joined anything.
A terrible mistake has been made.
I sympathize.
Unfortunately, I can only help people
willing to make a clean breast
of what they've done.
But I haven't done anything.
That's why I can't help you.
Mr. Hampton from the network.
Thank you. Yes, Torn?
Yes, I've got a report
on Howard Prince.
No, no proof he's a
member of the Party.
Of course, no proof that he isn't.
I suggest I keep investigating.
Well, no, I don't have to.
I can send you a bill right
now and forget about it.
You're the one who has to
answer to the American people.
Exactly. That's all I'm saying.
You can't be too careful
these days.
No, I don't suppose anyone can
object if you keep using him.
Nothing to object to...
So far. Thank you.
You can use him.
Thank God.
He's the best writer I've got.
Hell, he's the only writer I've got.
I don't know how he does it.
What about Hecky Brown?
He wrote the letter.
It wasn't good enough.
It's not my decision, Phil.
They tell me, I tell you.
What do I tell Hecky?
You decided he's not
right for the part.
You've changed the character.
You've fired actors before.
Tell him what you told them.
He'll know it's not true.
Can he prove it?
I should get back to the office.
Well, why? What's the rush?
You're having a script conference.
That takes time.
Then we ought to talk
about the script.
Oh, later. Come on.
Hey, what's the matter?
You're the only writer I know who
never wants to talk about his work.
I'm superstitious.
No, you're not.
Yeah, I am.
The way I see it, you're
either a writer or a talker.
You're genuinely modest.
I admire that.
What... What...
Do you like sports?
I'm embarrassing you.
No. Do you... I'm serious.
What do you think of sports?
I like swimming.
No, swimming's not a sport.
Swimming's what you do
so you shouldn't drown,
you know, and sport is
what you play with a ball.
I used to play basketball, in school.
You played basketball?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah?
You'd be interested maybe in
playing one-on-one sometime?
Or, you know, if you ever
want to lay a bet, I'm...
Jesus, forget that.
Hey, you know, I'm...
You know, I'm...
I'm not just a writer.
I mean, I...
I want you to, uh...
I want you to know...
I know.
You know?
How I feel about you.
That's what you know?
I don't have to know anything more.
It's first-class.
You know, I've never seen
an account like yours.
Up and down, up and down.
One week a big deposit, the next week...
If you don't mind my asking,
what does a man like you do?
Uh, futures.
Oh.
Mr. Delaney?
Federal Bureau of Investigation.
We'd like to talk to you.
I've got nothing to say to you.
We thought you might
be ready to cooperate.
Nobody has to know.
See you again, Mr. Delaney.
Keep walking.
You're here!
He's here!
We've been trying all over.
Thank God.
What's the matter?
I said I'd bring it to you today.
Forget that one.
What do you mean, forget it?
I said, forget it. You've
got to rewrite the old one.
What old one?
The one with the flashbacks
to the concentration camp.
You said that was great.
It's beautiful.
Well, Florence said she cried.
The scenes in the
gas chamber, I cried.
So then what, then?
The sponsor won't approve it.
You found him.
First, they said yes. Now they say no.
Right when we're in the middle
of dress rehearsal.
You want to know why?
They're a gas company.
They decided the show
makes gas look bad.
I think we'll make it a firing squad.
They killed Jews that way too.
Leave it to Howard. He's the writer.
What is the excitement?
They want changes, you know,
make it a firing squad.
You've got to write new scenes.
I'll go home and write them.
You don't have time.
I'll take a cab.
No, you don't realize. Time is
of the essence. Look at us.
We're stuck here! They're waiting
upstairs for the rewrite...
the network, the sponsor. They
don't approve, there is no show!
They can't wait till tonight?
They want it now.
I'm supposed to keep
you here till it's done.
No, I can't write except in my room.
We got a good office for you.
I guarantee you will not be disturbed.
No, no, no. I don't get inspired.
It doesn't have to be
inspired, only changed.
There really isn't
that much writing, Howard.
We have to be careful not
to lose the emotion.
Don't bother him with details.
He's got a lot of work to do.
Come on in.
Now, clear your mind and write.
Quiet, children. Quiet.
Boys and girls, we have a very special
visitor to our assembly today.
Not long ago, he sat
in the same seats
you're sitting in now. But
because he worked hard,
and studied hard,
he is now a famous
television writer.
Hecky, um...
I don't know how to say
this, but I'm worried.
I'm not the only one. Upstairs too.
Worried about what?
Here, Sussman, take a pickle.
No, no.
The show is a smash.
Yeah, well so far.
So far, so good.
I got to look ahead, Hecky.
Your quality, I don't know,
the character's not working.
I made up the character.
You loved it.
First impression was tremendous.
Don't get me wrong.
You think so too?
It's not her decision.
What decision?
I think you're wonderful,
Hecky, so does everyone else.
No one denies your talent.
It's...
Your personality is too dominant.
You belong out front,
like Berle, in one.
In a dramatic series, you're
throwing the whole show off balance.
Who says?
A talent like yours needs room.
You know what you need, Hecky? You need a
show of your own, where you can dominate.
As a matter of fact,
I got a few ideas.
We'll make some time, get
together, and kick them around.
Is it the letter?
Absolutely not.
I wrote what that snake
asked me to write!
Wouldn't I tell you?
The problem is artistic.
Female of the species.
No, I think you have to
safely say that Grand Central
is one of the few television shows
where the writer is really the star.
Yeah, but there's, you know, there
is a lot of other people too.
You know, I mean wonderful people.
I certainly understand
the importance of actors and
then, of course, directors.
Did you write in high school?
Did I write in high school?
Yeah, you had to.
It was Brooklyn. Is that correct?
It was formerly Brooklyn.
Oh, Hecky!
You know, I went around and I...
But the television form
is so different.
Oh, you know it.
Yeah.
And you're so terrific at it.
Well, you know, I didn't say it.
I wrote what you asked.
I was duped.
I didn't know what I was doing.
I'll never do it again.
What more can I say?
That's up to you.
I have to work. I can't
get work, Mr. Hennessy.
The doors are closed in my face.
My own agent, 30 years, he won't
even answer my telephone calls.
I appreciate your situation.
I do, Mr. Brown.
I've helped people
in your situation.
Then help me, please.
Tell me.
I'll turn myself inside out.
I'll do everything you tell me to do.
You make that difficult to believe.
What else can I do?
I'll do it, believe me.
You don't know
what I'm going through.
I'd like to believe you, but I have the
feeling you're not being entirely frank.
Give me a "for instance."
You'll see. I promise.
You marched in a May Day parade.
Only because of that girl with the big ass.
Whose name you say you can't remember.
Oh, what was her name?
Tessie? Bessie? I wasn't
interested in her name.
I was interested in her body.
Other people marched in that
parade, other actors, directors.
You don't remember their names
either?
I'm terrible with names.
They remember you.
I'm a well-known personality.
You talked with these people?
Some of them.
Some were kind enough to write letters.
Then you know who they are.
So it's not so important that I
remember. You know already.
Your sincerity is important,
your desire to cooperate fully.
I told you what I did!
I apologized!
I come to you on my hands
and knees, Mr. Hennessy.
Please. All I want to do is work.
That's all I care about.
I have a wife...
Two growing boys.
Children.
Look.
Here.
Plus a wife from before. If
the alimony doesn't come...
I sold my car last week for peanuts.
A brand-new model.
All the money I made, I ask
myself, where did it go so fast?
I can't pay the rent, Mr. Hennessy.
Nothing can go out
if it doesn't come in.
Do you know Howard Prince?
I was on the show.
A big talent.
Big.
Do you know him personally?
Only from the show.
Once in a while, a bite
to eat afterwards.
Do you think you could
get to know him better?
I'm not good at that sort of thing.
Honestly.
Actors, inside, you'd be
surprised, are very shy.
He knows you already.
You're very likable.
I'm sure he feels sympathy for you.
What could I find out?
Who his friends are.
What he does in his spare time. Where
he stands on the issues of the day.
Can't you ask him that yourself?
If he were a part of the Communist
conspiracy, could we believe what he said?
And if he isn't?
We'd like you to help us find out.
You want me to spy
on Howard Prince?
We are in a war, Mr. Brown,
against a ruthless and tricky enemy
who will stop at nothing to
destroy our way of life.
To be a spy on the side
of freedom is an honor.
And if I spy on Howard Prince,
I can work?
I don't do the hiring, Mr. Brown.
I only advise about Americanism.
But in my opinion, as the sign of a
true patriot, it would certainly help.
I quit.
Quit, quit, finished.
Resigned... Quit.
Let Sussman do his own dirty work.
I won't be part of it.
No more, not anymore. Finished watching
people destroyed, crucified like Hecky.
I'm going to fight it.
I don't understand. What
are you talking about?
Howard, this is beautiful.
You quit your job?
I feel so relieved.
You have no idea.
I've been such a hypocrite to take
their money and keep my mouth shut.
I still don't understand.
You quit your job?
They count on our silence, you know.
People keeping quiet, afraid to speak up.
Do you know what I'm going to do?
Publish a newspaper.
Well, anyway, a pamphlet...
Facts About Blacklists.
Do you like the title? I've
been on the phone all morning.
People are dying to talk, as
long as I don't use their names.
Oh, Howard, we'll shake them up. I'll do
the legwork and you'll do the writing.
Hey, not so fast. Jesus.
Florence,
you're making a big mistake.
I believe in personal responsibility,
Howard. If you believe, act.
Oh, but I don't under... You're
throwing away a whole career.
You... You... You could...
You're a terrific script editor.
You could be a producer. You'd be the
first woman producer of a dramatic series.
If I keep my mouth shut.
So? That's not such
a terrible idea sometimes.
But that's what they're counting on.
Florence, do me a favor.
Please, sit down. Sit down.
Relax, will you?
You're going off the deep end. Jesus,
let me give you some champagne.
I'm serious, Howard.
What do you mean you're serious?
You come bursting in here, you're
ready to start a revolution.
For God's sake, Florence,
what are you trying to do?
I want us to fight them,
not get bought off.
I'm not mad at anybody.
We live in the world, Howard.
No, you live in the
world, I live right here.
Hey, come on, what are
you trying to do to me?
You know how long it took me to get here?
I like it here. I like what I'm doing.
For the first time in my life,
I got everything that I want.
I'm not trying to take
it away from you.
No, but that's
what's going to happen.
Howard, I'm only talking
about a simple commitment.
I didn't ask you to marry me.
Oh, Jesus, you know,
we got such a terrific relationship
going. So why do you want to spoil it?
A relationship isn't only sex, you know.
There are more important aspects.
I know there are. Like what?
Human rights.
What about my rights? I'm human.
What happened to my rights all of
a sudden? I live here, it's clean...
Come on, what are you
putting me on the spot for?
You really want success, don't you?
So, what should I want, a disease?
Yes, I want success.
What's wrong with that?
More than anything else?
Florence, you're looking to get
me killed here. I'm a writer.
I'm not looking for any kind of trouble.
I don't want to make waves.
A writer looks for trouble.
No. Wrong.
A lunatic looks for trouble.
Florence, you're crazy. You're behaving
crazy. You're out of your mind.
You've already said that. There's really
no need in your repeating yourself.
I want you to go in to Sussman tomorrow,
and tell him that you made a mistake.
I should tell him?
Exactly. You should go in and tell him
that you're sorry and you should...
But I'm not sorry.
Florence, I don't think you know
exactly what's good for you.
But I do know when
I've made a mistake,
and I made this kind of a mistake before,
confusing the artist with the man.
I just want you to know
I still admire the artist.
You're going?
Yes.
I have a this club date in the mountains.
I thought maybe you could drive me.
Sure, you couldn't have
called me at a better time.
You know, when you work as hard as I
do, you've got to make time to relax.
Otherwise it's all work
and no play.
I guess you have a lot of friends.
Me? The usual.
I like to pick up a phone,
get out, have a little fun,
but the important thing is that you've
got to get right back to basics.
What do you like to do
in your spare time?
The usual.
The usual?
I used to love the usual,
but my ship has sailed.
Watch your step around this place.
The broads up here, take a look
at them, and you say to yourself,
"Where's this been all my life?" They
come at you from all directions.
It's like shooting fish in a barrel.
Later on, you find out you're the fish.
Yeah, well, don't worry about me.
Don't make any promises.
These broads come up
here with their lawyers.
Yeah? You play these places much?
Until I got in TV.
Do you know what I used
to get for one night?
What?
Three grand.
That should come in handy now.
Do you know what I'm getting tonight?
What?
500.
Five...
That doesn't seem fair.
And where is it written
it should be fair?
Come on, Howie, you must have some
friends in the same position.
Hecky! It's a pleasure.
How long? A year? Two years?
It's a pleasure having you back.
Likewise. I'd like you to meet my friend,
Howard Prince, the great and famous writer.
Pleasure, Howard.
Any friend of Hecky's.
Come on, we'll go inside,
have a little drink.
I never drink before a show.
We'll have a little talk.
How's everything?
Oh, it's Hecky Brown!
Would you please park my
car for me? Thank you.
You staying long?
Just the weekend. You too?
What do you do?
I'm a... a writer.
A writer.
You'll have a drink, Howard?
Sure.
Here we go.
To a giant of the
entertainment world.
Business looks good, Sam.
Full up.
Loss leaders. We give discounts
so the rooms won't stay empty.
To tell you the truth, we're
not even holding our own.
The upkeep, which comes
to what I want to mention.
The $500. I already accepted, Sam.
I don't need your song and dance.
250.
You promised five.
I was hoping five.
I figured I'd steal a little from
the band, from the dance team,
make it up that way, but
you know the unions.
They could shut me down.
You knew this when you said five.
I was still hoping.
Last year I played this
joint for how much?
All right, today is not like last
year, but I'm still Hecky Brown.
Don't you forget that. You
can't get Hecky Brown for 250.
Maybe 300...
Out of my own pocket.
I piss on your 300!
Who else is offering that much?
Don't be foolish. Face facts.
There's a cloud over your head.
If it was up to me personally,
I'd pay you the moon,
but business is business. Now,
you drove all the way up here.
You want to go home empty?
Take the 250.
You said 300.
I'll see what I can do.
♪ I need to be funny ♪
♪ Like some need cocaine ♪
♪ In a club
In a show ♪
♪ And the john in the train ♪
♪ When I enter, I entertain ♪
♪ Doing anything for a laugh ♪
♪ A laugh, a laugh ♪
♪ A laugh ♪
♪ Anything for a laugh ♪
You were great.
You were really great.
Let's stop this pretense. Room 904.
Isn't he fantastic?
I could watch him every night.
He's so hilarious.
You a guest here?
Yeah.
What do you do?
I'm a dentist.
Professionally?
I'm Sandy.
Herman. Herman Miller.
You have your own practice?
Yes, I do, but I got to get another guy
in with me, because it's getting too big.
Are you, by any chance, attached?
Only to my work.
Hecky, Hecky, what can I say.
I'm a well-known gynecologist.
Words fail me. One of
the great performances.
You can tell your children,
your grandchildren,
you saw one of the all-time
greats without peer.
Beautiful.
250.
I did what I could.
But you said 300.
Maybe next month.
Out of your own pocket.
By popular demand.
What comes out of your pocket?
Tell me.
Hecky, will you stop?
Hecky, stop.
Tell me what's inside here.
Hecky, don't tickle me.
Hecky, will you stop being so...
Appreciation? Sympathy?
Hecky, Hecky...
What comes out of your pockets?
You know what comes out
of your pockets?
Blood! Blood comes
out of your pocket!
Get him out of here! Blood!
Get this crazy...
I want to kill you, you son of a...
I want to...
Get him out!
Get him out of here!
Out! Out!
Get him out! Get him out!
I want to...
Get him out of here!
You fat pig.
You'll never work again!
I'm Hecky Brown!
You'll crawl in the gutter,
you red bastard!
You commie son of a bitch!
Come on.
Give me that.
Hey. Here's what I want you to do.
I want you to sleep
on the sofa tonight,
because you'll find it's
extremely comfortable.
It's brand-new.
You're going to like this.
See? Just stay here...
And, uh, open the window...
Let me make you some coffee, okay?
It's all Brownstein's fault.
I wouldn't be in this trouble
if it wasn't for Brownstein.
Yeah, who?
Brownstein.
Hershel Brownstein.
Who's Hershel Brownstein?
You can't make a deal with him.
That's the trouble.
He won't listen to reason.
Is that your real name?
Hershel Brownstein?
Brownstein!
Lay off, you hear me?
Lay off or I'll kill you!
Jesus, you know, people
change their names. It's no crime.
What do you know?
Who the hell are you?
A newcomer.
Why don't you sit down?
Why don't you shut up?
You think you're so special?
Talent is no protection.
You do as they say or else. I'm
going to make you some coffee.
This is a very nice
apartment. Very nice.
Thank you.
You have nice things.
Bookcases, hi-ﬁ...
And nice furniture.
You like this apartment, I bet.
You worked hard for it.
You deserve it.
You'd like to keep
this apartment, right?
You know what we should do?
We should call your wife,
because you should tell her, at
least, where you are tonight.
Where'd you go last week?
Nowhere.
Nowhere is somewhere.
From the heart, please.
No credit unless
it's from the heart.
Here and there, you know.
Like, around and about.
What do you want me to say?
Where'd you go last year?
Year before, who'd you see? Where did
you march? What did you sign?
Nothing.
That girl you go with,
on the show, what's her name?
Florence.
A troublemaker.
I heard her talking.
Subversive. She's a red.
No.
You like that girl?
Yes, I like her.
What's her name?
I told you.
Her full name.
Florence Barrett.
You know she's a red?
Stop it, Hecky.
I don't like this game.
Actually, I think you could say
that modern American fiction
began with Huckleberry Finn.
But what about Melville?
Especially today,
the sense of evil.
Oh, yeah. How could you
leave out Melville?
You must be so excited, the show
going from a half-hour to an hour.
I was expecting it.
With those ratings?
After all, they're
no fools up there.
Do you think you can get
the same quality in an hour?
Well, it is a problem,
no doubt about it.
It's like going from
a short story to a novel,
but one thing I've learned
in this business,
if you've got the talent,
you got the quality.
Ah.
Phil. Howard.
I want you to meet Hubert Jackson.
Jackson Supermarkets, you
know, out on the island.
Congratulations, gentlemen.
Thank you.
Hubert's a great fan of your show.
Never miss it.
Thanks again.
But he's a little concerned about some
of the actors that you've been using.
We go for the best, Mr. Jackson.
Well, in my opinion, some of them
are pretty pink, Mr. Sussman.
That's just the makeup.
I told Hubert that we are
as concerned as he is.
Not that they are,
of course. The actors.
We take every precaution.
The slightest hint.
I know my customers. If they
think a company is sponsoring reds,
they just don't buy their product.
How do they know?
I tell them.
Put a sign right up
over the product.
Yes, I thought you might send Hubert a
list of the actors you plan to use.
Let him look them over,
give you any ideas he has.
Absolutely.
You'll get full cooperation
from us, Hubert.
Nothing to worry about.
Thanks, boys.
How many stores that guy got?
Three, maybe four.
He's got three stores, he tells
a whole network who to hire?
Who wants trouble?
Nice to see you again, Mr. Prince.
Here's your check, Herb.
Thanks.
Here you go, Bill.
And yours didn't come yet, Allie.
What?
Because you were late with the script,
remember? You got to watch that.
Oh, by the way...
Here's your script back.
It needs a rewrite, I'm afraid.
What didn't Sussman like?
Well, I didn't show it to him.
What do you mean,
you didn't show it to him?
It wasn't ready.
Come on, Allie. You know. I can't
hand in anything, you know.
My name's going on that script.
I got a reputation.
Howard.
I'll try to write up to
your standards, Howard.
You know, it's possible
that maybe going to an hour
is a little too much
pressure for you guys,
because I've been noticing the stuff
lately, and it's thin, fellows.
You know what I mean? The key
word, I think, is "substance."
I've been reading what you...
the Eugene O'Neill plays,
and I would like, if possible,
something more along those lines.
But more laughs.
Exactly, you know, but gutsy.
Incidentally, I think... I think
I made a deal for a new series.
Well, we've got our hands
full here, Howard.
So you put on a couple more writers.
I mean, I need a pilot script.
How about Eugene O'Neill?
He's dead, Herb.
What's the subject?
It's a woman reporter, which,
I think, is a great idea.
You know, and I got the perfect
actress to play the part.
Her and a Howard Prince script.
We'll look around for somebody.
Right, but good, Bill, good,
because blacklisted is not enough.
Scrambled eggs, loose.
White fish.
Let's see... Eggplant steak.
Eat in good health.
I'm going to kill you.
I'm going to kill him.
You little rat.
Hey, hey, Al, take it easy, please.
Look, this is ridiculous, because I've
been calling you now for three weeks,
and you don't answer me. Nothing, you
know, and I mean, what's the big deal?
We had a little argument.
We don't think alike, Howard.
We don't believe in
the same things.
Jesus. What, do you think I like
the blacklist? I hate the blacklist.
But you... Did I send
money for your pamphlet?
Giving money is easy.
Oh, yeah, what's easy for you is not
always easy for everybody else.
You know, you see trouble, and
right away you run to get a gun.
Or a pamphlet, you know...
I'm just looking all the time
not to get killed, that's all.
So is that such a big difference?
We have to break up over that?
Yeah, maybe we do.
So, what do you say?
You want to stay broken up?
Howard...
You think I want to make
you lose everything.
You think I'm intolerant and demanding,
and maybe I am, but that's me.
Well, then...
Then I need more time,
because I've never met
anybody like you, you know?
Hey, I tried to get us tickets to
the Paul Robeson concert, you know,
but it happened to come on the same
night as the basketball game, so...
We'll go to a basketball game, right?
I have tickets for the concert.
All right, so here's what...
I'll give up the tickets
to the basketball game,
and you give up the tickets to the
concert, and we'll go to dinner.
Right?
Florence, I miss you.
I miss you too.
So we'll have a date.
A subpoena?
For me?
To appear before the House
Un-American Committee.
Well, what do you mean? When?
How do you know?
They found out upstairs. It hasn't
been issued yet, but any minute now.
But I'm not a communist.
So you go and tell them that.
I tell you. Isn't that enough?
Howard, you've got to go.
I don't like it any more than you do,
but if you don't do it, you don't work.
Why don't they all just go away
and let us do the show?
Who needs this?
You know, Phil...
I didn't believe Florence
when she told me that about you.
That crazy broad.
You know, because I know it was
very tough for you to fire Hecky...
I had a migraine for a week.
Phil, it just takes one guy
to say no to them. Just one.
What can I do, Howie?
You can be that guy.
No, I'm serious. If just
one person says no...
You know, especially a guy like you.
You're respected, you got a big name...
Tell them no.
Who the hell are they?
Come on, Phil, take a stand.
The real you.
Get me Hampton.
Hello, Tom? Phil.
There is no reason Howard Prince
has to go to that committee.
That's right. It's our network.
Who the hell are they, telling
us what to do, giving us orders?
No, no, no. You listen to me.
He doesn't have to go.
What are we, sheep? We make a stand, Tom.
We tell them to lay off his back.
We tell them to stop threatening.
Piss off, or they're in trouble.
We fight, Torn. We show them there
are some people they can't scare.
We tell them flat out,
"Howard Prince doesn't go."
Right.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
You got to go.
Howard, you've got nothing to worry
about. Nothing to worry about at all.
You see, we've dealt
with the committee before,
and they're, well, they're
really very understanding.
They understand our problems
and we understand theirs.
Yeah? And what about my problems?
You're cooperating.
That's all they care about.
Now, this friend of
yours, Alfred Miller?
We went to school together.
And you had no idea
that he was a communist?
He was only 12.
You have no idea now?
We never talk about politics.
Good.
Let's see, now. The two men,
Delaney and Phelps?
They're friends of Allie's.
All right.
And the girl, Florence Barrett?
That's just sex.
Is that why you gave money to
her pro-communist publication?
You know, we were going out, and
she wanted to start a magazine,
so how was I supposed to know what kind?
That's hardly credible, Mr. Prince.
Uh, Mr. Hennessy... You and your
staff have done a splendid job.
The network appreciates your efforts, but
Mr. Prince is being entirely cooperative.
I think that I can handle the legal end.
Thank you very much for coming.
Good luck, Mr. Prince.
Howard, don't mind him.
He's only doing his job.
I still don't see why we can't fix it.
You know, I mean, like pay somebody off,
because how much... how much could it cost?
Because they're just congressman.
It won't be necessary.
You see, they've agreed to an executive
session. No reporters, no publicity.
As a matter of fact, you won't
even have to go to Washington.
They'll send a subcommittee here.
Now, what we'll do is write you a
strong anti-communist statement
to go along with your testimony. You
will be out of there in no time at all.
Take my word for it.
Howard...
Howard, all they want
is a friendly witness.
Okay.
So I'll be a friendly witness.
Hi, Howard.
Is he here?
Hey, very nice.
You got to lay off health foods.
Jesus, when are they going to operate,
get rid of that ulcer already?
Then how am I going
to know when I'm mad?
Nobody knows how
to relax anymore, right?
You got to kind of roll
with the punches.
What about the subpoena?
Nothing.
Don't worry about a thing.
Did they write a statement for you?
Yeah. I'd let you read it, only
you'd start bleeding again.
Don't worry about it, really. You just...
You know, take care of yourself.
Worry about who's going to write
the scripts while you're in here.
We've got a very good writer.
You won't be ashamed.
Blacklisted? Impeccably.
Named by his own brother-in-law.
Visiting hours are over.
Nurse, I'm Dr. Prince.
This is a consultation, you know.
These are my associates.
Uh-huh.
Howard, why do you think
they want you to testify?
I'm a feather in their cap.
I'm a big writer. Howard Prince.
Why do you think they want you to name
names? They've already got our names.
Why do they need you to tell them again?
So it makes them look good. So what?
Howard, they don't care about names. They
care about getting people to give names.
They want to show there's nothing
they can't get people to do.
Fellows, if I don't cooperate,
you don't work. Nobody works.
Is that what you want?
Maybe we're laying too much on him.
Why should he take the rap?
Because I want him to
know what he's doing.
I'm helping.
You're helping them.
No, I'm using them.
I'm... I'm smarter than they are.
Howard, the time
for this bullshit is over.
Who does it hurt if I'm friendly?
Where is the personal crime?
I tell them that you're my
friend from public school.
They... They already got your name.
You said that yourself.
He's right. They can't
do anything more to us.
Why can't he just cooperate?
Tell them the truth?
He won't have to.
The network's made a deal.
He says the committee's
great, they leave him alone.
Yes, and everybody
gets what he wants.
That's what this is about, right? Stop
worrying. You know, they want publicity.
They want Howard Prince as an example
to scare people. To shut them up.
I think he should take the Fifth.
They'll blacklist him, he takes the Fifth.
What's the Fifth?
The Fifth Amendment.
Your right not to incriminate yourself.
Why do I have to take anything?
It's all fixed.
They might ask you questions
you don't want to answer.
But if you already answered
one, like did you know Alfred,
you don't have that right anymore.
Then, if you don't answer,
they can cite you for contempt.
Yeah, but I'm going to answer.
Schmuck.
Maybe he should.
What can he tell them?
I don't trust the committee or
the network. Take the Fifth.
I don't want to take the Fifth.
You can't cooperate!
Don't be a loser all your life.
You quit looking for an out!
Look, do not aggravate yourself.
You want that milk now?
Oh... Howard.
You did a big favor for all of us.
I don't have to tell you that.
Who's asking?
You saved our ass.
Don't you think I know that?
You did what a friend does.
Exactly. If I cooperate,
your ass is saved again.
You can't be on their side.
So, all right, fine. What do I do?
I tell the committee to shove it? So
then, you don't work, nobody works.
You let me worry about that.
Yeah, and what about me? What... What
do I do? Go back to the cash register?
I can't believe this guy.
You're laying here,
you can't use your name, you're bleeding,
and you're telling me what to do?
Al, can we ask him to do
what he doesn't believe in?
Protect yourself. Take the Fifth.
You know, you're always
looking for a middle
you can dance around in. Well, I'm telling
you, this time there isn't any middle,
and you can't lay any of it off on us.
Whatever you do, you're doing for yourself.
Open up in the name of the law!
Get out your guns, men.
Nobody move. This is a raid.
Everybody, everybody out.
We understand you have a girl
in your room. If not, why not?
Do you have a little tootsie for me?
Have we met before?
You know you scared me?
I was in the neighborhood and
suddenly everything went black.
Am I disturbing you?
Are you kidding?
If you really want to know, I came to
apologize for that terrible night.
I wasn't myself.
You had every right.
Two rights don't make a wrong.
I gave you a hard time and I'm sorry.
Silly. Have a drink.
Before the sun is over
the yardarm? Never.
A wee touch of scotch.
How's it going?
Not bad. Club dates.
Out of town, but not bad.
Scranton, Allentown, Altoona.
You didn't know I was a
big hit in Pennsylvania,
but my wife found a job, the kids
eat, we all have our health.
To a prince of a Prince.
You know, I never learned
how to sip a drink.
When I was very little,
every evening before supper,
my father would pour a shot glass
full of whiskey, mumble a prayer...
And down it went. I thought
that was the way you drank.
How are things going with you?
Fine.
I hear terrific.
It's nice when nice happens
to somebody nice.
It doesn't happen too often.
Are you sure I'm not being a nuisance?
Of course not.
Did you know Johnny Parker,
the actor?
Mm-mm.
No.
Blacklisted.
He couldn't get arrested.
Wife, three kids, you can imagine.
He drove a cab for a while.
Finally gave that up.
He came from someplace out west.
Oklahoma, Texas, some place like that.
He owned a little farm that his father left
him. Miserable. He showed me the pictures.
You'd go crazy in a
place like that.
But he could grow his own
food, so he went back.
We had a party for him.
Everybody cried.
Six months later, right in the
middle of that miserable property,
they struck oil!
You're kidding.
Honest to God. Oil!
He's a millionaire.
So you see...
♪ Every little cloud
has got a silver lining ♪
Come on, let me
make you another drink.
No, no, no, not really. I came,
I apologized. It's time to go.
Well, you know, what we should do
is we should have dinner sometime.
I'd like that very much.
Yeah?
Well, what about tonight?
Tonight? No, no, I'm busy.
So, all right, so what I should...
I'll call you.
Don't call us, we'll call you.
If I had a buck for every
time they said that to me
when I first started... Of
course, I don't have to tell you
later on, the shoe was
on the other foot.
Well, I really will call.
I know you will. I was making a joke.
You don't mind I came without phoning?
Come on, are you kidding?
Well, some people mind.
You're a good man.
You know what I think I'll do?
I'll call you tomorrow.
Take care of yourself.
The water is full of sharks.
Thank you, sir.
Where have you been? I was
so worried about you.
I called and there was no answer.
You know, I was just walking around.
Are you all right?
You know, I've been thinking
about a lot of stuff.
Well, I saved you your dinner.
I kept it warm for you.
Do you want a drink?
Yeah, but just a drink.
I saw you at the funeral today.
You did?
I didn't see you.
Well, I couldn't handle it.
I couldn't handle it either.
You're lucky you're a writer...
and not an actor.
At least with a writer, if he gets
blacklisted, he can always still write.
An actor, what's he going to
do if he can't show his face?
Florence...
How would you feel if I was...
if I was not a writer?
Howard, I know you. Whatever
else you might have to do
to survive,
you'll find time to write.
Well, but suppose
I said that, uh...
that I was not a writer.
I know you as a writer.
I love you.
Well...
I'm not a writer.
Don't be a defeatist.
Other guys wrote those scripts, not me.
I put my name on them.
They were blacklisted. I was helping
them out. It's my name and their scripts.
That's a very bizarre statement.
I'm not a writer, Florence.
I'm a front.
I front for blacklisted writers.
You're not a writer?
No. I... I... I couldn't
write a grocery list.
You never wrote
any of those scripts?
Nothing. Not one. I'm... I...
I'm practically illiterate.
You never wrote anything?
Hey... Jesus.
Don't get shell-shocked.
I'm not confessing to a murder.
Look at you.
Look, you're all white.
Let me get you a drink.
I don't want a drink.
You know, you should put your
head between your legs, I think.
You let me think that you were...
Well, why not?
What did you want me to do?
For God's sake, I was like a spy.
Did you want to?
Did I want to? Of course I wanted to.
You think I liked lying to you?
Come on, Florence, you know
that lying is not in my nature.
I don't believe this is happening.
I have to testify. Try and
keep your mind on that.
But it's like you're a complete stranger.
So we got off on the wrong foot.
The wrong foot?
I was sworn to secrecy.
For God's sake,
we're on the same side.
Didn't you trust me?
I wasn't allowed.
Well, did you think I'd
lose interest in you?
You were never interested in me.
You were in love with a writer.
Interested in you?
I don't even know you.
You know, I shouldn't have said anything
because now you're totally hysterical.
Nobody is hysterical. When
were you going to mention it?
When we were 90?
I mentioned it tonight.
Because you're in trouble.
Yes, I'm in trouble, for a very good
reason. Who was I spying for, Hitler?
I was helping blacklisted writers.
Think about that for a minute.
You lied to me.
What are you really, a druggist?
You want to know what I was?
I ran a cash register.
You were a cashier?
That's exactly what I mean.
See?
Unless it's a writer or an artist, you
know, catch you in bed with a cashier...
That's not fair.
You wouldn't have
looked twice at me.
It is not what someone does,
it is who he is.
And you don't even know who I am.
Did you ever give me the chance?
I'm giving you right now.
All right.
Who are you?
What?
I still don't know who you are.
I only know who you're not.
Who is Howard Prince?
Hey, Florence, I got to tell you,
you know, it's not easy
being in love with you.
You know why? Because what
you're looking for all the time
is, like, a knight on a horse or
something, which is not Howard Prince.
You know who Howard Prince is?
I'll tell you.
Howard Prince is his own man.
What does that mean?
Well, I think you're going
to find out when I come back
from the committee tomorrow.
What am I going to find?
You said it was all fixed.
Well, I've been thinking about it.
You know, everybody's
telling me what to do.
But, you know,
I don't see why I have to.
What are you going to do?
Well, I'll work something out.
Are you going to tell them
that you're not a writer?
I'm going to tell them exactly
what I want to tell them.
Howard, that committee
is dangerous.
They're out for blood.
You can't fool around.
Take my word for it. All those people,
Allie and Sussman and everything,
they're wrong, because I
can beat that committee,
and I can beat them my own way.
How?
Hey, what's the difference?
I'm telling you,
I'm not going to wind up
back at that cash register.
Take my word for it. And I'm not going to
do anything that makes you ashamed of me.
Trust me. Can you trust me?
And we would like
to thank this committee
for allowing Mr. Prince to
appear and voice his approval
of the great work that you're
doing for our country.
Communist subversion
is a real and present danger,
and you can rest assured that
it will never be tolerated
on the network that both Mr. Prince
and I have the honor to represent.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Thank you, sir.
This committee is here to help keep America
just as pure as we possibly can make it.
Well, I can't think
of anything more important.
Well, I would like to commend this
committee on the job that they're doing.
Thank you.
Counsel...
Just a few questions, Mr. Prince.
We know you're a busy man.
Mr. Prince, do you happen
to know an Alfred Miller?
Who?
Alfred Miller.
Why?
If you'd just tell the committee...
So I can't know why?
Mr. Prince,
you don't have to worry.
Anyone that comes here and tells the
truth has got nothing to worry about.
Which Alfred Miller?
Do you know Alfred Miller,
the writer?
Uh, when you say "know," uh... you know,
can you ever really know a person?
I think, you know... I grew up with
an Alfred Miller, but do I know him?
Would you say, do I know him? Can you
know... In a biblical sense, know him?
Am I right?
Would that be the same
Alfred Miller
you met with several times
in Hammer's Dairy Restaurant?
Who says I did?
Is it or is it not true?
No, I asked you first.
Is it true?
I don't understand. Is anybody
accusing me of anything?
If you would answer the question...
Which question?
You asked one question. I answered
that question, and then...
Do you know Alfred Miller?
You already asked that question.
Howard, what are you doing?
What do you mean?
I'm handling it. Don't worry.
You're under oath.
If you don't answer, they
can hold you for contempt.
Well, I am answering. I'm just
not replying, that's all.
Oh, don't split hairs.
But they can only get me
if I don't answer.
If I answer without
replying, I got them.
But you're getting them mad.
So what? What can
they do, throw me out?
Do you know Alfred Miller?
Hey, are you guys aware of
the fact that every week,
busloads of communists are
coming in over the border?
I mean, is anybody doing
anything about that?
We are not concerned at this
time with anything other
than the communist conspiracy
in the entertainment world.
But how come? Why aren't we
doing something about it?
I mean, why isn't everybody armed? You
know, everybody should learn to use a gun.
I think it's a big mistake that
anyone who goes to military school...
You send them there
when they're bad.
Mr. Prince, this committee
is just as concerned
about the threat of
communism as you are.
Since your memory is unclear
about Alfred Miller,
do you know any of
these other people?
William Phelps...
Herbert Delaney...
Florence Barrett...
Hershel Brownstein,
also known as Hecky Brown?
He's dead.
Did you know him?
Mr. Prince...
Now, you came here to
cooperate today, did you not?
Will you excuse us a moment,
Mr. Prince?
John.
I thought we had an arrangement.
With the network. I think
he's doing this by himself.
Why don't we hit him with contempt?
He's not giving us grounds.
We can't let him get away with this.
He hasn't even taken an amendment.
There's got to be something
you can nail him on.
Okay.
Mr. Prince, let me ask
you another question.
Do you know a Patrick Callahan?
Who?
Bartender at the Friendly Tavern,
where, I believe, you once
worked as a night cashier.
I did?
Do you know Daniel LaGattuta?
Doesn't he sell fruit?
You placed bets for Mr. Callahan
and Mr. LaGattuta, did you not?
In... In a... In a
strictly friendly way.
I remind you that placing
bets is a crime.
Howard, is this true?
You were a bookmaker?
Not professionally.
Oh, my God.
Uh, Mr. Chairman, may I have
a word with you, please?
They're willing to make a deal.
Give them names, right?
They're being very reasonable. You
don't have to give them more than one.
Yeah, which one?
Well, it's up to you.
Look, they've got you over a barrel.
You can go to jail. What's one name?
If it bothers you,
give them Hecky Brown.
Hecky?
He's dead anyway.
What difference does it make?
A token is all they want. Something
to show your cooperation, that's all.
Is the witness ready to proceed?
Yes, ready, Mr. Chairman.
Mr. Prince, I ask you,
for the record,
did you know Hershel Brownstein?
Howard, you'll go to jail.
Also known as Hecky Brown?
Be practical.
Did you know this man as
either Brown or Brownstein?
Either name will do, Mr. Prince.
Tell them.
Brown or Brownstein?
Just the name.
Are you refusing to answer?
Will you talk?
Fellows...
I don't recognize the
right of this committee
to ask me these kind of questions.
And, furthermore, you can
all go fuck yourselves.
♪ Fairy tales can come true ♪
♪ It can happen to you ♪
♪ If you're young at heart ♪
♪ For it's hard, you will find ♪
♪ To be narrow of mind ♪
♪ If you're young at heart ♪
♪ You can go to extremes
with impossible schemes ♪
♪ You can laugh when your dreams
fall apart at the seams ♪
♪ And life gets more exciting
with each passing day ♪
♪ And love is either
in your heart ♪
♪ Or on its way ♪
♪ Don't you know that it's worth
every treasure on earth ♪
♪ To be young at head? ♪
♪ For as rich as you are ♪
♪ it's much better by far ♪
♪ To be young at heart ♪
♪ And if you should survive
to a hundred and five ♪
♪ Look at all you'll derive
out of being alive ♪
♪ And here is the best part ♪
♪ You have a head start ♪
♪ If you are among
the very young at heart ♪
♪ And if you should survive
to a hundred and five ♪
♪ Look at all you'll derive
out of being alive ♪
♪ And here is the best part ♪
♪ You have a head start ♪
♪ If you are among
the very young... ♪
♪ At heart ♪