1
00:02:03,560 --> 00:02:05,599
I'm really sorry.

2
00:02:05,640 --> 00:02:07,639
Does he wear glasses or contact lenses?

3
00:02:09,080 --> 00:02:10,319
Glasses.

4
00:02:28,120 --> 00:02:30,039
You'll have to hurry up.

5
00:02:44,680 --> 00:02:48,639
He decided that his brown leather shoes were the best pair to wear.

6
00:02:49,320 --> 00:02:52,439
His back hurt a little but not like some other times in the past

7
00:02:52,480 --> 00:02:54,399
when the pain was intolerable.

8
00:02:58,160 --> 00:03:01,159
He was thinking his wife didn't love him at all any more.

9
00:03:02,680 --> 00:03:06,839
He didn't burst into tears and he didn't think that the first thing most people do

10
00:03:06,880 --> 00:03:10,159
when they realise someone doesn't love them anymore is cry.

11
00:03:14,680 --> 00:03:17,759
Sir, do you mind taking a look into the camera here for me?

12
00:03:19,720 --> 00:03:21,639
That'll do. Thank you.

13
00:03:26,080 --> 00:03:28,559
Have you ever been on your own before?

14
00:03:28,600 --> 00:03:30,639
No, never.

15
00:03:30,680 --> 00:03:32,199
Are you allergic to any foods?

16
00:03:32,240 --> 00:03:33,519
No.

17
00:03:33,560 --> 00:03:35,959
Your last relationship lasted how many years?

18
00:03:36,000 --> 00:03:37,719
Around 12.

19
00:03:37,760 --> 00:03:39,879
Do you remember how long exactly, sir?

20
00:03:39,920 --> 00:03:41,839
11 years and one month.

21
00:03:43,400 --> 00:03:45,319
- Sexual preference?
- Women.

22
00:03:48,080 --> 00:03:51,159
However, I had one homosexual experience in the past,

23
00:03:51,200 --> 00:03:52,799
in college.

24
00:03:53,840 --> 00:03:56,479
Is there a bisexual option available?

25
00:03:56,520 --> 00:03:59,839
No, sir, this option is no longer available since about last summer,

26
00:03:59,880 --> 00:04:01,919
due to several operational problems.

27
00:04:01,960 --> 00:04:05,039
I'm afraid you have to decide right now if you want to be registered

28
00:04:05,080 --> 00:04:06,999
as a homosexual or a heterosexual.

29
00:04:16,520 --> 00:04:19,199
I think I should be registered as a heterosexual.

30
00:04:20,320 --> 00:04:22,239
- Any children, sir?
- No.

31
00:04:22,280 --> 00:04:23,639
And the dog?

32
00:04:23,680 --> 00:04:26,519
My brother. He was here a couple of years ago but he didn't make it.

33
00:04:26,560 --> 00:04:28,439
You might remember him:

34
00:04:28,480 --> 00:04:31,239
medium build, 48 years old, bald patch, blond hair.

35
00:04:31,280 --> 00:04:33,399
I'm afraid not, sir.

36
00:04:35,160 --> 00:04:39,399
Ok, I would like you to write your name clearly on this form in capital letters.

37
00:04:39,440 --> 00:04:41,359
And sign it, please.

38
00:04:46,520 --> 00:04:48,439
That will do. Thank you very much.

39
00:04:49,760 --> 00:04:53,479
Ok, so you are not allowed to use the volleyball or tennis courts.

40
00:04:53,520 --> 00:04:55,439
These are only for the couples.

41
00:04:55,480 --> 00:04:59,519
You can use facilities for individual sports, such as squash and golf.

42
00:04:59,560 --> 00:05:03,039
You can stay at the hotel for up to 45 days.
You'll be staying in a single room.

43
00:05:03,080 --> 00:05:06,359
If everything goes well and you make it, you'll be moved to a double room.

44
00:05:24,400 --> 00:05:27,279
I'm afraid you cannot keep any of your personal belongings.

45
00:05:27,880 --> 00:05:29,479
We will provide everything you need.

46
00:05:29,520 --> 00:05:32,959
As far as garments, accessories and shoes are concerned.

47
00:05:33,840 --> 00:05:35,759
- You can keep this.
- Thank you.

48
00:05:36,280 --> 00:05:37,719
Shoe size, please?

49
00:05:37,760 --> 00:05:39,479
Forty-four and a half.

50
00:05:39,520 --> 00:05:42,159
Forty-four of forty-five?
There are no half sizes.

51
00:05:43,520 --> 00:05:45,079
Forty-five.

52
00:06:00,200 --> 00:06:02,999
If you need a haircut, call reception one day ahead.

53
00:06:03,040 --> 00:06:04,679
Smoking is not allowed.

54
00:06:04,720 --> 00:06:08,319
That way you'll be able to run for longer during the hunt without getting tired

55
00:06:08,360 --> 00:06:10,519
and your breath won't smell when you kiss.

56
00:06:10,560 --> 00:06:12,479
Enjoy your stay.

57
00:06:14,960 --> 00:06:17,279
Excuse me, if we need to get a haircut,

58
00:06:17,320 --> 00:06:19,919
we must call the reception the day before, is that right?

59
00:06:19,960 --> 00:06:21,639
- That's right.
- Great.

60
00:06:31,400 --> 00:06:33,679
His room number was 101.

61
00:06:36,680 --> 00:06:39,799
A tranquiliser gun was hanging on the wall above his bed.

62
00:06:42,760 --> 00:06:47,559
On the table were 20 tranquiliser darts, a black plastic watch,

63
00:06:48,120 --> 00:06:51,239
a pair of sunglasses and a cologne for men.

64
00:06:53,760 --> 00:06:57,599
Inside the wardrobe were four identical grey trousers,

65
00:06:57,920 --> 00:07:01,399
four identical button-down shirts in white and blue,

66
00:07:02,120 --> 00:07:05,159
a belt, socks, underwear, a blazer,

67
00:07:05,200 --> 00:07:08,279
a striped tie and a white bathrobe.

68
00:07:15,360 --> 00:07:17,079
He looked out the window.

69
00:07:18,080 --> 00:07:22,159
The unconscious bodies of the captured loners were lying on the wet ground.

70
00:07:23,160 --> 00:07:26,679
"Thank God they wear those waterproof ponchos," he thought.

71
00:07:28,360 --> 00:07:30,279
Room 195.

72
00:07:31,240 --> 00:07:33,159
Two loners, two extra days.

73
00:07:36,760 --> 00:07:38,679
Room 272.

74
00:07:39,640 --> 00:07:41,559
One loner, one extra day.

75
00:07:55,160 --> 00:07:58,919
Hello. I'm the hotel manager and this gentleman is my partner.

76
00:07:58,960 --> 00:08:00,839
We'd like to welcome you.

77
00:08:00,880 --> 00:08:02,119
You're one of the lucky ones.

78
00:08:02,160 --> 00:08:05,279
You have one of our superior rooms, which means you have a view.

79
00:08:05,320 --> 00:08:07,439
- Did you read the leaflet?
- Yes, I did.

80
00:08:07,480 --> 00:08:10,119
Very good. Now the fact that you'll turn into an animal

81
00:08:10,160 --> 00:08:12,959
if you fail to fall in love with someone during your stay here

82
00:08:13,000 --> 00:08:15,639
is not something that should upset you, or get you down.

83
00:08:16,440 --> 00:08:19,959
Just think as an animal you'll have a second chance to find a companion.

84
00:08:20,000 --> 00:08:21,919
But even then, you must be careful.

85
00:08:21,960 --> 00:08:25,519
You need to choose a companion that is a similar type of animal to you.

86
00:08:26,440 --> 00:08:28,999
A wolf and a penguin could never live together,

87
00:08:29,040 --> 00:08:31,039
nor could a camel and a hippopotamus.

88
00:08:31,080 --> 00:08:32,999
That would be absurd.

89
00:08:33,040 --> 00:08:34,599
Think about it.

90
00:08:35,480 --> 00:08:38,799
I understand this discussion is a little unpleasant for you.

91
00:08:38,840 --> 00:08:41,359
But it is my duty to prepare you psychologically,

92
00:08:41,400 --> 00:08:43,039
for all possible outcomes.

93
00:08:43,280 --> 00:08:46,359
Now, have you thought of what animal you'd like to be if you end up alone?

94
00:08:46,400 --> 00:08:49,479
- Yes, a lobster.
- Why a lobster?

95
00:08:49,920 --> 00:08:52,439
Because lobsters live for over 100 years,

96
00:08:53,760 --> 00:08:56,599
are blue-blooded like aristocrats

97
00:08:58,360 --> 00:09:00,839
and stay fertile all their lives.

98
00:09:02,200 --> 00:09:05,599
I also like the sea very much.

99
00:09:06,280 --> 00:09:09,279
I water-ski and swim quite well, since I was a teenager.

100
00:09:10,120 --> 00:09:13,879
I must congratulate you. The first thing most people think of is a dog,

101
00:09:13,920 --> 00:09:15,919
which is why the world is full of dogs.

102
00:09:15,960 --> 00:09:19,359
Very few people choose an unusual animal, which is why they are endangered.

103
00:09:19,400 --> 00:09:21,319
A lobster is an excellent choice.

104
00:09:21,360 --> 00:09:23,279
Could you stand for us, please?

105
00:09:29,200 --> 00:09:31,799
This is to show you how easy life is when there are two of something

106
00:09:31,840 --> 00:09:33,319
rather than just one.

107
00:09:33,360 --> 00:09:35,119
We tend to forget that from time to time.

108
00:09:35,840 --> 00:09:38,599
The handcuff will be removed at the same time tomorrow.

109
00:09:38,640 --> 00:09:41,599
- It's alright, Bob.
- I hope you enjoy your stay with us.

110
00:09:41,640 --> 00:09:42,999
Goodbye.

111
00:09:53,160 --> 00:09:55,079
Have a good day.

112
00:10:45,120 --> 00:10:47,119
Good morning.

113
00:10:47,160 --> 00:10:49,039
Room 101.

114
00:10:49,840 --> 00:10:51,759
44 days left.

115
00:10:51,800 --> 00:10:53,719
Breakfast is served.

116
00:11:00,400 --> 00:11:02,319
Sit where you like.

117
00:11:17,240 --> 00:11:19,799
His first day was one he'd never forget.

118
00:11:23,840 --> 00:11:28,119
Near his table at breakfast sat a young woman with her head tilted back.

119
00:11:28,600 --> 00:11:31,399
Later on he would learn that she often got nosebleeds.

120
00:11:32,480 --> 00:11:34,399
Next to her sat her best friend.

121
00:11:38,320 --> 00:11:40,959
He thanked the waiter who served him his coffee,

122
00:11:41,000 --> 00:11:43,119
and thought about his wife for a moment.

123
00:11:44,920 --> 00:11:47,199
A woman who seemed to like butter biscuits

124
00:11:47,240 --> 00:11:50,999
offered one to a man drinking a Campari and soda for breakfast.

125
00:11:54,120 --> 00:11:56,039
He then looked behind him and saw a woman

126
00:11:56,920 --> 00:11:59,719
who he would later find out was absolutely heartless.

127
00:12:02,920 --> 00:12:04,919
And some others in the couples area,

128
00:12:04,960 --> 00:12:07,639
whom he'd never meet during his stay at the hotel.

129
00:12:11,560 --> 00:12:13,479
That morning, he was really hungry.

130
00:12:14,480 --> 00:12:17,679
He could have eaten a whole chicken but ate almost nothing.

131
00:12:18,880 --> 00:12:20,799
- Hello.
- Hello.

132
00:12:21,760 --> 00:12:24,159
I've decided to go for a walk outside with my new friend.

133
00:12:24,200 --> 00:12:26,199
Let me introduce you. This is Robert.

134
00:12:26,240 --> 00:12:28,719
He stays in the room next to mine and has a lisp.

135
00:12:29,280 --> 00:12:31,919
Pleased to meet you.
I'm staying in room 101.

136
00:12:33,400 --> 00:12:35,879
I'm on the same floor. I'm 186.

137
00:12:35,920 --> 00:12:37,919
- Would you like to join us?
- Why not?

138
00:12:55,840 --> 00:12:58,479
One of these days, it's gonna be me on one of those yachts.

139
00:12:58,520 --> 00:13:00,439
What are those yachts?

140
00:13:00,480 --> 00:13:03,759
It's the final ordeal before letting you go and the hardest one.

141
00:13:04,800 --> 00:13:07,119
15 days of vacation, just a couple, alone.

142
00:13:07,160 --> 00:13:09,479
- Didn't you read the leaflet?
- I did.

143
00:13:12,360 --> 00:13:14,279
Have you seen John's leg?

144
00:13:14,320 --> 00:13:15,759
No.

145
00:13:15,800 --> 00:13:17,959
John, would you show your leg?

146
00:13:21,920 --> 00:13:23,519
Oh, yeah.

147
00:13:28,120 --> 00:13:30,039
Room 187, day two.

148
00:13:34,480 --> 00:13:36,399
Hello, everyone.

149
00:13:38,680 --> 00:13:41,559
My mother was left on her own when my father fell in love with a woman

150
00:13:41,600 --> 00:13:43,519
who was better at math than she was.

151
00:13:45,000 --> 00:13:49,239
She had a postgraduate degree, I think, whereas my mother was only a graduate.

152
00:13:50,440 --> 00:13:52,119
I was 19 at the time.

153
00:13:54,440 --> 00:13:58,359
My mother entered the hotel but didn't make it and was turned into a wolf.

154
00:13:58,400 --> 00:14:00,319
I really missed her.

155
00:14:01,520 --> 00:14:03,439
I found out she'd been moved to a zoo.

156
00:14:03,480 --> 00:14:05,399
I often went there to see her.

157
00:14:06,680 --> 00:14:08,199
I'd give her raw meat.

158
00:14:08,240 --> 00:14:09,999
I knew that wolves liked raw meat,

159
00:14:10,040 --> 00:14:12,679
but I couldn't figure out which of the wolves was my mother,

160
00:14:12,720 --> 00:14:15,079
so I used to give a little bit to each of them.

161
00:14:17,600 --> 00:14:19,919
One day,
I decided to enter the enclosure

162
00:14:21,880 --> 00:14:23,639
I really missed her and I wanted a hug.

163
00:14:24,840 --> 00:14:26,759
I climbed the fence and jumped in.

164
00:14:27,360 --> 00:14:30,279
All the wolves charged at once and attacked me,

165
00:14:30,320 --> 00:14:32,239
all but two, who stood motionless.

166
00:14:33,360 --> 00:14:36,439
My guess is that one of those two must have been my mother.

167
00:14:38,800 --> 00:14:42,319
The zoo guards got to me quite quickly and took me to the hospital.

168
00:14:43,160 --> 00:14:46,119
Thankfully, I didn't lose my leg, I just have this limp,

169
00:14:46,160 --> 00:14:48,479
which is also my defining characteristic.

170
00:14:49,400 --> 00:14:51,319
My wife died six days ago.

171
00:14:52,520 --> 00:14:55,159
She was very beautiful and I loved her very much.

172
00:14:56,280 --> 00:14:58,199
She had a limp too.

173
00:15:01,480 --> 00:15:04,119
Thank you, John.
You can return to your seat now.

174
00:15:13,160 --> 00:15:15,079
Let's move on to our next guest.

175
00:15:15,120 --> 00:15:17,039
Room 104, day two.

176
00:15:24,440 --> 00:15:26,359
Hello, everyone.

177
00:15:27,640 --> 00:15:29,679
This is only my second day here,

178
00:15:29,720 --> 00:15:32,759
but already I feel like a member of a wonderful group.

179
00:15:33,320 --> 00:15:37,559
My defining characteristic is that I have a very beautiful smile.

180
00:15:39,760 --> 00:15:41,759
♪ Something's gotten hold of my heart

181
00:15:53,600 --> 00:15:57,159
♪ Something's gotten hold of my heart

182
00:15:57,440 --> 00:16:02,119
♪ Keeping my soul and my senses apart

183
00:16:02,720 --> 00:16:05,999
♪ Something has gotten into my life

184
00:16:06,040 --> 00:16:07,999
Have you ever danced with anybody?

185
00:16:08,040 --> 00:16:09,439
Sorry?

186
00:16:09,480 --> 00:16:11,399
Have you ever danced with anybody?

187
00:16:11,440 --> 00:16:13,119
Yes.

188
00:16:15,360 --> 00:16:17,279
What sort of dancing did you do?

189
00:16:19,400 --> 00:16:21,319
Just depends on the music.

190
00:16:22,240 --> 00:16:24,159
Do you need to sit down?

191
00:16:24,200 --> 00:16:26,639
- No, no, no, I'm getting ready to dance.
- Ah.

192
00:16:26,680 --> 00:16:30,559
♪ In a time there was peace with no trouble at all

193
00:16:30,600 --> 00:16:32,519
Can I sit here?

194
00:16:32,560 --> 00:16:35,439
♪ But then you came my way

195
00:16:35,480 --> 00:16:36,799
Sorry.

196
00:16:36,840 --> 00:16:39,559
♪ And a feeling inside shook my heart

197
00:16:39,920 --> 00:16:41,839
♪ Made me want you to stay

198
00:16:42,400 --> 00:16:43,879
♪ All of my life

199
00:16:43,920 --> 00:16:46,199
- Can I sit here?
- Of course.

200
00:16:48,800 --> 00:16:50,839
Let me introduce you to my best friend.

201
00:16:53,120 --> 00:16:56,319
That woman you were talking to has no feelings whatsoever.

202
00:16:56,360 --> 00:16:57,959
She feels nothing at all.

203
00:16:58,000 --> 00:17:01,079
She's the best hunter in the hotel, silent and very fast.

204
00:17:01,920 --> 00:17:05,199
She's the women's record holder, 192 captives.

205
00:17:06,160 --> 00:17:10,079
♪ Changing the grey, changing the blue

206
00:17:10,640 --> 00:17:15,999
♪ Scarlet for me, scarlet for you

207
00:17:52,840 --> 00:17:54,759
Would you like to dance?

208
00:17:55,520 --> 00:17:57,439
♪ Every day

209
00:17:58,160 --> 00:18:01,959
♪ You touch me and my mind goes astray

210
00:18:02,360 --> 00:18:06,079
♪ And baby

211
00:18:06,800 --> 00:18:10,919
♪ And baby

212
00:18:10,960 --> 00:18:13,719
♪ Something's gotten hold of my hand

213
00:18:14,560 --> 00:18:18,839
♪ Dragging my soul to a beautiful land

214
00:18:19,560 --> 00:18:22,959
♪ Something's gotten into my life

215
00:18:24,200 --> 00:18:26,319
I'm sorry, I've got blood on your shirt.

216
00:18:26,360 --> 00:18:30,039
But don't worry, there are many ways to remove bloodstains from clothing.

217
00:18:30,080 --> 00:18:33,199
One way is to rinse the clothes with cold water then rub with sea salt.

218
00:18:33,240 --> 00:18:36,479
Another way is to scrub the stains with cotton wool dipped in ammonia.

219
00:18:36,520 --> 00:18:39,599
The third way is to mix flour and water into a paste, like toothpaste,

220
00:18:39,640 --> 00:18:42,479
especially if the clothes are delicate or brightly coloured.

221
00:18:42,520 --> 00:18:44,879
But just never use warm water on blood, ever.

222
00:18:45,720 --> 00:18:47,199
Ok.

223
00:18:48,400 --> 00:18:51,919
♪ But then you, you, you
♪ You

224
00:18:51,960 --> 00:18:53,919
♪ You came my way

225
00:18:53,960 --> 00:18:56,079
♪ But then you came my way

226
00:18:56,120 --> 00:18:58,759
♪ And a feeling I know shook my heart

227
00:18:58,800 --> 00:19:01,359
♪ Made me want you to stay

228
00:19:01,400 --> 00:19:06,159
♪ All of my nights and all of my days

229
00:19:06,200 --> 00:19:09,199
I think I have to rest for a little bit.
My leg's hurting.

230
00:19:09,240 --> 00:19:10,679
That's ok.

231
00:19:10,720 --> 00:19:13,679
Well, let me know when you feel better and we can dance again.

232
00:19:13,720 --> 00:19:16,359
♪ And my senses apart

233
00:19:17,680 --> 00:19:21,479
♪ Something has invaded my night

234
00:19:21,520 --> 00:19:25,279
♪ Painting my sleep with a colour so bright

235
00:19:25,320 --> 00:19:27,239
♪ Changing the grey

236
00:19:27,280 --> 00:19:29,199
♪ Changing the blue

237
00:19:29,640 --> 00:19:31,679
♪ Scarlet for me

238
00:19:32,280 --> 00:19:37,359
♪ Scarlet for you

239
00:19:48,040 --> 00:19:50,719
Leave the building in an orderly fashion.

240
00:19:50,760 --> 00:19:52,679
Do hurry up but please be careful.

241
00:19:52,720 --> 00:19:54,919
Nobody needs to get hurt or injured.

242
00:19:55,720 --> 00:19:57,279
And good luck with the hunt.

243
00:20:04,840 --> 00:20:06,759
I wish I didn't have this limp.

244
00:20:07,920 --> 00:20:10,919
I used to be very good at running but not anymore.

245
00:20:10,960 --> 00:20:13,159
I'm sure I'll be slower than them.

246
00:20:13,200 --> 00:20:17,399
If I were you, I'd think of some tricks that use the element of surprise

247
00:20:17,440 --> 00:20:19,119
instead of speed.

248
00:20:20,120 --> 00:20:22,039
You're right.

249
00:20:22,080 --> 00:20:23,719
That's what I'll do.

250
00:20:30,480 --> 00:20:33,679
Apo Mesa Pethamenos

251
00:23:29,280 --> 00:23:33,199
Room 186. One loner, one extra day.

252
00:23:34,240 --> 00:23:36,599
38 days' stay left, plus one, 39.

253
00:23:38,760 --> 00:23:40,679
Room 180.

254
00:23:41,520 --> 00:23:43,639
The days of your stay remain unchanged.

255
00:23:45,400 --> 00:23:47,319
Room 290.

256
00:23:48,520 --> 00:23:50,439
Four loners, four extra days.

257
00:23:51,760 --> 00:23:56,279
154 days left, plus four, 158.

258
00:23:58,120 --> 00:24:00,039
Room 101.

259
00:24:00,080 --> 00:24:02,199
The days of your stay remain unchanged.

260
00:24:04,760 --> 00:24:06,679
32 days left.

261
00:24:07,320 --> 00:24:09,239
Breakfast is served.

262
00:24:16,560 --> 00:24:18,479
Man eats alone.

263
00:24:38,600 --> 00:24:40,599
How many darts did you use yesterday?

264
00:24:40,640 --> 00:24:41,919
12.

265
00:24:48,000 --> 00:24:50,359
Please take off your trousers and sit on the bed.

266
00:24:51,480 --> 00:24:53,679
Can we not do this today? It's awful.

267
00:24:54,880 --> 00:24:57,439
I know. But I'm afraid we have to do it.

268
00:24:57,840 --> 00:25:00,479
And you have no idea how much it helps you psychologically

269
00:25:00,520 --> 00:25:02,199
in your search for a partner.

270
00:25:02,240 --> 00:25:04,239
Man eats with woman.

271
00:25:27,600 --> 00:25:29,039
Lie down.

272
00:25:31,200 --> 00:25:33,319
Spread your legs. More.

273
00:25:46,400 --> 00:25:49,319
- Is your room number 186?
- Yes, it is.

274
00:25:52,440 --> 00:25:54,799
I imagine you know that masturbation is not permitted

275
00:25:54,840 --> 00:25:57,159
in the rooms or any other area of the hotel.

276
00:25:57,200 --> 00:25:58,599
Yes.

277
00:25:58,640 --> 00:26:02,359
And yet it has brought to my attention that you continue to do it.

278
00:26:14,200 --> 00:26:17,799
Today you became erect quicker than on other days. 
That's good.

279
00:26:17,840 --> 00:26:19,759
Please, just a little longer.

280
00:26:19,800 --> 00:26:21,719
Have a good day.

281
00:26:21,760 --> 00:26:23,959
That's awful. Just awful.

282
00:26:24,000 --> 00:26:26,639
Were you looking at a photograph while you were masturbating?

283
00:26:26,680 --> 00:26:27,799
Yes.

284
00:26:28,360 --> 00:26:30,279
What did the photograph show?

285
00:26:33,080 --> 00:26:35,599
A naked woman on a horse in the country.

286
00:26:36,680 --> 00:26:40,119
If I were in your shoes, I would not be ogling the naked woman but the horse.

287
00:26:40,160 --> 00:26:43,959
I'm sure that the horse was once a weak and cowardly man just like you.

288
00:26:44,000 --> 00:26:45,919
Woman walks alone.

289
00:26:54,960 --> 00:26:56,399
Help.

290
00:26:57,800 --> 00:26:58,839
Help.

291
00:27:00,440 --> 00:27:01,879
Help.

292
00:27:01,920 --> 00:27:03,839
This is not necessary. Please.

293
00:27:05,240 --> 00:27:07,879
- It was an accident. I just got carried away.
- Please.

294
00:27:07,920 --> 00:27:10,679
- This is not necessary.
- Please place your hand in the toaster.

295
00:27:10,720 --> 00:27:12,119
This could be a warning.

296
00:27:13,160 --> 00:27:15,359
Look, I've been good otherwise, I

297
00:27:25,840 --> 00:27:27,759
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Please.

298
00:27:28,680 --> 00:27:31,479
Please, please, that's hurting.

299
00:27:31,520 --> 00:27:33,439
Woman walks with man.

300
00:28:01,360 --> 00:28:03,479
What they do, as soon as you enter the room,

301
00:28:03,520 --> 00:28:06,119
is to wash your body and your head really well.

302
00:28:06,160 --> 00:28:07,999
How do you know?

303
00:28:08,040 --> 00:28:10,399
My uncle used to know a waiter who worked there.

304
00:28:10,440 --> 00:28:12,439
No waiters know about the procedure,

305
00:28:12,480 --> 00:28:14,519
they're not allowed inside that room.

306
00:28:14,560 --> 00:28:16,879
Nevertheless, they peel off the skin,

307
00:28:17,600 --> 00:28:20,159
which has become soft due to the water and the soap.

308
00:28:20,200 --> 00:28:25,839
Afterwards, they remove the heart, the eyes and other vital organs of the body

309
00:28:25,880 --> 00:28:27,639
with a laser or scalpels.

310
00:28:29,040 --> 00:28:32,679
Then the procedure changes according to the animal one has chosen.

311
00:28:32,720 --> 00:28:34,639
That makes total sense.

312
00:28:34,680 --> 00:28:38,039
I mean, I suppose mammals demand a different kind of work

313
00:28:38,080 --> 00:28:40,759
than fowls, for example.

314
00:28:40,800 --> 00:28:42,199
Exactly.

315
00:28:42,240 --> 00:28:44,399
Afterwards they throw the remaining body parts

316
00:28:44,440 --> 00:28:46,599
into the casks outside the hotel's restaurant

317
00:28:46,640 --> 00:28:49,599
and distribute the blood to the hospitals in the city.

318
00:28:49,640 --> 00:28:51,159
Why is that?

319
00:28:51,200 --> 00:28:54,919
The blood is used for surgeries where there are no blood donors available.

320
00:28:59,720 --> 00:29:02,079
- New guests arrived yesterday.
- Yes, I saw.

321
00:29:02,120 --> 00:29:03,799
I think I saw a woman with a limp.

322
00:29:03,840 --> 00:29:05,759
It's just a sprained ankle.

323
00:29:06,800 --> 00:29:08,919
She'll be walking normally again in a few days.

324
00:29:08,960 --> 00:29:10,919
That's a shame.

325
00:29:11,960 --> 00:29:14,239
That is a shame indeed.

326
00:29:18,240 --> 00:29:22,599
One night on the coach, he sat next to the woman who liked butter biscuits.

327
00:29:23,320 --> 00:29:27,079
He gazed out of the window, not looking at anything in particular,

328
00:29:27,120 --> 00:29:29,039
just trying to avoid talking to her.

329
00:29:30,160 --> 00:29:32,439
- How's Bob?
- He's fine.

330
00:29:33,120 --> 00:29:36,559
I'd give anything to go for a walk with you and Bob one afternoon.

331
00:29:37,120 --> 00:29:40,039
The dog's not allowed out of the room, I'm afraid.

332
00:29:40,080 --> 00:29:43,519
"There are some excuses that no one can argue with," he thought.

333
00:29:43,560 --> 00:29:46,959
Some excuses are without doubt better than others.

334
00:29:47,000 --> 00:29:48,919
And that was a really good one.

335
00:29:52,080 --> 00:29:53,999
These biscuits are for Bob.

336
00:29:54,040 --> 00:29:55,240
I want you to give them to him

337
00:29:55,280 --> 00:29:57,319
whenever you want to reward him for something.

338
00:29:57,360 --> 00:29:59,479
- Tell him they're from me.
- Thank you.

339
00:29:59,520 --> 00:30:01,839
Can I come to your room sometime for a chat?

340
00:30:02,960 --> 00:30:05,919
I could give you a blow-job or you could just fuck me.

341
00:30:06,440 --> 00:30:10,079
I always swallow after fellatio and I've got absolutely no problem with anal sex

342
00:30:10,120 --> 00:30:11,439
if that's your thing.

343
00:30:11,480 --> 00:30:14,879
My ex-husband always used to say I had the most beautiful thighs he'd ever seen.

344
00:30:14,920 --> 00:30:16,639
But let's not talk about him.

345
00:30:16,680 --> 00:30:19,679
My room number is 180, so my telephone extension's 180.

346
00:30:21,280 --> 00:30:23,199
Hope I can catch some loners tonight.

347
00:30:23,240 --> 00:30:25,399
I haven't caught any the last few nights.

348
00:30:26,200 --> 00:30:28,119
Hope you catch lots too.

349
00:30:28,160 --> 00:30:30,079
Thank you very much.

350
00:30:33,160 --> 00:30:35,079
If I don't find a suitable partner soon,

351
00:30:35,120 --> 00:30:38,559
I'm gonna kill myself by throwing myself out of one of the rooms.

352
00:30:39,760 --> 00:30:41,679
Out of the window.

353
00:30:42,480 --> 00:30:44,399
I want you to know that.

354
00:30:44,440 --> 00:30:46,359
My room is on the first floor.

355
00:30:46,400 --> 00:30:49,439
"I hope I catch some loners today," she said.

356
00:30:50,120 --> 00:30:52,519
"And I hope you catch lots too."

357
00:30:52,560 --> 00:30:56,079
She then told him that if she didn't find a suitable partner soon,

358
00:30:56,120 --> 00:30:59,959
she was going to kill herself by jumping from one of the room windows,

359
00:31:01,040 --> 00:31:04,279
320, maybe, or one higher up.

360
00:31:04,320 --> 00:31:07,319
480, that would be even better.

361
00:31:08,720 --> 00:31:13,519
When she stopped talking, he stared at her blankly, not knowing what to say.

362
00:31:14,840 --> 00:31:16,639
He then looked out at the woods

363
00:31:16,680 --> 00:31:19,239
and thought once more how good his excuse had been.

364
00:31:22,280 --> 00:31:24,199
Not bad. Bit higher.

365
00:31:27,440 --> 00:31:31,159
Have you thought about what animals you wanna be if you don't make it?

366
00:31:31,880 --> 00:31:33,399
A lobster.

367
00:31:41,280 --> 00:31:43,319
I'm gonna be a parrot if I don't make it.

368
00:31:47,400 --> 00:31:49,319
Why don't you become parrots too?

369
00:31:49,360 --> 00:31:50,879
And then we'll all be together.

370
00:31:50,920 --> 00:31:52,719
You're a complete idiot,

371
00:31:52,760 --> 00:31:54,519
picking one of the few animals that can talk

372
00:31:54,560 --> 00:31:55,999
when you have a speech impediment.

373
00:31:56,040 --> 00:31:57,599
You'll lisp, even as an animal.

374
00:31:57,640 --> 00:32:01,559
As for you, they'll catch you and put you in a pot of boiling water until you die.

375
00:32:01,600 --> 00:32:04,439
And then they'll crack open your claws with a tool, like pliers,

376
00:32:04,480 --> 00:32:06,599
and they'll suck out what little flesh you have with their mouths.

377
00:32:06,640 --> 00:32:08,559
You're pathetic, both of you.

378
00:32:10,120 --> 00:32:11,999
I'm not gonna be turned into some animal.

379
00:32:12,040 --> 00:32:14,719
I'll come and visit you, though, with my partner,

380
00:32:14,760 --> 00:32:18,679
when we're walking together in some park or when we're swimming in the sea.

381
00:32:18,720 --> 00:32:20,639
Or when we're on one of our trips.

382
00:32:27,640 --> 00:32:29,079
Friends.

383
00:32:29,120 --> 00:32:30,959
I'm not afraid.

384
00:32:35,320 --> 00:32:37,239
Room 187, please.

385
00:32:39,600 --> 00:32:44,599
It's no coincidence that the targets are shaped like single people and not couples.

386
00:33:26,440 --> 00:33:27,559
Hello.

387
00:33:29,040 --> 00:33:31,079
- Hello.
- Your swimsuit is very nice.

388
00:33:31,120 --> 00:33:32,559
Thank,

389
00:33:34,400 --> 00:33:36,559
- Thank you very much.
- You're welcome.

390
00:33:37,840 --> 00:33:41,719
Do you like to swim breaststroke, front crawl, butterfly or backstroke?

391
00:33:41,760 --> 00:33:43,279
I like all strokes equally.

392
00:33:43,320 --> 00:33:45,239
You know, I love breaststroke.

393
00:33:45,280 --> 00:33:47,359
No, really.
My friends often tease me and say,

394
00:33:47,400 --> 00:33:49,399
"Stop swimming breaststroke all the time."

395
00:33:49,440 --> 00:33:51,359
And then they laugh.

396
00:33:51,400 --> 00:33:54,799
Breaststroke is great.
It's excellent exercise for the back.

397
00:34:22,640 --> 00:34:26,039
When swimming breaststroke, men shouldn't wear swim shorts,

398
00:34:27,200 --> 00:34:29,679
as it really limits movement in the buttocks.

399
00:34:29,720 --> 00:34:32,919
- But you knew that, didn't you?
- I think your nose is bleeding.

400
00:34:32,960 --> 00:34:34,479
Really?

401
00:34:36,520 --> 00:34:38,199
Ah, no.

402
00:34:39,400 --> 00:34:41,319
This happens to me all the time.

403
00:34:43,080 --> 00:34:44,999
It's really, really annoying.

404
00:34:45,480 --> 00:34:47,799
I know. I have a nosebleed problem too.

405
00:35:00,840 --> 00:35:03,359
I saw what you did. It must have hurt.

406
00:35:11,880 --> 00:35:13,799
Is it coming out?

407
00:35:15,160 --> 00:35:16,519
No.

408
00:35:19,560 --> 00:35:21,399
- Yes.
- Can I use a tissue?

409
00:35:21,440 --> 00:35:22,879
Yes.

410
00:35:25,600 --> 00:35:29,039
I'm gonna ask you a question and I want you to answer me honestly.

411
00:35:29,600 --> 00:35:32,759
What's worse: to die of cold and hunger in the woods,

412
00:35:32,800 --> 00:35:36,119
to become an animal that will be killed and eaten by some bigger animal

413
00:35:36,160 --> 00:35:37,999
or to have a nosebleed from time to time?

414
00:35:39,840 --> 00:35:43,279
To become an animal that will be killed and eaten by some bigger animal.

415
00:35:43,320 --> 00:35:45,239
- Exactly.
- Mm.

416
00:35:45,280 --> 00:35:47,759
- She doesn't suspect that you're lying?
- No.

417
00:35:55,360 --> 00:35:57,719
I'm very happy because we have a new couple.

418
00:35:58,400 --> 00:36:02,559
They met just two days ago but they're very much in love and perfectly suited.

419
00:36:02,600 --> 00:36:06,759
They both have the same problem with their noses, they bleed quite suddenly.

420
00:36:11,000 --> 00:36:13,359
Tomorrow they'll be transferred to a double room

421
00:36:13,400 --> 00:36:15,759
with a larger wardrobe and a larger bathroom.

422
00:36:15,800 --> 00:36:18,119
They will remain in the double room for two weeks,

423
00:36:18,160 --> 00:36:21,479
and then they'll be transferred to the yachts for a further two weeks.

424
00:36:21,520 --> 00:36:24,999
We wish you every success and we hope you will return to the city as a couple.

425
00:36:28,840 --> 00:36:30,999
- I'm very happy.
- Me, too.

426
00:36:31,040 --> 00:36:32,519
Congratulations.

427
00:36:32,560 --> 00:36:35,719
The course of your relationship will be monitored closely

428
00:36:35,760 --> 00:36:37,639
by our staff and by me personally.

429
00:36:37,680 --> 00:36:40,799
If you encounter any problems, any tensions, any arguing,

430
00:36:40,840 --> 00:36:44,119
that you cannot resolve yourselves, you will be assigned children.

431
00:36:44,160 --> 00:36:46,079
That usually helps, a lot.

432
00:36:59,240 --> 00:37:02,319
Good morning, room 101.

433
00:37:03,160 --> 00:37:05,079
Seven days left.

434
00:37:05,120 --> 00:37:07,039
Breakfast is served.

435
00:37:46,760 --> 00:37:48,959
You have really nice hair.

436
00:37:49,680 --> 00:37:51,199
I know.

437
00:37:51,240 --> 00:37:52,799
Look.

438
00:37:59,560 --> 00:38:01,359
How do you like mine?

439
00:38:02,360 --> 00:38:04,999
Well, I think you have quite dry hair.

440
00:38:05,800 --> 00:38:07,719
The colour is ok, though.

441
00:38:07,760 --> 00:38:10,439
The most important thing is that you're not bald.

442
00:38:11,360 --> 00:38:15,719
However, when it comes to men, baldness is always a possibility you can't avoid.

443
00:38:16,480 --> 00:38:18,399
- Is your father bald?
- No, he isn't.

444
00:38:19,240 --> 00:38:23,279
And even if someday I lose my hair, there are things I can do to get my hair back.

445
00:38:23,320 --> 00:38:24,919
I can have a hair transplant.

446
00:38:24,960 --> 00:38:27,719
- You can always tell when someone's had a hair transplant.
- I know.

447
00:38:27,760 --> 00:38:31,679
Nice hair is not something you can get.
It's something you're born with.

448
00:38:31,720 --> 00:38:34,919
And the fact that your father isn't bald shouldn't put you at ease.

449
00:38:37,560 --> 00:38:40,399
Have you decided what you're going to do on your last day?

450
00:38:43,520 --> 00:38:45,439
I'm still thinking about it.

451
00:38:49,200 --> 00:38:51,119
Morning, ladies.

452
00:38:56,680 --> 00:38:59,999
So today is your last day.

453
00:39:00,040 --> 00:39:03,999
And as is customary, you can choose how you would like to spend your last night.

454
00:39:04,040 --> 00:39:05,919
What I always say in these situations is,

455
00:39:05,960 --> 00:39:08,919
it would be wise to choose something you can't do as an animal...

456
00:39:08,960 --> 00:39:11,119
for example, read a work of classic literature

457
00:39:12,040 --> 00:39:14,079
or sing a song you really like.

458
00:39:14,120 --> 00:39:16,039
It would be silly to choose

459
00:39:16,080 --> 00:39:18,559
for example a walk in the grounds,

460
00:39:18,600 --> 00:39:20,839
or to have sexual intercourse with another person,

461
00:39:20,880 --> 00:39:23,399
because those are things you can do as an animal.

462
00:39:24,720 --> 00:39:28,359
But first your best friend has written something she'd like to read to you,

463
00:39:28,400 --> 00:39:30,319
which is really very touching.

464
00:39:33,120 --> 00:39:35,039
"We always sat together at school.

465
00:39:35,080 --> 00:39:37,279
And whenever I had a problem, I talked to you about it

466
00:39:37,320 --> 00:39:39,479
because you always gave the best advice.

467
00:39:40,160 --> 00:39:43,079
When we didn't manage to find dance partners at the school prom,

468
00:39:43,120 --> 00:39:47,079
the fact that we were together at that difficult moment gave me strength.

469
00:39:47,120 --> 00:39:49,239
I'm sorry that things have come to this.

470
00:39:50,000 --> 00:39:54,039
I'm sure that if you had a few more days, you would find someone, just like I did,

471
00:39:54,080 --> 00:39:55,959
because you're an admirable person,

472
00:39:56,000 --> 00:39:58,559
and you have very beautiful hair and very nice breasts.

473
00:39:59,200 --> 00:40:01,839
I was always jealous of your hair, you know that.

474
00:40:01,880 --> 00:40:06,199
You were, are, and always will be my best friend and I'll think of you often.

475
00:40:06,840 --> 00:40:10,679
And I'll always wear those silver earrings you gave me for my birthday.

476
00:40:10,720 --> 00:40:12,279
I'll miss you.

477
00:40:12,320 --> 00:40:17,079
And however many new girlfriends I make in a few days when I move back into the city,

478
00:40:17,120 --> 00:40:19,279
I don't think I'll find another as true."

479
00:40:22,440 --> 00:40:24,439
I'd like to watch the film Stand By Me,

480
00:40:24,480 --> 00:40:28,239
with River Phoenix, Kiefer Sutherland and Richard Dreyfus. 
Alone.

481
00:40:28,280 --> 00:40:30,199
Excellent choice.

482
00:40:30,240 --> 00:40:32,159
Lovely film.

483
00:40:49,000 --> 00:40:51,399
Please leave a message.

484
00:40:53,720 --> 00:40:56,359
Hello.
You're probably in the bathroom,

485
00:40:56,400 --> 00:40:58,679
that's why you can't hear the phone ring.

486
00:40:58,720 --> 00:41:00,839
Nothing like a cold shower in the morning.

487
00:41:01,560 --> 00:41:06,159
Well, I'll call you a little bit later, after you've finished your shower.

488
00:41:06,840 --> 00:41:08,119
We'll talk later.

489
00:41:09,200 --> 00:41:10,479
Bye.

490
00:41:17,680 --> 00:41:19,719
One day, as he was playing golf,

491
00:41:19,760 --> 00:41:22,039
he thought that it is more difficult to pretend

492
00:41:22,080 --> 00:41:24,279
that you do have feelings when you don't

493
00:41:24,320 --> 00:41:26,959
than to pretend you don't have feelings when you do.

494
00:41:29,280 --> 00:41:31,439
He also thought that he liked her accent,

495
00:41:32,280 --> 00:41:34,879
and he'd always preferred women with short hair.

496
00:41:35,440 --> 00:41:37,359
So he decided that she was the one.

497
00:41:38,440 --> 00:41:41,199
During the hunt, he would follow her,

498
00:41:41,240 --> 00:41:43,919
and as soon as she shot a loner, he would say to her,

499
00:41:44,560 --> 00:41:48,599
"I wish we had real guns instead of these silly tranquiliser ones.

500
00:41:48,640 --> 00:41:51,159
Why don't you kill him with your bare hands?"

501
00:41:51,720 --> 00:41:55,719
And the moment she puts her hands around the loner's throat, he would say,

502
00:41:56,400 --> 00:41:58,319
"I hope he dies right away."

503
00:42:31,280 --> 00:42:33,199
Did anyone see what happened?

504
00:42:45,120 --> 00:42:46,839
What happened?

505
00:42:46,880 --> 00:42:48,919
She jumped from the window of room 180.

506
00:42:50,240 --> 00:42:52,399
There's blood and biscuits everywhere.

507
00:42:52,440 --> 00:42:54,359
I hope she dies right away.

508
00:42:55,280 --> 00:42:57,199
On second thoughts

509
00:42:57,240 --> 00:42:59,719
I hope she suffers quite a bit before she dies.

510
00:42:59,760 --> 00:43:03,039
I just hope her pathetic screams can't be heard from my room.

511
00:43:03,080 --> 00:43:07,039
Because I was thinking about having a lie-down and I need peace and quiet.

512
00:43:07,680 --> 00:43:09,719
I was playing golf and I'm quite tired.

513
00:43:09,760 --> 00:43:12,879
The last thing I need is some woman dying slowly and loudly.

514
00:43:12,920 --> 00:43:14,919
I can't hear you with all this screaming.

515
00:43:14,960 --> 00:43:17,439
We'll talk some other time when it's quieter.

516
00:43:20,320 --> 00:43:21,839
Goodbye.

517
00:43:25,320 --> 00:43:27,239
Goodbye.

518
00:43:33,840 --> 00:43:35,799
One message.

519
00:43:35,840 --> 00:43:38,559
Hello.
You're probably in the bathroom,

520
00:43:38,600 --> 00:43:40,759
that's why you can't hear the phone ring.

521
00:43:40,800 --> 00:43:42,679
Nothing like a cold shower in the morning.

522
00:43:43,680 --> 00:43:48,279
Well, I'll call you a little bit later, after you've finished your shower.

523
00:43:49,240 --> 00:43:51,039
We'll talk later.

524
00:43:51,680 --> 00:43:53,039
Bye.

525
00:43:55,880 --> 00:43:57,799
Mind if I join you?

526
00:44:06,240 --> 00:44:08,159
Martini?

527
00:45:02,200 --> 00:45:03,719
I think we are a match.

528
00:45:03,760 --> 00:45:05,679
Yes, I think so too.

529
00:45:08,520 --> 00:45:11,319
The keys to the double room, please.

530
00:45:18,840 --> 00:45:21,959
I wish you the best of luck.
We all wish you the best of luck.

531
00:45:36,720 --> 00:45:39,839
Do you normally sleep on the left side of the bed or the right?

532
00:45:39,880 --> 00:45:41,799
- The right. You?
- The left.

533
00:45:42,600 --> 00:45:44,359
Perfect.

534
00:46:04,960 --> 00:46:06,879
Spread your legs.

535
00:46:21,240 --> 00:46:24,039
Should I turn off the light or would you like to read?

536
00:46:24,080 --> 00:46:26,439
I'd like to read.
Does the light bother you?

537
00:46:26,480 --> 00:46:27,759
No.

538
00:46:27,800 --> 00:46:29,719
I'm not bothered by light or noise.

539
00:46:29,760 --> 00:46:31,679
I'm a deep sleeper.

540
00:46:47,720 --> 00:46:49,479
- Hello.
- Hello.

541
00:46:49,520 --> 00:46:50,839
Congratulations.

542
00:46:50,880 --> 00:46:53,279
- Thank you.
- This is our new daughter.

543
00:46:53,320 --> 00:46:54,959
Her name's Elizabeth.

544
00:46:55,000 --> 00:46:58,119
Elizabeth, give the nice man a kiss.
He's a friend of mine.

545
00:46:58,920 --> 00:47:02,359
The last thing I want right now is a kiss from a silly little girl.

546
00:47:06,200 --> 00:47:07,519
Come on, move away.

547
00:47:07,560 --> 00:47:09,399
Don't cry, Elizabeth, you should thank me.

548
00:47:09,440 --> 00:47:11,999
Now you'll have a limp and be more like your father.

549
00:47:17,920 --> 00:47:19,839
What was that sound?

550
00:47:19,880 --> 00:47:21,599
Did you say something?

551
00:47:21,640 --> 00:47:23,559
No.

552
00:47:24,480 --> 00:47:27,439
Do you mind if we fuck in a position where I can see your face?

553
00:47:27,480 --> 00:47:28,639
Sure.

554
00:47:35,520 --> 00:47:38,199
Turn the light on please, so I can see you better.

555
00:48:30,240 --> 00:48:32,159
Good morning.

556
00:48:36,440 --> 00:48:37,839
Morning.

557
00:48:38,920 --> 00:48:40,839
I killed your brother.

558
00:48:41,520 --> 00:48:43,439
I left him to die very slowly.

559
00:48:43,480 --> 00:48:45,479
He may not be dead yet even as we speak.

560
00:48:46,440 --> 00:48:48,039
I was kicking him for ages.

561
00:48:49,480 --> 00:48:51,039
Doesn't matter.

562
00:48:52,200 --> 00:48:54,519
He whined a little, a strange kind of bark.

563
00:48:55,160 --> 00:48:56,759
Something like this.

564
00:49:03,480 --> 00:49:05,399
It must have been from the pain.

565
00:49:05,440 --> 00:49:07,359
- You didn't hear anything?
- No.

566
00:49:08,120 --> 00:49:10,039
You really are a deep sleeper.

567
00:49:10,880 --> 00:49:13,319
- Would you like some coffee?
- I'd love some.

568
00:49:14,600 --> 00:49:17,359
As soon as I wash my face and brush my teeth, though.

569
00:49:20,720 --> 00:49:24,159
I can't wait to hear the story you promised to tell me last night,

570
00:49:24,960 --> 00:49:27,439
about that student of yours at the university

571
00:49:27,480 --> 00:49:29,399
and his awful final project.

572
00:49:46,960 --> 00:49:48,879
It's really a very funny story.

573
00:49:49,960 --> 00:49:51,879
His name was Ryess...

574
00:49:51,920 --> 00:49:54,559
R-Y-E-S-S. Ryess.

575
00:50:00,640 --> 00:50:03,839
These aren't tears, it's just water.
I just washed my face.

576
00:50:04,600 --> 00:50:07,599
I knew you were lying.
I can't understand why you did it,

577
00:50:07,640 --> 00:50:11,679
when you know as well as anyone that a relationship cannot be built on a lie.

578
00:50:11,720 --> 00:50:16,039
We're going to the hotel manager right now and you'll get the punishment you deserve.

579
00:50:16,080 --> 00:50:17,719
What's the punishment for this?

580
00:50:17,760 --> 00:50:20,239
They turn you into the animal no one wants to be.

581
00:51:59,680 --> 00:52:01,839
I saw your partner running back that way.

582
00:52:01,880 --> 00:52:03,799
He looked frantic.

583
00:52:03,840 --> 00:52:05,759
Is everything ok?

584
00:52:29,160 --> 00:52:32,919
At first he wanted to kill her in some horrible and painful way,

585
00:52:32,960 --> 00:52:35,599
like the death she had inflicted on his brother.

586
00:52:35,640 --> 00:52:37,559
Take her legs, please.

587
00:52:38,160 --> 00:52:41,599
He thought about kicking her in the stomach over and over again, 

588
00:52:41,640 --> 00:52:45,039
and then stabbing her in the same spot in the stomach.

589
00:52:50,640 --> 00:52:53,319
But then he thought there wouldn't be much point,

590
00:52:53,360 --> 00:52:55,879
because she was already unconscious

591
00:52:55,920 --> 00:52:58,919
and wouldn't feel any pain from the kicks, or the knife.

592
00:53:01,120 --> 00:53:04,079
You have to shoot me so they won't suspect I helped you.

593
00:53:04,120 --> 00:53:06,039
A hotel maid helped him.

594
00:53:06,080 --> 00:53:09,279
He couldn't understand why she did it.

595
00:53:22,320 --> 00:53:24,439
So he decided to turn her into an animal.

596
00:53:26,040 --> 00:53:29,559
He dragged her to the room where the transformations took place.

597
00:53:30,840 --> 00:53:34,119
I asked him many times what sort of animal he turned her into,

598
00:53:34,160 --> 00:53:36,159
but he always gave me the same answer:

599
00:53:36,200 --> 00:53:38,119
"That's none of your concern."

600
00:53:46,760 --> 00:53:49,919
That night, he left the hotel once and for all.

601
00:53:53,560 --> 00:53:56,359
He began to run without knowing where he was headed.

602
00:53:57,320 --> 00:53:59,239
But he was headed towards us.

603
00:54:25,160 --> 00:54:27,079
This was the start of his new life.

604
00:54:28,600 --> 00:54:31,879
And back then, he didn't know how much it hurts to be alone,

605
00:54:34,840 --> 00:54:39,319
how much it hurts when you cannot reach to rub pain-relief ointment on your back,

606
00:54:39,360 --> 00:54:41,279
and you are constantly in pain.

607
00:55:25,440 --> 00:55:26,999
I found him in the woods.

608
00:55:27,040 --> 00:55:28,959
He escaped from the hotel.

609
00:55:29,000 --> 00:55:30,919
Are you a doctor, by any chance?

610
00:55:31,480 --> 00:55:33,959
- No.
- That's a pity.

611
00:55:34,600 --> 00:55:36,519
We need a doctor around.

612
00:55:36,560 --> 00:55:39,319
We had one, but they caught him a couple of months ago.

613
00:55:39,360 --> 00:55:41,279
I'm an architect.

614
00:55:42,160 --> 00:55:43,719
That's ok.

615
00:55:43,760 --> 00:55:45,159
So, welcome.

616
00:55:45,200 --> 00:55:47,519
You can stay with us for as long as you like.

617
00:55:48,240 --> 00:55:51,159
You can be a loner until the day you die.
There is no time limit.

618
00:55:51,200 --> 00:55:53,119
Thank you very much.

619
00:56:06,800 --> 00:56:08,039
By the way,

620
00:56:08,080 --> 00:56:11,799
any romantic or sexual relations between loners are not permitted.

621
00:56:12,120 --> 00:56:14,119
And any such acts are punished.

622
00:56:14,160 --> 00:56:16,079
Is that clear?

623
00:56:17,320 --> 00:56:19,439
Can I have a conversation with someone?

624
00:56:19,480 --> 00:56:21,399
Of course you can.

625
00:56:21,440 --> 00:56:24,319
So as long as there is no flirting or anything like that.

626
00:56:24,880 --> 00:56:26,879
That applies to dance nights as well.

627
00:56:27,720 --> 00:56:31,439
We all dance by ourselves, that's why we only play electronic music.

628
00:56:42,560 --> 00:56:44,479
What happened to your mouth?

629
00:56:45,800 --> 00:56:48,279
He can't speak.
He was given the Red Kiss.

630
00:56:49,560 --> 00:56:51,279
What's the Red Kiss?

631
00:56:51,320 --> 00:56:54,639
We slashed his lips with a razor and the lips of another loner,

632
00:56:54,680 --> 00:56:56,639
and we forced them to kiss each other.

633
00:56:56,680 --> 00:56:58,599
That was a couple of days ago now.

634
00:56:59,480 --> 00:57:03,319
But the cuts were deep and they're still in pain.
They were flirting, you know.

635
00:57:13,040 --> 00:57:15,919
Some punishments are worse than other punishments.

636
00:57:17,960 --> 00:57:21,119
Having your thumb cut is worse than having your head shaved.

637
00:57:21,880 --> 00:57:24,319
And having a hot boiled egg under your armpit

638
00:57:24,360 --> 00:57:26,359
is worse than having your leg kicked.

639
00:57:27,920 --> 00:57:31,759
The punishment I am afraid of isn't the Red Kiss but another one,

640
00:57:31,800 --> 00:57:33,559
that is called the Red Intercourse.

641
00:57:34,800 --> 00:57:38,879
I have never seen it happen, but it's not difficult to imagine what it means.

642
00:57:39,920 --> 00:57:42,279
Oh, my God, I am so afraid of it.

643
00:57:51,800 --> 00:57:53,519
Move.

644
00:57:54,800 --> 00:57:56,239
Hide.

645
00:57:59,200 --> 00:58:00,599
Move.

646
00:58:02,000 --> 00:58:03,039
Hide.

647
00:58:08,800 --> 00:58:10,599
That was the first time I saw him.

648
00:58:11,560 --> 00:58:13,719
He was hiding behind a tree close to mine.

649
00:58:14,960 --> 00:58:16,879
He seemed quite presentable.

650
00:58:17,680 --> 00:58:19,599
The next day, in the city,

651
00:58:19,960 --> 00:58:22,359
he found out that I was short-sighted too.

652
00:58:28,640 --> 00:58:30,359
That night in my sleep,

653
00:58:30,400 --> 00:58:33,519
I dreamt that we lived in a big house together in the city,

654
00:58:33,560 --> 00:58:35,639
with a large well-lit kitchen,

655
00:58:35,680 --> 00:58:39,679
and I was wearing dark blue trousers and a tight cream blouse.

656
00:58:39,720 --> 00:58:42,999
And he took my clothes off and fucked me up the arse.

657
00:58:49,720 --> 00:58:52,599
And as he was fucking me, a thug came into the kitchen,

658
00:58:52,640 --> 00:58:56,239
and took the steak knives from the second draw and attacked us,

659
00:58:56,280 --> 00:58:59,319
stabbing the knives into our bellies one by one.

660
00:58:59,920 --> 00:59:01,679
I woke up terrified.

661
00:59:12,000 --> 00:59:13,719
Try harder.

662
00:59:14,760 --> 00:59:17,879
Don't give up. You know you should have been more careful.

663
00:59:18,720 --> 00:59:22,759
Try harder or they'll find you and you'll be turned into an animal... a weak one.

664
00:59:25,080 --> 00:59:28,199
We must get a move on now.
It's really too dangerous to stay here.

665
00:59:28,240 --> 00:59:31,439
If you manage to free yourself, run as fast as you can and come find us.

666
00:59:31,480 --> 00:59:34,319
If you manage to free yourself but think you'll die from the bleeding,

667
00:59:34,360 --> 00:59:35,559
go straight to your grave.

668
00:59:35,600 --> 00:59:37,959
Have you dug your own grave?

669
00:59:38,000 --> 00:59:39,319
Yes.

670
00:59:39,360 --> 00:59:41,279
Very good.

671
00:59:41,320 --> 00:59:43,239
That's enough for now.

672
00:59:51,320 --> 00:59:53,319
I'm going to go hunting for truffles.

673
00:59:53,360 --> 00:59:56,839
They're delicious and quite rare.
A kilo can fetch a lot of money.

674
00:59:56,880 --> 00:59:59,959
You're going to need a pig.
They're impossible to find otherwise.

675
01:00:00,000 --> 01:00:01,279
- I know.
- Don't be long.

676
01:00:01,320 --> 01:00:03,399
- Gotta get them back in 50 minutes.
- Ok.

677
01:00:28,640 --> 01:00:30,199
Hello, David.

678
01:00:30,240 --> 01:00:32,159
Hello, Robert.

679
01:00:34,240 --> 01:00:36,359
What you did to that woman was dreadful.

680
01:00:36,400 --> 01:00:38,039
She killed my brother.

681
01:00:38,080 --> 01:00:40,479
I would have done the same thing if she'd killed you.

682
01:00:40,520 --> 01:00:43,679
You're like a brother to me. 
Oh, you're my best friend in the whole world.

683
01:00:44,400 --> 01:00:47,079
I don't think I'm your best friend in the whole world.

684
01:00:47,120 --> 01:00:49,119
You used to spend much more time with John.

685
01:00:49,160 --> 01:00:51,079
Oh, who's John?

686
01:00:51,120 --> 01:00:53,039
- John, the Limping Man.
- Oh, yeah.

687
01:00:53,080 --> 01:00:54,999
I didn't even remember his name.

688
01:00:55,040 --> 01:00:56,959
Or his face.

689
01:00:57,000 --> 01:00:59,679
You're the one I think of whenever I need a friend.

690
01:01:00,960 --> 01:01:02,879
Nevertheless, did John make it?

691
01:01:05,480 --> 01:01:07,479
They're getting ready for the yacht.

692
01:01:07,520 --> 01:01:08,999
It all begins this week.

693
01:01:09,040 --> 01:01:11,839
Everyone says they're gonna make it as they're perfectly suited

694
01:01:11,880 --> 01:01:14,599
and the child will help them get past the fighting and arguing.

695
01:01:14,640 --> 01:01:17,719
- That's great.
- You're not thinking about coming back?

696
01:01:17,760 --> 01:01:20,279
You know, if you told the hotel manager about your brother,

697
01:01:20,320 --> 01:01:21,599
she'd probably forgive you.

698
01:01:21,640 --> 01:01:23,639
No, it's really nice to be on your own.

699
01:01:24,320 --> 01:01:26,239
There's no one tying you down.

700
01:01:26,280 --> 01:01:29,839
You listen to music whenever you like, you masturbate whenever you want,

701
01:01:29,880 --> 01:01:31,799
go for walks whenever you like,

702
01:01:31,840 --> 01:01:33,759
have a chat whenever you like.

703
01:01:33,800 --> 01:01:35,639
I don't miss companionship at all.

704
01:01:36,280 --> 01:01:38,639
I just miss you, 'cause you were my one true friend.

705
01:01:40,600 --> 01:01:42,279
Are you gonna shoot me?

706
01:01:42,320 --> 01:01:43,919
I'm afraid so.

707
01:01:43,960 --> 01:01:45,879
I only have two days left.

708
01:01:45,920 --> 01:01:48,879
What did you say?
I can't understand the way you speak.

709
01:01:48,920 --> 01:01:52,639
I'm going to shoot you. 
I only have two days left, I need more time.

710
01:01:52,680 --> 01:01:54,799
Do you actually believe another day will make a difference?

711
01:01:54,840 --> 01:01:56,599
Have you seen how ugly you are?

712
01:01:56,640 --> 01:01:58,599
You haven't got a chance.
If I was a woman...

713
01:02:04,560 --> 01:02:06,479
Don't tell anyone I helped you.

714
01:02:06,520 --> 01:02:08,519
If you want to repay me, there is a way.

715
01:02:08,560 --> 01:02:10,799
If you kill a rabbit, bring it to me to eat.

716
01:02:11,960 --> 01:02:13,599
Do you promise?

717
01:02:13,640 --> 01:02:15,359
- Yes.
- Bye.

718
01:02:15,400 --> 01:02:16,759
Bye.

719
01:04:48,080 --> 01:04:51,799
You carefully flay the rabbit with a sharp knife and cut off its head.

720
01:04:55,200 --> 01:05:00,039
You then slice open its belly and stuff it with well-washed red and green peppers,

721
01:05:00,720 --> 01:05:03,599
not too spicy, and a little garlic and mint.

722
01:05:08,360 --> 01:05:12,399
You then soak it in lemon juice and leave it a while to marinate the flesh

723
01:05:13,520 --> 01:05:17,919
before you skewer it on a stick and roast it over the fire for about an hour.

724
01:05:20,240 --> 01:05:22,319
That's my favourite food,

725
01:05:23,240 --> 01:05:24,679
rabbit.

726
01:07:45,080 --> 01:07:47,919
Woman, brunette, 50 years old.

727
01:07:48,920 --> 01:07:51,239
Marriage certificate expired two months ago.

728
01:07:51,280 --> 01:07:52,879
My husband's away on a business trip.

729
01:07:52,920 --> 01:07:55,239
Yeah, ok. Can I have a look?

730
01:08:02,680 --> 01:08:04,199
Hands.

731
01:08:12,320 --> 01:08:14,479
No dirt under her nails or mud on her shoes.

732
01:08:15,480 --> 01:08:17,199
9 Belsize Road.

733
01:08:17,880 --> 01:08:19,799
- So your husband is away?
- Yes.

734
01:08:19,840 --> 01:08:21,479
Where?

735
01:08:21,520 --> 01:08:23,559
Good morning, sir. Are you here alone?

736
01:08:24,840 --> 01:08:26,439
Good morning, Officer.

737
01:08:26,480 --> 01:08:28,399
No, I'm here with my partner.

738
01:08:28,440 --> 01:08:31,239
She's inside one of the stores, shopping right now.

739
01:08:31,840 --> 01:08:33,879
Can I see your certificate, please?

740
01:08:35,000 --> 01:08:36,919
My partner keeps it in her purse.

741
01:08:37,600 --> 01:08:40,559
You see, I am losing it all the time.

742
01:08:41,280 --> 01:08:42,519
I see.

743
01:08:42,560 --> 01:08:44,479
And what store is she shopping in?

744
01:08:51,480 --> 01:08:53,399
Oh, here she is.

745
01:08:54,600 --> 01:08:56,119
I'm sorry, darling.

746
01:08:56,160 --> 01:08:59,119
They had such a huge variety of pain-relief ointment.

747
01:08:59,160 --> 01:09:02,479
I bought you this one.
I hope it's the one you were looking for.

748
01:09:02,520 --> 01:09:04,439
That's wonderful, dear.

749
01:09:04,480 --> 01:09:06,399
Can I have my certificate, please?

750
01:09:07,680 --> 01:09:10,999
Of course, darling.
Would you like to see mine also, Officer?

751
01:09:11,040 --> 01:09:12,959
No, that's ok.

752
01:09:13,000 --> 01:09:14,919
Thank you, sir.

753
01:09:14,960 --> 01:09:18,279
- You have a good day.
- Thank you, Officer. You have a good day.

754
01:09:18,320 --> 01:09:20,319
- Madam.
- Sir.

755
01:09:24,880 --> 01:09:28,159
If I'm walking too slowly, just say, and I'll pick up my pace.

756
01:09:28,200 --> 01:09:30,119
This pace is fine.

757
01:09:31,360 --> 01:09:35,399
Maybe don't squeeze my hand so tightly, my palm's getting a little sweaty.

758
01:09:35,440 --> 01:09:37,159
- Better?
- Yes.

759
01:09:37,200 --> 01:09:38,639
Much better.

760
01:09:39,800 --> 01:09:43,359
Are you planning on buying anything else nice for yourself while we're here?

761
01:09:43,400 --> 01:09:47,119
Yes, contact lens solution and a Parker Rollerball.

762
01:09:48,880 --> 01:09:50,919
I didn't know you were short-sighted.

763
01:09:52,240 --> 01:09:54,159
I'm short-sighted too.

764
01:10:19,200 --> 01:10:21,959
Will you stay a few days?

765
01:10:22,000 --> 01:10:23,759
I'm afraid not, Papa.

766
01:10:23,800 --> 01:10:25,719
We're heading back again today.

767
01:10:25,760 --> 01:10:28,119
Tomorrow I'm going away on a business trip.

768
01:10:28,840 --> 01:10:30,759
You know how demanding my job is.

769
01:10:30,800 --> 01:10:33,479
Don't ask if I can stay a few days every time I come.

770
01:10:35,040 --> 01:10:37,399
Do you all work for the same company?

771
01:10:39,040 --> 01:10:40,959
- Yes.
- Yes.

772
01:10:41,000 --> 01:10:44,599
My daughter says me it's a very fine company.

773
01:10:44,640 --> 01:10:46,559
Do you agree?

774
01:10:47,240 --> 01:10:49,239
- It's a rather good company.
- It is.

775
01:10:50,160 --> 01:10:52,079
- One of the best, I'd say.
- Mm.

776
01:10:53,240 --> 01:10:54,999
The only problem with the job

777
01:10:55,040 --> 01:10:58,119
is that I don't have enough time for my wife and kids.

778
01:11:02,240 --> 01:11:04,439
We have four beautiful children.

779
01:11:05,360 --> 01:11:07,399
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.

780
01:11:07,440 --> 01:11:08,959
Thank you.

781
01:11:12,120 --> 01:11:14,039
But even if we'd never had children,

782
01:11:15,160 --> 01:11:17,199
I would never dream of leaving my wife.

783
01:11:18,240 --> 01:11:21,119
Even if it was just the two of us, on our own,

784
01:11:22,080 --> 01:11:23,999
we'd go on trips.

785
01:11:24,040 --> 01:11:28,079
We'd go to Portofino in Italy or go to a Greek island for the summer.

786
01:11:29,000 --> 01:11:33,079
And so our relationship would be as intense as it was at the start.

787
01:11:35,840 --> 01:11:39,119
I love my wife so much

788
01:11:39,880 --> 01:11:41,799
I could die for her.

789
01:11:44,480 --> 01:11:46,399
That's how much I love her.

790
01:11:57,480 --> 01:11:59,919
For your first day in the city, you did great.

791
01:12:00,520 --> 01:12:05,119
That part about holiday destinations in the Mediterranean was brilliant.

792
01:12:05,160 --> 01:12:06,559
Thank you very much.

793
01:12:17,240 --> 01:12:19,159
When did you become short-sighted?

794
01:12:20,400 --> 01:12:22,319
When I was 16.

795
01:12:22,360 --> 01:12:23,759
You?

796
01:12:23,800 --> 01:12:25,719
When I was 12.

797
01:12:25,760 --> 01:12:28,319
What was the make of your first pair of glasses?

798
01:12:30,240 --> 01:12:32,159
I don't remember.

799
01:12:33,160 --> 01:12:35,159
- Do you have astigmatism too?
- Yes.

800
01:12:43,880 --> 01:12:46,519
Would you like me to rub some balm on your back

801
01:12:47,600 --> 01:12:49,759
on the bits you can't reach on your own?

802
01:12:51,720 --> 01:12:53,359
I'd like that.

803
01:13:08,520 --> 01:13:09,799
Here?

804
01:13:09,840 --> 01:13:11,759
A little lower, please.

805
01:13:11,800 --> 01:13:13,519
- Here?
- Yes.

806
01:13:41,640 --> 01:13:43,559
"Hello, everyone, and good luck.

807
01:13:43,600 --> 01:13:46,039
The room numbers are as follows:

808
01:13:46,400 --> 01:13:49,159
room 306, the hotel manager and her partner.

809
01:13:49,200 --> 01:13:50,599
They both,

810
01:13:50,640 --> 01:13:52,559
they both have nice voices.

811
01:13:52,600 --> 01:13:55,039
Room 240: couple who both love to ski.

812
01:13:55,600 --> 01:13:59,799
Room 282: couple who both studied social sciences.

813
01:14:00,440 --> 01:14:03,439
Name of yacht Bliss: couple prone to nosebleeds."

814
01:14:14,880 --> 01:14:16,799
You and you take 306.

815
01:14:16,840 --> 01:14:18,759
You and you take 240.

816
01:14:18,800 --> 01:14:20,719
You take 282.

817
01:14:20,760 --> 01:14:22,679
And you two, take the yacht.

818
01:14:22,720 --> 01:14:24,239
Can I go to the yacht?

819
01:14:25,000 --> 01:14:27,239
Ok, then, so you take the yacht.

820
01:14:27,280 --> 01:14:29,159
And you take 282.

821
01:14:29,960 --> 01:14:32,679
And us three, we'll take the manager's room.

822
01:14:32,720 --> 01:14:34,239
We have 40 minutes.

823
01:14:50,440 --> 01:14:52,039
You need to speak with the manager.

824
01:15:22,520 --> 01:15:23,959
Wake up.

825
01:15:24,840 --> 01:15:26,279
Get up.

826
01:15:27,800 --> 01:15:29,719
Sit in that seat over there.

827
01:15:31,040 --> 01:15:32,959
Put your hand behind your back.

828
01:15:34,280 --> 01:15:37,559
A basketball weighs between 550 and 650 grams.

829
01:15:37,600 --> 01:15:39,959
- Did you know that?
- No, I didn't know that.

830
01:15:41,240 --> 01:15:42,799
Yes.

831
01:15:43,800 --> 01:15:46,359
The weight's different for men's and women's games,

832
01:15:46,400 --> 01:15:48,439
but that's roughly how much it weighs.

833
01:15:48,480 --> 01:15:50,639
Do you know how much a volleyball weighs?

834
01:15:51,320 --> 01:15:53,039
No, but I'd like to find out.

835
01:15:54,640 --> 01:15:56,559
- Good evening.
- Good evening.

836
01:15:56,600 --> 01:15:58,519
I have something to tell you.

837
01:15:58,560 --> 01:16:00,719
His nose doesn't really bleed on its own.

838
01:16:00,760 --> 01:16:04,679
He bangs it against a wall or a piece of hard wood, or something like that.

839
01:16:04,720 --> 01:16:07,599
Or he cuts it with a penknife when you're not looking.

840
01:16:07,640 --> 01:16:09,559
You two are not suited.

841
01:16:10,200 --> 01:16:12,999
Shut up. Dad, tell him to leave.
I'm sleepy.

842
01:16:13,040 --> 01:16:16,479
And, and I'm quite sure that stain on his T-shirt isn't blood,

843
01:16:16,520 --> 01:16:18,039
but cherry juice or tomato ketchup

844
01:16:18,080 --> 01:16:20,919
or red water colour paint or something like that.

845
01:16:20,960 --> 01:16:22,879
Or beetroot juice.

846
01:16:25,160 --> 01:16:27,079
Do you love her?

847
01:16:28,240 --> 01:16:30,159
With all my heart.

848
01:16:31,240 --> 01:16:34,159
How much do you love her, on a scale of 1 to 15?

849
01:16:38,600 --> 01:16:39,999
14.

850
01:16:41,160 --> 01:16:43,079
14 is a very impressive score.

851
01:16:43,800 --> 01:16:45,719
He loves her very much indeed.

852
01:16:46,600 --> 01:16:48,519
Who do you think we should kill?

853
01:16:48,560 --> 01:16:50,919
Who will be able to live on their own better?

854
01:16:57,920 --> 01:16:59,839
Here's a knife, mum. Kill him.

855
01:17:01,640 --> 01:17:03,479
You'd better get out while you still can.

856
01:17:03,520 --> 01:17:05,239
Ok.

857
01:17:06,280 --> 01:17:08,199
That's all I came to say, anyway.

858
01:17:18,360 --> 01:17:19,759
You.

859
01:17:20,360 --> 01:17:23,599
If this woman dies, d'you think you'll manage on your own?

860
01:17:23,640 --> 01:17:25,799
Or will you get involved with someone else?

861
01:17:25,840 --> 01:17:27,039
No.

862
01:17:27,080 --> 01:17:28,999
I can live alone, she can't.

863
01:17:29,880 --> 01:17:32,679
I'm on my own for hours when she's running the hotel.

864
01:17:33,720 --> 01:17:35,639
I like sitting in the room.

865
01:17:36,440 --> 01:17:38,839
It relaxes me, calms me.

866
01:17:40,320 --> 01:17:42,239
I like it a lot.

867
01:17:44,160 --> 01:17:46,919
I can definitely live on my own.

868
01:17:46,960 --> 01:17:49,399
Be quiet.

869
01:17:57,000 --> 01:17:58,439
Take it.

870
01:18:01,200 --> 01:18:02,839
Shoot her.

871
01:18:14,680 --> 01:18:16,119
No.

872
01:18:16,880 --> 01:18:18,279
No, no.

873
01:18:18,320 --> 01:18:20,239
No, God, no.

874
01:18:34,240 --> 01:18:36,679
I'm going to fucking kill your arse.

875
01:18:37,640 --> 01:18:39,559
Don't you fucking care?

876
01:19:03,800 --> 01:19:05,399
Where were you?

877
01:19:05,440 --> 01:19:06,879
I was looking for you.

878
01:19:06,920 --> 01:19:09,919
I was masturbating behind those trees over there.

879
01:19:12,240 --> 01:19:14,159
Why aren't you dancing?

880
01:19:14,400 --> 01:19:15,919
My leg's a little sore.

881
01:19:17,160 --> 01:19:19,079
Did you dig your grave?

882
01:19:19,120 --> 01:19:21,039
Not yet.

883
01:19:21,080 --> 01:19:22,999
I don't mean to pressure you,

884
01:19:23,040 --> 01:19:25,599
or to ruin the mood now that we're celebrating,

885
01:19:25,640 --> 01:19:27,639
but at some point you'll have to do it.

886
01:19:27,680 --> 01:19:31,639
Don't expect anyone else to dig your grave for you or to carry your corpse.

887
01:19:31,680 --> 01:19:34,439
We'll throw some dirt over you but that's about it.

888
01:19:35,120 --> 01:19:37,039
Tomorrow find a spot you like,

889
01:19:37,080 --> 01:19:40,239
where the ground isn't too rocky, and make a start.

890
01:19:41,960 --> 01:19:44,399
- Enjoy the rest of your evening.
- Thank you.

891
01:19:56,800 --> 01:20:00,839
As soon as his last patient left, I entered his office and I said to him,

892
01:20:01,960 --> 01:20:05,879
"Honey, the dinner's ready.
However, I'm not sure I can eat right now.

893
01:20:05,920 --> 01:20:07,839
One of my front teeth hurts a lot.

894
01:20:07,880 --> 01:20:09,799
Can you take a look please, dear?"

895
01:20:09,840 --> 01:20:11,759
"Yes, sure, no problem," he said.

896
01:20:11,800 --> 01:20:16,079
And the minute he turned his head, I took the drill and I shoved it into his chest.

897
01:20:19,480 --> 01:20:22,519
That story sounds really interesting but I have to leave.

898
01:20:22,560 --> 01:20:25,239
I just remembered I left some batteries next to a tree down there.

899
01:20:25,280 --> 01:20:27,519
And the last thing I want is to lose them.
Sorry.

900
01:20:36,800 --> 01:20:38,959
Did you catch rabbits?

901
01:20:39,600 --> 01:20:41,599
- No, someone brought me them.
- Who?

902
01:20:41,640 --> 01:20:43,479
A friend of mine.

903
01:20:43,520 --> 01:20:45,439
- Do you want one?
- No.

904
01:20:47,360 --> 01:20:49,799
You don't need to accept rabbits from other people.

905
01:20:49,840 --> 01:20:53,039
If you need more rabbits, just ask, and I'll bring you more.

906
01:20:54,800 --> 01:20:57,759
Catching a rabbit is difficult, but I'll try to do better.

907
01:20:57,800 --> 01:21:00,199
There's no need for you to be indebted to the others.

908
01:21:00,240 --> 01:21:02,159
Thank you very much.

909
01:21:03,080 --> 01:21:04,999
The man who brought you the rabbits,

910
01:21:05,040 --> 01:21:06,959
is he short-sighted?

911
01:21:07,000 --> 01:21:09,479
I don't know. I don't think so.

912
01:21:09,520 --> 01:21:10,839
Ok.

913
01:21:22,400 --> 01:21:24,319
Is that a sparrow up in that tree?

914
01:21:25,880 --> 01:21:27,719
I can't really see that far.

915
01:21:27,760 --> 01:21:29,319
But I don't think so.

916
01:21:29,360 --> 01:21:31,279
- Are you short-sighted?
- No.

917
01:21:31,320 --> 01:21:32,639
You're lying.

918
01:21:32,680 --> 01:21:34,479
It's the truth.

919
01:21:39,120 --> 01:21:41,039
What does it say here?

920
01:21:41,080 --> 01:21:42,999
YKK.

921
01:21:43,760 --> 01:21:46,519
You knew that already.
All zips say the same thing.

922
01:21:46,560 --> 01:21:48,279
I'm not short-sighted.

923
01:21:48,320 --> 01:21:50,759
I don't understand why you won't believe me.

924
01:21:50,800 --> 01:21:53,239
I can see really clearly.
I used to be a pilot.

925
01:21:53,280 --> 01:21:55,199
You're wearing contact lenses.

926
01:21:55,240 --> 01:21:58,359
I don't wear contact lenses.
I'm not short-sighted, I swear.

927
01:21:58,400 --> 01:22:00,879
You are.
You think I'm an idiot and can't tell.

928
01:22:03,000 --> 01:22:04,639
Let me see.

929
01:22:06,000 --> 01:22:08,239
Let me see. I want to see your eyes.

930
01:22:10,080 --> 01:22:11,479
Look up.

931
01:22:12,160 --> 01:22:13,399
Look up.

932
01:22:14,640 --> 01:22:16,159
Up, up.

933
01:22:17,080 --> 01:22:18,719
Look down now.

934
01:22:20,000 --> 01:22:21,599
Look left.

935
01:22:22,960 --> 01:22:24,559
Look right.

936
01:22:24,600 --> 01:22:26,039
Up again.

937
01:22:33,640 --> 01:22:35,159
I'm sorry.

938
01:22:36,360 --> 01:22:38,279
I thought you were trying to fool me.

939
01:22:39,880 --> 01:22:41,559
I'm sorry.

940
01:22:44,760 --> 01:22:48,399
For this synchronisation exercise, we have to fully concentrate,

941
01:22:48,440 --> 01:22:51,439
as we both have to press "play" at exactly the same time.

942
01:22:52,480 --> 01:22:54,399
Why don't we just use one headset?

943
01:22:55,560 --> 01:22:57,479
Because that's the whole point.

944
01:22:57,520 --> 01:22:59,439
This is an exercise for us.

945
01:22:59,480 --> 01:23:01,399
We have to be totally synchronised.

946
01:23:02,320 --> 01:23:03,759
Ok.

947
01:23:09,320 --> 01:23:11,239
- I'm ready.
- Ok.

948
01:23:14,000 --> 01:23:16,639
Five, four, three,

949
01:23:17,200 --> 01:23:18,319
two,

950
01:23:22,480 --> 01:23:25,239
♪ Where the wild roses grow

951
01:23:49,520 --> 01:23:53,919
♪ If I show you the roses will you follow?

952
01:23:56,000 --> 01:24:00,039
♪ They call me the Wild Rose

953
01:24:02,680 --> 01:24:05,599
♪ But my name is Elisa Day

954
01:24:13,200 --> 01:24:16,479
We've developed a code so that we can communicate with each other,

955
01:24:16,520 --> 01:24:20,239
even in front of the others, without them knowing what we are saying.

956
01:24:20,760 --> 01:24:23,399
When we turn our heads to the left, it means,

957
01:24:23,440 --> 01:24:25,879
"I love you more than anything in the world."

958
01:24:25,920 --> 01:24:28,559
And when we turn our heads to the right, it means,

959
01:24:28,600 --> 01:24:30,479
"Watch out, we're in danger."

960
01:24:32,800 --> 01:24:35,679
We had to be very careful in the beginning not to mix up

961
01:24:35,720 --> 01:24:39,959
"I love you more than anything in the world" with "Watch out, we're in danger."

962
01:24:42,000 --> 01:24:43,919
When we raise our left arm, it means,

963
01:24:44,800 --> 01:24:46,719
"I want to dance in your arms."

964
01:24:46,760 --> 01:24:49,759
When we make a fist and put it behind our backs, it means,

965
01:24:49,800 --> 01:24:51,719
"Let's fuck."

966
01:24:52,960 --> 01:24:55,759
The code grew and grew as time went by.

967
01:24:55,800 --> 01:24:58,999
And within a few weeks, we could talk about almost anything

968
01:24:59,040 --> 01:25:01,359
without even opening our mouths.

969
01:26:28,600 --> 01:26:30,199
Stop it.

970
01:26:30,240 --> 01:26:32,399
That's enough.
Show my parents some respect.

971
01:26:32,440 --> 01:26:34,359
They are playing you music.

972
01:26:35,280 --> 01:26:38,919
- That's ok.
- No, mother, it is not ok.

973
01:26:39,800 --> 01:26:41,199
Please continue.

974
01:26:41,240 --> 01:26:44,359
Do you want us to perform the same piece or something else?

975
01:26:45,800 --> 01:26:47,239
Something else.

976
01:27:09,800 --> 01:27:11,839
Didn't her parents play beautifully?

977
01:27:14,960 --> 01:27:16,599
Yes, they did.

978
01:27:16,640 --> 01:27:18,559
It was wonderful.

979
01:27:24,280 --> 01:27:26,319
We love each other and we suit each other.

980
01:27:26,360 --> 01:27:29,159
And that's the reason why we've decided to leave the woods

981
01:27:29,200 --> 01:27:31,239
and stay together forever in the city.

982
01:27:40,920 --> 01:27:42,839
Tomorrow during the hunt,

983
01:27:42,880 --> 01:27:47,399
we're going to disappear and everyone will think we've been captured,

984
01:27:47,440 --> 01:27:50,959
and that we're going to be turned into dogs or canaries or something.

985
01:28:05,840 --> 01:28:07,639
I think the first thing I'm going to do

986
01:28:07,680 --> 01:28:10,159
when I get into the city is buy a bathrobe.

987
01:28:10,200 --> 01:28:14,519
And then we'll go to a pool with a high diving board, perfect for diving.

988
01:28:14,560 --> 01:28:17,199
"And we'll do lots of different things together,

989
01:28:17,240 --> 01:28:19,159
serious things, not silly ones,

990
01:28:19,200 --> 01:28:22,719
like go for walks in the park or play the guitar together."

991
01:28:30,600 --> 01:28:34,239
"Portofino. Italian fishing village and upmarket resort,

992
01:28:34,280 --> 01:28:36,279
famous for its picturesque harbour.

993
01:28:37,000 --> 01:28:38,919
Population: 439.

994
01:28:38,960 --> 01:28:40,879
Beaches nearby:

995
01:28:40,920 --> 01:28:45,079
Paraggi Beach, Camogli, Chiavari and Lavagna.

996
01:28:46,160 --> 01:28:50,319
Serifos: Greek island located in the western Cyclades."

997
01:29:09,800 --> 01:29:13,319
Can you imagine why I brought you to such a quiet place today?

998
01:29:20,160 --> 01:29:21,239
No.

999
01:29:22,480 --> 01:29:25,359
Because I think it's the perfect spot for your grave.

1000
01:30:12,000 --> 01:30:13,919
Now cover yourself with soil.

1001
01:30:14,520 --> 01:30:16,439
Use your hands.

1002
01:30:32,480 --> 01:30:34,199
Over your face too.

1003
01:30:34,240 --> 01:30:37,439
You wouldn't want your face to get eaten by dogs, would you?

1004
01:31:03,120 --> 01:31:06,119
If you die before me, I'll visit you as often as I can.

1005
01:31:06,160 --> 01:31:07,919
I promise.

1006
01:31:18,840 --> 01:31:21,439
I think we should leave right now.

1007
01:31:23,240 --> 01:31:25,399
The three of us coming here instead of

1008
01:31:26,200 --> 01:31:28,959
two or four is very dangerous.

1009
01:31:30,160 --> 01:31:32,439
Why didn't we think of that earlier?

1010
01:31:33,560 --> 01:31:36,079
Highly likely the doctor will suspect us.

1011
01:31:37,200 --> 01:31:40,559
I suggest that we leave the first chance we get.

1012
01:31:42,000 --> 01:31:43,919
Right now, in fact.

1013
01:31:44,800 --> 01:31:46,719
Don't be afraid.

1014
01:31:47,440 --> 01:31:49,359
No one will suspect a thing.

1015
01:31:50,280 --> 01:31:52,599
I bet you weren't expecting this surprise.

1016
01:31:54,280 --> 01:31:56,639
- Isn't it wonderful?
- Yes, it is.

1017
01:31:58,280 --> 01:32:01,399
Still, I'd like a few days just to think it over, so that

1018
01:32:02,520 --> 01:32:07,239
I could maybe have the surgery when we next come to the city.

1019
01:32:09,960 --> 01:32:11,879
What's there to think about?

1020
01:32:11,920 --> 01:32:15,359
If it's better to see clearly or to be short-sighted? Is that it?

1021
01:32:17,000 --> 01:32:19,319
That's absurd, you know that.

1022
01:32:19,360 --> 01:32:21,359
Anyway, this doctor is the best there is.

1023
01:32:21,400 --> 01:32:23,919
And it's really very difficult to get an appointment.

1024
01:32:23,960 --> 01:32:26,639
I called him months ago to get him to see you today.

1025
01:33:17,000 --> 01:33:18,919
She's blind.

1026
01:33:18,960 --> 01:33:20,879
Thank you.

1027
01:33:46,200 --> 01:33:48,879
Throw down your knife and stand up.

1028
01:33:51,520 --> 01:33:53,839
Why did you have to blind me?

1029
01:33:53,880 --> 01:33:55,759
You could have blinded him.

1030
01:33:56,320 --> 01:33:58,479
I have no idea what you're talking about.

1031
01:33:58,520 --> 01:34:00,519
The drugs are messing with your head.

1032
01:34:01,080 --> 01:34:05,159
If I were you, I would try and be a little braver about the whole thing.

1033
01:34:05,200 --> 01:34:06,959
Now get up and give me your knife

1034
01:34:08,120 --> 01:34:10,119
or I'll hit you and take it by force.

1035
01:34:11,160 --> 01:34:13,999
- Here I come.
- I swear I'm going to kill you.

1036
01:34:26,240 --> 01:34:28,999
Let go of my hair, you're hurting me.

1037
01:34:48,000 --> 01:34:51,079
Just think, that when someone goes blind

1038
01:34:52,240 --> 01:34:54,159
one of the other senses

1039
01:34:54,200 --> 01:34:56,119
is heightened.

1040
01:35:31,360 --> 01:35:33,359
You could also catch a dog in the woods

1041
01:35:33,400 --> 01:35:35,319
and train it to guide you.

1042
01:35:36,440 --> 01:35:38,359
Dogs can do that, you know.

1043
01:35:39,320 --> 01:35:41,239
I'll help you catch a dog myself.

1044
01:35:42,800 --> 01:35:45,919
Now calm down, or I'm going to leave you here

1045
01:35:45,960 --> 01:35:49,559
and I don't think you'll manage to find Meeting Point 2 on your own.

1046
01:36:02,560 --> 01:36:04,479
Are you enjoying the view?

1047
01:36:05,960 --> 01:36:07,279
Sure.

1048
01:36:09,640 --> 01:36:11,559
What happened to your hand?

1049
01:36:12,880 --> 01:36:16,919
I was cutting a tree branch with a knife and I cut myself by accident.

1050
01:36:16,960 --> 01:36:19,719
You look handsome today, did you get your hair cut?

1051
01:36:19,760 --> 01:36:21,479
Thank you.

1052
01:36:21,520 --> 01:36:23,439
No, I didn't get a haircut.

1053
01:36:23,480 --> 01:36:25,399
I'm going to get my hair cut today.

1054
01:36:25,440 --> 01:36:26,959
Look what I brought you.

1055
01:36:27,000 --> 01:36:30,199
Oh, thank you so much.
I'm so hungry, I'll eat it right away.

1056
01:36:30,240 --> 01:36:32,159
It's a bigger flashlight.

1057
01:36:32,200 --> 01:36:34,119
Oh, I'm sorry.

1058
01:36:34,160 --> 01:36:36,159
It's so big, I thought it was a rabbit.

1059
01:36:37,200 --> 01:36:39,239
The biggest flashlight I've ever seen.

1060
01:36:39,280 --> 01:36:40,519
Oh.

1061
01:36:41,440 --> 01:36:43,359
Are you ready for tonight?

1062
01:36:43,400 --> 01:36:45,319
Of course I am.

1063
01:36:48,880 --> 01:36:51,839
I want to tell you something but please don't be angry.

1064
01:36:52,680 --> 01:36:54,599
Ok. What's wrong?

1065
01:36:54,640 --> 01:36:56,559
I can't see anything.

1066
01:36:57,920 --> 01:36:59,839
I'm blind.

1067
01:36:59,880 --> 01:37:01,799
What do you mean?

1068
01:37:02,520 --> 01:37:06,039
There's no point in lying to you, you'll find out sooner or later.

1069
01:37:07,520 --> 01:37:09,639
Our leader blinded me in the city.

1070
01:37:10,760 --> 01:37:14,959
She must have realized that I love you and you love me

1071
01:37:15,000 --> 01:37:18,519
and that we were going to run away to the city together.

1072
01:37:20,840 --> 01:37:22,319
I'm sorry.

1073
01:37:24,440 --> 01:37:26,359
You can't see at all?

1074
01:37:27,680 --> 01:37:29,599
No, not at all.

1075
01:37:30,920 --> 01:37:33,039
And when you asked if I'd had my hair cut?

1076
01:37:35,880 --> 01:37:37,799
I was just saying that

1077
01:37:39,480 --> 01:37:41,839
so you wouldn't realise that I can't see.

1078
01:37:44,640 --> 01:37:46,559
I'm sorry.

1079
01:37:46,600 --> 01:37:48,279
Don't cry.

1080
01:37:48,320 --> 01:37:50,319
Crying will make your eyes hurt more.

1081
01:37:54,000 --> 01:37:55,679
We'll find a way.

1082
01:38:11,880 --> 01:38:13,799
What blood type are you?

1083
01:38:14,560 --> 01:38:15,599
B.

1084
01:38:27,000 --> 01:38:30,239
♪ From the first time I saw her, I knew she was the one

1085
01:38:31,120 --> 01:38:33,679
♪ As she stared in my eyes and smiled

1086
01:38:34,520 --> 01:38:37,199
♪ And her lips were the colour of roses

1087
01:38:38,240 --> 01:38:41,319
♪ That grew down the river all bloody and wild

1088
01:38:45,880 --> 01:38:48,439
Do you like berries?
Blueberries, blackberries?

1089
01:38:48,480 --> 01:38:50,399
- No, no.
- Mm.

1090
01:38:51,680 --> 01:38:53,599
Can you play the piano?

1091
01:38:54,400 --> 01:38:55,959
No.

1092
01:39:02,680 --> 01:39:04,239
Plastic cup.

1093
01:39:04,280 --> 01:39:06,199
That's right. Very good.

1094
01:39:09,040 --> 01:39:10,959
Do you speak German?

1095
01:39:13,480 --> 01:39:14,919
No.

1096
01:39:16,080 --> 01:39:17,999
I could teach you German.

1097
01:39:18,680 --> 01:39:21,679
But it would take at least a year for you to be able to speak the basics,

1098
01:39:21,720 --> 01:39:23,639
not fluently, so there's no point.

1099
01:39:23,680 --> 01:39:27,399
You know, German is one of the most difficult languages in the world to learn,

1100
01:39:27,440 --> 01:39:29,999
because its grammar is very complicated.

1101
01:39:33,440 --> 01:39:35,359
I brought you something.

1102
01:39:37,040 --> 01:39:38,839
It's a fish.

1103
01:39:38,880 --> 01:39:40,159
Oh.

1104
01:39:43,040 --> 01:39:45,599
♪ On the second day, I brought her a flower

1105
01:39:47,040 --> 01:39:50,119
♪ She was more beautiful than any woman I'd seen

1106
01:39:50,600 --> 01:39:53,799
♪ And I said, do you know where the wild roses grow

1107
01:39:54,240 --> 01:39:56,599
♪ So sweet and scarlet and free

1108
01:40:02,760 --> 01:40:04,079
Kiwi.

1109
01:40:04,120 --> 01:40:06,439
That's right, ten out of ten again.

1110
01:40:08,600 --> 01:40:10,519
Can I give you a kiss?

1111
01:40:13,680 --> 01:40:16,759
I can't thank you enough for all the activities and games

1112
01:40:16,800 --> 01:40:18,519
and for keeping me company,

1113
01:40:18,560 --> 01:40:21,079
but you know we can't do that anymore.

1114
01:40:24,680 --> 01:40:27,759
Would you like to play another round of Touch-Guess-Think-Win?

1115
01:40:27,800 --> 01:40:29,719
No, that's enough for today.

1116
01:40:31,760 --> 01:40:34,399
In any case, I've run out of things to test you with.

1117
01:40:34,440 --> 01:40:35,679
Oh.

1118
01:40:35,720 --> 01:40:37,639
Maybe tomorrow

1119
01:40:37,680 --> 01:40:39,919
or one of these days.

1120
01:40:39,960 --> 01:40:41,999
Tomorrow morning?

1121
01:40:42,040 --> 01:40:43,639
We'll see.

1122
01:40:47,800 --> 01:40:49,519
- Bye.
- Bye.

1123
01:41:21,280 --> 01:41:23,199
Good afternoon.

1124
01:41:25,000 --> 01:41:26,919
How are you?

1125
01:41:26,960 --> 01:41:28,279
Fine.

1126
01:41:29,640 --> 01:41:31,079
I'm hungry.

1127
01:41:31,920 --> 01:41:34,079
You haven't brought me a rabbit for days.

1128
01:41:35,400 --> 01:41:37,319
Or things for me to touch and guess.

1129
01:41:39,080 --> 01:41:40,999
I've got good news.

1130
01:41:41,040 --> 01:41:42,959
I've had a great idea.

1131
01:41:43,880 --> 01:41:45,559
Have you a minute?

1132
01:41:46,320 --> 01:41:48,239
What kind of idea?

1133
01:41:50,760 --> 01:41:52,679
I raise my left foot,

1134
01:41:54,320 --> 01:41:57,039
I bring my elbow to my knee and tap it twice.

1135
01:41:58,400 --> 01:42:00,959
I bring my foot to my knee and tap it three times.

1136
01:42:01,000 --> 01:42:03,159
I lie face down, I kneel down.

1137
01:42:04,560 --> 01:42:06,759
I touch my left cheek

1138
01:42:06,800 --> 01:42:08,439
and then lie face up.

1139
01:42:15,080 --> 01:42:17,199
Are you sure you're prepared to do that?

1140
01:42:22,560 --> 01:42:24,479
Yes, of course I'm sure.

1141
01:42:25,160 --> 01:42:27,079
I wouldn't propose it otherwise.

1142
01:42:31,880 --> 01:42:33,239
When?

1143
01:42:34,520 --> 01:42:36,039
Tomorrow.

1144
01:42:41,920 --> 01:42:43,759
Tomorrow.

1145
01:44:30,480 --> 01:44:32,399
We should speed up a little.

1146
01:44:36,160 --> 01:44:38,079
I can't go much faster.

1147
01:44:38,120 --> 01:44:40,279
The trousers are too tight. I'm sorry.

1148
01:44:41,520 --> 01:44:43,559
It was dark and I couldn't see clearly.

1149
01:44:43,600 --> 01:44:45,519
And I didn't have time to try them on.

1150
01:44:46,880 --> 01:44:48,439
I'm sorry.

1151
01:44:50,320 --> 01:44:52,079
Never mind.

1152
01:44:54,440 --> 01:44:56,359
There's a bus coming.

1153
01:45:20,000 --> 01:45:21,919
It was the hotel coach.

1154
01:45:22,680 --> 01:45:24,599
They didn't see us.

1155
01:45:48,720 --> 01:45:50,479
Profile.

1156
01:46:00,080 --> 01:46:01,679
Fingers.

1157
01:46:08,880 --> 01:46:10,439
Elbows.

1158
01:46:29,440 --> 01:46:31,439
Would you like me to show you my belly?

1159
01:46:31,480 --> 01:46:32,919
No.

1160
01:46:33,560 --> 01:46:35,479
I, I remember your belly very well.

1161
01:46:38,680 --> 01:46:40,279
Smile.

1162
01:46:58,320 --> 01:47:02,039
Can I have a knife and fork, please?
Not a butter knife, a steak knife.

1163
01:47:02,080 --> 01:47:03,359
Certainly.

1164
01:47:16,200 --> 01:47:17,679
Thank you.

1165
01:47:26,560 --> 01:47:28,479
I'm going to do it with a knife.

1166
01:47:29,040 --> 01:47:30,959
Do you want me to come with you?

1167
01:47:31,000 --> 01:47:32,919
I'd rather you didn't.

1168
01:47:33,680 --> 01:47:35,599
Don't worry.

1169
01:47:35,640 --> 01:47:38,799
It's strange at first, but then you get used to it.

1170
01:47:39,840 --> 01:47:41,879
And your other senses are heightened...

1171
01:47:41,920 --> 01:47:44,399
touch, for example, and hearing.

1172
01:47:45,480 --> 01:47:47,239
I know.

1173
01:47:56,680 --> 01:47:58,599
I won't be long.

1174
01:49:22,480 --> 01:49:24,399
Thank you very much.

