Captioning made possible by
Warner bros.
We want Neil! We want Neil!
A short time ago,
our CBS
vote profile analysis
declared bingham
the winner,
and now nbc and abc
computers agree.
While Neil Atkinson
has not yet conceded...
How's your sister?
She's fine, thank you.
...newly incorporated
suburbs.
Woman:
That's madam sundar's.
Jerry...How you doing?
I thought you were in Philly.
I came back for
the victory speech.
Victory? Come on, I want you
to meet somebody, Jerry.
Neil, we'd better
go down now.
Let them through.
Let them through,
please.
Excuse us.
Howard, get the elevator.
You got any
hors d'oeuvres left?
We're with you.
Don't worry about it.
[Cheering and applause]
They, uh...
They said
when we got into this,
we didn't have a chance.
[Groaning loudly]
They said there was
nothing we could do...
And, uh, and now, the count
has gone against us.
Well, whatever that means.
Well...I'm not sorry,
and I hope
you're not sorry.
No!
I think--I think
we've proved our point.
We may have lost
our personal campaign--
that's not important.
What really matters is...
A little sauce
for the road.
Next time,
we'll get a live one.
Well, I knew we didn't
have a chance...
Your golf clubs
are in my car.
Yeah. Hey, let's
clear out anyway.
Let's go
to the Bahamas.
Hey, big Luke,
have a good night?
Yeah, we took
2 out of 3.
That's not bad for
an off-year election.
Because--
[cheering and applause]
You should be glad
you weren't running
this campaign, huh?
It was in the cards.
Hell of a guy, though.
Oh, yeah, nice guys.
He never had a chance.
Wait a minute.
I want to talk to you.
...until we've licked
the conditions
that brought us
into this.
I--
[Crowd cheering]
Luke, what's your hurry?
I'll walk you out.
We're supposed to have
a drink with Forbes, right?
Forbes wants to talk
about California.
You got something going
in California?
Maybe.
Democrats should nominate
jarmon themselves out there,
they're so afraid of him.
Am I right?
You never know.
What's this?
Thank you, sir.
The son, huh?
Guy I knew at Stanford.
McKay's son. Yeah,
I saw all this stuff--
the legal aid bit.
Doesn't prove
he's got kishkes.
Nobody's going to beat
jarmon, Luke.
Tell me something else
I don't know.
[Men speaking spanish]
Occupation charges?
Por favor, por favor.
What are these
occupation charges
he keeps talking about?
He's talking about
storage charges.
It's not enough
to sock it to us
for 3 times
what it's worth.
He wants to charge us
for not getting
our car back?
You got it.
That's beautiful.
Beautiful.
Bill McKay?
[Mechanic
speaking spanish]
Marvin Lucas.
[Speaking spanish]
I thought a beard
was taboo in politics.
It is.
I got thrown out
of superior court.
He won't budge.
Ask him if knows what
a license renewal hearing is.
I'll try.
What happened?
They threw me out.
He wouldn't let me start.
Told me it was a matter
for the federal courts.
Go back
with a petition.
Oh, Christ. We've had
3 months' worth of briefs.
The watershed thing's
too important.
Anything I can
help you with?
No, I'll wait
for McKay.
Those courts
aren't going to move.
They'll have to move.
Senator.
You have
thought about it.
You know what I see?
A stampede of
18-year-old party hacks
reacting to a lot
of magazine publicity.
Of course, I have talked
to some people about it.
What do you
think of jarmon?
Smooth character.
You think someone
ought to take him on?
Some big-time
democrat.
They're all afraid of him.
I guess you're
up against it, then.
Unless we find
something new,
someone who has something
he believes in.
Whatever that means.
Someone who can
spend spend a whole year
telling people what
he thinks is important.
Not that way,
he doesn't.
Not in any
political campaign.
Oh, it doesn't
have to work that way.
Don't tell me
how it works.
I watched my dad
for 20 years.
That was no good, huh?
Yeah,
it was good for him.
He loved it.
He got be governor
John j. McKay.
What good it did
for anybody else,
I don't know.
I'm not talking
about him.
I'm talking about someone
who can call his own shots.
This stuff
you call politics?
Politics is bullshit.
I was wondering
what it was.
Hey, I have to go home
for about an hour.
Janice, did Nancy
drop the car off?
No.
Didn't she call?
I can drive you home.
O.K.
I'll wait outside.
No. These--these
have to be signed
on the bottom,
and then just give
them to Donna, o.K.?
See you later.
You could go on
filing lawsuits
in the sticks
for a hundred years.
Or you could take
a year and lay out
a real position
for yourself
in this state.
It's a question of--
hi, kid.
Marvin, this is
my wife Nancy.
Nancy, this is
Marvin Lucas.
Don't let us
interrupt.
Want a beer?
Yeah.
[McKay whistling a tune]
Here you go.
Here's some goodies.
But the contacts,
for example--
you're going to
meet people
who know how
to get things done.
Hey, listen--
it's a matter
of resources.
I just worked straight
through the weekend,
20 straight hours...
And I loved
every minute of it.
So why do I need
what you're offering?
I'm happy.
You're happy.
Yeah.
Clams are happy.
[Chuckles]
What did
you accomplish?
Would you like a list?
Yeah.
You saved some trees.
You got a clinic open.
That's no good?
Does that
make you feel good?
Not bad.
Meanwhile, jarmon
sits on his committees
and carves up the land,
the oil, and the taxes.
You ever seen him?
Have you ever
seen him operate?
Marvin...
Yeah.
What's in it for you?
Oh, uh...
An air card,
a phone card,
1,000 bucks a week.
And that's all?
Well...
Marvin wants me
to go into politics.
What else is new?
For what office?
Senator.
Well, why not?
If he really
put his mind to it.
That means you'd
have to register.
He never has,
you know.
Hasn't been any reason.
I hope you
keep that a secret.
Unless you
took it seriously.
Look, the point is,
you can go with the
things you believe in.
For openers,
you've got credibility.
You've got the name.
What do you mean,
the name?
You're not going to bring
my father into this.
O.K., we won't.
He's got the looks.
Right.
And he's got the power.
What does that mean?
You know
what that means.
No, I don't.
Well...If you gentlemen
will excuse me,
um, I have to remove
some film from the bathtub
before it rots.
You're saying I can
say what I want,
do what I want,
go where I please.
Hmm?
That's right.
Here's
your guarantee.
I lose?
That's it.
So what are you
worried about?
You're free, McKay.
You don't have a chance,
so say what you want.
It's just between
you and the public.
The question is...
Whether you can put
your ass on the line.
No. The question is
whether it's worth it.
Well...
Thanks for the beer.
But I remember this...
I remember my mom and dad
went through the 1930s
without welfare,
without poverty programs.
Why, none of us kids
even had a social worker.
[Crowd laughs]
How did we do it?
Well, ladies, excuse me,
but we worked our butts off.
But I tell you this,
good people,
that Crocker jarmon
still believes
that individuals
are responsible
for themselves.
And so does the vast majority
of the American people!
And that's why we're
going to tell big brother
to get lost!
[Cheering and whistling]
The solution to welfare
is not more welfare.
It's more enterprise,
more industry,
and more jobs.
Now, there are those
who say to industry,
don't build,
don't develop,
don't cut
a single tree,
or you'll destroy
our watershed, and so on.
But I know when
the time comes for building,
we will build, because
building means jobs.
And...
We'll find a way
to love mother nature
and preserve her...
Without
going to extremes.
[Applause]
You think I'm mean?
No!
Well, if I am,
I've spent the last
18 years in the senate
being a meanie,
and if need be,
I will spend
another 18 years
working to keep this country
healthy and growing
and booming
into the future!
[Band plays marching song]
Thanks for coming.
Oh, you did, huh,
you old devil?
I wish I could, but you know,
the old ball and chain.
How are you?
Senator,
good to see you.
Harry rich.
Hello, Harry.
How's business?
Fine, fine.
Good. Good, good, good.
Senator jarmon,
remember our
little toddy?
Well, hello there, toddy.
He's an ugly little cuss.
My--
what's that?
My daddy thinks
you should run
for vice president.
Get this child
to a violin.
Remember me?
Why, sure do, son.
How's the old throwing arm?
Oh, please, please.
I'm a married man.
Woman:
Senator!
[Clears throat]
And rolling.
Today, at 10:00, I filed
the papers to enter my name
in the Democratic primary
as a candidate for
the United States senate.
[Telephone rings]
Any questions?
Community legal service.
Why are you doing this?
Because I don't think
the incumbent
is really in touch
with how people live
or what they need.
That's what I tried
to do as a lawyer,
and that's what
I hope to go on doing
as a candidate.
How do you feel
about welfare?
We subsidize trains.
We subsidize planes.
Why not
subsidize people?
What about busing?
What about it?
What's your stand on it?
I'm for it.
That's a first.
Reporter: What would you do
about property taxes?
I don't know.
Jesus.
[Laughter]
What is
your platform?
I'm sor--what do
you mean, platform?
Bill, would you mind
moving over there
with your office staff?
No...Sorry.
Any other questions?
Why won't you
move over there
with your staff?
They're not
responsible for me.
I dig it. It's raw,
but I eat it up.
A lot of work
to be done, my friend,
but I get the feeling
you know where
you're going.
[Intercom buzzes]
I don't.
Yeah? Ha ha.
No, no, no, honey.
I told you,
5 to the party.
One more, we got
to use another car,
so we blow
the whole conversation.
Bill is concerned
over what kind
of control we'll have
over which
of your commercials
will go out over
the tube, et cetera.
Luke knows this.
He's worked with me before.
He knows
I checked you out.
Bottom line is I like
what you stand for.
You got balls.
Otherwise
I wouldn't take you on.
We take my crew,
we get you doing your
thing, and that's it.
Thanks, honey. Huh?
You just get it on
with the people.
Let me worry about
the cameras.
I come back in a week,
I show you my stuff,
you see for yourself
if I sold you out.
Yeah, but I have
final say, though.
What?
I have final say.
You don't like
what you see, you pull it.
It's your money,
my friend. That fair?
We'll see.
But I'll tell you
one thing...
Tell me one thing.
You might just
make it, my friend.
People are going
to take a look
at our stuff
and see a guy
who's got guts.
They're going to take
a look at the crock
and think maybe he can't
get it up anymore.
That's what
it's all about, huh?
[Chuckles]
Forget I even said it.
I want to show you
one thing over there.
Keep an eye on this.
I think I got something
for you.
My friends, the issue...
[Intercom buzzes]
Is whether we are
going to hold on
to the most
successful philosophy
in the history
of mankind
or whether we are
going to trade it,
trade it in
for a collectivist state.
You see that?
He works
from a stage pose.
How many politicians
do you know
can look straight
in the camera
without
coming off shifty-eyed?
This philosophy
is the work of
free individuals...
Corny, right?
But watch--
it's what he wants.
He's a master.
Just watch him.
...has made
this nation great,
but we will not
continue in greatness
unless we resolve
to protect our way of life.
Crocker jarmon...
He's been good
for California.
Think about it,
my friends.
The preceding has been
a political message--
we'll label him
"Mr. geritol,"
and you'll do the
"I'm my own man" bit.
For starters,
we got to cut your hair
and 86 the sideburns.
All right, let's go.
Crocker jarmon has
spoken with you often.
Crocker jarmon has fought
to make this country sound.
I think we must
have the money
on its way in
before we start
sending it out
the other end.
This was 12 years ago,
doing the man-of-the-people
number.
Guy can go
anywhere he wants.
Crocker jarmon
has fought
to make
this country strong.
...who is one of
the greatest generals
in the history
of the United States--
general eisenhower--
and no one hates war
more than a military man.
There may a day come
when China should
enter the u.N.,
but I think they must
earn this entrance.
Let's keep America
strong and sound.
Crocker jarmon
trusts people,
and people trust--
the guy has sincerity.
There's nothing
new in the world,
except maybe you.
[Intercom buzzes]
The idea is to get you
in completely natural
situations.
Honey, honey--
no, hold all my calls
for 5 minutes. Yeah.
Go on, follow him.
Not too close.
Go shake some hands.
What?
Just say hello.
Hello. Bill McKay--
running for U.S. senate.
Bill McKay--I'm running
for U.S. senate.
Hello, I'm bill McKay.
Hello. Bill McKay--
running for U.S. senate.
How are you?
Here, like
a pamphlet, sir?
Hello, bill mc--
bill McKay--U.S. senate.
How are you?
What are you
trying to do?
I'm trying to talk to you.
What about?
About how the economy
throws everything
on the backs
of the working man--
interest rates--
I don't know--
rents,
food costs--
all go up faster
than your paychecks.
That's very interesting.
Most people think because
you've got a union
that you've got it made.
They do?
Yeah. But you still get
laid off, don't you?
Yeah, well...
I got to go now.
All right.
Take it easy.
Uh, hi.
Hello. Bill McKay--
running for
U.S. senate.
[Classical music playing]
Nancy: Bill?
Yeah.
You better hurry,
or we'll be late
for the banquet.
We don't have
very much time.
Would you hand me
that earring there?
Hey...Let's go for a walk
on the beach.
In your tux?
No. We could talk
or something.
Bill...
Come on.
We could talk on the way
to the banquet.
Or we could not
go to the banquet.
I just want to talk--
bill, don't do this!
Oh...
They cut your hair.
Let me see it.
Really. Turn--
let me see it.
I really like--
bill...
Bill...
[Applause and cheering]
Hello. How are you?
I'm sorry.
We're late.
Look, uh, I wrote down
some stuff for you.
You want to go over it?
No, I got it.
Here.
O.K. Then, uh,
on to the ballroom.
All right,
I'll do my part.
O.K.
Hey.
Bill.
What do you make
of this evening?
I really can't say
because I haven't...
Thank you.
[Microphone feedback]
Moving right along,
I see we have
one more candidate,
and I happen to know
this man personally.
So I welcome
this opportunity
to say a few words
about him.
I can say to you
unequivocally
he is the only man
in California
who at his age
has already had experience
in higher office.
He used to have
his diapers changed there.
[Laughter]
I know he looks
a little bit young
to be present tonight,
but don't worry, he's got
a note from his teacher.
[Laughter]
I don't mean that.
I really don't.
He is a fresh, new talent,
because 2 weeks ago,
he was discovered
on a stool in schwab's...
Seriously, folks,
you'd better watch your step
when he comes out here
because he's a man
who shoots from the hip,
and a man who's hip
when he shoots.
Join me in welcoming
Mr. bill McKay!
Don't get
my notes messed up.
I've got to wrap it up.
I guess...
I guess it is
pretty funny.
In fact, when you think
about it, the whole idea
of 2 guys
making decisions
for 20 million people,
that's pretty funny.
But, still,
you can't laugh too much
when you think
what's at stake.
The fact is,
in the next few elections,
we're going to decide just
what it's going to be like
to live in this country.
O.K., cut.
We got all we need.
Whether people
will have more power
to shape their own lives.
Or whether we're going
to lose that power.
I know that anyone
can stand up
and say that much.
It's the details
that's hard,
just how you get
people involved.
Our lives are more
and more determined
by forces that overwhelm
the individual.
I don't know. Maybe...
Maybe these questions
can't be raised
in a political campaign.
Maybe people
aren't ready to listen.
But I'm going to try,
and I hope that you'll
support that effort
and at least give me
the benefit of the doubt.
Thank you.
Mr. McKay, your speech
was wonderful.
I enjoyed
every moment of it.
You'll be
a wonderful senator.
Thank you very much.
Mrs. McKay.
Yes. Hello.
Oh, you're lovely.
Of all the candidates'
wives,
you are the loveliest.
It's a pleasure
to meet you.
Thank you. You look
lovely, too. Thank you.
Hello, sir.
Mrs. McKay, I really
enjoyed being with you
here this evening.
I'm glad you came.
Thank you very much.
It's a thrill
to meet you.
What's the pin?
Oh, this is our laborers
international pin.
I'm sorry?
The laborers
international pin.
How do you do,
Mrs. McKay?
I love your dress.
Oh, thank you
very much.
Mr. McKay, I've
heard it all before,
but never put
quite like that.
You were great.
Thank you very much.
Right. You are.
Mr.--I'm sorry.
I can't--
medina.
Medina. And you were
with your wife.
I remember that
very well.
See, I have a terrific memory.
You didn't know that.
Did you enjoy the speech?
It was terrific.
Good. Good. Mr. hodely...
As for credibility...
As I understand it,
it depends on whether
you mean what you say.
You say you wouldn't
draw the line in Vietnam.
Well, then just
where do you propose
to stand up
against the communists,
on the beaches
in Santa Monica?
I...
Well, that depends
on the circumstances.
There's no set answer
for that one.
Well, hold it.
There's no set answer.
Well, that's honest,
all right,
but that leaves us
nowhere.
But it's not
a serious question.
It's exactly what you're
going to get asked
tomorrow in long beach.
You got an answer
for him, Corey?
Well, he could say,
uh...
Japan or India
or countries with certain
kinds of governments
which legitimately
request our help.
You're speech-writing.
This isn't the cow palace,
this is practice
for a local TV interview.
A lot of people
in this state
still expect an invasion
in Pasadena.
Then we'll fight 'em
in the rose bowl.
Frankly, I don't think
this is a gag-writer
situation.
Well, I can kill myself,
I suppose.
Look, he could refer them
to our foreign policy
position paper.
What position paper?
We'll have it written
in 2 weeks.
I'll tell you
what I think--
hold on.
Come on,
what am I here for?
I've got it.
Will you shut up?
McKay says he will not
let them land
on the beaches
of Santa Monica
because the parking problem
is bad enough already.
[Laughter]
O.K., that's it.
Thank God
for small favors.
O.K., that's it.
It never hurts
to toss one off.
But does he really
want to say that?
Next question.
Mr. McKay,
what do you think
about
legalized abortion?
Ah, good question.
I'm for it.
I think every woman
should have that right.
Wait a minute, bill.
You can't put it that way.
That's what I think.
Well, it's not going
to be understood
without a hell of
a long explanation,
so how about this
for the time being?
Uh, just say
it's worth studying.
O.K. I'll think
about it.
All right.
Uh, Mr. McKay--bill...
We notice your father
hasn't said one word
about your campaign.
Is he sitting it out?
Uh, let's have
that again.
Is your father sitting out
your campaign?
I'm running on
my own hook.
[Everyone talking at once]
Oh, to hell
with it.
Where's he going?
That's all for now.
I said
that's all for now.
We're going to have to give
a lot more consideration
to his appearance.
If that's the way
he's going to be--
Lou.
We got a stand set up
right over there.
Just pull up behind it.
Hey, I don't want to
drive up in this tank.
Stop here.
That's a good idea.
He's going on foot.
Come on.
I don't know what good
this is going to do.
It's good for him.
Folks, I want you
to meet bill McKay.
He's running for
the United States senate.
Would you like to
step up here, please?
No, no.
Hi, red.
Hi.
Can I have a sip?
Do you do this often?
That'd be great if he
were running for alderman.
I'm not running
for alderman.
Well, then what are
you doing down here?
Like the leaflet says,
I'm here because
I'm running for senator.
I wanted
to come here today
because I used
to spend some time
around this place
a few years ago.
In those days,
you could swim here.
It was before they
turned this harbor
into a chemistry set.
In those days,
there used to be
a beach right there
where that
parking lot is.
Anyhow, coming out here
used to be something
pretty special.
Today, it wasn't.
It wasn't so special.
You know, I look
around this beach,
and you know
what I see?
Freaks.
[Cheering]
You know it.
I see lost people.
Ha ha. Oh, really?
Maybe I am middle-class,
in a way,
but I didn't
find that out today.
I found that out
working with people
who are trying
to make sure
their kids have enough
to eat tomorrow morning.
Hey, this is good.
We can certainly use
the pollution angle.
Yeah. I'll speed it up.
I don't know.
Maybe we can use a line
or two out of context.
Look what he says.
[Rewinding]
Instead of building
atomic reactors,
you could clean up
every river,
and instead
of drilling for oil...
Hey, that's too much.
I got union problems
already.
O.K. How fast
do you need these spots?
June. He's the only name
in the primary,
so we're not going to
waste too much money.
And we can fire
the board of regents.
How can a senator fire
the board of regents?
It's meaningless.
It sounds good.
Anything else?
Don't worry.
It'll cut together.
Wait till we get
the stuff at watts. Trust me.
Gentlemen, this way, please.
This way.
We're going to proceed
5 blocks
to our watts headquarters.
Question--could jarmon
walk through watts?
Is your father going
to join the campaign?
Pardon me?
Is your father going
to join the campaign?
Whether he does
or not,
I can tell you
what's basic
for the ghetto--
it's a scandal.
There's no hospital here.
There's no
on-the-job training
for medical aides.
They have
no housing program--
excuse me just a sec.
They have
no housing program.
no public transportation.
There's
no birth-control centers.
Tell it, bro.
So what else is new?
Gentlemen, there
will be a cookout
in the park
at 3 P.M.
Hello.
Shake hands with me.
Gentlemen, gentlemen.
Hey, brother.
How ya doin'?
Bill McKay.
You the golden wonder
of the west.
I wouldn't
say that.
Well, what do you
think about my dog?
Well, that's--
that's a fine dog.
Gimme five!
Huh?
Hey, man.
Hey, hey. Five!
That's my man.
But lookee here.
Lookee here.
What about my dog?
What do you think
about my dog?
That's a fine dog.
Ooh, now,
what have we here?
Gentlemen, gentlemen.
Excuse us.
Why are you so eager
to defeat jarmon?
Because I think
the people
should be able
to decide
for themselves.
Let them make
the comparison.
What does that mean?
Peace and "up yours."
Hey, look at that.
You used to play ball,
didn't you, bill?
Yeah.
Well, come on.
Shoot a few.
No, look, it's just
on the other side.
Come on.
It's a great idea.
Be fast, bill.
Be fast.
Yay!
Come on.
It's a good idea.
Great idea.
Get out of here!
Come on.
Hey, bill,
look at this.
3 calls
from the chronicle.
God said it!
God means it!
Repent of all sins!
Walter, here at the McKay
campaign headquarters,
they're celebrating
his victory in the primary.
A winner, like
his famous father.
He's assumed
a strong lead
over a field of virtually
unknown Democratic candidates
in the Democratic
senatorial primary.
Mr. McKay...
Your victory
was predicted.
Could it have been
any sort
of surprise?
Everything that happens
is a complete surprise
to me.
¶ The power, the glory ¶
¶ as said in the west ¶
¶ the voters
are shouting ¶
McKay is the best!
¶ Win with all the... ¶
bill, you got to get
on the horn to Mrs. York.
She won't talk
to anybody but you.
Is she on now?
Yes.
Bill, Natalie wood's here.
We got to get
some pictures.
Oh, really?
Yes. Nancy, come on.
¶ He'll deal with issues
that have weight ¶
¶ McKay's the people's
candidate ¶
¶ to the senate,
here we co-o-ome ¶
I'd like you
to meet bill McKay.
Hello. How are you?
And Nancy McKay.
This is my wife Nancy.
Hello.
The campaign, the dinners
that you've hosted...
It's a pleasure.
I admire what you stand for.
Oh. Thank you.
Mrs. barron,
have you met...
Do you like fruit?
Yes, I do. Do you?
Oh, yeah,
I like strawberries.
Miss wood, I'm--
do you like yogurt?
I'm Arthur
fleischer.
You do?
We met at
the peace seminar
in Santa Barbara.
Oh, yes.
I'm on leave
of absence to work
on foreign policy
aspects
of this campaign.
That's...Wonderful.
It's
very interesting,
you know. It's--
Arthur, you're
needed over here.
Natalie wood: You know
what you should do?
Bill. Mr. McKay? Bill?
Mr. McKay?
Oh, you
just throw it in?
Mr. McKay, we've got
to get on the phone.
Could you move
it through?
If you don't
have much time--
we've got to get
to the phone.
Anyway, nice
to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
She's been waiting
on the phone
a half an hour, bill.
What's her name?
York.
Ah.
¶ We love him,
we need him ¶
¶ we know
that he'll win... ¶
I know. I know.
¶ I say, he will win ¶
¶ we're all for McKay ¶
¶ he can do it today ¶
¶ he can show you
a better way... ¶
thank you.
I hope so, too. Bye.
Well, that's it.
I don't know what
her name is,
but she's sending a check.
Yeah. I must
talk with you.
Mr. McKay? Hi.
I'm your coordinator
from San Pedro.
Hi.
Hey.
Hello, bill.
I'm really sorry.
I'm very sorry.
We need the room.
Bill...
Bill, can you
get in here?
Honey, can you
get that later?
Just wait right here.
Have you seen these?
Have you seen
these figures?
You seen
the breakdown?
You want me to look
at these now? Oh, sorry.
Oh. Ah.
Look, you
can still read--
I got it.
I'm a little
disappointed.
[Knock on door]
Uh, yoo-hoo.
Why? I've got 47%
of the primary field.
Yeah,
but if you look
at the projection
on the printout,
it adds up to 32%
in the election.
So?
So if those figures
hold until November,
it'll be jarmon--68,
McKay--32.
[Knocking]
[Doorknob rattles]
I thought I was
supposed to lose.
Well, now
I'm telling you
you'll be wiped out.
You'll
be humiliated.
That wasn't part
of the deal.
[Knocking]
Somebody's in here!
Maybe I should just quit,
go back--
you can't quit.
Don't be ridiculous.
You can't go back.
You're the Democratic
nominee for senator.
You make that sound
like a death sentence.
No, no, no.
All that means
is that you're just
reaching the people
who agree with you
already.
Now we have
to go after the rest.
Yeah? And what
does that mean?
Well, it means more
in terms of TV,
for one thing.
Like what? I already
agreed to the--
[banging on door]
Get your ass
out of here!
Look, there's
a lot to be done.
We're just starting.
Such as?
[Banging on door]
Goddamn it!
I can't think.
Can't we talk about
this in the morning?
All right. O.K.
I'll go along
to Pasadena,
and we'll talk
in the car.
O.K., but I want
to work this out.
We will.
Bill McKay
is one Californian
who remembers
what kind of a state we had
before the polluters
took over.
You can take some of
the gas and the oil taxes,
and you can clean up
this harbor,
and you can get
some real law enforcement
on that sewage dump
across the bay.
Let's put it together
and give California
another chance.
For a better way,
bill McKay in the senate.
I feel that a lot
of the politicians
don't talk to them.
There's no dialogue at all
whatsoever with the people.
People don't listen,
and the politicians
don't talk.
They make sound.
[Horn honks]
It's just noise.
I think the government
has overlooked
that one point.
Bill McKay
believes in our system
and wants to make it work
for all of us.
And the food costs rise.
To put some real
faith and hope
back into government.
For a better way in
the U.S. senate, bill McKay.
[Upbeat music plays]
If we're ever going
to tackle the problems
of the 1970s,
we need all the strength
a young man can give.
Bill McKay has it.
The conviction to push
for real solutions
to the problems
of unemployment,
poverty, and crime,
the determination
to put some action back
into the United States
senate,
the energy to fight
the special interests
on behalf of all the people
of California.
For a better way...
Bill McKay.
I think they're
awfully good, Howard.
Thanks, Howard.
It comes at a good time.
Hey, just
for the hell of it,
what happened to the bit
about the health clinics?
You want
health clinics?
I'll give you
health clinics.
I'm bill McKay.
I'm running
for U.S. senate.
[Babies crying loudly]
See? They're
not responding.
What about
what I'm saying?
What about it?
3 hours?
Well, that's just
totally unacceptable.
Oh, what do you
know about it?
You don't understand--
I'll tell you
what I do know--
if we can put
a man on the moon,
we can put--
oh, I don't believe it!
There's got to be
more jobs, too.
We can start
training people
for medical careers
right in their
own communities.
[Babies crying]
Grim scene, baby.
Grim scene.
Look at that. You're off
into other issues now.
You look uptight
and uncool.
Nobody's listening,
and nobody's diggin' you.
Ha ha ha.
Ha ha ha!
Aside from that, though,
it's a great bit.
Oh, yeah.
And so the money bill
now goes to committee.
Despite
the continued dryness
and the threat
of new fires,
it was politics as usual
around the state today.
Crocker jarmon took
his campaign to long beach,
where he visited the rams
on their practice field,
and he had a present
for the coach.
Van, I was just
presenting the coach
with a copy
of life magazine
because they have it
here in this issue
on the newsstands today
how much it meant
when I went down
to the locker room
with my little
grandson Dickie
and we saw all
those big, tough guys
down on their knees...
Shooting crap.
In a simple moment
of prayer.
You should
get some sleep.
This TV stuff
isn't working.
Give it a chance.
I'm not talking
to anyone,
and I'm not
saying anything.
The point is,
you're showing your face.
That's what we
have to sell first.
Oh! Sell.
Exposure.
You might want to take
a little glance
at these polls klein
had done in key counties.
In every one,
you're up 3-4 points.
You know what
I'm going to do?
Learn something
about economics?
I'm going to challenge
jarmon to a crapshoot.
[Sighs]
Crapshoot is a matter of
individual enterprise.
Crapshoot made
this country great.
God made this country great.
God shoots crap.
My little...
Grandson's playing it.
Los Angeles
international airport.
For those of you going on
with us to San Diego,
our scheduled
departure time will be...
Got to get off.
There's been a change of plan.
Get off? What about
the group in San Diego?
Never mind that.
We got a fire in Malibu.
It's perfect.
Looking down at a major
brush and forest...
It looks to me like about
a 30-square-mile area
on both sides
of the Mountain.
[Siren]
There's the nbc
helicopter.
Yeah, that means that
the wire service guys
are up there, too.
We can hit them
on 3 points--
the fire-disaster
insurance,
the watershed stuff,
and the fire-prevention
program we talked about.
I want to do
the watershed
because fires like this
come from neglect.
Yeah, but disaster
insurance is now.
These people
are losing their homes
and their possessions,
and the companies
won't underwrite them.
That damn jarmon
is against the
federal government
even getting
into it.
Don't turn this
into an issues thing.
It'll look
like you're trying
to make political capital
out of a fire.
I'm not making political
capital out of it.
O.K., but don't hit them
over the head with it.
Closer, will ya?
Closer!
Start with
the watershed,
and then go into
insurance, o.K.?
O.K. All right.
Bill wants to talk
to some of the firemen.
Bill, over here.
O.K., fellas,
bill McKay here.
Bill McKay.
That's it,
bill McKay.
[Everyone talking
at once]
We've lost
over 40 homes so far.
You want to make
a statement?
Yes, I do.
To me, this is a result
of what we've been
talking about.
That is, when you
erode the watershed
with large-scale,
indiscriminate road-building
and development
so that you lose
the root system
that keeps the water
in the ground
in the first place,
that's why this brush
all dries out.
Of course, you need...
[Helicopter drowns him out]
Do you know
who that is?
McKay: Yeah.
Smokey the bear.
All right, gentlemen,
can we have your attention?
The senator's going
to make a statement.
Here. This way, please.
Hello. How are you?
I'm still hoping for
a chance to debate you.
Don't blame you
a bit.
Hi, Jack.
Glad to see
you got your wet suit on.
All right, now...
I'm, uh...
Everybody set?
I will make this
very brief.
I have been on the phone
with the president,
and one hour from now,
Malibu will be declared
a national disaster area,
and I am assured
that within
the next 24 hours,
this fire will be checked.
Our concern is to make
absolutely certain
that these disasters do
not occur in the future.
That is why I am
very happy to see
that Mr. McKay
took the trouble
to be on hand
for this announcement.
When I leave here,
I am flying
back to Washington
to introduce the jarmon
watershed bill,
which will
include provisions
for federally financed
disaster insurance.
I think I can guarantee
swift passage of that bill
through the senate
finance committee
because I happen to be
chairman of that committee.
So, we are doing
all we can,
and I want to add
my personal thanks
to all
of the heroic volunteers
who have risked
their lives
in this holocaust
to save the homes
of their neighbors.
Your actions
and your efforts
have been an inspiration
to us all.
So I say goodbye,
God bless you,
and good luck.
Thank you,
senator.
Reporter: Do you have
a statement?
What's
your reaction?
Any comments?
Any comment on that?
What about
the watershed bill?
I haven't read the bill.
I, uh--
sounds like
a good proposal.
Look, it's an emergency.
I welcome any action at all.
Uh, Mr. jarmon
says that--
[crowd cheers]
Says that he's taking
his case, uh, to the public.
Well, then why does
he refuse to meet me
in open debate?
Jarmon's the one!
[Crowd heckling]
Mr. jarmon says the economy
is moving again.
Then why is my office
in San Diego
filled with people
looking for work?
Now, I say there's got
to be a better way.
We have to retool--
[microphone feedback]
Some of our industry.
We have to build
our strengths--
[microphone squeals]
And make things
that people can use.
[Microphone squeals]
I'm sorry.
I'll have it
fixed in a second.
Man:
Here, just like this.
[Microphone squeals]
Thank you.
Man: McKay--
man: Jarmon! This is
the one you want!
Man: Right!
Just about got it.
Woman: Jarmon!
It doesn't
matter, right?
Never mind.
It doesn't matter.
Bill, I'm sorry,
but this has got
to be lunch.
Now, look, jenkin's
got 500 farmers
in a high school gym
over in Bakersfield.
That's where
we're going?
Yeah.
They're furious
about the whole
farm program,
and jarmon's
the one
that got it
out of committee.
A better way...
And that way is to subsidize
the small farmer directly,
rather than pay the huge
agricultural combine
to wipe him out.
[Sighs]
[Man clears throat]
Are there any questions?
[Chair squeaks]
I'd be happy to respond
to anything that's
on your minds.
[Clears throat]
Any comments?
Suggestions?
Dirty jokes?
Damn that jenkin!
Why didn't he call?
Why couldn't he just
pick up a phone
and say that
there's no one there?
He was probably trying
to get through.
Where is he now,
off with some
farmer's daughter?
You hear about
Evans and novak?
I was just about
to tell him.
It's going to be in every paper
in the state tomorrow morning.
Just leave us alone,
please?
We've got to counteract
this now, or we're dead.
Now, those guys want
to talk to the candidate.
They got to file
in half an hour,
and they want
a statement.
The statement is,
it's not true.
We'll give them
more tomorrow.
No. I can't go--
the candidate is not
going to comment
until tomorrow.
That's it.
It's not
good enough, Luke.
Look, you want me
to pull the old man
out of my back pocket?
Now get out there and
tell them what you can.
And don't come back.
Bill...Those giants
of journalism,
Evans and novak,
have issued a--
a column...
Saying that your dad
is really for jarmon.
You're kidding.
No. It's coming out
tomorrow morning.
Uh, I'll get you
more in a minute.
Tom brokaw
and his crew
have gone up
to John j.'S cabin
this afternoon.
They went up
to his house?
Yeah, operator?
I want to make a call
to Los Angeles.
I can just see him
loving it!
"Hello, boys!
How are you?"
Got through to brokaw,
and he confirmed it.
We got through to brokaw,
and he confirmed it!
I'm a half hour
ahead of you.
Now, will you get
out of here, Wally?
Hello?
Are you ready?
Are you going to put
somebody on the door?
Why don't you put one of
your brilliant advance men?
All the reporters
are on the bus.
O.K., start
the bus, then.
All right.
And drive them
over a cliff.
Uh, honey, where
the hell did you go?
Uh, I'm sorry.
No, I wasn't
cursing you.
Excuse me.
O.K., operator,
I'll wait.
Apparently,
John j. Refuses to say
one thing or another.
Yeah.
Well, that makes it
look true.
We'll have to look
at that on the 6:00 news.
David, will you go outside
and watch the door, please?
Just talk to me
straight, man.
O.K., honey,
are you ready?
Bill, you're just
going to have to go up
and talk to him.
It's the only way.
Oh, no.
We don't use him.
I told you that
from the beginning.
O.K., uh, we'll just
announce you're quitting.
Announce whatever
you like.
Come on!
Operator,
is the trunk busy
or a line busy?
I'm going to kick
this mother to pieces!
Come on!
Operator?
Stuck!
Damn!
God!
All we need is
a simple statement--
oh, Luke, stop it!
Will you get off my back?
Just a straight
denial!
I'm just not going to do it,
and I can't think!
Does anybody
want a coke?
No!
[Football game plays
on television]
Nice to see you.
He's in the library.
O.K.
Hello, bud.
Well, what the hell?
Well...Right.
You know
miss Ford, bud.
Hello, mabel.
Hello, bud.
There's the snap...
He fades back...
He's being rushed...
[Whistle blows]
You want a beer, bud?
Johnny,
get this man a beer.
Yes, sir.
There's a flag
on the play...
They're calling
pass interference.
Well...
How are you, bud?
Pass interference.
[Sighs]
How you doing?
Oh, the old knee
kicks up once in a while.
When it rains,
I guess.
How's that?
Your knee--I said,
your knee hurts
when it rains?
Oh, you think
that's it, huh?
Yeah, well--
thank you.
See your mother?
I saw her about
a month ago.
She's started
playing golf.
She has, huh?
Yeah.
How is she?
She's fine.
Ah, that woman
will bury me yet.
Wouldn't be surprised.
Oh, you wouldn't, huh?
Hey, mabel...
Did you know
that old bud here
is running for
the United States senate?
That's very good, bud.
Yeah.
Get him a real drink.
He'll need one.
No, thanks. No.
Oh, well,
get him something.
Have Johnny fix him
a sandwich or something.
Any man running
for the senate
has to want something.
Right, bud?
[Whistle blows]
The lineup...
[Crowd cheers]
There's the snap...
He hands off
to the right...
It's just a matter
of a statement.
You sure you don't want
to get the other gun?
You don't have to
do anything.
Watch that branch.
In fact, I really
wish you wouldn't.
Wouldn't what?
Do anything.
Slow down, now.
Slow down.
Can you feel it?
Feel what?
Tell me, bud...
What does it feel like
to run a campaign
in this state these days?
I wouldn't know.
Ha ha ha!
Did you really run
your own campaign?
Why, shit, yes!
What do you take me for?
I don't know.
I just didn't--
I hear your advance work
is unbelievable.
Hold it!
Will you do it?
I don't know what
you said to your dad,
but it sure was
a snappy denial.
Hi. Bill McKay.
I'm running for
the U.S. senate.
That's a cute kid.
[Sighs]
Hi. Bill McKay.
I'm running for
the U.S. senate.
Is this your table?
No, it isn't.
Hi, girls.
Hi.
Want to shake hands?
Ha ha.
Hey, where's the--
hey, corliss,
where's the men's room?
Uh, this way.
Uh, hey, rich...
Huh?
Excuse me.
We got a sneak
on the field poll,
and we're only
8 points behind.
8 points.
Hell, if we can just pick up
one point a week...
[Urinal flushes]
You know, this is
a heaven-sent opportunity.
There's something I've been
meaning to tell you, McKay.
You're shit.
And what's more,
you know you're shit.
And your father
was shit before you.
Hey, hey, hey,
come on, mister,
what's going on?
In fact, you come
from a long line
of total shits.
Now, now,
hold on...
All right, all right.
Just between
the two of us, McKay...
Am I right,
or am I right?
I don't believe it.
Over by the red sailboat,
you can get free
McKay t-shirts,
bumper stickers, buttons.
Also meet bill McKay.
[Crowd cheers]
Hey!
O.K.
No, no. Come on,
let us get through.
Hi.
How are you?
Don't crowd.
Everyone will get a chance.
Hi.
Easy.
Sign me!
Please sign me!
Uh, that's
very nice, but--
please,
for a souvenir!
I don't think--
please!
Oh!
O.K., hi.
Yay!
Hey.
Hey, bill McKay.
Have a drink.
And have a hot dog.
Oh, thank you--
oh!
Grab him!
Hold him!
What the hell
was that?
You all right,
bill?
You all right?
Yeah.
Let us through,
please.
[Men talking]
Yeah, I'd put it
right up there.
Sort of to the left.
That's really good.
Hey, those books
on the mantle
are going to be
a problem.
Move them over a bit.
O.K.
No, all the way off
would be better.
Yeah, that's fine.
What are you
doing in my house?
I'm having an affair
with your wife.
Huh?
Well, she said if
you came in, I was to say
I was a writer
from parade,
but you don't
believe that, huh?
Bill?
This is Mr. sherick,
and this is Mr. Scott.
Bill.
From parade.
Yes.
I trust this is
the beginning
of a lifelong affinity.
The beginning
of something, anyhow.
Would you excuse me
a minute?
What's going on?
They want
to photograph me
in my riding outfit.
I said, would you
excuse us a minute,
please, gentlemen?
All right.
Thanks.
But even more than that,
I think we need...
What is this?
What?
You haven't worn
that stuff in years.
You haven't worn that
dark suit in years.
Just not in
the house, Nancy.
Get these guys
out of the house!
I was just trying
to do this for you!
For me?
[Crying]
I'm sorry.
You don't understand.
For example, he still
hasn't come out
with a welfare program.
If only he would--
you are so dense.
Don't you understand
the man cannot fake
what he doesn't feel?
I am talking
about the purely
political problem
of reassuring
the suburban mentality.
When his instinct
tells him it's time
to reveal his feelings
on a subject...
Make sure that the men
are there
and that
they have equipment.
Shh! Hey, you want to be quiet?
It's coming on now.
A television commercial is
a way of selling a product.
A political candidate's bid
for our votes
is supposed to be
a higher order of expression
with moral implications
for the kind of people we are
and the kind we want
to become.
But increasingly
in this country,
candidates
are merging the two,
selling themselves
like an underarm deodorant
in commercials
just long enough
to pound in
some mindless slogan
that cheapens candidate
and voter alike.
But in the California
Senate Race,
young bill McKay
was different.
He conspicuously rejected
the machine-type politics
by which his father
won office and fame
and ran a campaign
refreshing in frankness
and directness.
But now, with only
a month to go,
McKay's ways
have visibly changed.
Those early
hard statements of his
are turning into mush.
Specific policies dissolve
into old generalities.
The Madison Avenue commercial
has taken over...
[Blows raspberry]
As his standard means
of persuasion.
The voters are being asked
to choose McKay
the way they choose
a detergent.
Socko salesmanship,
no moral considerations
involved.
Once again, it appears
virtue is too great a strain
for the long haul
of the campaign.
I want to talk
to you.
Don't take it
seriously.
I do take it
Look,
it won't hurt us.
Wait--wait a minute.
No one's going
to listen to that.
He gives us a boost
when he says
we're pulling even--
what about the people
who give us money?
That's the only thing
the average voter's gonna get.
Lynn, you don't
understand.
I do understand.
You don't
understand.
Luke:
Say that again?
You shouldn't
go in there!
I'll be damned.
Lynn, please.
The old coot. He did?
That's just...Ducky.
I agree. Right.
Well, let's just hope
we don't get killed.
Right.
Back to you
in the morning.
Jarmon's agreed
to a debate.
He obviously thinks
he's going to wipe
the floor with you.
What about--
on this
Howard k. Smith thing,
I hope you don't think
I've gone behind your back.
It's all been
your decision.
[Telephone rings]
Listen, I'm beginning
to wonder.
Hello? Bob, would you
please hold the line?
Lynn! Will you
get in here?
Yes, my lord?
I don't want anything
coming in here.
Jarmon's agreed to a debate.
Well, that's
fantastic!
I want you to hold off
everything coming in here
for 15 minutes.
But the board's
plugged through
for the evening.
Find Harry and
get him to replug it.
And close the curtains!
Whatever you say.
Now, I've got to go down there
and negotiate tomorrow.
We've got to pick
a panel to question you,
I got to make sure
you're sitting down.
Find out about
lighting...Panel...
Why sitting down?
Makeup...
The man comes on
like your father.
To avoid another
handshaking stunt
like at that damn fire.
He'll try to make you
look like a kid.
Well, I don't
give a damn.
And I don't want
a panel, either.
I just want to get
up there
and say
what I came to say.
Well, we'll go over it,
but you can't say
too much on TV.
I thought the point
was to say what I wanted.
Well, it is,
but in the right way
at the right time.
We never discussed
a right time.
We never had to
because you know--
don't tell me
what I know!
Don't make me.
Get me--
put that damn phone down
and let's get this straight!
I want to know what
the hell this campaign is!
We've come up 14 points
since we began.
That's why jarmon
is debating you.
The man is scared.
For the first time
in this campaign,
you're getting through.
And we're not at
the beginning anymore,
and it's not my job
to explain everything
to you anymore.
My job right now
is to avoid having you look
like you're sitting
on jarmon's lap,
and if you don't feel
I'm doing my job...
Well, then, you just tell me,
and I'll shove off.
Anytime.
Did you get spivak?
Uh...No. Hold on.
Uh, Bob, hold on.
Uh, Lynn,
will you get--
Marvin...
From here on out,
no promises.
I never asked you
to make promises.
Lynn, will you
get fleischer
for an 11:00 briefing session?
Right. David?
You hear that,
Corey?
Get carr on the phone
and tell him to start
earning his money.
Wally? Wally?
Here, here!
Oh, Wally...
Uh, yeah...
No, no, no.
What line is spivak on?
Yeah.
I can't call
from in here.
Call from
the other room!
How much time do you need?
Well, we need...
[Everyone talking at once]
Ladies and gentlemen,
have a pleasant afternoon
in San Diego.
O.K., group,
we're going to disembark
through the front exit.
Then we'll proceed
to the South parking lot.
Wally: We'll be going
out the back.
Wally, out the front!
Just a minute.
What's wrong?
It's stuck.
Is jarmon taking
unfair advantage
of backlash?
Um, yes, I think--
excuse us, please.
Wally: Hold it!
Hold it, everybody!
Bill, I've got
to talk to you.
What about?
Wally:
Just follow me.
Excuse me.
Coming through.
Wait a minute!
What is it?
Pilot: I'm sorry,
but you can't come in here.
Nobody's allowed in here.
Jesus!
What's going on?
This isn't any
cocktail lounge. You--
look...It's not even
worth mentioning
an ad like that.
As far as
the shooting stuff
in Oakland goes,
you have compassion
for all concerned,
but you're waiting
to hear the details.
And the reason
you're vulnerable
on this stuff
is you haven't
established yourself
on crime, right?
You're going to have
to get out of here.
In a second,
officer.
This is bill McKay.
I don't care if
it's Henry Fonda.
Give him
the damn program.
Here it is.
This is your
crime program.
You have to get this
in your lunch speech
today,
and you have to
get it in the debate
tomorrow night.
Whatever questions
they ask,
just give them
our answers.
Crime isn't an issue.
It's a symptom.
Hey, that's
a good line.
Yeah, for when
you write your book.
The point is now
to hit the 5-point
prevention
and enforcement stuff.
Part of
"the better way."
Right.
Better way
to screw 'em all.
Lots of it.
Come on, fellas.
Only 15 minutes to air.
Let's get to
the lighting effect.
Are you sure it's o.K. On
the health insurance stuff?
Terrific stuff.
Jarmon will be left
no air if you say it like that.
Got the figures?
Here they are.
It's number 23.
You want
to check it?
Want to go
over it again?
No.
Give them our answers
no matter what
the questions are.
Hey...
What?
Tie. Boring.
Let's change ties.
Why?
Never mind.
Otherwise, you'll smudge
your makeup, you get it?
When you
get up there,
you're going to be
sitting camera right.
All the time that
jarmon's talking,
just keep looking
at jarmon.
[Cough]
Jarmon talks,
you look at jarmon.
[Cough]
Right.
Try to keep your eyes
steady. Don't blink.
Whatever you do,
don't look up at all.
Don't look up.
'Cause your eyes
are glazed,
then you look
all cockeyed.
You look
like a moron.
When you're
not gesturing...
Who's that?
Keep your fingers
interlaced.
Who's that?
You got that?
Yeah. O.K.
I'm just
trying to help.
I can interlace
my own fingers.
O.K., o.K.
5 seconds...
4 seconds...
3 seconds...
2...
1.
We're on the air,
and cue van.
Tonight...
Senator Crocker jarmon
faces opponent William McKay,
his challenger in the race
for the U.S. senate seat
from the state
of California.
The jarmon-McKay debate.
Good evening,
I'm van amberg, abc.
I'll be your moderator
for tonight's debate.
We have 3
of California's
best-known
broadcast journalists
on our panel tonight.
They are...
Rollin post...
Ken Jones...
And Maury green.
We'll begin our questioning now
with Maury green.
Mr. McKay, at the beginning
of your campaign,
you favored busing
to achieve integration
in the schools.
Lately, you seem
to be against it.
Which is it--
for or against?
Well, we can't
let a school bus
carry all the burdens
of our society.
The main problem
is still,
how do we get
a first-rate education
for each
and every child?
We can't afford
to have inferior
schools anywhere,
and we--we should
always try to preserve
the concept of
the neighborhood school
in achieving this.
Aw, shit.
Gentlemen, is pollution
a political issue
in this campaign,
or is this one subject
you both can agree on?
Ha ha. Of course
it's not political.
Now, let's look at that oil
spill that fouled our beaches.
Now, I warned about
that oil spill.
I testified, I hollered
for stronger regulation.
But...We needed the oil,
and we weren't
careful enough
about how we went in
and got it.
So, I end up in the shower
along with everybody else,
trying to scrub the oil
out of my old gray hair.
Now, when
it comes to smog,
we are bucking the dream
of every private citizen
in his own automobile.
So...We had to
take on the battle
of installing devices,
and we are gradually seeing
that shift-over take effect.
In fact, I think
we can now say,
as a result of
our herculean labors,
that we are turning
the corner on smog
here in California.
Moderator:
Mr. McKay.
I don't think we
can see the corner,
much less turn it.
I won't say it's
a matter of Republicans
or democrats,
but it's politics,
all right,
when the politicians put
the needs of the polluters
over the needs
of the public.
We have the money
to do this job.
We don't have to
raise taxes one cent.
We just have to
have the leadership
to get the job done.
Mr. McKay,
what do you think of
legalizing abortion?
Well, this is a matter that
not only concerns women,
but all of us.
We can't tolerate
leadership
that shuts its eyes
to the problem.
And it certainly deserves
a lot more study
than it's been getting.
Senator jarmon.
Well, I'm an old-fashioned guy
when it comes to this,
and I don't care
who knows it.
I say that human life
is sacrosanct.
It is God given,
and we must have control
over just how and when
we let people take it away.
Mr. McKay,
until recently,
the public opinion polls
have shown senator jarmon
substantially ahead,
but reportedly, you are
beginning to catch up,
although
you're still behind.
Now, what effect will
the public opinion polls
have on your campaign?
I'm the underdog, so I
don't believe in polls.
I wouldn't believe
in them anyhow.
I don't think you can
trim what you say
to suit someone's poll.
Mr. McKay,
your opponent has implied
you have nothing
to say about crime.
Do you?
I have put out
a 5-point program
on prevention
and enforcement.
That program
spells out in detail
the training and equipment
of the men
who enforce the laws,
and we must
give them every means
with which to handle crimes
against person and property
with speed,
effectiveness, and safety.
In addition,
we've got to set forth
the type of system
that can stop crime
before it has a chance
to start.
Senator jarmon.
Well, of course
it's very easy
for anyone to come
into it at this time
and say anything
that might capitalize--
to pretend that you
have all the answers
for a situation
that you--you may
have helped encourage.
Indirectly, that is.
The question is, where
do you draw the line?
For some people,
their idea of getting tough
is longer
suspended sentences.
Let's just think
where crime comes from.
Studies have proved that
it's this whole attitude
of permissiveness.
Well, let's face it.
That attitude has
given us
some real bums
to contend with.
Society has gone soft
as an old banana.
Senator jarmon,
at the beginning
of your campaign,
your supporters
predicted
a record-breaking
victory margin.
Do you still go
along with that?
Well, Ken, I've played
on too many losing
football teams
where we thought
we had it won...
Of course I've played in
many more winning occasions.
But I have learned
never to predict
whether you're
going to win or lose
or what that point spread's
going to be.
If the people
have faith in you
and think that faith will
be reflected, that's fine.
Mr. McKay--
but you don't predict.
Moderator:
Thank you, senator.
Gentlemen, relax
for just a moment
while we pause
for this message.
We'll be back with our
debate in just a moment.
I told you,
you got balls
in both hands.
Just wait, o.K.?
[Muted conversations]
I think so.
...not the fireworks
I expected
with this group.
Say something.
Yeah, probably.
Lay them right over
each other.
Just a normal shot...
Wider...O.K.
3, tighten up
just a touch.
Get ready
to fade in.
We come now to our
concluding statements.
Each candidate
will have one minute.
The order was picked
by the flip of a coin,
and senator jarmon
will go first.
Senator jarmon.
To me, this country
was never stronger,
but the test
of a strong country
is how it faces
its difficulties.
And now and then,
when I hear the barking
and the baying
of those who would
knock our system down,
I'm reminded
of the last days
of the great Roman empire.
They argued about what vices
they could legalize,
and what happened
was an onslaught
that nearly spelled
the end of civilization.
Now, I am not suggesting
that that
is what will happen
if the people do not send me
back to the senate.
I just promise you this--
I will continue to stand up
for the philosophy
that has made
this nation great,
and is more than ever
called for
if we are to face
the future
with hope
and confidence.
I have that hope
because I believe in America.
I believe that
our greatest moment
is yet to come.
Thank you.
Mr. McKay,
you now have one minute
to sum up.
Mr. McKay.
In the begin--I don't--
I think it's important
to note what subjects
we haven't discussed.
We've completely
ignored the fact
that this is a society
divided by fear, hatred,
and violence.
And until we talk
about just what this
society really is,
then I don't know how
we're going to change it.
For example, we haven't
discussed
the rot that
destroys our cities.
We have all
the resources we need
to check it,
and we don't use them,
and we haven't discussed
why not.
We haven't discussed
race in this country.
We haven't
discussed poverty.
In short,
we haven't discussed
any of the sicknesses
that may yet bl--
send this country
up in flames,
and we'd better do it.
We'd better get it
out in the open
and confront it...
Before it's too late.
Gentlemen--
you had to do it,
didn't you?
I never dreamed
that my opponent
would stoop
to encouraging violence.
I very seriously
doubt--
that is not
what I said.
[Candidates arguing]
This has been
the jarmon-McKay debate
that you've been watching
tonight. Our panelists...
[News intro music]
...tonight's news
in Philadelphia,
rod Perry.
Here, let me--
I can do this.
Bill, you were great.
You touched
all the bases.
I thought you
were splendid.
You see? That 5-point
program works right in.
You liked it, huh?
Bill, your wife's waiting
in the clients room.
Should she stay here
or go back to the hotel?
I'll be out
in a minute.
Be out in a minute?
Yeah.
That was
quite a show.
What does
that mean?
I don't know.
Uh, bill,
about that speech--
bill, dandy.
Really took care
of business.
Uh, that stump speech
tomorrow--
hey, jaime!
How are you?
How goes--what---
[everyone talking at once]
Keeps us beating our meat
for a whole year,
and all the time,
he's just been
waiting behind a bush
to unzip himself.
He probably doesn't
see it that way.
Oh, no? Well,
he goddamn will
when I get through
with him.
[Whispering]
Howard, don't say a word.
No? After I bring
jarmon down
from 20 points
to 4 points, huh?
He says what he wants.
Now I say what I want.
Goddamn it! I feel
as bad as you do.
You do, huh?
Bud? Where is
that son of mine?
Hey, that's a goddamn
endorsement.
Hello, son.
Heh heh heh.
[Reporters
shouting questions]
Well, bud, I think
the old crock
looked a little sick,
except at the end when he
kind of turned it on you.
I wonder if anybody
understood
what I
was trying to do.
Don't worry, son.
It won't make
any difference.
Ha ha ha ha!
Governor!
Well, look at that
gorgeous female creature.
Hello.
What do you think
of our boy, huh?
Oh, I'm proud of him.
Aren't you?
We're all going over
to big Sullivan's.
I helped him get
his liquor license.
Now he'll have
to pay for it.
Governor, can we
have you right here?
Did I get
all this crap off?
Yeah.
Thanks.
I'll see you.
Yeah.
What the hell...
Forget it.
[Crowd cheering
and chanting]
We want bill!
Ladies and gentlemen,
aren't I something?
I think
I should be senator,
then this state would
really be a keen place
for us kids to play.
Right, dad?
Right, son.
Yeah, we're getting to him.
Crocker's worried.
No, no. Lou...
No, we don't have any time.
We don't have any time
to shoot some new--
don't worry about it.
I got the way to handle it.
We, uh--we recut
some of the old stuff,
and then I give you
30 seconds
of McKay the statesman.
If we're ever
going to tackle
the problems of the 1970s,
we need all the strength
a young man can give.
Bill McKay has it--
the conviction to push
for real solutions
for the problems
of unemployment,
poverty, and crime,
the determination to
put some action
back into
the United States senate...
The energy to fight
the special interests
on behalf of all
the people of California.
For a better way,
bill McKay.
[Cheering and applause]
Now, I know--
I know that it's fashionable
to weep for criminals,
but sometimes,
the person who is
weeping the loudest
is the one who has taken
the fullest advantage
of all the system
has to offer.
You know who I mean?
McKay!
Bill McKay!
I would say one thing to him
about our country--
the United States of America
is the most
successful country
in the history of mankind.
Is it worth respecting?
Yes!
Is it worth defending?
Then above all,
we must obey our laws
and honor the men
who enforce them.
And that's the scene
here in anaheim, Walter.
A scene of confidence
and celebration
as Crocker jarmon
proves once more
that he certainly hasn't
lost his velvet touch.
I'm sure bill will
be along in a minute,
Mr. starkey.
Keep in mind that Floyd
has to get to a meeting
at the local down on
mission street at 7:30.
Bill was telling me
how he appreciates
your being here,
Mr. starkey.
He's got a hell
of a way of showing it.
He probably got held up
on the freeway.
No. I saw him
in the hotel.
Well, there are some
things more important
than an election.
I don't know what the hell
you mean by that.
John.
I'm telling you, John,
I'm just about
to the point
where it's not worth it.
You think not, huh?
I think he's gonna
get his ass kicked.
He's not gonna get
his ass kicked.
Oh, yeah?
He's cute.
I'm sorry.
Am I late?
Hello, bud.
Hi.
Bill, this is
Floyd j. Starkey.
He has to leave
in a few minutes
because 100,000
teamsters in this state
are waiting to hear
what he has to say.
Is there
any cream?
Uh, here.
Bud, this is a man who
can do you a lot of good.
Oh, yeah?
And you can probably
do us some good,
if you get
to Washington.
You didn't do much good
trying to break up
the farm workers.
Oh? Yeah?
That isn't
how I'd put it.
Well, there's no point
in us chewing over
our differences.
When we get
right down to it,
you might find we have
a lot in common.
I don't think we have
shit in common.
[Laughing]
[Everyone laughing]
And now...The man--
the man you've all
been waiting for.
Our next senator, from this
great state of California,
bill McKay!
[Loud applause and cheering]
We want bill!
We want bill...
I, um...
Just happened to be
in the neighborhood.
Seriously, it's nice
to be talking
to an audience
of working people,
because I can congratulate
you on having jobs.
[Applause]
You do have jobs,
don't you?
How many are out of work?
Well, the unemployment figure
for this state is 8%.
Think of it.
The biggest, the richest,
the most powerful country
cannot keep
its full job force working.
It cannot tend
all its sick people.
It cannot feed
all its hungry people
or decently house
its poor people.
It cannot educate everyone
who needs an education.
I say there has got to be
a better way.
We want bill!
To me, that's what this
election is all about...
Because the time has passed
when you can turn your back
on the fundamental needs
of the people.
And don't think that you
can distract them anymore
by playing off
the young against the old,
the black
against the white,
the poor against
the less poor.
I think the time has come
when the American people
realize
that we're
in this together...
And that we sink or swim
together.
And I say to you, maybe--
just maybe--
that that's the way
it should be--
a test of our courage...
Of our compassion...
Our faith in ourselves,
and our faith
in our country.
[Applause]
No candidate
can come before you
and say that he's got
all the answers.
Crocker jarmon says
that he has the answers.
[Laughter]
Does he?
No!
[Applause]
All a man can say...
Is "here I am."
And that's what I say
to you tonight--
here I am. I'm willing
to give it all I've got.
Let's make a beginning!
Tell him we
believe in him!
We want bill!
Thank you
very much.
Oh, hello, Pete!
Mr. McKay!
How are--
how are things
at the office?
Well, you know,
some of the guys
are down on you,
but, hell, we knew that.
Look, I've been there
since the beginning.
I know what this
is costing you.
I saw something
out there tonight.
Believe me, this
is really effective.
I can feel it.
You can do it.
You can go
all the way.
You and I both know
this is bullshit,
but the point is,
they're believing it.
Bill, come on,
the car's waiting!
Right.
Excuse me.
It's good to
see you, Pete.
Ladies...Ladies...
If we can all
just simmer down now
and keep our blood pressures
under control,
Mr. McKay has something
very important
he wants
to talk to us about.
Thank you.
First, I would
like to say that...
I'm sorry I ate
all the shrimp.
The unemployment figure
for this state is 8%.
That's just
the official figure.
Really, it's closer to 12%.
The biggest, the richest,
the most powerful country
can't afford to keep its
full job force working,
cannot afford to feed
all of its hungry people
or decently house
its poor people.
Don't think we can any longer
play off the young against--
black against the white--
rich against the poor.
It's not gonna be
decided by newspapers.
It's gonna be decided
by you!
I say, there's got
to be a better way.
There's got to be
a better way.
A better way--
a better way--
way--way--way!
Ladies and gentlemen...
The time has passed...
Got to be a better way.
I say to you...
Can't any longer--
oh, no. Can't any longer
play off black against old,
young against poor.
This country cannot house
its houseless,
feed its foodless.
Larylarylarylaryl...
They're demanding
a government
of the people...
Peopled by people.
Our faith, our compassion...
Our courage
on the gridiron.
[Imitates explosion]
The basic indifference
that made
this country great.
And on election day...
We won't run away.
Vote once, vote twice...
For bill McKay...
You middle-class honkies.
[Whistle blows]
[Band playing]
Hey!
Hey! Hello!
Oh, I shook
his hand!
Girls, I'm sorry.
Hi!
I'm fine.
Uh-huh. Yeah.
[Honking horn]
Goddamn it!
Losing 15 minutes
of free air time
is like throwing out
$80,000--
go on, rich! We're only
5 minutes late.
Look out
for the bus!
Go ahead. I don't care
what you do.
No. Cut in there.
[Tires screeching]
What floor is it?
What floor is
news scene on?
You can't
go up there.
I have to call
your name up first.
This is bill McKay.
I don't care
who he is...
Mr. McKay, you're
doing a great job.
My girlfriend
would kill me
if I didn't
get your autograph.
We have to do
an interview.
If you gentlemen will
please take a chair,
we'll be happy to send
your names up.
We're only doing
our job.
You can't do this!
Back! Back, I say!
Hey. Aren't you
a little late?
I'm sorry.
We got hung up--sorry.
We'll go right on.
We are not going to
reassemble. I'm sorry.
Hello, Mr. McKay.
We'll just play it
as it is
if that's o.K.
It's up to you.
But we only have time
for one take.
All right. Everybody
off the floor now.
Clear the floor, please.
Hold it.
Ready number one.
O.K.
Is this buttoned?
Yes.
Stand by.
O.K.
Tape rolling.
This is bill McKay.
What is that?
Cut.
Take it from the top.
Sorry.
Ready.
All right, keep rolling.
Tape rolling. Go.
This is bill McKay.
I'd like to
talk to you tonight
about the crisis--
[laughing]
I fail to see the humor.
Hold it just
a second, o.K.?
Ha ha ha.
Relax.
Take it easy.
Grim up.
This is it, gentlemen.
Stand by.
Ready?
Ho ho.
Blahh!
Tape rolling.
Ready?
Go!
This is--
I can't.
That is just about
enough, gentlemen.
Look, give us
30 seconds.
There is nothing
I can do.
Ha ha ha ha.
I got it. No.
No, I've got it.
I want to run through
this motorcade stuff
with you.
O.K.
Here we've got
a 4-block area
on Montgomery street.
Now, see this--
damn it.
[Doorbell buzzes]
Al.
Thank you.
4-block area
on Montgomery street.
This is the entire run
of the whole parade,
right here.
This is the only place
we could find buildings
that were big enough
and old enough
so that the windows
still open.
O.K. Now,
we come through here
at exactly 12:04.
This is the time
when everybody goes
on their lunch break.
Food.
Now, when
these people
pop out
of those elevators,
hit the street,
you'll see a lot
of activity.
In the middle
of the confusion,
in the middle
of the activity,
they have to see
the smiling teeth
of bill McKay
bearing down on them.
Now, we ensure that
2 ways.
First, we stall cars
right here...
And in
the adjacent streets.
Nobody else
can get through.
2--we run a sound truck
in and out of there
half an hour
ahead of time.
Uh, bill McKay,
a better way.
Take a day, parade today,
blah, blah, blah, blah...
Half an hour before
McKay ever gets there.
Somebody must have
a medium-well down there.
I got a medium-rare up here.
We got to deal
with the union.
We're going to start
dropping leaflets
from the roofs of
these buildings at...
12:15.
Oh, no, no.
That's exactly what
I'm talking about.
Timing is critical.
12:05.
Uh, rye bread.
That's mine.
It's the end cut?
I got--I got
a medium-rare.
First, you've got
your dixieland band
on a flatbed.
You have
any a-1 sauce?
All right.
In the first car,
you've got Lucas--
first car, Lucas,
plus congressman--
what's his name?
Frawley
or something.
The mayor's not
going to be there.
What?
The mayor's not
going to be there.
Beautiful.
Uh, can we get
this thing straight?
Who has the medium-rare?
[Horns honking]
Your autograph?
Sign this, please.
[Horns continue honking]
Mr. McKay.
Just a few words.
Just that
it's been fantastic.
It's a great crowd.
[Applause]
All right, that's enough.
Luckily for bill,
he hasn't got to know
some of you the way I have.
[Crowd groans]
Otherwise he'd know
what a miracle
this campaign really is.
[Scattered applause]
Let's face it.
What we have in this room
is essentially a bunch
of lazy dilettantes.
The polls say
we are within 3 points.
We haven't made
many converts,
but we sure have made
a lot of undecided.
One final word--
get out the vote tomorrow.
We want one more
long day's work.
Stay off the hard stuff...
And leave your number
at the desk.
Hey, Luke.
Hey, wait--
what's that?
Nothing.
An early return.
[Telephone rings]
Yeah. Yeah.
Bill, jenkin.
Yeah.
What are you,
still in bed?
Come on. You got
to vote by 7:00.
What?
You got to get out
and vote by 7:00,
or you're not going to
make the afternoon papers.
What time is it?
Bill, what do you
think of the weather?
When are you going back up
through L.A., bill?
After lunch,
I believe.
Do you think bill
will take the precinct?
Pardon, what did you say?
Walter, it's raining today
on election day,
all over the state,
we understand.
And here
at McKay headquarters,
there's frantic concern
to get out their voters.
Generally, they believe
a big turnout
will favor their man.
Hundreds of volunteers are
going out to knock on doors.
Crocker jarmon
has authored 76 other pieces
of major legislation.
Crocker jarmon has done
a great job for California.
What has bill McKay done?
Nothing much, but his father
was governor.
Good day.
You come with me
for a minute, please?
Guess there's no point
in asking who you voted for.
Oh, you wouldn't really
want me to say that,
would you?
I hear it's raining
in the Southern part
of the state.
It is?
It is.
How do you think
this affects
your son's chances?
I would think it might help
a great deal.
It'll keep the enemy indoors.
And it's going to be
a great day for America.
Kiss her.
That's the best suggestion
I've heard all morning.
Are those phone banks
working in east L.A.?
Yeah.
You double sure?
Yes.
Well, check again.
Is everything all right
at the hotel?
Don't you have
anywhere to go?
Look, I have to make sure
that things happen here.
You're driving
everyone crazy.
Well, there are
a lot of details.
Why don't you go
clean your beard?
Would you mind telling us
who your friends voted for?
Well, the other people
on my block voted for McKay
because he was handsome.
Would you mind telling us
who you voted for?
Well, I always say
handsome is
as handsome does.
I'm talking with
Dr. Benjamin Dwight,
who in the last
3 elections
here in the state
of California
predicted
every major race
hours before
the polls closed.
Dr. Dwight, can you explain
to us the technique you use?
We pick the key precincts
in Los Angeles county,
and we interview the voters
on the way from the polls.
Now, based
on your interviews,
what is your projection
for this Senate Race?
Crocker jarmon by 8%.
8%? What kind
of shit is this?
The polls don't close
for 3 hours.
Well, that doesn't
change anybody's mind.
That doesn't change
their minds--
they stay home, schmuck.
Who did you vote for?
Crocker jarmon.
Who'd you vote for?
Bill McKay.
Crocker jarmon.
He takes care of me.
Bill McKay.
Crocker jarmon.
Jarmon.
McKay.
It looks like much
of Los Angeles county
is still having trouble
with their voting machines
down in the Southern
California area.
In the state assembly race,
the democrats are still
holding a slight edge.
The surprising upset is...
You can't go in there.
2, 4, 6, 8.
Who do we appreciate?
The polls closed
just 20 minutes ago,
but as you can see
on your screen,
we already have
some early returns.
As expected,
the absentee ballots
heavily favored
senator jarmon.
That advantage
has been offset
by early returns
from the San Francisco area,
which remains
a Democratic stronghold.
Of course, this is just
a fraction of the total vote--
occasionally may be
something to grab and check
as more results come in.
7% of the precincts
tabulated,
bill McKay still clings
to a narrow lead
in the race
for the U.S. senate.
However, we still only
have scattered returns
from the southland.
¶ You may stand
and do it all... ¶
we want bill.
We want bill.
...Southern part of the state
and the margin he needs
to offset McKay's surprising
strength in the north.
We want bill.
We may be able to call
this one any moment.
We want bill.
Rreow!
We'll have bill stout
standing by
at McKay headquarters
at the regency Hyatt.
We want bill.
Roger, as this
tremendous upset
becomes more
and more evident
with each
passing minute,
people gathered here
in the auditorium
are getting ready
to tear the roof off.
We want bill.
Our abc computers
have now declared
young bill McKay
the winner
of California's
senate seat.
And now we have
with us...
I don't think we're closing
for a month, you know.
Where are you gonna look
for a house?
I--I'd like to look
in Georgetown.
Now we have word that CBS,
nbc, and abc...
[Excited chatter]
Chevy chase,
you know.
That's lovely there.
Yeah. Have you
lived there?
Yes. We're just across
the river now.
Oh...
Man: Congratulations.
Oh, thank you.
[Cheering]
...and we found them favoring
McKay by a solid 70%.
Please, people, please!
Clear the rooms.
Clear the hall.
We'll bring him out
in a second.
Mrs. Evans in here?
We did it!
Art, I told you to stay
in the other room.
Have you seen
dick bergoski?
No, I haven't seen
dick bergoski.
Bill, we're going
to clear the hall.
It'll be just
a couple of minutes.
Son...
You're a politician.
Bill, we're ready.
Here he comes!
It came from
the undecided.
It was a great campaign.
I understand that you
were seen last night
taking your own poll.
It's a rumor.
Don't believe it.
Where are you going
from here, Lucas?
I'm going downstairs
to have a drink
with a thousand close friends.
I heard another rumor
you were headed
for a long vacation.
No, no, no.
Lucas!
Luke! Luke!
Uh, no comment.
Hi. I want to talk to you.
O.K., we'll, uh--
now. Now.
I want to talk to you.
Well...
Hey!
You guys are not
supposed to be here.
O.K. We've got about
60 seconds of privacy
before they find out
we're here. Now, so, uh,
what's on your mind,
senator?
I don't know.
[Knock on door]
O.K. You got
to get out there.
I told you they'd be here.
Marvin...
What do we do now?
Wait a minute.
What?
What do we do know?
[All talking at once]
There's a big party
downstairs.