This is KKNG Stereo 92, KKNG,
Oklahoma City.
The magnificent American Ballet Company
is at the Civic Center Music Hall.
Great dancing stars are performing
full-length Tchaikovsky ballets,
plus many classic and contemporary
favorites from ABC's vast repertoire.
Tickets are available
at the Music Hall box office and all agencies.
KKNG. And now we continue
with music from the ballet.
Is everybody ready?
Gorgeous.
Very smart!
- I thought you were gonna set up the bar.
- There'll be time after we get back.
Dad.
The wife's always the last to know.
Emilia, will you get dressed?
Janina, that's enough.
There'll be time when we get back.
And it takes you an hour to get ready.
Will you go and do it? Where's Ethan?
Mom, those beads look
absolutely gross with that dress.
These beads were given to me by Emma
before you were born.
Well, they look gross now.
- Ethan? Ethan, will you quit that?
- It's the lights. I'm crazy.
Well, the lights are for the party.
Come on, we're leaving in two minutes.
Come on, let's go.
- Who's got the tickets?
- I don't have them.
- I got 'em.
- You have the tickets.
I am so nervous.
Momma, don't be so nervous.
- How are you doin'?
- OK.
- Did you have a good cry?
- A beaut.
- What'd you tell the kids?
- Nothing. They know you.
They've heard the tale of you and Emma
rehearsing for the same part a hundred times.
- There's no law says we gotta go backstage.
- Yes, there is.
Come to the party. Relax, Sevilla.
What's the point of doing a perfect arabesque
for audiences who don't know the difference?
I was terrible tonight.
I'm going home to soak in a hot bath.
You are no fun, Sevilla. I'll put you in a taxi.
No, thanks, love. My limo's waiting.
- Where are the showers?
- Over that way, I think.
Deedee?
- Freddie.
- Baby, how are you?
Freddie. Oh, I'm so glad to see you.
Meet our kids.
This is Emilia, Janina and Ethan.
You look just great.
Deedee.
...instead of four.
- Yes. And he loops that part, so...
Hello, Adelaide.
Well.
You've held up very well, dearie.
- So've you.
- Running this company keeps me trim.
You could lose a few pounds, Deedee.
So you always said.
- No cakes or candy tonight at the party.
- Not a cookie, cookie.
Deedee?
It's Michael.
Michael Cooke.
Wayne? Wayne, Michael's here.
Michael...
- Hi, Wayne.
- Look at you.
- Damn, you look impressive, sir.
- So impressive Deedee didn't recognize me.
You weren't the world's greatest
choreographer when we left.
- Wasn't I? I thought I was.
- He'd done Anna Karenina.
Hey, come on.
- From bar four on?
- Yes. But then I think it's gotta build.
- Towards the end.
- Tonight it was slow.
We should speed it up.
That's how it should go. It shouldn't be any
slower than that. I feel like I'm on point for...
Here you are. Oh, God.
- You were wonderful.
- Oh, I wasn't wonderful.
- I wanted to be, but I wasn't.
- Yes, you were.
- I loved your flowers. Thanks so much.
- You were fabulous.
No, I wasn't.
You know my foot was acting up. I wrote you.
You couldn't notice it. I couldn't tell at all.
- I was so nervous because you were here.
- You were wonderful.
- I wasn't.
- Yes, you were.
You really were, Emma.
Oh, Wayne.
You moved me like you always did.
Thanks.
- Oh, Wayne, it's been too long.
- Yeah, it sure has.
Well... how would you like to see
your godchild? Emilia, come over here.
Oh, my God.
- Isn't she somethin'?
- Oh, my God.
Last time I saw you, I could pick you up.
Oh, she's lovely.
She's lovely, Deedee.
She is.
Janina.
- Janina, yes.
- Hi.
- And...
- Ethan.
Ethan. Hi.
OK.
He's a little dangerous.
Look at you.
They don't know how fast time goes, do they?
No. They don't.
Oh, Deedee.
Oh, Deedee...
Still disgustingly neat.
I was always such a total slob, wasn't I?
I only minded when you borrowed
my eyeliner and didn't return it.
To its proper place.
Oh, Emma. You don't travel
with this picture everywhere you go?
That and Mother. The rest appear
and disappear into a scrapbook.
- Oh, sweetheart.
- Did you really wear this hat to my wedding?
I love that hat.
God, can you believe how young we looked?
- I look like shit.
- Well, we all did next to Wayne.
- God, he's beautiful.
- Even in those pleated pants.
No wonder the whole company wanted him.
It's a good thing you had your eye elsewhere.
- You mean on Michael.
- No, I mean on the ball.
Tell me something, Emma.
What's it like to be you now?
I dance.
I take class, I rehearse, I perform.
I go home to my hotel.
Some cities are better than others.
So are some nights.
I thought I was good tonight.
I wanted to be, for you.
You couldn't help being good.
- Still?
- Yes.
You're an artist.
- Now what are you doing?
- I hate this picture.
I'll send you a new one.
How many bedrooms?
You've seen them all.
Wanna see the cellar? We don't have one.
I bet Momma would have been
a much better Anna Karenina. Emma stinks.
You're so stupid.
Mark, you know what this
fantastic little Russian's gonna do?
He's going to make it respectable
for American boys to be dancers.
See, on a good day I can do
entrechat sixes with double cabrioles.
- You beat me to it.
- Nice of her to have brought it.
- It's all she drinks now.
- You haven't talked to her yet.
I've been busy with the rest of the company.
Wayne, I love the company.
I don't want 'em to ever leave.
I wanna go with 'em. I miss 'em. I want...
Oh, what the hell. Your eyes.
Your ass.
Emma? Anybody seen Emma?
With all that experience
you're really a professional.
Would you like to take class
with the company in the morning?
Emilia, it's pointless to be shy.
You must know what you want
and say it.
- I know some things I want.
- Such as?
To take class with the company.
Had I understood 38 years ago
what I was getting myself into,
I'd never have started
this bloody ballet company.
I had just one thought.
"We need a first-class American company."
- But you've got a lot of foreigners in yours.
- Dance is international.
My company's almost gone under five times.
But here we are,
the best ballet company in the world.
Well, in this country, anyway.
- Is that the way you were brought up?
- Yes.
Your mother.
Well, I want her and your father
to introduce me to some rich oil folk.
They have a ballet school, dearie,
and that always means
a half a dozen rather lumpy little girls
with very rich daddies.
Now, I won't interfere
with their business, Janina.
I know how to handle the rich.
You give them hope, they give you money.
Don't put that ham away.
Save the commercial, Adelaide.
Janina hasn't got a penny.
- She should open a restaurant.
- Thank you.
It's a choreographer's prerogative
to keep his ideas to himself.
But, Arnold, must you be so secretive? Tell
us a little something about your new ballet.
There won't be a swan onstage.
- That's a little something.
- But not enough to guarantee you'll do it?
- Don't run, Adelaide.
- I told you Michael and I will do our best.
And I never run.
Deedee?
How do you get anywhere with her?
By realizing she knows
exactly what she's doing.
Oh, by the way, we'd like to have
a new ballet for Emma this season.
Oh, you don't have to use her, Arnold.
It's just a thought.
- Oh, were you pleased with Emma tonight?
- Yes, very.
I made Emma, Janina.
No, she didn't. Michael made Emma.
But you helped, Adelaide.
Booze brings out the nit-pickers.
I could have helped make you.
- Really, Mom?
- Were you as good as Emma, Mom?
- I was different.
- Very. From the day you both joined us.
Different how?
Your mother preferred to get married.
- Well, good night, all.
- I'll walk you to the car.
- Good night.
- Coming. Good night.
God, dancers have ugly feet. Ugh.
If I were a man, I could have had all the feet...
I mean children... I wanted, and still danced.
How many children?
Three. Like yours.
And a husband like Wayne.
Yes.
You're a very lucky girl.
Wanna change places?
No, I can't see you
teaching a pack of klutzy kids.
Or living in a town
where the company finally, finally comes.
And when they do, it's for a two-night stand.
No, you picked the life you wanted, Emma.
So did you.
No, not really.
You didn't let me.
- How not?
- "How not?"
We've picked up some fancy-schmancy
expressions along the way, haven't we?
Deedee...
I honestly don't know
what you're talking about.
- Remember Michael doing Anna Karenina?
- Yes, of course I do.
- Who did he rehearse for the part of Anna?
- You and me.
And?
And...
- You got pregnant.
- Yeah.
And you got 19 curtain calls.
Oh, Deedee.
Deedee...
- You resent me for that?
- No, not for that.
Would you like to change places?
I don't get 19 curtain calls any more.
But somebody will in something else,
and it won't be me.
Remember Dahkarova?
Well, she lives in an apartment
in Carnegie Hall that's as old as she is,
splattered with photographs
of herself as Giselle.
She coaches...
when she can.
She rents rooms to dancers when she can.
She was a great ballerina. She was our idol.
But Michael never considered her for Anna.
She was too old.
Exactly.
Well, that's a fact of life, Emma.
And I have to take class in the morning.
That's another fact of life.
Hi, Mom.
Ethan... Ethan?
Women aren't allowed in here.
I suppose the game was called
on account of rain.
It wasn't a game, only practice.
- You're gonna get kicked off the team.
- I won't.
- Oh, you think you're so valuable?
- No. But they do.
Get dressed. Out. Go home.
- It's Dad's advanced class.
- I know the schedule.
I'm not gonna miss that class,
so you can save your breath.
You save yours.
Now, get this straight, young man.
You wanna play baseball, finish practice.
You wanna dance, be on time.
I prefer baseball, because athletes last
a lot longer and make a lot more money,
but either way you follow the rules.
You got it?
I got it.
OK, second group, please.
See you in the rehearsal later. Bye.
Be ready.
Préparation. Music start.
Turn. Heel forward.
Continue. Come on, girls.
Together. Not too late.
Everywhere she's studied,
she's been on scholarship.
She studied with Carmelita
in Los Angeles, again on scholarship.
Thank you. Boys, please.
She's danced professionally
in Houston and Santa Fe.
Lots of money in Santa Fe.
And pause. Hold it. Pause.
Girls, continue immediately.
Arabesque. Feet close.
All the time in proper position.
Take the time right.
Good.
Proper ending,
and the whole combination to the left side.
Deedee and Wayne did a good job.
What do you think, Adelaide?
Dad, is it true that Yuri does doubles in the air
then a twist, and comes down on one knee?
- That's what I heard.
- Jesus.
My girlfriends couldn't care
if he did triples and landed in a split.
- They just like to see him in his tights.
- And you don't?
No. Dancers are boring. They're all in love
with themselves. It's those mirrors.
Dad, did you hear that?
Mom and Dad are teachers,
not dancers. You're neither.
- Is that so?
- As a matter of fact, yes.
- Mom...
- If you don't know by now...
- They asked me to join the company.
- Oh, Emilia.
Quiet. Quiet.
When do you start?
With rehearsals in New York
before the summer season.
But, Daddy, I didn't tell them I'd go.
- Jerk.
- Ethan!
- I said I wanted to think it over.
- Why, for God's sake?
'Cause she's got more brains than you.
She knows it's the fork in her road.
- The what?
- Don't laugh. It is.
And I want to know where I'm going.
Right. Why shouldn't you?
That's very smart of you, Emilia.
Let's eat.
The air conditioner in the office
is still on the fritz.
Yeah, I know. Thanks, hon. They said
they'd fix it first thing in the morning.
They always say that,
they just never say which morning.
Why do you think she's hesitating
about joining the company?
She won't say it
but she feels funny about leaving us.
I do too. Even funnier.
I have this image of Janina
going off to college, and then Ethan, and...
You know that Emma travels
with these three little dogs?
- Would you rather Emilia didn't go?
- No.
God, no.
I don't want her to spend the rest of her life
buried here in Oklahoma City.
I was thinking - if she does go,
you should go to New York for the summer.
You always baby her.
She doesn't make friends as easily as Janina.
She will, in the company.
There's always a lot of jealousy
in the company.
Well, that never bothered you.
Why don't you go? Why should I go?
You know you wanna go,
you know we have to keep school open,
and you know
I'm a better teacher than you are.
Only in the summer.
It's too damn hot here for me.
Besides, I can't leave the other kids.
Well, Janina's happy as a clam here, and she
takes good care of the house. And Ethan...
Oh, Ethan would kill
to go to New York and study.
So?
You know me too well.
I would love to go there.
I think you have to.
- Are you trying to get rid of me?
- No, trying to hold onto you.
- I thought it over, but I have two questions.
- Sure.
Ethan says I'm scared of competition. I'm not.
But it's a big company,
so how much will I get to dance?
Depends on how good you are.
Well, how good am I?
Very. Now, what's the other question?
Should I know now
whether I want to stay in the company?
What made you ask that?
Well, it seems if you really stay,
there are things you have to give up.
You nut. You deal with that
when and if it happens.
But for now, if you know
what you want to do then you do it.
- It's not always that easy to know.
- Oh, it is for me.
I mean, I know what I want for now.
What?
Just to dance.
Then go ahead.
Left hand on the barre.
Shoulder down. Arm. And...
Grand plié.
One shoulder back.
Open. Look over your hand. Feet together.
Lift your arm. Port de bras. Front. One...
Watch.
No. In the middle of the movement. That's it.
Perfect.
OK, now développé. Pull it up. Keep your pull.
One, two, three.
And one, two, three.
A little late. Three.
And one. Your toes will be in fifth position.
Last time. Again.
- Don't...
- I'm sorry.
- OK.
- That's enough.
How can you dance on it
if you can't even stand a Band-Aid?
And one, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven...
Now, behave.
You're on a scholarship so be grateful.
I am. And it keeps me off the streets,
like you said.
You better not be so smartass
with your teachers.
So long, Mom.
- No.
- You don't wanna be seen with me?
- Don't you have anything better to do?
- Frankly, I don't.
Well, let me go first.
Control.
One. Stay.
And a-one.
Grand finale.
Shit.
Hello, Florence.
Is Adelaide around, by any chance?
No, sorry.
She had a fundraising meeting, Mrs Rodgers.
Deedee, Deedee.
...five, six, seven, eight.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight...
- Sevilla. How are you?
- Oh, hello.
That's as far as I got.
Interesting.
Thank you, everybody.
Shall I show you your solo now?
Please do.
You have three piqué turns
to two chaénés and plié.
- Arabesque. Preparation fourth.
- Double pirouette, right?
You can do a single.
I can do a double.
- Where do you want my head here?
- Down and to the side.
Fascinating.
You know, Arnold, it might help
if you told me what I was playing.
There's no story, Emma. It's abstract.
I'm aware of that. I asked what I was playing,
not who I was playing. What am I feeling?
Nothing, Emma. You just dance.
Arnold...
you've got the wrong lady.
Just watch your blood pressure, Arnold.
I did not say that if we don't use Emma,
we won't put on your ballet.
I did say that with Emma it will get
the serious attention it deserves.
Actually,
that's why you showed it to her, isn't it?
I was surprised Emma Jacklin
wanted to be in it.
Why? Emma's always worked
with young choreographers...
Michael.
I'm in bad need of a new ballet, Arnold,
and you know it.
Now, we're using each other, so play fair.
You're very talented.
Talented enough to change it, so that
you can use me at what I can do best. Now.
I'd like to, Emma, but it's not that simple.
- Your ambivalence is showing.
- Don't get bitchy.
- I'm not referring to your sex life.
- Ballets are for dancers, not to oblige stars.
I'm afraid Arnold wants his choreography
to be the only star.
It is, and it should be.
So you don't want me.
Well, then, it is that simple.
Your choreography looked very good
on Emilia. Use her. She'll surprise you.
Back to work.
The little bastard didn't even have the grace
to talk me into staying in his bloody ballet.
Drink slowly.
By the way, you and Freddie
aren't doing any Giselles this season.
- Trying to scare the hiccups out of me?
- No.
Sevilla's doing two,
then she alternates with...
Carolyn.
You picked a lovely time to tell me, Michael.
Better to get everything
dumped on you all at once.
Better for whom?
I'm the artistic director, Emma.
You tell me when and how
you'd say it to an artist you respect.
And a friend.
Poor Freddie.
You know we're only getting paid
by the performance this season.
No, I didn't know.
Well, the hiccups are gone, too.
Now, if I can just find
something to put these in...
You know, everything she has in here
is either an icon, a samovar or broken.
Usually all three.
- "D D Vanyo phone?"
- What?
That's what it says, I think.
Oh, that's from last night. You have to learn
how to break Dahkarova's code.
- "Wayne phoned."
- Yep.
He's so smart. He knew
if he gave me enough rope I'd hang myself.
- How's Janina?
- She's OK.
Crazy. Hates ballet, loves Oklahoma.
How did I raise one normal child?
Now, this will pass for a vase.
Oh, Em, if I could just get that teaching job.
And all I need is Adelaide's OK,
but I can't get the old bitch on the phone.
Who's she coaching?
Oh. The blonde, with the big eyes.
She's been coming over. Carolyn.
Yes.
I just heard Carolyn's going
to be doing Giselle this season.
Oh, dammit. I will not get the hiccups... again.
Put your arms up. How about
if I kill Adelaide? I'd like to anyway.
Don't blame Adelaide.
It's not her fault. I swore I'd quit at 35.
And 36, 37...
And then I closed my eyes.
How old were you
when you started taking lessons?
Eight.
I was seven.
- Our bodies always objected.
- I know.
But you didn't stay around long enough
to find out they revolt.
And too soon.
They just refuse to do what one wants.
They can't.
But even now, there are moments
when it comes together.
The music, the dancing...
the lights...
the costumes...
Well, you wanted to know
what it was like to be me.
Deedee, all I'm doing offstage
is just waiting to get back on.
How about a beer?
- I beg your pardon.
- No, tea.
- I'll make it.
- No, you sit.
- I'm gonna talk to Adelaide about your job.
- Don't talk to Adelaide about a damn thing.
Will you tell me something?
Why do the problems of people like you seem
so much more important than my problems?
- It's obvious. You're more important.
- Well, if I am, it's not for long.
A couple of years ago
Dahkarova was coaching me.
Today, Carolyn.
But next year...
Emilia.
- Emilia?
- Oh, yes.
She's really that good?
- I think she's gonna do it for you, Deedee.
- That's it, that's better.
Excuse me.
Mrs Rodgers, could...
- Emma, you're here.
- Still.
- What do you want, Carolyn?
- A glass of water, please.
Ah, kettle is boiling.
- Emma.
- Madame.
- I'm sorry.
- Why? It's not your fault.
- I understand.
- Yes. I understand too.
I went through the very same thing.
Carolyn.
- Cup of tea?
- Thank you, Emma.
Getting ready for my first performance
of Giselle is so difficult...
Stop talking. Sit.
- Any little cakes, Deedee?
- Cakes? Certainly. Anybody else?
- I'd love some. What kind do you...
- No.
- Hello, Momma.
- Hi, sweetie. How...
Emma. Hello, Mme Dahkarova. Hello, Carolyn.
Emma, Arnold was so mean after you left.
- But he'll give you the part?
- I knew it was your idea.
- Would you like some tea, darling? Emilia?
- Please.
- A lot of Arnold's scowls and mutterings?
- Yes.
- You'll get the part.
- What part?
- In Arnold's new ballet.
- Who, Arnold? Good ballet?
It's a good part for Emilia.
Then you must help and coach her.
All right.
I will.
But, Emma... you? Coaching?
Nonsense. I do it. It's necessary
to teach someone else be good like me.
But, Madame, you don't... You're not...
I don't what? I'm not what?
I think what Carolyn means is that
you don't dance any more and I do.
- Who helped you the most?
- Kschessinska.
From Mariinsky to me.
From me to you while I still was dancing.
Now to Carolyn, and very soon to you, Emilia,
if you work sur les pointes every day.
- Opening nights are so exciting.
- Aren't they?
I wish you were doing
the first Giselle tonight, not Sevilla.
It takes all the running you can do
to stay in the same place.
Pardon?
It's from Alice in Wonderland, dear.
- It goes down a little bit?
- No, it just follows the natural line.
Yeah, just out just a little bit.
- Can I try it again?
- Sure.
It's wonderful.
Remind me to ask you about something.
And one and two and three and four
and five and six and seven and eight.
And three. Two and three and four
and five and six and seven. Close eight.
A little faster.
- Not bad.
- Don't spoil me, dear.
Well, would you rather
I buttered you up like Adelaide does?
Why don't we butter each other up?
You're revolting. And about as subtle as she
is. This morning she came up to me and said:
"Sevilla, dearie, you're the greatest
prima ballerina in the whole world."
No, I am.
Gosh, that is awkward.
We ought to try that again, that lift.
The reason Adelaide goes on and on is
she knows I want to dance in Milan and Rio.
- She's determined I'll do that bloody tour.
- Well, you don't say no.
- That's exactly what Richard said.
- Who is Richard?
- Sevilla, long-distance phone call for you.
- Coming.
Excuse me, please. I won't be a moment.
Richard is why
I'm not going to end up like Emma.
I hate to be interrupted for phone calls.
Could I have the second cast, please?
Let's go from the wheelbarrow.
Ready? And...
You can turn on the light, it's OK.
- I didn't mean to wake you.
- You didn't.
I was with Yuri.
- Are you OK?
- Oh, yes.
I've been taking the pill.
Just in case.
Good God.
There's nothing to worry about.
Go to sleep now.
- Don't you wanna talk?
- No.
It might spoil it.
- Go back to bed. Sleep well.
- Oh, Emilia.
- Be glad for me, Momma.
- I am.
I am, I just didn't think it would...
it would be so soon that you...
That I what?
That you wouldn't just... wanna dance.
Oh, Mom.
Go back to bed.
Go on. It's OK.
Go on.
- How are you?
- OK.
Let's go.
About once a week,
Dad and I would check out all the new stuff.
And Emma and I would go up to the third
floor, try on all the most expensive dresses.
Once we stayed so long
we missed rehearsals...
Hey, I'll see you later.
...stay up there for hours,
trying these dresses...
Oh, Rosie.
- Meet my children. This is Emilia and Ethan.
- Hi.
Joe Rosenberg, the conductor
of the company when Dad and I were in it.
- He was the best.
- I still am.
Only now I conduct musicals.
More bread and a permanent pad.
Hey, where are you goin'?
There. We live at Carnegie Hall.
How's your wife, Joe?
Which one? I've had two since I last saw you.
No. Well, how's all three of them?
Dynamite. I never see 'em.
- How's whats his name?
- Wayne.
In Oklahoma with our other daughter.
We're here for the summer.
Terrific. I'm loose.
You gave up the ballet
to conduct on Broadway?
- You are a man without soul.
- And you are a woman without wine.
- Did he bring this wine?
- Yes, he brought it.
Taste, he got.
- You have much soul, darling.
- But not much taste.
Correct.
- I'll get it.
- "I'll get it."
Shut up.
Hello?
- Deedee, it's honor to Emilia.
- "Honor"?
- Yuri is the best dancer I know in years.
- Of course, my dear. He's Russian.
Correct.
And, believe it or not,
Linda's been accepted at Yale.
I guess nobody wants
to go to Princeton any more.
Well, obviously not my kids.
All five picked different schools,
but not one picks my alma mater.
- Would you say that was a reflection on me?
- No, Carter.
I'd say that was a reflection on Princeton.
You're biased.
For years.
- Excuse me, Miss Jacklin.
- Just put 'em down anywhere.
- Obviously I can't kiss you here.
- It wouldn't upset me.
It might upset Maggie.
Enough to give you a divorce?
All I'd have to do is ask for a divorce, Emma.
You know that.
Well?
- Would you give up dancing?
- Why not?
I asked you 15 years ago. 14 years ago. 13.
Ask me now.
You know, I...
I've always wondered -
what do you do with all these flowers?
Give them to hospitals.
Emma...
You know one of the reasons
we've lasted so long?
Tell me another, Carter.
Because the whole arrangement
has suited you. You liked the limitations.
I'm not so sure I do any more.
Well, now I do.
I'm sorry.
So am I.
Come in.
Well, I guess I'd better be running along.
Would you rather I didn't stop by later?
No, stop by.
We might as well finish out the season.
See you later.
Really, you are crazy. Stay.
- Yuri, my mother would have a fit.
- Then she is also crazy.
She's just a very proper lady.
- You're crazy. I can't.
- Yes.
- Half an hour, then.
- No, all night.
Please.
Why?
I'm homesick.
Now turn your back
to the new direction and look up.
Spot over your hand-arm line.
OK, good. Second group, please.
Let's do a port de bras. Be ready.
And...
Don't tighten your shoulder.
Very soft.
- You're late.
- Why you come so late?
Stuck in the bathroom.
- Boys, see the ink lighters?
- Lines. Together.
- They're flashing.
- Straight lines, please. Arms. Don't forget.
I had more than
just the hots for you back then.
But back then I didn't look so good in tights.
Now the toe shoe's on the other foot.
- Is it, now?
- Yeah.
Now we both don't look so good in tights.
- You speak for yourself.
- I am.
I can open up new vistas for you, my sweet.
Dancers are dumb.
I mean, what do you know?
Babies and ballet, right?
Well, what do you know
except for music and divorce, right?
One moment for station identification, please.
Books. Corruption. Dirty pictures.
Divorce is a bummer,
violets are blue.
Tchaikovsky is great...
and so are you.
That's nice. I needed that.
Back in the icebox age,
I had an apartment on West 52nd Street. You...
You left before the best part.
- You don't remember, do you?
- Yes, I do.
It was over a jazz joint.
Don't... leave now.
- Feel better?
- Much.
- It was my own fault, Yuri.
- Nah.
- I was so nervous.
- Why?
You're so fabulous. And I have weak knees.
I like girls with weak knees.
- You just like girls.
- Very much. Is wrong?
No. I personally think everyone should have
the right to make their own choice.
- I like yours.
- My what?
Your choice.
- I'm sorry. My English...
- No, it's mine. I have trouble sometimes.
Carolyn, you know,
it sometimes better... not to talk.
- I agree. And particularly with me, because...
- Carolyn.
Yes?
Hello?
- Emilia?
- Daddy.
Hi.
How are you? How's Janina?
Janina's taking care of me just fine.
And she's great at the school.
That's good.
Listen, I really had forgotten
how much later it is there.
Daddy, did you hear about
my part in the ballet?
- Yeah, Ma wrote that you got the lead.
- Yeah.
Well, don't let that Arnold Berger scare you.
You just sic your boyfriend on him, OK?
How is he, by the way?
He's OK. I don't really have time
for that sort of thing.
I don't wonder. You know, they always work
you a lot harder when you're really good.
Put Ma on for a minute, will you?
Mom's with Emma. They're always yakking.
Sometimes she even stays over.
Yeah, well, that's good.
You have her call me when she gets a chance,
OK? Meantime, you get back to bed, and...
Daddy, could you come to New York soon?
You bet, honey.
Soon as school finishes, Janina and I are
gonna get on the first plane out of here. OK?
Yes. I love you, Daddy.
I love you too.
- Bye.
Up late?
Good morning, darling.
Daddy called last night.
I told him you were with Emma.
- Why didn't you wake me?
- It was very late.
Daddy and Janina send their love.
Emilia, what time are you
having your lunch today?
I'm busy.
Goodbye, Madame, Ethan.
Something's funny.
One, two, three, four.
Two, two, three four.
Three, two, three, four.
Four, two, three four.
Five, two, three, four.
Six, two, three, four.
Emilia...
all that emotion is terrific...
for the mad scene in Giselle, not for my ballet.
You're not an uptight village virgin. You're
just a body moving in space with music.
Not to music, with music.
That's what dancing is. So please
don't fly around the room emoting.
Don't think. Just move as I tell you to move
to the counts I give you. OK?
I don't count.
Then how do you know
what to do when? ESP?
I feel it, with the music. And I make it fit.
Well, don't feel it. Count it.
Where were we, Peter?
Bar 132... with no feeling, please.
- Look over here. Cute, ain't she?
- She's real pretty.
- Howdy.
I was wondering if you could
settle a little wager we just made.
We're from out of town,
and we bet you are too.
Right?
See, I knew it.
Bartender, get us another round over here.
- This is...
- I'm Barney Joe. Lake Charles, Louisiana.
And...
I'm Bill Britt, from Amarillo, West Texas.
Pleased to meet you, ma'am.
Where are you from?
Leningrad, Soviet Union.
No kidding? What are you doing here?
I need artistic freedom.
Hey, what are you, anyway?
Artist. Is why I need artistic freedom.
That blows me away.
Now, what are you
saving them cherries for?
I save them for supper.
- Oh, no.
- What?
- Is time to go.
- Oh, no, don't leave.
Hey, you forgot your...
You forgot your briefcase.
Listen, why don't you come on back, now?
I have a marvelous man for that, Sevilla.
No injections, Emma.
I faint at the sight of a needle.
Just massage.
I'll leave his number in your room.
- Thank you, darling.
- Clear the stage.
Would everyone clear the stage?
Take the house to half. Conductor, stand by.
Hi.
What in the world did you take?
Cherries, for remembrance.
Let me out of here.
- Here.
- It's cold in here.
You can do it. You can do it.
Five. Six. Seven. Eight.
Something's wrong.
I'm not quite sure, but she's really wonked.
Sorry.
Take this. Hang on. You'll be OK.
Not a word to Adelaide. I'll tell you
all about it in my dressing room. Bye-bye.
- Emilia...
- She's OK.
Go.
Yes, I agree.
The right partner is absolutely essential.
And Michael was so good for me.
- What happened?
- He became a choreographer.
Now, my dear child...
you should get some sleep.
Oh, not yet.
I meant, what happened
between you and Michael?
- Priorities.
- He liked boys better than girls?
Not then. I... Well, how should I know?
We didn't talk about it
quite so openly in those days.
I meant Michael knew
that my priority was dancing.
Are you sorry?
No, I don't believe in being sorry.
We are what we are.
Am I like you?
I don't know.
- Now, listen, shouldn't you call home?
- I'd only wake Ethan.
Emma, I've stayed at Yuri's a lot.
Emilia, you continually surprise me.
And me.
I wish I knew who I was.
- You will.
- When?
Something happens.
There's always a moment.
- Maybe when Yuri wants to come back.
- I don't want him back.
Course, I'd love to dance with him,
and I love going to bed with him.
But I wanted it to be more,
and that gets in the way, doesn't it?
Which do you want the most?
Both? Well, that's something to dream about.
- Good night.
Emma?
It's so nice here.
I'm glad.
...I have simply got to reach him.
- May I?
- Of course.
- Hello, Emma.
- Michael, your call to London.
I'll take it here.
Emma, look at the poster Michael unearthed.
Our very first gala performance.
- You were still dancing. You too, Michael.
- You were in the corps de ballet.
Well, I'm behind a desk now.
Never mind. We've all kept this company
going, and that's what matters.
Yes, another year, another gala.
They remind me of the Olympics.
Dearie, you're not nervous after all this time?
All right, I'll call back in an hour.
This is going to be a super gala.
Marcia and Richard
are coming from Stuttgart, and...
- Do you suppose they'll travel tourist?
- Now, Adelaide.
I hear you're also going to do
Arnold's new ballet.
Dearie...
No, no. I was just wondering
if Emilia was going to be invited to the party.
So she will.
It's very pretty.
Why are you angry?
- Why are you?
- I'm not.
You damn well are, you're just
covering it up with ice, like Emma.
That horny little Russian behaved
like a bastard so you take it out on me.
I didn't hide anything from you.
I brought Rosie here. You knew exactly...
- I gotta wash my hair.
- Come here. Come here, Emilia.
You'll sit down. I wanna talk,
you'll listen to me. I'm still your mother.
When Daddy and Janina come,
do you want them to see us like this?
You wanna hurt them too?
- Talk. Can we talk it out?
- There's nothing to talk about.
Stop punishing me.
Look at me.
Look at me, please.
You know, Daddy and I have been
away from each other all summer.
Daddy wouldn't do what you did.
- How do you know?
- I know Daddy.
Like you know Yuri?
I'm the only louse?
Come on, Emilia. Be fair.
You hurt, I... I know.
And I understand. I can help you.
Let me. Don't shut me out, sweetheart.
We're friends.
Nobody can help you better than I can.
Nobody knows you better than I do. Nobody.
Momma. You're really just
angry about Emma, aren't you?
No.
Emilia, I love you.
I may have seemed like a monster,
but it was to help you understand what my
ballet is, not what you wanted to make it. I...
Bravo, Arnold. Keep talking like that.
She'll be more hysterical.
- I'm not hysterical.
- I'm not hysterical either.
- I don't know why you're not.
- What do you mean by that?
Maybe you're right. Some lousy gala,
biggest night of season.
It's only your biggest opportunity...
Emilia's biggest opportunity...
It's really nothing special.
- I have to go to the john again.
- Are you all right?
Don't worry about him. He'll be all right.
I have little secret for you. You know,
I think it's perfectly all right to be nervous.
- Really?
- Really. I know.
Dance well.
I'm not at all surprised. You know,
if we sell out the last two weeks,
we end the season
with a deficit of less than 80,000.
- Imagine.
- About the price of your necklace.
Oh, no, Dennis. This is paste.
The real one went for...
- What did it go for, Michael?
- The musicians' strike.
Oh, yes. Pigs.
Oh, hello, Mrs Stewart. I love the Stewarts.
They gave us $25,000 last year.
Emilia?
Oh, don't you look nice.
- You should see the glamour out front.
- I don't wanna think about it.
- You're doing Anna.
- The suicide scene.
All the other ladies will be in short tutus
and do at least a hundred pirouettes.
So this not-so-young lady will be
covered to the floor and act up a storm.
This is a knockout.
Wanna be my date for the party?
- Or do you have one?
- No, that's kaput.
Terrific dress you gave Emilia, too.
But you shouldn't have.
Why not? She's my godchild.
You just shouldn't have, that's all. Good luck.
Even now, there are moments
when it all comes together.
The dancing, the music, the lights...
Your mother chose to get married.
You got 19 curtain calls.
And you got pregnant.
I can't watch it any more.
They're too old for it. That depresses me.
I'm too old to do another one.
That depresses me more.
It's a beautiful ballet, Michael.
It'll live forever.
Why can't we?
Why aren't you watching?
It hurts. I keep seeing me and Emma
rehearsing for you.
Hey, if I ask you a question,
will you answer me truthfully?
What?
Jesus, can you believe this?
I've wanted to ask it for 20 years.
OK.
If I hadn't been pregnant, would you have
used me as Anna instead of Emma?
I don't remember, Deedee.
Honestly, I don't.
I wish to God I didn't.
Hurry up. You're going to miss my ballet.
I think she's gonna do it for you, Deedee.
It's wonderful.
I've gotta take my bow.
- To Emilia, dearie.
- I'm so glad for her.
Tradition is continuity,
and thank God I've lived to see it.
Second generation in our own family.
And yours, of course. Now,
what should we do with our baby ballerina?
I think she'd be lovely in Sleeping Beauty.
Perfect. We'll warm her up this season,
and then she'll warm up the box office
the next season.
- Do you want to tell her?
- No.
- I think it's a fabulous idea.
- I do too.
Isn't it wonderful? Aren't you excited?
I'm so proud of you. I was so excited...
- Has anyone seen my bitch of a wife?
- Now, dearie.
Very smart of you to do Anna.
Next time you'll have to lift me, Emma.
My back is ready for traction.
- Oh, poor Freddie.
- It's worth it.
- You know what we'd like you to do, Emma?
- A new ballet?
- Tradition makes a company...
- This is "tradition" night.
Oh, shut up, Michael.
I'd like to restore the full-length
Sleeping Beauty to our repertoire.
Oh, thank you very much,
but I don't think I could dance that any more.
No. But you could stage it.
You know it inside out.
It'd be fun, a new challenge.
She'd do it beautifully.
Don't you think so, Michael?
I think your timing's lousy, Adelaide.
Excuse me.
I really must do something to my face.
For God's sake, Adelaide.
Dearie, even Emma has to move on.
Like all the rest of us.
Hello, Deedee.
Champagne, please.
Emma?
Do you remember the fairy tales
we used to take turns reading to Emilia?
Like the one about the two princesses?
Every time one would open her mouth,
out came diamonds and rubies.
Every time the other one opened her mouth,
out came newts and hoptoads.
Newts and hoptoads, coming out.
Yes.
One of those little toads
has already made an appearance.
- Really? When?
- Tonight, in my dressing room.
When you said I shouldn't have
bought that dress for Emilia.
Twice you said it. Just before a performance.
I danced better tonight than I have in years.
So I heard.
Another little toad. You must have kept
quite a few bottled up all these years.
No.
Embalmed, really.
No, I think not.
Why don't you let them out?
I don't have a performance tomorrow.
OK.
Pick.
This is a tiny little one.
I'd practically forgotten him.
Why'd you make your best pal doubt herself?
And her hubby? Why, Emma?
Why'd you take the chance
of lousing up her marriage?
Why'd you say, "You better have that baby.
If you don't you'll never hold onto Wayne?"
I'm just curious.
You have a curious memory.
But don't we all. As I remember, I said if you
had an abortion you might lose Wayne.
No. That's sweet, but that's inaccurate.
I remember exactly your words.
For lo, these too many moons.
And eventually I figured out why you
said 'em, because I also remember...
that you said, " Forget about Michael's ballet,
there'll be others."
You clever little twinkle-toes.
You knew a ballet like that comes along
once in a career, and you wanted it.
Real bad.
So you lied to make sure
you got what you wanted.
I never had to lie to get what I wanted.
I'm too good.
Really.
Yes.
And I suppose if you said "bullshit"
you'd say it in French, wouldn't you?
If that word came as naturally to me as to you
I'd have used it several times by now.
In English.
But I think it's more appropriate
that you say it to yourself,
for trying to blame me for what you did.
Deedee, the choice was yours.
It's much too late to regret it now.
The same to you, Emma, me darlin'.
I don't regret mine.
Then why are you trying
to become a mother at your age?
That's not a little toad.
That's rather a large bullfrog.
I don't wanna be anybody's mother.
I think of Emilia as a friend.
And one reason I tried to help - stupid me -
I thought you'd be happy if your daughter
became what you never could be.
Meaning you. It's so lovely to be you?
- Well, obviously you think so.
- No.
And anyway, I doubt if
Emilia could become you.
She's as talented as you are,
and she works as hard.
There's one thing, dearest friend, that you are,
that Emilia, poor darling, is not.
And what, pray tell, is that?
A killer.
You'd walk over anybody
and still get a good night's sleep.
That exactly how you got
where you are, Emma.
Good girl.
Deedee...
- I'm sick to death of your jealousy.
- So am I.
Stop blaming your life on me. You picked it.
You picked it. You never let me
find out if I was good enough.
- You weren't. That's why you married Wayne.
- I loved Wayne.
So you said to hell with your career
and got pregnant to prove you meant it?
- Yes.
- Don't lie to me, lie to yourself.
You knew you were second-rate.
You got pregnant because Wayne
was a dancer and that meant "queer" then.
- To prove he was a man, you had a baby.
- That's a goddamn lie.
It's the truth and you know it. You saddled
him with a baby and blew his career.
Now she's better than you were
and you're jealous.
You're certifiable.
You'll use any excuse.
- What excuse?
- For trying to take away my child.
- I return the compliment. You're a liar.
- And you're a user. You know that?
You're a user, and you always have been.
First me, and then Michael.
Pretending to be in love with Michael.
Then Adelaide, and now Emilia.
- How Emilia?
- "How Emilia."
That display five minutes ago, upstairs.
Curtsy, embrace, applause.
It wasn't for her, it was for you.
You were using Emilia so that everybody in
the room would say, "Isn't Emma wonderful?"
You are wonderful. You are really amazing.
It is incredible how you keep going on.
You're over the hill and you know it.
You're terrified.
All you've got are your scrapbooks,
your old toe shoes and those ridiculous dogs.
What are you going to fill in with, Emma?
Not my daughter. You keep
your goddamn hands off my daughter.
- I'm better for Emilia then you are.
- The hell you are.
She came to me 'cause her mother wasn't
there. She was busy screwing her head off.
You bitch.
You know, if there'd been a photographer
here, you'd have had a whole new career.
I must look awful.
No, you don't. You look beautiful.
I don't know how you do it.
Give me your comb, I'll show you.
I'll take this half. Thank you.
I lost an earring.
I'm sorry.
- I'm not.
- You're not?
No. I'm not.
Boy, that jealousy.
Its poison, you know?
- It can make you a monster.
- It does make one unfair.
You got off some bull's-eyes.
So did you.
Deedee...
I don't really remember
what I said about having the baby.
But I do know...
I would have said anything
to make sure I got that ballet.
I just had to have it.
You were good. Good enough to threaten me.
Jesus...
Emma, you don't know...
how many years
I wanted to hear you say... just that.
Next bus to midtown Manhattan
in 30 minutes.
Emma had her all morning, coaching her.
Dahkarova's got her this afternoon.
- What's all the coaching for?
- OK, surprise.
Your daughter is dancing with Yuri
on the 15th.
- He'll wipe her out.
- The hell he will.
Emma and Dahkarova
have knocked themselves out.
- Ethan, show Janina her room, please.
- Sure.
You're going to love it here...
You wanna see something wonderful? Come.
Left, right, left, right.
OK?
Now, left shoulder. And...
Left, right. No...
So remember, it's left, right, left, right.
You must do it so that really you shine.
Like diamond, you know?
OK. And...
One. One. One.
More close. Close.
That's right, that's right, that's right.
More this way, this,
instead of this and this, OK?
Just very sharp. One.
Tap, tap, tap, tap, tap, tap.
That's very good. That's good.
No, it is good.
You think she can make it, Wayne?
Will you care if she doesn't?
No.
As long as she doesn't.
Still care you didn't?
Emma said I married you
'cause I knew I couldn't.
That's not true.
She said something else.
She said I got pregnant
that first time with Emilia...
because I wanted to prove to everybody...
that you weren't gay.
And that's partly true.
I knew that.
You did?
I had to prove it too.
So I let you ruin your career.
No, I saddled you with a family.
You could have been something...
Me? No, no, no, never. Not me.
Hey, I got what I wanted.
So did I.
- Why you don't ask me?
- Adelaide hates to pay overtime.
How you supposed to rehearse
without partner?
You make too much from Carolyn and me.
But I apologize anyway.
Keep doing. Come, come, come on.
So...
- Can we have supper?
- I'm busy.
- After supper?
- Bed.
OK.
Emilia...
Is joke.
I don't think so.
Come on. And...
That's no joke.
Nice?
Yes.
So smile.
Let's go on.
Bravo.
Emilia, it was marvelous. It was so
wonderful. You... Wasn't she wonderful?
Up these stairs and to the left.
Just one more kiss.
It was so good. Now it's all done.
Emilia. You were so good.
- You were so good.
- I just loved you.
And there he is. There's Yuri.
Yuri, this is my sister Janina.
You got it? You're kidding me.
You got his autograph?
You were absolutely wonderful, dearie.
You were incredible.
That was beautiful...
Pick a feeling.
Envy.
Her life is just beginning.
It's not a very long one, Deedee.
I know.
Well, as long as it gives her what she wants.
It will.
Oh, Emma.
If only she knew everything we know.
It wouldn't matter a damn.