- Playback, please.
- Five, four, three, two, one.
- Camera two, clear bars.
- Come on, let's hustle up.
Camera two is clear.
- The red hair was a good idea.
- We talked about cutting it.
- What did she say?
- She'll do what we tell her.
- Forty seconds.
- Studio B, this is remote.
We come out tight.
Studio B, this is Kimberly.
How soon do we go live?
Hey, hey, fellas!
Anybody listening to me?
- Is Mac there?
- Mac here. What is it?
We need five minutes before we go on.
How about after the commercial?
Not a chance, Kimberly.
We're coming to you in 40 seconds.
- No! We don't have a cameraman.
- Where's George?
He's taking a leak.
He locked the camera down.
You can't have a 2 and a half minute spot
on a static shot.
Better tell Pete to stretch
because remote's gonna be late.
Stretch, Pete. Slow it down.
Mac, can you start on a tight shot
and pull back to a wide?
Just get George back.
George?
We've got less than a minute.
We're about to go on the air.
Thanks.
You all ready? Everybody ready?
Break a leg!
Do I look okay?
The wind is from the south-southwest
at 5 miles an hour.
Now we switch to Kimberly Wells
for a live mini-cam report.
What did you do on
someone's birthday?
Send a card or flowers? Boring?
Here's something more imaginative.
What the hell is this?
This is one part of a new group
taking L.A. By storm.
"Live Wires", singing telegrams.
There's one for every occasion.
If it's your parents' anniversary,
you could send them an "operagram".
Or maybe your message
can't be expressed in words.
- That's the stuff I want to see.
- Look at this!
Get in tight on the navel.
Oh, mercy!
That is a "bellygram."
- Words cannot express that.
- That's the kind of stuff I like.
- Our ratings have gone up.
- Our research said she'd do well.
Very nice show, Kimberly.
Mac here. Can you hear me?
- Change of schedule.
- Again?
- We're going to Ventana.
- Great!
- Be there at 1:30.
- What about Richard and Hector?
- They'll pick you up.
- Right, okay.
Can I have a hit? Thanks.
I don't smoke.
It's 12:40 in Los Angeles...
temperature is 68 degrees
at the Civic Center.
Here's a new one, on the charts
for the first time this week.
They're here, Mr. Gibson.
Hi, Miss Wells.
Bill Gibson, Public Relations.
- Ventana special, take one.
- Okay, Kimberly, any time.
I'm Kimberly Wells, and I'm here
at the Ventana nuclear power plant.
The dome is called the "containment"
and houses the nuclear fuel.
Today in "Energy in California,"
we focus on nuclear power...
the transformation of matter
into energy, that experts tell us...
may be our best shot
at energy selfish sufficient...
- What happened?
- She said "selfish sufficiency."
- "Self-sufficiency."
- Let's keep going.
This simulated uranium is the exact
size of those used in the fuel rods.
This pellet contains more energy
than six carloads of coal.
Twenty million pellets are inside
the reactor vessel, here, at the "core."
Around the core is water,
which is used as a coolant.
Inside here is another set of rods
called the "control rods."
They control the nuclear reaction.
What happens is this:
When the core is activated,
the control rods are lifted out.
The nuclear fuel then sets up a
chain reaction, producing heat.
This boils the water,
that turns the turbine...
that turns the generator,
that produces electricity.
- That's it.
- That's great.
Let's get a reaction shot
of Kimberly.
- You made it seem simple.
- It is. I'll get your hard hats.
- Can you take us inside?
- That's next.
- All set, Kimbo?
- Oh, my God.
Get rid of my circles, Richard.
- I'll do my best. Let's see.
- Don't you touch my hair.
Reaction shot on William Gibson.
Did you get the pellet?
- It's not cheating too much?
- No, a highly complimentary angle.
Gibson's talking. Very interested.
Steam turns the turbine,
then the shit hits the fan.
Come on, Kimbo, hold it together.
Very good.
Uranium, they make bombs out
of that. They didn't mention that.
Wait till you get radiation
all over yourself.
- Those pellets will turn you on.
- Mr. Gibson?
- You got our hats?
- One size fits all.
- Can we film the containment area?
- Not when we're on-line.
- Can I leave my jacket here?
- Fine.
That man really does his job.
Don't blow it for me, Richard.
This is coverage, not controversy.
Be a friend?
This is the turbine room.
Sound rolling.
Ventana Power Plant, take one.
This is a rare chance
to see inside a nuclear power plant.
Right here, you can feel the power.
And power is what it's all about.
This 800 megawatt plant
makes enough electricity...
for a city of three quarters
of a million people.
We're now 50 feet above the turbine
room on an incredible moving crane.
What is this crane used for?
We use it to transport heavy pieces
of machinery, hundreds of tons.
- I think it'll support us.
- I hope so.
- How many people work here?
- At the present time, 150.
- Can they work in this noise?
- What noise? I don't hear it.
- What?
- This is 80 feet further down.
- Richard? Can you shoot here?
- No way.
Our supervisor, Herman De Young.
Kimberly Wells.
- I recognize you.
- Richard Adams, Hector Salas.
If I can do anything for you,
let me know.
- It's too dark here to film.
- I've got a better idea, anyway.
I think you'll like it.
- Is the containment that way?
- Yes.
God, my ears!
How old is this plant?
- We came on-line four years ago.
- Isn't another one opening soon?
Yeah, we'll license Point Conception
after the safety hearings.
They'll make more electricity than
the Hoover Dam and Grand Coulee.
Very interesting.
Your tongue is black, Richard.
You're contaminated.
- This is the control room.
- The brains of the beast.
The glass is bullet-proof
and soundproof.
- They're so young.
- It's a young industry.
- I see an older guy.
- Make you feel better?
No, he just looks competent.
Ted Spindler's been with the company
for years.
I'm sorry, you can't film here,
for security reasons.
- Not one shot?
- No. A cold drink?
- No, thank you.
- I'll take one.
- You always work together?
- Yeah.
No, we're just doing this together.
I made commercials with these bums.
Kimberly's full-time,
but Hector and I are independent.
Very independent.
- What was that?
- It felt like an earthquake.
- What have we got? Turbine trip?
- Yeah.
- "Generator trip, turbine trip."
- Reactor scram.
Okay, we're off the line.
Ted, stabilize the reactor.
- Radiation in containment!
- What level?
- Level eight, Jack.
- Okay. Borden, relax.
- It must be that safety valve.
- Holt, cut down the pumps.
Barney?
Come here and watch the feedwater.
Holler out the numbers.
Line up the valves.
Turn off that goddamned alarm!
How can I give orders in a racket
like that?
Within limits, Ted?
- Systems status?
- Pressure normal.
- Jack? Phone for you.
- We still have radiation.
- It's normal.
- Feedwater flow is decreasing.
- Godell.
- Bill Gibson here.
We've got some people here
shooting a TV news special.
- What the hell's going on?
- It's just a turbine trip.
- Nothing to worry about.
- High water level in the reactor!
Okay, relax. Everybody relax.
Dump the water.
It's just a routine turbine trip.
Find out
where that water's coming from.
We've got to get rid of it.
Look, Ted.
- Barney. Open 14 and 15.
- You can't do that, Jack.
- The book says you can't do it.
- We have to.
The flashing lights, "enunciators,"
means something needs attention.
- Godell says it's routine.
- Are you filming?
Godell was a submarine commander.
Turbine trips happen now and then.
It means the turbine is shut down.
It may be a feedwater leak,
but we can't tell which valve.
- Shut the isolation valves.
- You're gonna need that later.
You want to do it by hand? Do it!
- Closing isolation valves.
- Please go back to your stations.
Jack! Look at this
water level indicator. It's low.
This says it's high.
But that's...
Jesus Christ!
Barney, give me feedwater.
Ted, we may uncover the core.
Operations.
Jack Godell. We have an emergency.
Get everybody into safety areas.
All personnel, go to safety areas.
Caution! This is not a drill.
We stay here. This is a safety area.
Jesus!
Hurry up, Frank.
Move it!
Routine?
Talk to me, Barney.
Only one system is operational.
- Under nine inches.
- Is it holding?
- It's dropping.
- We're losing it.
My God.
Where's the coolant injection?
- It's down for maintenance.
- I don't believe it.
- We have to dump pressure.
- You can't take that chance.
Borden, let me know exactly
when the LPCI comes in.
- Water.
- Eight inches. Still dropping.
Please God, cover it!
- Cover it!
- We've got LPCI!
It's coming up.
- Don't bother with the interviews.
- Just give them the accident.
- Did you shoot normal?
- Normal ASA. It'll take 40 minutes.
- Mort! We've got a rush.
- There's a film in the machine.
- It's hot, do it. Will you wait?
- Go get them.
- What is it?
- Dynamite. Nuclear dynamite.
It's about time.
George has already written
the marathon piece.
- How did it go?
- I've got the lead story.
Fine. You'll be on
after the first commercial.
Did you hear me? I've got the lead
story. I'll write the script now.
An accident at Ventana.
It's all on film.
- Why didn't you call in?
- We didn't want to use the phone.
- The hostage story is ready.
- Frank, will you check that out?
- You want a beeper?
- Call me... No, we'll plan on it.
Kimberly, there's nothing
on the wire about an accident.
We were in the visitors' gallery
when it happened.
Whatever it was,
they were scared to death.
- Richard's got it on film.
- I'd better call Jacovich.
This is the script that goes with it.
Hello? Yeah.
Mr. Jacovich? It's for you.
Yeah. Who? Okay, I'll be right there.
- Do they know this film exists?
- No.
I'm not putting it on until
I find out what's going on.
- It's an exclusive!
- It's our best story in months.
We don't know exactly what it is.
We have to check our facts first.
- The fact is it happened.
- Put it in the vault. And move it!
Kimberly, you'd better hurry.
- I'll talk to you, Richard.
- Yeah, please do.
Gonna open on one, then Camera 2.
Places, everyone! Hurry up, Kimberly.
Bernie, you want to get me a spritz?
Just a little powder.
Stand by, studio. Hurry up, Kimberly.
Ten seconds.
Five, four, three, two...
Channel 3 Update, California's
most complete newscast.
With award-winning anchorman
Pete Martin...
and Kimberly Wells
with California Close-up.
Good evening. Six people died
in a light-airplane crash...
the social funding bill
may pass...
and the FDA have been asked
to ban all food additives.
If the license on Point Conception
is delayed, our cash flow dries up.
We have debts to every power utility
west of the Rockies.
I figure we'll be losing
$492,000 a day.
Well, after that, Herman,
you can only bring good news.
There's no damage, just cleaning up.
There will be an accident hearing.
The NRC is investigating.
Our testimony starts tomorrow.
- Can you be back on-line this week?
- If there are no snags.
Herman, I want you to
keep that investigation on track.
Be thorough,
make sure everything's all right.
But let's not waste any time.
- Let's get it over with.
- Yes, sir.
And for God's sake,
we've had our surprise for the year.
Hello? It's Gibson.
Hi, Bill. Yeah?
What kind of film? They were where?
- Good morning, Kimberly.
- Hi, David.
What are you talking about?
I filmed an accident!
- In a nuclear power plant.
- Is "accident" the right word?
Nice of you to make it.
- This station is yellow.
- Obviously, you've made a decision.
- Don't start.
- It was just an observation.
Listen to this. "Nuclear plants
are security installations..."
and as such fall under title 18
of the United States criminal code.
"Unauthorized photography is a felony."
We're all accessories
just for keeping that film here.
Bullshit!
Don't kick me, I won't shut up.
Have you seen the official release?
"An unanticipated transient."
What the hell is that?
We could have been killed.
- Isn't that stretching it a bit?
- You think so?
They say you were never in danger.
If you'd been there, you'd find it
hard to believe there was no danger.
Let's show it to an expert.
- It stays in the vault.
- This is all a cover-up.
Kimberly told me she saw
you talking to their PR guy, Gibson.
I told him the film
stays in the vault.
- Is this a conspiracy?
- It is not a cover-up.
- They didn't have to say anything.
- They only did because of us.
They did what they should do.
They're holding an investigation.
It'll be a fast investigation with
another plant waiting for a license.
Calm down.
Who is conducting the investigation?
The Nuclear Regulatory Commission.
We'll get a full report.
Then we will decide
what to do with the film.
I really don't believe this. I just...
- Are you just going to sit here?
- Performers don't make policy.
She's a professional, right?
This is a sensitive subject.
We're not going to risk a massive lawsuit.
- You're being pressured.
- You're being hysterical, Richard.
And you're being
a chickenshit asshole.
Richard.
I'll talk to him.
- Why did you do that?
- They really got to you?
All we could hope for is that they'd
go for the scoop, but they didn't.
And they're right. They'd be sued.
I'm not ashamed of having a
good job, and I intend to keep it.
If that means they've got me,
then they've got me.
You were the one that called me
and asked if I could get you work.
- Thank you very much.
- Anytime.
Talk to him later, Kimberly.
The van is waiting to take you
to your "Live at Noon" spot.
I'm going to the zoo.
It's the tiger's birthday.
A faulty relay opened
the generator breakers.
The transient in water and pressure
caused the turbine to trip.
Relief valve number eight
opened automatically.
This shut down the reactor.
A "scram" situation.
- But the second shock wave...
- Excuse me.
Sir, it's not really a shock wave.
It was more of a shudder.
A vibration.
So you were clear in your mind
up to this point?
Yes, sir.
- The water level began to drop?
- We thought the level was high.
The water level recorder was stuck.
You began to cut off the feedwater,
thinking the water was too high?
Yes, sir.
- But the water was dangerously low?
- Low, yes.
Why didn't your operator
look at the other indicators?
I don't know.
I didn't look at it, either.
- Jack, how did it go?
- Okay.
- What did you tell them?
- I'm not allowed to discuss it.
- Mr. Spindler.
- Yeah, right here.
- Can I interest you in this?
- In your ear, Pete.
Do you know what she's getting?
Two hundred and fifty thou.
- Did you know that?
- She started out doing the weather.
Her visual image is perfect.
I like her hair red.
We're sitting there.
- Puerto what?
- Puerto Vallarta.
- How can you afford it?
- Three hundred and sixty-nine dollars.
- May I?
- Mr. Jacovich.
- Excuse me.
- Enjoying yourself?
I saw your zoo piece, it was brilliant.
We got a lot of calls.
How are you doing
on the energy specials?
We just have the beginning
and ending to do. We're editing.
I think you'll be pleased.
I want to apologize for Richard.
He's difficult sometimes.
But he's the best cameraman I know.
- You haven't worked with many.
- Yes, as a matter of fact, I have.
If he was on the staff,
I'd fire him. I don't like him.
There were no staff crew available
for the specials.
And Richard's won awards.
Hot-head award, Foul-mouth
award, Can of Worms award.
What he said was wrong, I agree.
- What will you do with the film?
- The legal hassles have just begun.
Don't you worry,
we'll take care of it.
- Coffee?
- No, thank you.
You just keep doing a good job.
Our ratings have gone up
because of you.
So Don,
let me do some hard news.
You're better with the softer stuff.
You're not an investigator.
Don't try to be anything else.
- I love you doing what you do best.
- I'd be good doing news.
We'll see.
Let's take a look at the specials.
I like your hair like that.
Don't stay too late.
You lonely old coot.
You want to come inside?
Come and have a little chat with me.
Us two girls sitting by the fire.
What can I give you?
How about some yucky old lettuce?
You must be hungry.
Let's see here.
Just you and me, kid.
You want a bath?
Hi, it's your mother.
I hate these machines.
Call me. Bye-bye.
Corrine here. I was going to ask
you to take me to the party.
See you there, bye.
How about those ratings!
Hi, Kimberly, it's Buck Brewer,
the American Airlines pilot.
I'll be here for a couple of days
and I'd love to see you.
Call me if you're in before 11.
Oh, shit.
It's your mother again.
Don't forget your father's birthday.
He says he doesn't want presents,
but you know him. Call me tomorrow.
This is Richard.
You really are an asshole.
Ted? Can I see you a sec?
I wanted to get your impressions
of one phase here.
Just after the turbine trip,
did you feel a vibration?
- The steam line closure.
- No, that's here. I mean later.
- More of a vibration.
- Right here. It's relief valve 14.
I don't think so.
Didn't they ask you about this?
- They asked us not to discuss it.
- That's during the investigation.
- Is this part of the investigation?
- What's the matter?
I was in there
for twice as long as anyone else.
You Navy guys have credentials,
but I'm a 25-year company man.
I knew nothing nuclear before.
You tell me, where do you think
the axe of "human error" will fall?
Why do you think
they want a scapegoat?
Tradition.
I'm going to get a cup of coffee.
What goes up, must come down,
and that's what happened in Cudahy.
Hot-air balloons
are lighter than air...
but not lighter than gravity.
So sometimes, they don't fly.
William Levin was flying near Cudahy
when his balloon came down.
It didn't land in a tree-top.
It wouldn't land on a flat roof.
It landed on a camper.
There were no injuries,
except wounded pride.
But the police held no grudge.
They gave him a ride home. Pete?
- Is that your hot-air report?
- You're the expert.
I don't know about that.
We'll be back at 6:00.
For Kimberly Wells and all of us,
I'm Pete Martin, have a good day.
I can't believe what you said!
What about my credibility?
You'll recover.
Kimberly.
Have you seen Richard?
Not since yesterday,
but I'll probably see him today. Why?
The son of a bitch stole the film.
I just came from the vault.
You brought him in, so it's your neck.
Jacovich is away until tomorrow.
I want the film back by then.
Okay, Mac. Thanks.
Hey, guys!
- Give me a look.
- Where did you get it?
- Ted, what's going on?
- It's the preliminary report, Jack.
That was fast.
Listen: "Personnel responded
swiftly and professionally," et cetera.
"While some errors were made
and procedures violated...
the overall result was containment
of a potentially costly event."
We're going back on-line tomorrow.
In this section of "Energy in
California" we look at solar power.
What will it do for our economy
and our environment?
Mr. Thurston,
according to a recent study...
Richard!
Hector? Where's Richard?
I don't know where he is.
He gave me some work to do
and he left.
He stole the film from the station.
He's going to get us into trouble.
- Where is he, Hector?
- I don't know.
You're an observant person. You must
have some idea where he was going.
He took the projector and the film.
Maybe he went back to the plant
to get someone to explain it.
And he calls me an asshole.
- Tell him to call and fill me in.
- You're a real mensch.
- See you guys.
- Good night.
- Is that the girl from Channel 3?
- Yes.
- Are you looking for somebody?
- Yes, a friend of mine.
Drink? Your friend will show up.
It's the only decent bar around.
- That's what I heard.
- Come on, have a drink.
- Yeah, I could use a drink.
- Good. Harry?
Someone from the plant?
What would you like?
- Scotch on the rocks.
- I saw you on the 6. Terrific.
- You work at the plant.
- Yes, Jack Godell.
This is Alma and Ted Spindler.
Kimberly Wells.
- What's all the celebrating?
- We got a clean bill of health.
- The investigation's over?
- Why are you so surprised?
- I was there. I saw the accident.
- There wasn't any accident.
- What was it?
- A faulty relay in the generator.
- A what?
- A faulty relay in the generator circuit.
- And that's all?
- And a stuck valve.
On the house.
- You seemed relieved afterwards.
- There wasn't any accident.
When do you start up again?
The plant?
Tomorrow or something.
Was the investigation so quick
because of Point Conception?
Because the same company is trying
to get a license for a new plant?
You are here looking for a friend?
You're not trying to get a story?
No. I wish I were.
I'm not an investigative reporter.
I don't like reporters.
Most feel the only good news
is bad news.
And, God,
they give our industry a rough time.
Excuse me.
Jack, we'll see you in the morning.
Don't you think reporters
serve a public function?
Ask me a "public function" question,
and I'll tell you.
All right.
Was the public, at any time,
in danger...?
Miss Wells,
could I have your autograph?
Oh, my God, it is.
I thought he was kidding.
- You look just like you do on TV.
- Who shall I write it to?
- Cindy, C-l-N-D-Y.
- Do you know who's here tonight?
The most beautiful TV personality,
Miss Kimberly Wells!
Unreal. Wait, where were we?
You were asking me
a public function question.
Was the public in danger
as a result of the accident?
I use that word deliberately,
because a good reporter would.
Watch out, you'll be on TV.
Excuse me. Let's sit there.
Let me try to explain something
that people do not understand.
These plants are designed
for the possibility of accidents.
Everything that could go wrong
was considered.
Our quality control
is only equaled by NASA.
Every part is tested again and again.
Every weld is radiographed.
Everything is checked
and double-checked and re-checked.
You haven't answered the question.
All right. In everything man does,
there's an element of risk.
So we have "defense in depth."
That means two back-up systems.
You saw it.
There was no radiation leakage.
The system works. Even with
a faulty relay or a stuck valve...
that system works.
There was no accident.
- Can I get you another drink?
- No, thanks. I have to get up early.
I'm covering the migration
of grey whales at Point Mugu.
You're halfway there.
Why don't you spend the night...
somewhere around here?
Then in the morning,
slide over the mountains.
No, I have to read so much.
- And find your friend.
- And I have to find my friend.
- Thank you.
Good night.
When you turn on a light,
think 10 percent me.
- What?
- That's how much power we supply.
Good night, Miss Wells.
You got a map? I'll follow you.
Kim.
- I talked to Richard.
- Where is he?
He said if you want the film,
he's at Point Conception.
Some big demonstration.
You've got great timing.
Hang on,
we may change our plans.
Get me Mac.
Marty, Jim.
Get a crew to clean this up.
Rusty, go over this pump.
Check every seal, every rivet and nut.
I want a full report
after every shift, okay?
Let's go, Jack. We've got to talk.
- That could be very, very serious.
- What the hell are we going to do?
- Tear the pump down and inspect it.
- We can't do that.
We'd be down for two weeks.
- The leak must be in a pump seal.
- You don't know that.
- We tighten the seals and test it.
- How will we really find...?
TV monitors
might tell us what's happening.
They might tell us what's happening.
Get on top of this, Jack.
Test it as soon as possible.
I have to call them.
I said we'd be back on-line by 3:00.
To the Atomic Safety Board:
These are pictures of our children.
They cannot be here, so we ask you
to consider them in your decision.
They are the ones who will inherit...
the consequences of your actions.
And now the names of the children.
Ronald Borsak, 5 years old.
Tony Bulotti, 7.
Robert Grimble, 1 and a half.
Douglas Brown, 2.
Arnold Kelsey, 14.
Ernest Chullet, 10. Dean Smith, 12.
Juan Garcia, 3.
Lonnie Lewis, Scott Lewis, 12.
Blake Holtfield, 2.
Eric Jones, 5. Steven Lang, 13.
- Richard!
- I have to talk to this lady.
Did you miss me?
Unbelievable! Where have you been?
Where's the film?
If you don't get it back,
Jacovich will call the cops.
Come on,
I want to show you something.
- I'm working.
- I'm in room E309.
- I need that film.
- I understand. E309, all right?
You wait for me.
- They'll be in the background?
- Yeah. Over there.
Here?
Them, and a two-shot with me?
How much time do we have?
The sun will be in my eyes.
- Who have you got for me?
- This man's pro-nuke.
Okay, we're going with the red-head
for a whale story, right?
What's she doing? A nuclear story?
Hard news? Okay, I'll handle it.
Now here's Kimberly Wells
at Point Conception.
- I'm speaking with Al Baietti...
- I hope Jacovich isn't watching.
I believe that means
you have particular concern...
about health and safety measures
and nuclear energy, is that correct?
Studio control. One moment, please.
Mr. Jacovich.
Hi, Don.
I want the cameras here,
here, and here.
Stuart, I need somebody
in the generator room.
We run a pump test at 1300.
What is that?
Demonstrators at Point Conception.
Watch, Jack. They're unbelievable.
Hazel Washburn. I'm a housewife.
I have six grandchildren,
two of whom are here.
I'm protesting because I'm
frightened of nuclear energy.
How will you keep
your grandkids warm?
What do we do
in case of an accident?
How can we be absolutely sure the
waste disposal is taken care of?
- We still go on-line at 3?
- According to De Young.
- Who is it?
- Kimberly.
This is the lady I told you about.
- You can't show this.
- Wait, listen to them.
That guy is a physics professor,
and the other is a nuclear engineer.
You can stop it here.
I thought we'd better show you.
What do you think?
I think you're
probably lucky to be alive.
And the same goes
for all of Southern California.
- Steady as a rock.
- Ted, go to 110.
Wait a minute.
We're at the top of the scale.
It can go up to 110. We'll watch it here.
Okay, go ahead.
Take it to 110.
The seals are holding. Shut it off
and go back on-line as planned.
Leave it there a minute.
In a reactor scram, the system
works automatically for 10 minutes.
They obviously have a problem.
Could you stop it there?
- They're doing it manually.
- It's a stuck valve.
- How do you know?
- I was there last night.
I talked to Jack Godell.
He said it was a stuck valve.
- You talked to him last night?
- That's right.
The stuck valve is forcing them to
deal with the reactor water level.
It looks serious.
In the control room...
these lights are concerned
with core water level.
They might have come close
to exposing the core.
If that's true, we came very close
to the China Syndrome.
If the core is exposed,
the fuel heats up in a matter of minutes.
Nothing stops it. It melts through
the ground, theoretically to China.
But when it hits ground water,
it explodes into radioactive clouds.
The number killed
depends on the wind.
A vast area would be uninhabitable,
with many cancer cases later.
ED8.
D8. R6.
Perfect.
And perfect.
"D.B. Royce."
Herman, we've got a serious problem.
- The pump checked out.
- Those tests tell us nothing.
My God, Jack,
you ran it up to 110 percent.
That won't tell us what will happen
if we scram at full power again.
Any sudden shock...
Goddamn it, listen to me! Just once.
I'm sorry.
I went through the quality reports.
There were irregularities
in the contractor's documentation.
So I checked the welding X-rays.
Here's a sample.
They're identical.
It's the same picture over and over.
Jack, no contractor can supply
every stupid document.
They cheated a bit, so what?
These X-rays are six years old.
- So are the welds.
- For God's sake, Jack...
Listen to me.
- We need new radiographs.
- What? That's absurd.
It would take a long time,
and cost 15 to 20 million dollars.
We've got to get back on-line today.
The company's losing a fortune.
Start her up, Jack.
Borden, get some service
water samples for health analysis.
- Yes, sir.
- Barney, did you check the pumps?
Yes. Flow and temperatures are okay.
The valve at station 47 is clear.
How are you coming, Jack?
It's almost 3:00.
Reactor on stand-by.
Turbine on turning gear.
All right.
Load dispatch.
Load dispatch, this is Ventana.
Approaching power, normal procedure.
I'll contact you to synchronize
the generator.
We'll be back on the grid soon.
We've got a clear board, Jack.
We've got a clear board.
Follow normal sequence
for rod withdrawal.
Group one.
Group three.
Group five.
Group seven.
Group two.
Group four.
- Get these films developed.
- Mr. Royce?
- Can I speak to you for a minute?
- Sure.
- I'm a shift supervisor at Ventana.
- What can I do for you?
- We had a problem at the plant.
- But everything checked out fine.
- You're going back on the line?
- Yes.
- Did you sign for these X-rays?
- Yes. What about it?
- You kept signing the same one.
- The welds are fine.
- How do you know?
- Every weld I checked was fine.
- How many didn't you check?
- They're fine.
- But the plant may not be safe.
- It's perfectly safe.
I don't have the time to go through
every goddamn X-ray.
- How many? Which ones?
- I don't remember.
- There's plenty more.
- You know the procedures.
There's no problem.
The welds will hold for 6000 years.
- I'll go to the NRC.
- Wait, think it over!
You're talking about
a billion-dollar lawsuit.
Wait, slow down!
Don't make trouble for yourself.
This isn't some piss-ant company,
this is Foster and Sullivan.
They've got their own security men.
Do I have to spell it out?
Wait!
They have their own security men!
Redman!
We've got a problem.
- The whales will be there tomorrow.
- It was scheduled.
We advertised it.
I want to see her. And you too.
Who is it?
It's Kimberly Wells.
I need to talk to you.
This is my cameraman.
- You lied.
- It was a stuck valve.
- It was not.
- I filmed that accident.
I showed it to a nuclear engineer.
You almost uncovered the core.
We won't leave
before you tell us what happened.
Some nut told you we almost
uncovered the core, but we didn't.
The system works.
That's not the problem.
If that's not the problem, what is?
I love that plant. It's my whole life.
- What is the problem?
- The shudder.
The vibration I felt
during the turbine trip.
No one else was worried.
I found that some idiot...
phonied the welding X-rays.
How can someone falsify
the records of a nuclear reactor?
- Holy shit.
- The plant's not safe.
The vibration was a warning.
It should be shut down and X-rayed.
But that means millions of dollars,
so we don't want to talk about that.
And no one will believe me.
But if they ever put too much
pressure on that pump...
- If they rupture those pipes...
- It's the China Syndrome?
That's possible.
Would you go on television
and tell the public?
When I said I'd go to the NRC,
a man threatened my life.
- Who?
- A bastard at the building company.
The same company that built
Point Conception.
If I gave you those X-rays, could you
get them shown at the hearings?
- Lowell will present them.
- He'll do it?
I'll try to get the station to send
me there, so it gets on the air.
Richard, I'm late.
I'll call you
to work out the transfer.
I can't give them to you.
Get me someone you trust.
- Don't leave here.
- Call me later.
- Stand by, commercial.
- Roll V1.
Five, four, three, two, one. Fade up.
- Where's Tasha?
- Tell Tasha we'd like to see her.
Tell her to hurry up.
Boy, is that hot!
Hello? No, she never showed up.
- Thirty seconds.
- Stand by.
Camera two, is that as wide as
you can get? Okay, lock it down.
Fifteen seconds, quiet please.
- Come to your wide shot.
- V1, set for your next piece.
- She's here!
- Tell her to hurry.
- Kimberly just walked in.
- Five, four, three, two...
This is Channel Three Update...
So nice of you to drop by.
Cutting it a little close, Kimberly.
And Kimberly Wells.
And now, Pete Martin.
Good evening. There's been a
bombing in the Middle East...
- When am I on?
- What the hell is going on?
- Get Jacovich, I have a story.
- Richard, I want that film.
- Kiss my ass.
- You'll get the film. Get Jacovich.
Winds of up to 100 mph.
A storm-related death was reported.
We'll get the X-rays to you
tomorrow by noon.
You're not doing it. It's not your job.
Not as you define it.
But I'm tired of birthdays
with tigers and lions.
- It's my story, I'll do it.
- Who's the guy at the plant?
- He has to be anonymous.
- Lowell will submit the evidence.
Elliot Lowell is not objective.
If you don't want it, someone will.
Some stations like hard news.
Crossing in three, two, one...
Up two, cue Pete.
Now it's time for Kimberly Wells.
What do you have for us tonight?
From Burbank, a veterinarian
who makes house calls on sick fish.
Or is it aquarium calls?
He says owners should try
to think like fish.
Then when it's time to change
the water, they'll just know.
The doctor offers classes ranging
from fin congestion and tail rot...
to pop-eye and bladder bloat.
The most common fish ailment?
People problems. Dirty hands
and cigarette ashes in the tank.
- I guess no one's immune.
- It's quite a service.
To the Atomic Safety Board
and the public:
I speak for my friends,
who choose not to speak.
These hearings do not hear
public sentiment.
The NRC has held 60 hearings,
and not a license has been refused.
We are proceeding to build
nuclear plants...
yet we have no program
for the disposal of nuclear waste.
Any further words are pointless.
- What do you think?
- I don't know.
You think it's the film?
Your five minutes are up.
Dr. Elliot Lowell.
Mr. Chairman?
I'm expecting some information
which will arrive shortly.
- I'd appreciate a delay.
- Granted.
What the hell are you doing?
What are you doing?
Hey, man!
What the hell are you doing?
Hey!
Hey, man!
I am also concerned about the
misinformation about nuclear waste.
Much is made of the fact
that this waste is radioactive...
and therefore there is some
special problem produced by it.
One hears that it is necessary
to wait centuries before it is safe.
Channel 3, KXLA Los Angeles.
- Yes?
- It's Kimberly.
- Did you meet Hector?
- A couple of hours ago.
- He's not here. You must help us.
- What?
You've got to testify.
- I understand.
- Please hurry.
My God.
- Ask if they've heard from Hector.
- Jim, see if Hector's checked in.
Thank you for the opportunity
to put this on record.
Dr. Lowell?
Has your information arrived?
- Could I request another hour?
- We have a very busy agenda.
We'll schedule you for another day.
We'll now take a 20-minute recess.
I'll be downtown.
The Highway Patrol called. Hector's
been in an accident on Highway 6.
- What?
- Hector's been in an accident.
Hector's been in an accident.
He's on Highway 6.
Make sure Godell's on the agenda.
- Jesus, Mr. Godell.
- Sorry.
He'll get shot
driving up here like that.
What the hell is that?
What's going on?
Don't fight it. Okay.
Ready? Cover up his face.
Hector!
- Is he alive?
- Yes, he'll be all right.
It's okay, he's going to make it.
- Herman?
- I can't hear.
- How high will you be going?
- Are you drunk?
Spindler?
Hi, Jack.
Okay, I'll take care of it.
- How high are we?
- We'll have full power by midnight.
- No, we can't risk another scram!
- Have you been drinking?
What?
There may be a defect in the pump.
- I've got my orders.
- There was a vibration!
Ted, a sudden surge
could kick that off again.
Go home.
Why don't you just go home?
- What's the matter with Jack?
- I don't know.
- Where are we at?
- Seventy-five percent of full power.
- Take it up to 93 percent.
- All right.
- Leave it there, Jim.
- Jesus Christ, Jack!
Just get out. Go on. Get out.
Get out!
- You can't do this, Jack.
- I mean it, Ted.
Get out. Everybody, out.
It's all right, Hector. Hang on.
Easy.
- Have you come to finish him off?
- We had nothing to do with this.
I must talk to Kimberly.
Godell took over the control room.
He wants to talk to you.
Someone's tampering
with the security circuits.
If they don't stop,
I'll flood the containment area.
- You understand?
- Ted. He knows.
- We must find another way in there.
- And fast.
Thank you for coming.
I hope you can convince him to come out.
- Kimberly's here.
- Bring her down. Alone.
He wants you to go down alone.
Bill, step out where I can see you.
Kimberly, when you hear the bolts,
come in alone.
Go ahead.
What happened to your friend?
- There was an accident.
- No accident.
- I know. The radiographs are gone.
- Those bastards.
They chased me, so I came here.
But the idiots want full power.
It can't take that.
- What will you do?
- What I was going to do.
You'll interview me on TV. Here. Now.
Can I talk to my cameraman up there?
He wants an interview.
You have to talk him out of it.
We've managed to keep it quiet...
but if anyone knows,
there'll be a SWAT team here.
Get him to come out,
and we'll listen to him.
No one will get hurt.
Don't mess around. He said,
either he makes a public statement...
or he'll flood the containment
with radiation.
- Can he do that?
- Yes. He can just open the valves.
He can do anything he wants.
But if he floods the containment...
you may as well bury this place.
We'll do it. He can go on the air.
- Mr. McCormack...
- Shut up, Gibson.
Joe, keep an eye on this gentleman.
They agreed.
But I won't just call your station.
- I'll call every TV station in L.A.
- They agreed.
I can't take responsibility for this.
Should we let him wreck
a billion-dollar investment?
It'll take the press an hour
to get here.
- Don't count on it.
- I expect you to take care of them.
- You do your job, and I'll do mine.
- Yes, sir.
What's holding you people up?
You spent a fortune on security
to prevent entry to the control room.
Don't tell me what you can't do.
Tell me what you can do.
We could scram the plant.
If we can do it without him knowing,
it'll distract him while we get in.
- Can you do it without him knowing?
- We can sure as hell try.
Scram the son of a bitch.
No, Tom, that won't work.
Who's the man standing up there?
McCormack, chairman of the board.
- Are we in danger?
- I brought it down to 75 percent.
- Why don't you just shut it down?
- Then I'd lose power.
If we're on-line, I'm a threat.
Look. If we take over the generator,
we can cause a turbine trip.
- That will make the reactor scram.
- That's what spooked him, a scram.
Whose side are you on?
You want to give him a hand?
- How long will it take?
- I have to bridge a dozen circuits.
They all terminate here.
Maybe 30 minutes, maybe an hour.
Okay, get started.
I'll start with an introduction
to explain where we are.
Then I'll introduce you.
You should say who you are
and how long you've worked here.
Have you thought about
what you'll say?
You want a cup of coffee?
Yeah.
You want cream and sugar?
Agent four, over.
Level six, report in.
It's going to be fine.
Agent 14,
report to the staging area.
Tell McCormack
the police cars are arriving.
Hey, right here!
Come on.
Right here.
Kimberly's in there?
You'll take a crew in with you?
Just like I did it before.
We'll get sound from the intercom.
- Use all the available light.
- Can I ask you some questions?
- Let's go.
- Are we on the air right now?
We have nothing to say right now.
Just be patient.
- Can you give us his name?
- Godell.
Is this a SWAT team being deployed?
What the hell is a SWAT team
doing here?
- Is he armed up there?
- There are rumors.
Have your men follow me
up the back elevator, okay?
- GB3, 17.
- No, that's a front circuit panel.
Studio B, this is remote with
tone and bars. Do you copy?
We've got tone and bars.
We have bars.
Give us picture as soon as you can.
- Video, can you get camera two?
- We can go at any time.
- This is irresponsible.
- I can't hear you, Gibson.
They're here.
Bobby, set up on sticks here.
David, a two-shot at the console.
Ron, take sound from this speaker.
Okay, we made it.
The press is everywhere.
Let's just work out the sound,
and we're ready. All right?
- What?
- It'll be a few minutes.
Stay clear of the TV monitor.
There are two doors,
locked from the inside.
Get De Young.
- How do you turn on the speaker?
- Right here, that button.
- Do it.
- Lock it open?
You all set? Give us a voice level.
Testing, one, two, three, four.
- Move closer to the speaker.
- Testing, this is Kimberly Wells.
Get a little closer together.
- What's next?
- TB 46, a ground wire.
- TB 39, a ground wire.
- Nearly ready.
We've got picture.
Pete to the phone, please.
We're getting close.
Just checking levels.
Hold up something white
for color test.
- Okay?
- He's setting color balance.
Let's get the show on the road.
Stand by.
When the red light comes on,
you're on the air.
Goddamn it, do something.
He's about to go on the air.
Okay, David? Stand by, let's go.
Spindler?
We're almost ready. I'll call you.
Do something.
Camera one.
Stand by, camera two. Go, Pete.
This is Pete Martin.
We interrupt our programming...
- power plant, where an employee...
- And is demanding to make...
exclusive live coverage...
This is Kimberly Wells.
I'm in the control room
of Ventana Nuclear Power Plant.
With me is Jack Godell,
who has taken over the plant...
and has demanded
to make a statement. Mr. Godell?
I'm a shift supervisor,
I've been here since it opened.
I don't want to hurt anybody...
or contaminate California.
I just want you to...
Monday last, at 3:36 p. m...
we had an event happen...
We had an accident.
- Jesus Christ.
- Nobody was hurt.
It was more serious than you'll
ever know. It was human error.
A faulty relay caused the generator
breakers to trip.
- Don't be technical!
- I know it sounds ridiculous...
That's the reactor water level.
The pen in the meter got stuck.
Because of that,
we got the wrong reading.
We tried to keep water out.
But in fact the level
was dangerously low.
We only had one auxiliary pump left
to get water into the core.
- Come on.
- But that's not why I'm here.
- I'm not making sense.
- It's all right.
There's something else. You see...
- We got it.
- Ready to cut the circuit.
It's so complex, yet it's simple.
It's so complex, this whole place.
It's very difficult.
But that's not why I'm...
The vibration was not normal.
There was a vibration. I know.
Do it, for Christ's sake.
Oh, no. No!
- Cut him off.
- We're losing picture.
What happened?
Oh, my God, why? You idiots!
- He's gone nuts.
- We've lost our picture.
Please, God, no!
Stop!
Stop it!
Check the feedwater.
- Get a doctor.
- Get a medic!
I can feel it.
- What did he say?
- "I feel it."
My God, it's that pump.
- Check feedwater valves!
- Stabilize the reactor.
Stay at your stations!
Damn it, shut up!
Christ.
It's over.
It's stable.
If you've just tuned in,
what happened was this:
At 4:00, an armed employee
at Ventana took control.
We began an interview,
but lost the signal.
- We do have a second camera.
- We have picture.
I'm told we can switch
back to our second unit.
There, you see it.
A big crowd outside the plant.
This is what's going on.
Don't deviate.
Stick to the prepared text.
- Mr. Gibson, what's happening?
- Gather around, please.
I have an announcement.
A few minutes ago,
the situation was resolved.
The Ventana nuclear plant is secure.
- Did you get any of it?
- He looked like a lunatic.
I stress that the public
was never in any danger.
- Was there any damage?
- Yes, but it was totally contained.
A disturbed employee was humored,
so that we could regain control.
- Had he been drinking?
- Yes, we think so.
Mr. De Young is superintendent,
and Mr. Spindler ran the operation.
Get your picture back.
There's Kimberly.
Mr. De Young, a few minutes ago...
Please let me ask a question.
- Losing picture.
- Let me ask a question!
A few minutes ago, Jack Godell
was shot dead. Why was he killed?
Just a minute, Miss Wells.
He was emotionally disturbed.
- Who ordered the SWAT team in?
- He was out of control, dangerous.
Mr. Spindler, do you agree?
Was he disturbed?
- Had he reason to be disturbed?
- I don't know.
- Had he been drinking?
Why did he do it?
What did he say to you?
- What did he say to you?
- That the plant should be closed.
Do you agree with that?
- It's not my place to say.
- Then whose is it?
- Ted, we have to go...
- Mr. Gibson, let him speak!
Whose place is it?
Wait a minute!
Jack Godell was my best friend.
These guys say he was a loony.
He wasn't a loony.
He was the sanest man I ever knew.
- He believed the plant was unsafe?
- Yeah.
Otherwise he wouldn't have done it.
He wasn't like that.
I didn't know all the details.
He told me a few things.
There will be an investigation
this time.
Then people will know
Godell was a hero.
Jack Godell was a hero.
I have to go.
- Those were personal comments.
- Come on, we're live.
Godell was his friend,
and obviously he's distraught.
Come on. Hold on.
Remind Kimberly we're still live.
- Spindler is only an employee...
- Come on, we're on the air.
Pete, I met Jack...
I met Jack Godell two days ago.
He wasn't a drunk or a crazy man.
He was about to present evidence
to show this plant should be shut down.
I'm sorry, I'm not very objective.
I hope it doesn't end here.
This is Kimberly Wells,
live at Channel 3.
Go right to commercial.
We'll be back with more about the
Ventana nuclear plant take-over...
right after this.
- Incredible.
- She did a hell of a good job.
I must say, I'm not surprised.
The SWAT team appeared on the scene,
went into the control room...
and something took place there
to trigger the accident.
Mr. Godell died at the controls
of this atomic plant.
Val Clenard, Channel 7 News.