THREE COLORS:
RED
Come here.
320 04 86.
Leave your name and number
and I’ll get back to you.
Valentine?
Are you home?
Are you there?
I’ll call back later.
Michel...
I was having breakfast.
First it was busy, now the machine.
Are you alone?
Alone.
All alone?
All alone. They just called me
for a photo session.
They want to see me.
When did you get back?
Yesterday. I called,
but you weren't home.
Our car was stolen in Poland.
They got everything:
passports, money, clothes, everything.
So what happened?
We found a nice guy
who put us up.
The Embassy gave us money
and passports. We made it home.
Michel?
I felt lonely last night.
What did you do?
All night long,
I slept with your jacket.
I wanted to be with you.
I can't now, Valentine.
I know.
What's the weather like there?
Typical English weather:
it's pouring.
It rained here yesterday.
Now it's sunny. It's springtime.
What did you do last night?
At the cinema.
I went to see "The Dead Poets Society".
What a good movie!
Yes, I liked it a lot.
I'll call you tonight.
I’ll be back at 7. I’ll stay in.
I’ll talk to you later.
- Michel?
- Yes?
I miss you.
Me too.
Kisses.
Personal weather reports.
Hello.
Lose?
Take that out.
Take your sweater.
Tie it around your neck.
The sleeve too.
Like this?
Give me a profile.
No, don't smile.
Be sad.
Sadder.
Think of something awful.
There.
Sad.
Now it's coming!
That's it!
Turn. And 6 and 7
on the bar.
And 1 and 2
and 3 and 4 and stretch,
and 6 and 7 and 8 and bend,
and 3 and 4 and arch,
and 6 and 7 and stretch,
and stretch and stretch.
Stretch out your chin,
your arm, your fingertips.
Stretch out your hand. Your neck.
Relax your toes.
Stretch.
Good day.
I almost fell!
"General criminal law"
"POLICE ORGANIZATIONS"
Section 3:
"The powers of judicial procedure
conferred on certain judicial authorities."
Excuse me...
The door was open.
I'm sorry, I ran over your dog.
Rita. A German shepherd.
That's possible.
She disappeared yesterday.
She's in my car. Alive.
I don't know what to do.
Should I take her to a veterinarian?
As you wish.
If I ran over your daughter...
-would you be so indifferent?
I have no daughter, Miss.
Go away.
Don't close the door!
She's fine.
We stitched her up.
Otherwise, she has a few bruises.
She'll need some rest.
She's pregnant.
Will you take her
or leave her here?
I'll take her.
We'll help you carry her.
Marc?
Are you alone?
No.
Tell him something.
Come on.
Did you hear?
I have a dog.
A dog?
A dog. I ran her over.
Michel, I'm sorry.
That wasn't funny.
No, it wasn't.
I knew it was a joke.
As if I could see you laughing.
Do you remember how we met?
I remember...
We're lucky I stepped
out during the break.
That's true.
Valentine, return the dog.
I tried.
The owner doesn't want it.
Who is he?
I hear an alarm.
Could be my car.
It is my car.
Wait for me to turn it off.
I'm in a hurry.
I understand.
Move.
We could use these.
I'd say:
"In any situation, a breath of life".
Which do you prefer?
I like this one.
Me too.
8 meters by 20.
Will they recognize you?
Who?
Who are you thinking of?
Not you.
Well, that's a bad sign.
I think I know why I won.
Goodbye.
So long.
"DRUG ...Continued from page One:
AFTER ZURICH, GENEVA!"
You're back already?
The mailman left money for you.
Who sent it?
I have no idea.
Isn't that your brother?
Or someone who looks like him.
What a shame.
Does your family read this paper?
I don't know. Thank you.
Goodbye.
Hello.
Good morning. May I speak to Marie, please?
Yes?
It’s Valentine.
Will you see Marc soon?
Tonight, probably.
Tell him to call me, any time.
I’ll let you go so you can run.
But don't run away, okay?
Promise?
Go on.
Rita...
Rita!
Excuse me.
My dog ran away.
Call her. She's yours.
Rita!
- Was it you?
- For the vet.
- You found my address?
- That was easy.
You don't know the price.
It cost 130 francs.
You sent me 600.
Wait here. I'll get the change.
What about Rita?
She's a very clever dog. Very.
Take her.
- You don't want her?
- I want nothing.
Then, why not stop breathing?
Good idea.
Have you stopped breathing?
Sir?
If you don't come,
you'll never see me again.
But today is Sunday.
Yesterday was Saturday,
and you were with me.
Excuse me, Sir, I can't talk.
We're about to have lunch.
I'd ask one thing of you:
-Don't call me "Sir".
Speak to me like you did yesterday.
Call me Pierre. Or Pierrot.
Call me "My love".
Say: "My love..."
Please excuse me.
Let me pick up the phone in the other room.
Pierre?
Pierre, I'm alone.
I'm also alone. Far away from you.
And I want you to
come over. I don't want to be alone!
Pierre...
You'll see me tomorrow.
- I miss you.
You must understand...
I don't want to understand!
I think about you.
You're naked in front of the mirror.
But for someone else, not for me.
I want to kiss you.
I lean forward...
I touch your lips...
What are you doing?
This is my favourite...
I'm spying.
What?
I'm listening to my
neighbors' phone calls.
You cut it off just as it
was getting interesting...
You don't find it entertaining?
It’s disgusting.
Yes.
What's more, it's illegal.
Your 30 francs.
One minute, Miss.
You're convinced you are correct, right?
Yes.
Then why don't you do anything?
What?
Can't I touch your scar?
Like yesterday?
Go see this man.
Tell him someone listens
to his conversations.
And while you're at it,
tell him it's me.
I will.
It’s that house.
- Good afternoon.
- I would like to speak to Mr...
- My husband?
He's upstairs on the phone.
Please excuse me, I have to shut off the gas.
Come in, please.
Have a seat.
He'll be right down.
Caroline... Leave the phone.
Dad is talking.
Excuse me.
I'm at the wrong address.
This is number 22.
I'm very sorry.
No problem.
Have a good day.
Goodbye.
I'll call you later.
You lost this.
So? Did you tell him?
No.
Would you like
something to drink?
No, I wouldn't.
I came back...
I came back to ask you something.
Don't do this anymore.
I've done it all my life.
What were you?
A cop?
Worse. A judge.
A judge?
You've never seen one for real?
Would you like to try?
It makes...
a lovely sound.
I don't know whether I was
on the good or the bad side.
Here, at least, I know
where the truth is.
It's a clearer view
than in a courtroom.
No.
Everyone deserves a private life.
Of course.
Why did you stop short?
Why didn't you tell him I'm spying?
Because he has a sweet wife?
-Devoted to him?
And a beautiful little daughter who loves him?
-So you couldn't.
Did you feel remorse?
-Or were you afraid to do harm?
Maybe both.
Let me tell you;
It matters little whether I
spy - or you tell them.
Sooner or later,
it'll be thrown out the window.
-Or, it'll be she who discovers everything.
Someone will tell their daughter -
and there will be a living hell.
What can we do about it?
Why are you so quiet?
Does this remind you of something?
- Yes.
- What?
-Say it.
A boy I know.
A boy you know who...
What...
found out his mother was a whore?
-Who learned...
he's not his father's son.
He was fifteen.
That man's daughter...
She knows too.
Stay a minute.
Why?
The light is beautiful.
- Personal weather reports.
- I'm driving to Turin tomorrow.
- I checked. The weather
will be fine to Chamonix.
From Chamonix to the tunnel,
it may snow.
And after the tunnel...
One minute...
-I know the weather all over Europe.
Up to Turin,
the weather will be fine.
Leave early to avoid the snow.
- This service is a great idea.
- Thank you. Goodbye.
- Personal weather reports, how may I help you?
- It’s me.
Did you get any sleep?
- A little.
I didn't tell you.
By telephone it may be easier.
It was really great.
We'd never made love so well,
so long.
- We learned something.
Me from you. You from me.
When I woke up, you were
still sleeping. Like a child.
- I'm older than you.
- One year!
- No, two.
- Okay. Two. But this morning, when I loooked
at you, I got scared.
What is this leading to?
- You sound a little down.
- No.
- Are you nervous
about your exams?
- No. About what I'm going to do.
Will it be enough?
- Why not go bowling?
- I've already opened all my books.
Perhaps you're right.
Do you have a coin?
- Yes.
- Flip it. Tails is bowling.
Heads is Penal Code.
- Tails. Bowling.
- I’ll work a couple of hours more,
then I’ll call you.
- Or I will.
I'll wait. If I go out,
it's just to buy cigarettes.
- Bye.
You didn't listen?
What a shame. It was romantic.
I heard the beginning.
They're in love.
Yes.
He hasn't met the right woman yet.
How do you know?
I watch them from my window.
Do you think I'm a scoundrel?
Yes.
Come look.
That guy bought a telephone in Japan
that uses another wavelength.
My radio can't pick it up.
Too bad.
I think he's responsible for most
of the heroin trade in Geneva.
We have nothing on him.
He never takes risks.
Do you like it?
Very much.
I’ll call him.
You have his phone number?
-Hello?
- You deserve to die.
What do I do?
Here's his phone number.
If you feel like saying mean
again, don't hesitate to call him.
- At 10 o'clock, I turned off
the lights. I couldn't sleep.
Next program.
-Not very interesting.
I kept tossing and turning.
It kept hurting.
It still does.
I haven't done the errands.
- I'm sorry, mother.
- I have no milk or bread.
- I bought you some.
I put it in the freezer.
- I ate it all.
- You didn't eat 7 loaves in 4 days.
I'm sick of this!
Go do her errands.
Maybe you'd feel better.
Maybe she's the one
who'd feel better.
Why did you pick up Rita?
Because I had run her over.
She was bleeding.
Otherwise, you'd have felt guilty.
You'd have dreamt of a dog
with a crushed skull.
Yes.
So who did you do it for?
Don't bother doing
that lady's errands.
She has everything she needs.
She wants to see her daughter.
She already came 5 times,
when her mother
faked a heart attack.
After she dies,
I'll have to call the daughter.
She doesn't believe her any more.
You're mistaken.
About what?
About everything.
Everything.
People aren't bad.
It's not true.
Yes.
They may be weak sometimes...
The boy who learned
his father wasn't his father...
Was it your boyfriend or your brother?
My brother.
How old is he?
16.
How long
has he been shooting up?
How do you know?
It wasn't hard to guess.
I can only feel pity for you.
Maybe you don't know...
Your dog is pregnant.
It’s Valentine.
Hello, darling.
Mom, did Marc come?
Two days ago. With his girlfriend.
Do you know her?
Yes. Marie.
We're all together.
They're watching TV.
I'm sorry I can't be there.
Too bad.
It’s like old times.
Your brother's a good boy.
Can I talk to him?
Marc!
He's coming.
Call me, Mom.
I love you.
Hi, Valentine.
Thanks for going there.
We're leaving tomorrow.
I can't stand it.
Mom didn't see the paper?
I don't think so.
She'd never believe it...
You're right.
You should go home.
Bye.
Call me, Michel.
Please, call me.
Hello?
Valentine?
Did you see the picture?
The picture?
Is that you, Jacques?
Isn't it amazing?
You didn't see it?
I forgot.
I've had a hard day.
Come meet us.
It'll relax you.
Where?
Not bad!
Valentine...
I'm sorry to bother you...
Someone played a stupid prank.
I can't get in.
Those kids...
Turks. Always trouble.
I don't know.
They stuck chewing gum in my lock.
Tweezers.
Hello?
It’s me.
Hi, Michel...
I just called.
There was no answer.
Someone stuck chewing
gum in my lock.
I couldn't get in.
-I heard the phone.
- Chewing gum?
- Yes.
I did an ad for chewing gum.
It must be why.
I told you not to do it.
They're using you!
Michel...
Forget it.
There was no answering machine.
No.
All I want is peace.
A life of peace and quiet.
Life won't be peaceful with me.
You've chosen badly.
Did you meet someone?
No. I'm waiting for you.
Why didn't you answer before?
I told you - I was at the door,
but I couldn't get inside.
I understand.
How are you?
I'm going to Hungary next week.
And what do you do?
I'm going to bed.
Go ahead!
Go on!
Are you there?
Michel, are you there?
All over again...
Hello.
Are you asleep?
No, I'm not.
Get into bed.
Are you in bed?
I'm taking a shower.
I was getting undressed.
No one is helping you?
Valentine. Are you there?
No. Goodnight.
I knew you'd make it. Well done.
Did they ask the question?
From the book you dropped in the street?
The one you told me about...
You don't like it?
Thank you very much.
I wonder... What'll will be the
first verdict I'll sign it with...
Civil procedure.
The inhabitants of the muncipality
of Pinchat - versus Joseph Kern.
Please enter.
Hello. I would like number 432;
Van den Budenmayer.
- Did I pronounce it right?
- Yes, that's correct.
This one?
Yes.
I just sold the last one.
I'll have others this afternoon.
I can set one aside, if you want it.
Whose paper is this?
Yours.
"Scandal in the district of Pinchat"...
"RETIRED JUDGE SPYING"
-"Listening to neighbors' phone conversations for years."
Good afternoon.
I came...
I saw the newspaper...
I want you to know
I didn't tell a soul.
I know.
No one. Not the police. No one.
I know who it was.
Who?
It was me.
You asked me to.
Won't you come in?
Let me show you something.
- One, two, three, four, five, six.
Seven?
- Seven.
Won't you have some pear brandy?
I've had it for ages,
but I've never had an occasion.
To my health.
Why did you do it?
Why I turned myself in?
Yes.
I wanted to see your reaction
once you saw it in your paper.
You suspected I'd come?
After our last conversation,
I thought so.
Why?
Do you expect something from me?
Yes.
The other day, before you left,
you mentioned pity.
Afterwards, I realized
it was disgust.
Will you sit down for a moment?
Will you smile for me?
The day you left, you cried.
I cried.
And I shut off my radio.
I sat down at my desk.
The fountain pen I'd used
all my life was out of ink,
so I took a pencil...
and wrote letters to my
neighbours and to the police.
I mailed them that evening.
While you were sleeping soundly.
I wasn't sleeping.
- I went bowling.
- Bowling?
Do you remember the
conversation of that couple?
The boy and the girl?
I remember.
They wanted to go too.
That same evening.
Maybe you were right next to them.
Maybe.
You didn't like her.
It’s almost over.
I was right.
You seem happy about it.
Did you provoke it?
Yes or no?
Because of my eavesdropping
and informing thereof,
the woman has met another man.
Good day.
Since then, she's been alone.
I asked my brother
to go see her.
He stayed three days.
In one week
I'm going to England indefinitely.
I'm abandoning them,
him and my mother.
Every day he gets a little worse.
I shouldn't leave.
Leave. It’s your destiny.
You can't live your
brother's life for him.
I love him.
If only I could help.
You can.
Be.
What do you mean?
That's all: Be.
- Do you like flying?
- No.
Then take the ferry.
I've never taken one.
It's less expensive and healthier.
That's a good idea.
Do you like it?
Today is my birthday.
I didn't know.
35 years ago today,
at about the same time, 5 o'clock,
I acquitted a man. A sailor.
One of my first big cases.
It was a tough time in my life.
I have since realized,
I made a mistake.
He was guilty.
I'm all out of bulbs.
What happened to him?
I did my own investigation.
He's married, with three children.
And recently, a grandson.
He lives in peace.
So you did what you had to.
You even did well.
Don't you understand?
You saved him.
Perhaps.
But how many others
have I have acquitted...
guilty ones?
Deciding what is true and
what isn't, now seems to me...
a lack of modesty.
Of vanity?
Of vanity.
Could I have a drop?
To you!
If I had to go to court...
-Are there still judges like you?
You won't go to court.
Justice doesn't deal
with the innocent.
See that?
It's the sixth window
they've broken.
Even though they've changed
the wavelength,
and I no longer can eavesdrop
on their conversations.
Where is the broom?
In the kitchen closet.
Put the stone on the piano.
You're not afraid?
I wonder what I would
do in their place.
The same thing.
Would you throw stones?
In their place?
-Of course.
And that goes for the one's I judged too.
Given their lives and
situations, I would steal,
I would kill, I would lie.
-Of course I would.
But I wasn't in their shoes - I was in mine.
Is there someone you love?
No.
Have you ever loved?
Yesterday I dreamt...
I dreamt of you.
You were 40 or 50 years old,
and you were happy.
Do your dreams come true?
It's been years since I
dreamt something nice.
Stay here!
I bought a ticket
for the ferry.
I arrive in England
next Wednesday.
At 7:30 a.m.
Why the ferry?
So I can visit my
mother near Calais.
I’ll meet you at 8:00.
I'm happy you're coming.
Michel, tell me...
Do you love me?
I think so.
You love me or you think so?
It’s the same thing.
The battery...
Auguste!
Personal weather reports, may I help you?
I've tried calling
for a few days.
I was sick. I'm sorry.
What will the weather be
on the English Channel next week?
Wonderful. Sunny, a slight breeze,
chilly in the morning.
Why are you laughing?
I intend to go there.
Or even farther.
For your work?
No, for pleasure. On a yacht.
A nice cruiser?
Yes, very beautiful.
Will you be closing?
I'll have to.
That's too bad.
This line was a good idea. Goodbye.
We told you not to smile!
Be serious!
Excuse me. Can you send an
invitation to this address?
Just one person?
Are you okay?
- So long.
- Have a good time.
So long.
Does anyone have make-up remover?
Here.
Everyone noticed
that guy.
During the entire show
I kept staring at him.
Good night, Valentine. Goodbye.
You came.
You knew the invitation
came from me?
I'd hoped so.
Did you look for me?
During the entire show.
I'm leaving tomorrow.
I wanted to say goodbye.
Goodbye.
I'd like you to tell me about
that dream you had. In detail.
You were 50 years old,
and you were happy.
In this dream...
was there someone else?
There was.
Who?
You woke up
and you smiled at someone
next to you.
I don't know who.
That's what will happen?
In 20 or 25 years?
Yes.
What else do you know?
Who are you?
A retired judge.
I feel something important
is happening around me.
And it scares me.
Is that better?
I used to come to this theatre often.
Where did you usually sit?
Where I sat today.
That's why you couldn't see me.
One day,
during the intermission,
the elastic holding my books broke.
One of them, a big
one, fell down...
somewhere around here.
It was just before my exams.
I ran down immediately.
The book had opened to a certain
page. I read a few sentences.
And that was the questions
they asked me during my exam.
Getting out of the house
did you good.
I had to recharge the battery.
It was dead.
The storm.
Lousy coffee.
I was wondering...
-why you mentioned that sailor.
Do you know why?
Yes.
Because...
-there was something more important,
you didn't want to tell me.
About the woman that you loved.
She betrayed you.
She betrayed you,
and you never understood why.
And you kept on loving her.
How do you know all this?
It wasn't hard to guess.
What was she like?
She graduated two
years before me.
She was blond.
Delicate.
Radiant.
-And with a long neck.
Her clothing was light-colored.
Her furniture too.
In the foyer there was a mirror,
with a white frame.
It was in that mirror,
one night,
that I saw her white legs spread...
-With a man between them.
Why...
did that happen?
Do you know?
This man,
whose name was Hugo Holbling...
-could offer her what she wanted.
They left.
I followed them.
I crossed France, the Channel...
I was...
humiliated.
Until the day she died
in an accident.
Since then,
I've never loved another woman.
Yes.
I stopped believing.
Or maybe, I have never found the woman...
Maybe you're the
woman I never met.
The story doesn't end there.
No.
A while ago,
I was given a difficult case.
On it was written the name
of the defendant:
Hugo Holbling.
- The same man.
- Yes.
He'd come back here.
I'm closing up.
Did you see a woman
with a bucket?
The storm flooded the wardrobe.
If you see her,
tell her I'm upstairs.
You shouldn't have taken the case.
I didn't want to.
At first I wanted to kill him.
I would have,
if it would have changed something.
Now,
he was waiting for my verdict.
He was building a covered
market - which caved in.
Several people died.
I said he was guilty.
It was a legal sentence.
Afterwards, I asked for early retirement.
Did you see her?
No.
I'm always running after her!
Milana!
Milana?!
Ah, there you are! Give me the buckets.
They're heavy.
You seemed to like
my pear brandy.
Thank you.
I have another favor to ask you.
I'll be gone two or three weeks.
I’ll come see you afterwards.
Please give me
one of the puppies.
Will the fashion show be on TV?
Probably.
I better buy a TV.
I have one I never use.
My brother can bring it to you.
His name is Marc.
I'd like to meet him.
I’ll see you soon.
Be seeing you.
Do you have your ticket?
Where do I go?
This deck. That corridor.
Welcome.
Excuse me, I'm lost. F38?
The deck above.
Welcome!
"...1365 people on board.
TRAGEDY ON THE CHANNEL"
"The car-ferry -King Edward- capsized off the French coast.
Seven passengers escape."
Very bad weather
on the English Channel
is making the rescuers' task
all the more difficult.
Several fishermen
are reported missing
as are two people
aboard a yacht.
The cause of the accident
is unknown.
According to sources,
the ferry was carrying
1435 passengers.
Rescue operations
are still under way.
Hundreds of bodies
have been recovered.
Many passengers are still missing.
A police boat,
responding to the SOS,
retrieved 7 passengers.
All are reported unharmed.
The widow of a French composer
who died last year, Julie Vignon.
Steven Killian, English citizen,
barman on the ferry.
A businessman
from Poland, Karol Karol.
Dominique Vidal, French citizen.
Frenchman Olivier Benoit.
Among the survivors
are also two Swiss citizens:
Auguste Bruner, legal expert,
and a model, student
at the University of Geneva,
Valentine Dussaut.