Hello, George. Only me.
How are you today, dear?
Having a little doze
or just resting your eyes?
I'll make you a fresh cup.
Shan't be a minute. Couple of biscuits.
Here you are then, dear.
There.
There. That better?
Yes, thanks.
- Forward a bit.
- Bit more?
Mm.
There. Do you need anything else, dear?
- No.
- You sure?
- Yep.
- Drink your tea up before it gets cold.
I'll be on my way.
Tell Ivy I was asking after her,
won't you?
And don't get up to any mischief.
Ta-ta, dear.
- Hello, Reg.
- Afternoon, Mrs Drake.
- You all right, dear?
- Can't complain.
- Going off for your tea?
- Yes.
- What you having?
- Bit of bread 'n dripping.
- That all?
- Cup of tea.
You want to look after yourself,
Reg. I told you.
You want to come over
our house for tea one night.
- I don't want to put you out.
- Oh, don't be daft.
What about tomorrow?
You could come over after work.
You know where we are.
Number 82.
Could feed you up a bit.
Do you fancy that?
- You sure?
- Be no trouble, Reg.
- Go on, then.
- Oh, lovely.
See you tomorrow, then.
Now don't you forget!
- Hello, Nellie.
- All right, Vera?
- Yes.
- Innit cold?
Yes!
Oh!
That's better.
Nice cup of tea.
- That you, Ethel?
- Hello, Mum.
Oh.
- Oh, nippy today, weren't it?
- Yes.
Ooh, hold up, Ethel.
- 'Scuse, Mum.
- What you doing?
I'm washing me hands like you told me to.
- Oh, yes. Oh, your dad's here.
- Hello, Dad.
- Hello, Mum. You all right, Ethel?
- Yes.
- All right, Dad?
- Yes, thank you.
- Good day?
- Not bad, you?
- Can't complain.
- Oh, Ethel, take the teapot through.
Cor, I'm starving. I could eat an 'orse.
Wash your hands, Dad,
I'll put the tea on the table.
Just get me slippers on.
Well, he's all on his tod, ain't he?
Seems a nice enough fellow, though.
- Ooh, yes. Hard worker.
- Is he the little bloke, bald?
- No.
- No. Stocky fella.
- Lives opposite.
- Oh, yes. Does he?
I shouldn't wonder he don't have
bread and dripping every night.
Ain't nothing wrong
with bread and dripping.
- Not every night.
- I wouldn't mind.
Oh, yes? Like to see your face
if I put bread and dripping
on the table every teatime!
No, I'll do him a nice stew.
- Can we have dumplings, Mum?
- Oh, course you can.
- I love a dumpling.
- You are a dumpling.
- Oh, that's nice!
- What you got your work clothes on for?
It's a Tuesday, Dad.
I've got me night school.
- Oh, yes.
- That's right.
Better leave in a minute.
Dumpling!
I'm meeting David this evening.
You're looking very flat-chested.
Have you lost weight?
I don't know.
That was lovely, Vera.
Thank you very much.
- Very tasty.
- You're welcome, I'm sure.
Why don't you sit on the settee, Reg?
Make yourself at home.
'Ere you are, Reg, sit down.
We'll have a smoke.
Make a fresh pot, Ethel.
- No, 'ere you are.
- No, go on.
Ta.
- Sid?
- Oh, cheers, mate.
How's work going, Stan?
- What is it, motors?
- Motor mechanic, yes.
Well, they bring 'em in,
we mend 'em, push 'em back out again.
It's just the two of us, see?
Me and my brother.
Oh, what, family business like?
Well, it's Frank's business.
I work for him. Well, with him.
You always worked on the roads,
then, Reg?
- Nah, started in the war.
- Oh?
Oh, what kind of war did you have, Reg?
- Pioneer Corps.
- Oh, yes?
We laid tarmac
on all the American bases.
- Did you?
- We did.
- Went out in France, 1940.
- You was out there early then?
Dunkirk. We done a runner
when they broke through.
Then we went out a few days after D-Day.
Same as you, Dad.
About a month after D-Day,
we went out there.
- Just after the Battle of Caen.
- Oh, yes?
It was murder then.
Mind you, others had it worse than us.
I was in the Service Corps, driver.
We pushed through Normandy
into northern France, Belgium.
I ended up in Hamburg.
I was in Hamburg an' all, Reg.
- Was you?
- Not then, though.
- No, after the war. National Service.
- Oh, I'm with you.
I tell you, they got it worse
over there, the Germans.
Well, we all had it bad.
- It weren't cosy for no one, was it?
- Right an' all, Dad.
No, but we done demolition
before the war.
- Me and my brother.
- Oh, does he live round here?
Not now. He's in Australia.
- Melbourne.
- Ooh, is he?
He went out two year ago.
- That's a long way away, innit?
- Well, he was in Burma in the war.
- My brother was in Burma.
- Was he?
Well, he met a few Australian blokes,
came back, married a Scottish girl,
went out there.
Cor! Well, I never!
Was he a POW, Reg?
He don't talk about it, Stan.
No, my friend won't
talk about it, neither.
You lose any mates, Reg?
A few, yes.
I lost a couple of pals, an' all.
I lost my best mate.
- Oh, that's right, Bill.
- Did our basic together and everything.
Out in Palestine.
He got ambushed in an orange grove.
I had to pack his kit up for him, like.
Sit next to Reg.
- It's dreadful, innit?
- Terrible.
You warm enough, Reg?
Put the fire on, Dad.
I lost my mum in the Blitz.
Did you, Reg?
Chapel Street market, 1941, March.
Oh, now, we remember that bomb,
don't we, Dad?
- It blew all the windows out.
- Yes, it did.
We was just round the corner,
Penton Street.
- Opposite the church.
- Oh, yeah?
Our flats never got touched.
She popped in to see my aunt,
went shopping...
gone.
Want another cup of tea, Reg?
Sorry to hear that, mate.
That was a lovely spread, Vera.
Thank you very much.
Well, enjoy your pub.
Make sure you wear a coat, Susan,
if you're travelling in
an open-top sports car.
- Yes, I am.
- Cheerio, old chap.
Goodbye, sir.
Goodnight, Sid.
- Night, Dad.
- Night-night, Ethel.
Night-night, Dad.
Night, Ethel.
Goodnight.
Where are you tomorrow, Mrs Wells'?
No, Mrs Fowler's tomorrow.
I was at Mrs Wells' this morning,
bless her.
- Night-night, love.
- Night, dear.
Ooh, Stanley, your feet!
- Warm 'em up for us.
- Oh, come on, then.
I reckon that Reg would make
a good husband to some nice girl.
Where's a bloke like that
gonna meet anybody?
We managed to find each other.
That's right, love.
Miracles do happen.
Oh.
Let me go.
Don't.
Stop.
- You're terribly beautiful, you know.
- I should get...
- I should get a taxi.
- Shhhh.
- Come on, let's dance.
- Please don't be silly.
- I do apologise.
- What?
I haven't got a gramophone.
That's not funny.
- It's not funny.
- It's not funny?
It's not funny.
Oh, morning, Mrs Fowler.
- Good morning, Mrs Drake.
- Am I in your way, dear?
Lost something?
- I am in your way, aren't I?
- Oh, no, I just...
Oh, can't see for looking, sometimes.
I'm like that myself,
when I'm looking for things.
All right, Mother?
Ain't you been up today?
Now...
Leave it alone!
You getting married yourself, sir?
No fear.
No, it'll be a sister of mine
that's getting married.
- Oh, lovely.
- Yeah.
Well, to tell you the truth,
I haven't met your man yet.
He's a bit of dark horse, so I...
- Just lower your arm for me.
- Yeah.
So when are you catching the boat?
A week this Saturday coming.
- Oh, doesn't give us much time, then.
- From Holyhead, I'm goin'.
- Just lower your arms for me, please, sir.
- Yeah, yeah.
Thank you.
So I'll be having
a waistcoat with it, then?
That's no problem whatsoever, sir.
As I said, it's, uh... We charge
ten guineas for the two-piece suit,
moving up to 13 guineas
for the three-piece.
- Well, I have no money on me now, so...
- Oh, lovely.
And I want the jacket just
like the one you have on there.
Well, you have chosen
the double-breasted jacket, sir,
- with the four buttons.
- Yeah.
Now, the only difference is
your lapel is going to fasten
down to the bottom button,
- giving it a much more streamlined effect.
- Oh.
And what with the light blue barathea,
plus the stripe
to accentuate your height,
it's bold, it's sharp,
and it's certainly going
to make an impression
when you walk into the church, sir.
Well, that's exactly what I want, sir.
- Just face the mirror for me.
- Yeah.
- I'll be the lord of the manor in it?
- Oh yes, sir.
- I'll be like your man, George Raft.
- You will indeed, sir.
Me daddy won't know me, huh?
Well, if you're going
for the George Raft look, sir...
we can always supply you
with a pair of spats.
Oh, no. No spats.
Whatever you want, sir.
I'm just going to measure
your outside leg.
Yeah.
Come on!
Seized up?
She's there.
Is Joycie all right?
She's fine.
We ain't seen her in ages.
She's started talking about moving.
Moving where?
To a bigger house.
Your house is big enough, innit?
Yes.
- You ain't been there a year.
- I know.
We had a bit of company last night.
- Did you?
- You know what Vera's like.
She finds a young fella,
lives on his own, no family,
hoicks him in with us,
gives him his tea.
She's got a heart of gold, that woman.
She's a diamond.
You're a lucky man.
You're a lucky man an' all, Frank.
What she invited him round for, anyway?
- He lives on his own.
- A lot of people live on their own.
Don't mean you've got to invite them
all round for tea though, does it?
It's just Vera's way, ain't it?
Maybe he wants to be on his own.
She wants to mind her own business.
She's a little busybody, bless her.
She's going to get herself in trouble
one of these days.
I'm glad we moved out here, aren't you?
I seen the washing machine I want
this morning. It's twenty-five pound.
Oh, no, not now, Frank.
Not your accounts.
- It'll take me ten minutes.
- I know your "ten minutes".
An hour and ten minutes, more like.
I thought we was going
to have another early night.
I'll finish this and we can
have an early night.
All right, dear.
Frank?
Frank.
You asleep?
Don't go to sleep on me.
Frank?
Mmm?
Oh, you come on top of me then.
- Come on.
- Can't we leave it till tomorrow?
No, we got to do it now, ain't we?
Afternoon, dear.
Thank you.
This way.
Right then, dear.
First thing we've got to do...
is put the kettle on.
Oh. Got a bowl in here.
There.
Now, where are...? Oh, yeah.
You got a towel, dear?
Oh, very good. Where's your bed?
Through here.
Now, what I want you to do,
take your knickers off for me,
lie down here.
Don't you be upset because
I'm here to help you, aren't I?
And that's what I'm going to do.
So, pop your bottom on the bed
and I'll be back in a jiffy.
Here we are, then.
Hop on the bed for me.
- How long is it going to take?
- Not long, dear.
Open your legs. There.
- You on your own?
- Only for a bit.
Now, what I'm going to do
is have a little feel,
make sure everything's as it should be
and then we'll get
the soapy water inside.
- So you go all floppy for me.
- What do you mean?
Just lie down, dear.
Wet my hand a bit and feel.
You're all right, all right.
Push this little tube in.
All right.
Here comes the water.
When you feel full,
we'll stop.
Was you at work, today?
I went in this morning.
- Weather's turned.
- Yes.
Now...
- That feel full?
- Yes.
Right.
There. Now...
You dry yourself off.
Hold that towel there for a minute
and I'll clean out the bowl.
Now, what's going to happen
is tomorrow or the day after,
you'll get a bit of a pain down below.
Take yourself to the toilet,
you'll start bleeding,
then it'll all come away.
What do you mean,
"it will come away"?
It'll all be over, dear.
You'll be right as rain.
I won't die, will I?
No, dear.
Right. I'll be on my way.
- I'll see meself out.
- It's all right.
- Look after yourself, dear.
- Right.
I've got 200 Craven "A" and he's
given me eight pair of nylons.
Well, I'll have some nylons.
I'll take three pairs of nylons
off you, Sid.
- Right, what you offering?
- Five packets of Players.
- What, for three pairs of nylons?
- That's right.
No, no. These are the Italian nylons.
They ain't the Czech ones.
- Yeah, they're nice they are.
- I don't care.
I'm offering five packets of Players
for three pairs of nylons.
- Take it or leave it.
- Turn it up, Ron, eh?
I mean, either I'm talking
in another language,
- or he's a bit Mutt and Jeff.
- I heard you.
Look, make it ten packets.
- I'll give you six... seven.
- Eight.
Look, take 'em out with you Saturday.
"How you doing, darling? Fancy a turn?"
Slip her a pair, happy days!
- All right, eight.
- Done.
Good boy.
I'll give you two packets of tea
for a pair.
What are you two, a double act?
- Hello, Lily.
- Your bleedin' stairs.
- They'll be the death of me.
- You've must've heard the kettle boil.
No.
Just made a fresh pot.
How'd that go the other week?
Same as usual.
- Nervous little thing, wasn't she?
- I know.
I put her right. Set her mind at rest.
- You always do, don't ya?
- Don't you want a biscuit, Lily?
Won't say no.
Thank you.
- I got another one for you.
- Oh, yes? Friday, is it?
- Is Friday all right?
- Mm.
- I told her five o'clock.
- That's all right, yes.
Want some tea?
- Sardines?
- I'm all right this week, Lily.
- Oh, now what sweets you got?
- Boiled sweets.
'Ere you are.
Don't you want some for your Ethel?
- How much are them, then?
- Tuppence a bag.
- Penny ha'ppenny to you.
- Righty-oh.
- Kelp Street.
- Oh, I know.
Nora. Got seven kids already.
Oh, can't she manage?
- Well, could you?
- I've only got a threepenny bit.
I've got change.
Ain't the husband around?
I expect so.
Can't control himself, if you ask me.
Oh, ta. Poor woman.
Serves her right.
Don't you want no sardines
for your mother?
No, she can't eat them no more, Lily.
Gives her heartburn.
How's she keeping anyway, your mum?
Oh, you know, getting older.
Ain't we all?
That's Ethel.
- That you, Ethel?
- Hello, Mum.
- Lily's here.
- Oh.
Hello, Ethel.
Hello.
- You want a cuppa?
- Yes, please, Mum.
- Ain't she got a boyfriend yet?
- No.
I ain't surprised.
That was a lovely spread, Vera.
Thank you very much.
- You're welcome, Reg, you know that.
- Doing a bit of mending?
Yeah. You got anything needs doing?
You've got a bit of leg poking
through your trousers there, Reg.
- Yes, he has.
- I done that at work.
- I ain't got round to it yet.
- You do your own sewing?
Well, I'm all fingers and thumbs,
but I have a go.
- You want to bring 'em over here, Reg.
- You need a little patch on that.
I'll get you a bit of cloth
from the shop, Reg.
What is it? Navy serge, 19 ounce.
Give it to Mum, she'll
mend it for you, no problem.
- I could do that.
- Course you can.
- Ethel will see you right.
- I don't want to put you out.
- I don't mind.
- Not now.
Thanks very much.
- It'll cost you, half a crown!
- Don't be silly.
- He was only joking, Reg.
- Do you want another sweet?
Ta.
- What are you doing, love?
- Go back to sleep.
You're ill.
You'll have to be quick.
Is it going to take long?
- No, dear.
- I haven't told him, you see?
- He's supposed to be at work.
- Yes, dear.
- What's he want to come home sick for?
- Take your knickers off for me.
Can't have no more kids, see?
I've got seven already.
I ain't having no more.
- I know, dear.
- It'd kill me.
Lay the towel on the bed for me.
You sit right on the edge.
- What's that?
- Just soapy water, dear,
bit of disinfectant.
- Do you want me to lie down?
- Stay where you are.
- I've just got to get this inside.
- All right.
- Oh!
- All right, all right, all right?
Yes.
Oi-oi.
- What?
- See them, blonde, brunette?
- Oh, tidy!
- Ain't they?
How do you do?
Right-oh, mugger, bright-eyed,
bushy-tailed and look lively.
- Leave it out, we only just got here.
- Oh, come on, Kenny!
- Let your hair down.
- Enjoy the view.
- Let's have a swap, eh?
- All right.
Do you reckon she likes him?
Well, she's gone for a walk with him.
She wouldn't go, would she,
if she didn't like him. Would she?
He should take her out dancing.
- I don't think he's that type.
- I can't see Reg dancing.
She'd come back
black and blue, wouldn't she?
- Dad!
- She'd have to give her feet a soak.
No, hold on, they might turn out
to be a proper Fred and Ginger,
the pair of them. You never know.
- Did you have to come far?
- Not far, dear, no.
- Are you sure you wouldn't like a drink?
- No, thank you.
- Have you done this before, dear?
- Yes, as it happens.
Here we are.
One bowl, one towel.
- Kettle's on.
- Oh. Thank you.
- Are you sure you wouldn't like a drink?
- No, dear.
What?
You know, your hair looks really lovely.
- Do you think so?
- Yes.
Oh.
Why don't you make us all a cup of tea?
What, do you want a cup of tea as well?
Oh.
Good luck.
Right, dear.
You're gonna have
to take your knickers off.
Okey-dokey.
So, how are you?
This is rather a surprise.
- Haven't seen you for ages.
- Yes. No, um...
Sugar?
No, thank you.
- Thank you for coming today.
- Oh, not at all.
An excuse to get out of that
dreary old bank.
- Would you like a fag?
- No, thank you.
Thank you for...
Sorry.
What's the matter?
- Um...
- Oh, sorry.
Have some cake.
I had a piece before you arrived.
Can't resist, it's delicious.
I wanted to talk to you.
Fire away.
Um...
The first person I thought of.
Really.
Crikey, Susan, what is it?
I have this, um...
friend, who...
She needs some help.
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
You've got yourself into trouble,
haven't you?
Oh, Susan, you clot.
Who told you to phone me?
Oh!
All right. I'll tell you
what you have to do.
Oh, and when you see the psychiatrist,
you have to make up a fearful fib
about some potty aunt
or something or other.
Here. Have a hanky.
Thank you.
You'll be all right, you know.
Hello, George. Oh, hello, Peggy!
- You off work, today?
- Sit up, then.
Oh, she's all right, George. Bless her.
This has slipped a bit.
Ivy taken bad again, has she?
Oh, dear. Well, I'll make
a fresh pot of tea.
And you'll want a biscuit, Peggy,
I shouldn't wonder.
- Hello, Ivy.
- All right, Vera?
Having one of your bad days?
- I'm sick of it.
- Oh, dear.
I'll put the kettle on.
Didn't you sleep last night, dear?
You don't sleep
when you're like this, do you?
Have you managed to kip at all today?
- No, I ain't.
- Oh, ain't you?
Still, you're in the best place, Ivy.
I should be at work.
You can't go to work in this state.
Somebody's got to earn the money.
If I stay off, she wants to stay off.
I'll lose me job if this goes on.
It's not your fault, dear.
Try telling that to your boss.
They don't understand nothing, men.
Bastards.
Now...
is this your first pregnancy?
Yes.
And what does the father say?
Um...
I don't want my parents to know.
No, no, no.
I mean the father of the child.
Big as you can. Come and sit down.
Have you considered the possibility
of having the child?
I can't.
Very well. I'll help you.
But I'm afraid we are obliged to discuss
the delicate matter of money.
It'll come to one hundred
and fifty pounds.
How much do you have available?
Um...
Just over a hundred pounds.
I see.
Well...
let's say 100 guineas, shall we?
In advance, in cash.
Now, I shall require you
to see a psychiatrist.
I know.
Do you?
Yes.
And I'll arrange the nursing home
and the obstetrician.
Baxter. Terribly good man.
Any questions?
Pretty day.
Yes.
- How many weeks pregnant are you?
- Seven.
And were you a virgin?
Yes.
Miss Wells, it would be helpful
if you would give me simple
and honest answers if you can.
What does your father do?
- My father?
- Yes.
Um...
He works in the Ministry of Defence.
And are your parents happily married?
Um... I think so.
Is there any history
of mental illness in your family?
Yes.
An aunt of my mother's committed suicide.
Did she?
Yes.
And your own mental state,
how would you describe it at the moment?
Um...
Anxious?
Depressed?
Tell me your feelings
towards the father of the child.
- Do you love him?
- No.
- Does he love you?
Did you love him
at the point of conception?
No.
Did he force himself on you?
Miss Wells...
if you were to have the child,
would you keep it or have it adopted?
I can't have it.
I'd rather kill myself.
Well, I don't think
we can allow that to happen...
can we?
Tea's brewing.
- Miss Wells.
- Hello.
- I'm Nurse Willoughby.
- How do you do?
- Is this all your luggage?
- Uh, yes.
- If you'd like to follow me.
- Thank you.
- Have you had far to come?
- Not really, no.
- Miss Wells.
- Hello.
- Sister Beech.
- How do you do?
I hope you'll be comfortable.
Thank you.
There, dear.
I'll put this back under the bed for you.
Now, that didn't take too long, did it?
What, you finish already?
Yes, dear.
So when I gonna see you again?
What did you say, dear?
You have to come back, yes?
Oh no, dear.
I've done all I've got to do.
Now you've just got to wait.
What is it me waiting for?
For it to come away, dear.
But all you used
was a lickle bit of water.
Don't you worry.
What happen if somethin' go wrong?
Now what's going to happen is this...
tomorrow...
or Sunday, you'll have a pain down below.
Get yourself to the toilet.
You'll start bleeding, it'll all come
away, you'll be right as rain.
What you need now
is a nice hot cup of tea.
Take care, dear.
Ta-ta.
- Oh, hello, dear.
- Good morning, Mrs Drake.
- Hello, Mummy.
- Good morning, dear.
- How was your weekend?
- Lovely, thank you.
How was Norfolk?
Oh, bearable.
Terribly sunny.
Extraordinary.
Have you got the money?
I've got the two pounds.
- Two pound?
- That's what she told me.
Well, she told you wrong.
It's two guineas.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- Ain't no use being sorry.
Oh, you want payment
now then, do you?
Well, I don't want paying
next week, do I?
Where is your husband, anyway?
Korea, since you're asking.
- In the forces, is he?
- Yes.
- Two guineas.
- Thank you very much.
So it's not his, then?
What's the matter?
Cat got your tongue?
Done this for a lot of girls then,
have you?
Mind your own bleedin' business.
- I'm only asking.
- And I'm only telling ya.
Right.
You put your address down there.
She'll be there at five o'clock.
Don't mention the money.
That's between me and you.
Is that understood?
- Yes!
- Good.
Can you do one on Friday?
- At five o'clock?
- Yes.
That's all right.
- Married lady.
- Oh, yes?
- Got herself in a bit of trouble.
- How's that, then?
Having a bit of "how's your father"
on the side.
- Oh, that's not right, is it, Lily?
- Well, I don't think so.
Still, gotta help them out, ain't you?
How'd you get on with that darkie?
- Oh, I did feel sorry for her.
- Long way from home.
She was very scared.
What are they doing over here, anyway?
Trying to make a better life
for themselves, I shouldn't wonder.
- They should stay where they are.
- They're hard workers.
- You need any sugar?
- How much you charging this week, Lily?
One and threepence ha'penny to you.
All right, then.
- Here you are.
- Ta.
There.
Thank you.
Oh! Oh! I'm ever so scared!
- Try not to upset yourself, dear.
- I'm sorry. I can't...
I've got to pull myself together.
Oh, I've got to go through with this.
Oh! I know I have to, it's just that...
nobody knows...
Well, my friend knows,
but she doesn't know.
I mean, she doesn't know
it's today and...
So if anything were to happen to me,
no one would know.
You've got to get your knickers off,
dear, and lie down.
Oh. Oh, no. No, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Oh, no, no...
Oh, I'm a terrible person!
What's the matter?
Nothing.
Ain't you had a nice night?
Yes.
You?
You ever thought about moving out?
What do you mean?
What do you think about getting married?
What, to you?
Yes.
I ain't never thought about it.
- I've been thinking about it.
- Have you?
About three or four weeks.
What do you reckon?
Do you wanna?
Yes.
I do.
All right, then.
Better tell your mum.
Dad...
- Dad, wake up.
- What's the matter?
I've got to go in the kitchen.
Woke me up.
- Oh, hello, Reg.
- Hello, Stan.
Good kip?
Yes, all right.
Can I have a word, Stan?
What's the matter?
Can I have your permission to marry Ethel?
Have you asked her?
Yes.
What'd she say?
She said yes.
Well, of course you can.
- Are you sure?
- Congratulations!
- Thanks very much.
- Vera? Ethel?
- You know what he's just asked me?
- I'm ever so pleased.
- I'm delighted!
- Me too.
- What's all the shouting about?
- These two just got engaged!
No!
- Oh, congratulations, mate!
- Thanks very much.
I was asleep on that chair, there.
Sorry about waking you up.
- Oh, that's all right!
- Oh, don't you worry about that.
- I asked her last night.
- Oh, did you?
Yeah.
- Well done, the both of you.
- I can't believe it.
Wow, Reg, good going.
- Don't look so worried.
- You're sure?
Course, I'm sure.
I've been to the doctors and I'm sure.
About time an' all.
You have to start taking things easy.
What, you gonna look after me?
- Yes.
- Are you?
We'll have to tell Stan and Vera.
Yes, we'll tell Stan and Vera.
We'll tell them together, properly.
We'll go around there...
- next weekend.
- I'll ask him in the morning.
Can I have my washing machine now, please?
- Morning, Frank.
- Morning, Stan.
Got some news for you.
What?
'Ere you are. Have a guess.
Good news or bad news?
- Bad news.
- Wrong. Try again.
All right, good news.
Well, come on, then. What is it?
Eh?
Spill the beans, old cock!
My little Ethel, she got engaged.
- What?
- Yesterday afternoon.
- What, to Reg?
- I couldn't believe it.
I thought they'd be courting for years.
Well...
- Congratulations.
- Thank you, Frank.
You must be a very proud man.
You should've seen Vera's face.
It was a bolt from the blue.
So, on Sunday,
you and Joycie got to
come over for your tea.
We'll get some beers in,
some sherry for the girls.
We'll toast the happy couple
and Reg can meet the family.
- On Sunday?
- About four o'clock.
- You'll tell Joyce?
- I'll tell her.
Can you feel that, dear?
Starting to fill up?
Yes.
- Does that feel peculiar, Pam?
- Yes.
That's how it's meant to feel, ain't it?
- Peculiar?
- Yes.
- You've done this before, ain't you?
- Yes, dear.
- So, it's safe.
- It's safe, innit?
- Yes, darling.
- And when it's full,
that's when we'll stop.
I know your face from somewhere.
- Who, me?
- Yes.
- Do you?
- I can't think where, though.
You all right?
Of course. Sunlight Laundry.
- Oh, dear.
- It's Vera, ain't it?
- That's right.
- Vera Drake.
- I knew your mother before the war.
- Did you?
- Was you doing this back then?
- That feel full, dear?
Yes.
All right.
Just dry yourself off. There.
Get that down you, come on.
Cold. Cold.
Cool you down.
Make you nice and cool.
Cheers. Here's to 'em, eh?
Hello again, Pamela.
How are you feeling?
Poorly, hmm?
Now, I need to take
another look at your tummy.
Don't worry,
I'll be as gentle as I can.
Pamela, we just need you
to straighten your legs.
That's it. Good girl.
Right down on to the bed.
I promise you, I have very warm hands.
Bring your bottom up.
Good girl. That's it.
Now, I'm going to press gently
and I want you to tell me
what happens when I let go.
- No!
- Good girl, well done.
- We'll do an internal, Sister.
- All right, doctor.
Now then, Mrs Barnes,
I, uh... I don't have
very good news, I'm afraid.
Why? Why? What's happening?
I'm going to have to operate.
Pamela is a very sick girl.
She ain't gonna die, is she?
We sincerely hope not, Mrs Barnes,
but this is a grave situation,
as I'm sure you'll understand.
Now then...
when Pamela was admitted this evening,
you stated that she was
having a miscarriage.
Yes.
But that isn't the whole truth, is it?
Mrs Barnes,
did you do something to Pamela to try
- to bring about a termination?
- No, I didn't!
Well, somebody did.
You know that and I know that.
Mrs Barnes, I've been a doctor
for over 25 years.
Sister and I see cases like this
every weekend, don't we, Sister?
Yes, we do.
All right.
Someone come to the house.
And what did they do?
She grated pink soap
into a bowl of warm water
and she had
a bottle of stuff and put...
- And she used a syringe?
- Yes.
And no doubt,
she'll use her syringe again.
And again and again
and again, and Sister and I
will have to deal with dozens of cases
just like Pamela's.
Mrs Barnes, these people must be stopped.
You're going to have to inform the police.
I ain't talking to them!
Sister Coombes.
Righty-oh. They're ready for you
in theatre, Mr Walsh.
Thank you, Sister.
Mrs Barnes, if you don't inform
the police, I'm going to have to.
Unfortunately, it's my
legal obligation to do so.
Excuse me.
- Excuse me, nurse.
- Yes, sir?
We're police officers.
We're looking for Sister Coombes.
Yes, sir, if you'll just follow me.
Sister, it's police.
Good evening, Sister.
I'm Detective Inspector Webster.
- This is DS Vickers...
- Good evening.
Oh, good evening.
We was sitting by the side of the road,
there was bodies everywhere,
stink, petrol.
I'd had enough.
I couldn't do nothing.
Couldn't run away, couldn't cry,
couldn't feel nothing, just sat there.
And all of a sudden,
there was this old girl
staggering past us,
muttering in French.
Guess what she was carrying under her arm?
- What?
- A pair of old mirrors.
You ain't told me that before.
We've got a lot to be thankful for.
- Yes, we have.
- I have.
For one thing, you ain't turned out
nothing like your mother.
She can't help it.
Did you ever ask
who your dad was in the end?
No.
If I'd have been 11 or 12
when Mum died...
I'd have had to gone
in an orphanage, like Frank.
I know. You were straight out to work.
I had to fend for meself, didn't I?
- Still, it did you no harm.
- No, girl.
- Look at everything you got now.
- Yes.
I'm a lucky man.
You telephoned for an ambulance
this afternoon, is that right?
- Yes.
- Now, why did you do that?
She was having a miscarriage, weren't she?
- A miscarriage?
- Yes.
Mr Walsh has told us that somebody
came round to your house
to perform an operation on your daughter.
Well, there you are,
Mr Walsh has told you.
Doctors know everything.
Why don't you ask him?
I want to hear it from you, Mrs Barnes.
He's the one what phoned you.
I never phoned you.
It ain't got nothing to do with me.
Keep your voice down, Mrs Barnes.
Who was it that performed this operation?
A woman.
- Do you know her name?
- No.
How did you get in touch with this woman?
I don't know. You just ask about.
- Who did you ask?
- People at work.
Where do you work, Mrs Barnes?
Allied Laundries, Clerkenwell Road.
- Who did you talk to at work?
- What does it matter now?
Your daughter's just
nearly died, Mrs Barnes.
It would be in your best interests.
You do realise this is a criminal matter?
All right.
- Vera.
- Vera?
- Vera Drake.
- That's who you talked to at work?
No, she's the one what come round.
She's the one what done it.
Vera Drake is the person that performed
the operation on your daughter?
- Yes.
- So you do know her name?
Yes.
Had you met her before?
We both worked in a laundry in 1931.
- Have you seen her since then?
- No.
- Do you know where she lives?
What does she look like, Mrs Barnes?
Um, small, small hands. I ain't going
to get into trouble for this, am I?
It's a bit of a coincidence, isn't it?
Somebody you haven't seen for years
just suddenly turns up
on your doorstep.
Well, I ain't lying!
You're twisting my words.
That's not fair!
It's all right, dear.
I'm not suggesting
you are lying, Mrs Barnes.
I'm just trying to get
to the bottom of things.
- 'Ere you are, Sid, round here.
- Come on then.
Yeah, that's better.
Where we always have it.
- Gives us more room, don't it?
- Oh, yes.
Got the Christmas cloth.
Well, we want it to look nice,
don't we, Mum?
Yes. There.
- Yes?
- Good afternoon.
Are you Mrs Lillian Clark?
- Why, who wants to know?
- DI Webster, Metropolitan Police.
There we are!
There you are.
- Hello! Hello, Joyce!
- All right, Stan?
- Just catching my breath.
- Hello, Joyce!
Oh, don't she look lovely?
- All right, my darling.
- Hello, dear.
- Hello, Auntie Joyce.
- Hello, Sidney.
- How are you?
- Look at the inside of this!
- How are you doing, Uncle Frank?
- All right, Sid.
- Cor, I ain't seen you for ages.
- Oh, you look like a film star.
Congratulations, Ethel,
it's lovely news.
- Do you like it?
- Yes, I do!
- I sewed the lining in myself.
- Did you?
- It's leopard print.
- Leopard print?
Cor, blimey, look at that, eh?
'Ere, I hope you left your rifle
at home, Auntie Joyce!
Do you know Mrs Edna McKenzie?
What if I do?
Just give us a straight answer, please.
I might.
Are you familiar with the standard
tearooms in the Holloway Road, Mrs Clark?
- Yes.
- Were you there last Wednesday?
- I can't remember.
- You're not helping yourself, Mrs Clark.
What's this all about, anyway?
Do you know Vera Drake?
Quite a grocer's shop
you've got here, love.
- It's for the old people, for Christmas.
- How much you charge 'em for a bag of tea?
Did you take two guineas off
Jessica Barnes last Wednesday?
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- I think you do, Mrs Clark.
Nice living you're making for yourself.
Have you got a little bit
of lipstick on, Ethel?
Don't she look lovely
in that top an' all?
- Did you knit that yourself?
- No, got that from the market.
How's the house coming along,
Uncle Frank?
I've been keeping Frank busy,
ain't I, Frank?
Been up a ladder
the best part of six months.
- The neighbours have just got a TV.
- Have they?
- In the front room.
- Have you seen it?
- Only through the window.
- You'll have to get one now, Frank.
- That's next on my list.
- Dear though, ain't they?
- Only thirty-six pound.
- Thirty-six pound!
- A bit steep, that.
- They must have a few bob.
Oh, yes. Got a lovely colour
an' all, ain't they, Frank?
V-8 pilot.
He's dying to have a shifty at the Javers.
I was hoping for a little spin
round the block.
- You can see it out the window.
- That ain't the same thing, is it?
Will it be
all right out there, Frank?
I've already told you.
- It'll be fine.
- Course it will.
Well, you can't be sure,
can you?
There he is!
Let him in, Ethel.
Talk of the devil, the man himself.
Hello.
- That you, Reg?
- All right?
- Come on in.
- 'Ere you are, Reg, in you come.
- 'Ere he is!
- Afternoon.
Oi-oi! How's your luck, pal?
Reg, this is my brother, Frank.
- Pleased to meet you, Reg.
- How do you do?
- Congratulations.
- And his wife, Joyce.
- Hello, Reg.
- How do you do?
Here, take your coat off.
We can eat now. I'm starving.
Didn't hold everybody up, did I?
Oh, don't be so silly.
Go on, sit yourselves down.
- Where do you want us then?
- Looks smart, don't he?
- Yeah, he does.
- You sit there, Reg.
- Here, Uncle Frank. You're next to me.
- Well, don't make trouble.
- Come on, everyone, tuck in.
- Fill your boots!
Ethel, thank you.
- This is nice.
- Aw.
Eh-up. Eh-up.
Here's to Ethel and Reg.
Welcome to the family, Reg.
And all the very best
to the both of you. Cheers.
- Cheers.
- To the happy couple.
- Here's to you.
- Ta very much.
And if you're half as happy with your wife
as I've been with mine,
you'll be a lucky man.
- Quite right.
- It's the truth.
Well, there's no turning back now, Reg.
You'll be coming to us for your
Christmas dinner, won't you, Reg?
Yeah, you don't want
to miss Christmas here.
Well, Frank and Joyce,
you'll be here, won't you?
- Course we will.
- We ain't made no plans yet.
- Wouldn't be the same without you.
- We'll be here, don't worry.
- We have a laugh, don't we?
- Yes, we do.
And you want to get your name
down on the housing list, Reg.
Ooh, yes, you want to get
yourself somewhere nice.
We'll be all right at my place.
Mind you, we was in one room after
we got married, weren't we, Dad?
We was in one room for years,
yeah, in Windmill Road.
- Yeah, we had some good times in there.
- Christmases.
But one of these days
you might find that...
one room ain't enough.
I'm being a bit previous there.
- He knows what I mean.
- Take no notice.
'Ere you are, I'll be an uncle.
We've... we got a bit of news to tell you
ourselves, me and Joyce.
- Oh, yes?
- What is it?
I've had to keep me trap shut all week.
- Oh, dear.
- Come on, Frank. Spit it out.
- Well?
- Well, go on then.
- Joyce is going to have a baby.
- Aah!
Gonna have a family.
Congratulations, Frank.
I'm really pleased for you.
- Congratulations, Uncle Frank.
- That's marvellous!
- Congratulations, Auntie Joyce.
- Thank you, Sidney.
Well, blimey, this is
a double celebration, innit?
'Ere, Joyce. You'll have a little top up?
'Ere, you kept that one quiet,
didn't you?
- I'll go. Hey, Sid, pour the drinks.
- All right, go on.
'Ere you are, pass 'em over.
Good afternoon, sir.
- DI Webster, Metropolitan Police.
- Oh, yes?
Does Mrs Vera Drake live here, sir?
Yes, she does, yes.
Would you be Mr Drake, sir?
Yes.
- Is Mrs Drake at home now?
- Yes.
We'd like to have a few words with her,
if we may.
Oh, well, we're having a party.
My daughter's just got engaged,
celebration.
I'm sorry about that, sir, but we do
need to talk to your wife.
- What about?
- I can't tell you that, sir.
But it is a serious matter.
Well, she's good as gold. She's never
done a dishonest thing in her life.
Yes, sir.
May we come in?
Hold up, hold up. It's the police.
Eh?
Good afternoon.
Sorry to interrupt your celebrations,
but we need to talk to Mrs Vera Drake.
This is my wife.
- What's going on?
- Could you sit down please, sir?
Do as you're told, Sid.
May I speak to you in private,
please, Mrs Drake?
Vera?
This way, Mrs Drake.
What is it, Dad?
Hold on, Sid. I'll come with her.
If you wouldn't mind staying
in the parlour, please, sir.
- What's all this about?
- We will keep you posted.
I'm her husband,
I've got a right to know.
I appreciate that, sir.
If you'll just do as I've asked.
Close the door. Thank you.
Mrs Drake.
I'm Detective Inspector Webster.
This is Detective Sergeant Vickers
and WPC Best.
I know why you're here.
Beg your pardon?
Why are we here?
Cos of what I do.
Because of what you do?
Yes.
What is it that you do, Mrs Drake?
I help young girls out.
You help young girls out?
That's right.
How do you help them out?
We're having a party today.
Can I sit down, please?
Yes, of course.
I don't want to spoil it for my family.
Can't you come back tomorrow?
I'm sorry, Mrs Drake.
But we have to deal
with this matter today.
Oh, do you?
Yes.
What are they taking so long for?
I don't know, Sid.
- Someone might've been murdered.
- Oh, my godfathers, Sidney!
- All right, Sid.
- No, in one of the houses she cleans in.
I mean, he said it was serious, didn't he?
Someone's pinched something, that's all.
But there were a couple of detectives.
Plain clothes, aren't they?
Can you answer my question, please?
How do you help them out?
When they can't manage.
When they can't manage?
That's right.
You mean, when they're pregnant?
So, how do you help them out?
I help them start their bleeding again.
You help them to get rid of the baby?
I've spoilt their day for them now,
haven't I?
You perform an abortion.
Is that right, Mrs Drake?
You perform abortions, don't you?
That's not what I do, dear.
That's what you call it but...
they need help.
Who else are they gonna turn to?
They've got no one. I help them out.
Did you help Pamela Barnes in this way?
Pamela?
Yes, I did.
On Friday?
That's right.
Is she all right?
She nearly died, Mrs Drake...
last night.
Oh, God.
She'll live.
- Thank you.
- She's in hospital, but she'll live.
Mrs Drake, I'm arresting you
for carrying out an illegal operation
on Pamela Mary Barnes,
of 37 Flixton Street, London, North 1...
on the 17th of November, 1950.
You're not obliged to say anything,
but anything you say
may be given in evidence.
Do you understand?
I think so, dear, yes.
I must ask you to accompany me
to the police station.
Mrs Drake...
does anybody in that room
know why we're here?
No.
You won't tell them, will you?
Now, the equipment you used
to perform these operations...
is it here on the premises?
Can you get it for me, please?
- Can you manage?
- Thank you, dear.
Pop it on the bed for me, please.
Would you mind showing me
what's inside?
Sorry, dear?
I need to see the contents of the bag.
Take your time.
Can you open it up, please?
Thank you.
- Go on.
- Ask him, Dad.
It's your house, Stan.
Could you stay in the room, please?
- I want to know what this is about.
- I don't know, sir.
Mr Drake.
Could I have a word with you, please?
What's going on?
I'm afraid I'm going to have to take
your wife to the police station
- to help us with our inquiries.
- Well, I wanna go with her.
You're free to do that, sir.
- You'll have to make your own way.
- Will I?
She's got to go to the station.
Well, it's just a mistake, ain't it?
- Yes, it is.
- Course it is.
- How we doing?
- Ready, Sarge.
Follow the sergeant.
- You'll be all right, Vera.
- Love you, Mum.
- You know where the station is, sir?
- Yes, I do.
- I'll just get my coat.
- I'll take you.
- You stay 'ere.
- I've got the motor.
- Be better if you stayed.
- Go with her, Dad.
- What are you doing?
- Having a look.
- Sid.
- Frank!
Ethel, come back inside.
You'll catch your death.
Mum!
Don't worry, love.
I'm coming with you.
As I say, Vera, this is just procedure.
It's nothing to worry about
and we'll look after everything
we've taken from you here today.
Just have to pop them on for me.
Sit yourself down.
Thank you.
Now, Vera, do you have any jewellery?
No, dear.
Your wedding ring.
I'm going to have to take
that off you, I'm afraid.
I... I can't.
I know this is difficult for you.
I never took it off.
I know.
Twenty-seven years.
We'll take extra special care of it.
It is regulations.
Thank you, my love.
I'll just hand this over
to the station sergeant.
Do you know how long
this is gonna take?
I have no more information than you, sir.
Take a seat, please.
Excuse me.
- Excuse me.
- Sit down, sir.
Don't get up, Mrs Drake.
Now, Mrs Drake...
You help women who are in trouble?
How long have you been doing this?
I don't know, dear.
Well, roughly speaking.
Five, ten years?
A long time.
Twenty years?
Maybe, yes.
About 20 years?
No, I...
I don't know.
Mrs Drake, you're in a police station
under arrest for
a serious criminal offence,
- do you understand?
- Yes, I'm sorry.
It's very important that you try
to answer my questions truthfully.
Yes.
Is my... Is my husband in yet?
Yes, Mrs Drake. He is.
How did you start...
helping girls in this way?
I can't...
Don't worry, Vera.
Just answer the inspector's question.
Mrs Drake...
did it happen to you
when you were a girl?
Now...
as far as you're aware...
have any of the other girls you've
helped over the years become ill?
What did you say, dear? Sorry.
Have any of them gone to the hospital?
No.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Do you always use the syringe?
You never use knitting needles or hooks?
- No.
- Or any other metal objects?
No, no, I wouldn't do that.
- How much do you charge, Mrs Drake?
- What?
How much do they pay you?
I don't take money.
I never take money. I wouldn't...
That's not why...
You do it for nothing?
Of course I do.
They need help.
Do you know a Mrs Lillian Clark?
Yes.
How long have you known her?
I think since... since we was kids.
She puts young girls
in touch with you, doesn't she?
Sometimes.
Did she put you in touch
with Pamela Barnes?
Did you know that Lillian Clark was paid
two guineas by Pamela's mother?
No!
She never gives you any money?
No.
- Are you telling me the truth?
- Yes, I am.
Can I go home now, please?
No, Mrs Drake, I'm afraid not.
My children will be worried sick.
They won't be long now.
Well, we can't stay here all night,
can we?
Well, we'll be all right,
if you want to get off.
We don't mind.
He told us to stay,
so stay is what we'll do.
I don't like driving in the dark.
It's already dark anyway.
Well, can we have
the wireless on, please?
So now, Mrs Drake,
I'm going to invite you under caution
to make a statement in your own words
which I shall write down
and then read back to you.
If you agree it to be a true statement,
you shall then sign it. Is that clear?
Yes.
So if I can begin by asking you how long
you've been helping girls out?
A long time.
Can you be specific?
Exactly how long?
Um...
You previously stated to the inspector
"about 20 years".
Oh, did I?
So if I put...
"I have been...
helping girls out...
for 20 years."
- "For about 20 years."
- Yes, sir.
What's wrong with climbing a wall?
Well, it depends what's on
the other side of it, sir. Sarge.
You are charged that you, Vera Rose Drake,
on the 17th day of November, 1950,
at 37 Flixton Street, North 1,
with the intent to procure a miscarriage,
did unlawfully and feloniously use
an instrument
on Pamela Mary Barnes,
contrary to Section 58
of the Offences Against
the Person Act, 1861.
Do you wish to say anything
in answer to the charge?
You are not obliged to say anything
unless you wish to do so,
but whatever you say
will be taken down in writing
and may be given in evidence.
No.
Thank you, sergeant.
Very good, sir.
This way, Vera.
- Mr Drake...
- What's going on? What's all this about?
Look, I'll tell you what,
could you bear with me for a minute?
Have a seat.
Sir.
Mrs Drake, I've just
been talking to your husband.
He doesn't know why you're here, does he?
No.
He's going to find out, you know.
Why don't you tell him yourself?
I can bring him through now.
I think it's for the best, don't you?
Yes, dear.
Myself and the WPC will have to be
present, do you understand?
- When you're finished.
- Sir.
That's it, Vera.
I'm sorry.
What... What you got to be sorry about?
What is it, love?
Look at the state of her,
she don't deserve this.
You're going to have to tell him,
Mrs Drake.
- I...
- What?
Your wife has been charged.
I'm afraid she's going
to have to spend the night
- here in the police station.
- Oh! Oh...
We will take good care of her, sir.
She'll be appearing before
the magistrate in the morning.
If you'd like to come with me, sir.
Don't tell Ethel and Sid.
Promise me.
- Where's Vera?
- Where's Mum?
Dad?
They're going to keep her
in there overnight.
What for? Dad, what's going on?
Let your dad take his coat off.
Let me have a word with your
Uncle Frank. It'll just be five minutes.
- Why can't you tell--
- Five minutes.
Come on.
- She's in serious trouble, Frank.
- Why, what's happened?
What am I gonna do?
What is it?
- Tell me.
- I can't.
She's been helping young girls out.
How do you mean?
What find themselves in the family way.
You mean...?
- I don't believe it.
- She told me herself in front of the cops.
She asked me not to tell the kids.
What shall I do?
- You got to tell them the truth.
- I know.
- What's gonna happen to her?
- She's got to go to court in the morning.
Copper give me the name of a... solicitor.
- Got to go around there first thing.
- I'll come with you.
- Will you?
- Course, I will.
Thanks.
Joyce, get your coat.
Thank God for that. Excuse me.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Ethel, where's my hat, please?
It might be better if you
was to get off home, Reg.
Yeah, course.
- Nice to meet you, Reg.
- Nice to meet you.
- Cheerio, then.
- Cheerio.
Night.
You still got your hat and coat on, Dad.
- Pop round tomorrow.
- After work.
All right.
- Thanks for the do, Stan.
- You're welcome.
- Look after yourself, Reg.
- And you, mate.
Here you are.
Tea?
How about a sandwich?
- No, thank you.
- Are you sure?
Well, goodnight then, Vera.
Thanks, Arthur.
I don't believe it.
How could she do that?
She was trying to help people out, Sid.
It's wrong though.
Well, whatever she done, she's done it
out of the kindness of her heart.
- She's let us down.
- No.
Mrs Drake.
- Yes?
- My name is Mr Lewis.
I'm your solicitor.
Stanley came to me this morning
to ask me to represent you.
- Oh.
- He's waiting outside with Frank.
- Is Frank here?
- Yes, they're taking care of each other.
Now, I have a number of questions
I need to ask you, but I would imagine
that you have a thousand and one
questions that you'd like to ask me.
So why don't you go first. Hmm?
This is case number five on the list,
Your Worship.
Vera Rose Drake.
Good morning, Your Worship.
It is my privilege to appear
for Mrs Drake this morning.
It is my intention
to make an application for bail,
subject to Your Worship's
views in this matter.
I understand from the inspector,
the police will raise
no objections to this application.
Thank you, Mr Lewis.
Are you Vera Rose Drake?
Yes.
What is your address?
- 82...
- Would you speak up?
82, Essex Buildings...
Oslow Street,
North 1.
You are charged for that you,
on the 17th day of November, 1950
at 37 Flixton Street, North 1,
did unlawfully and feloniously
use an instrument on Pamela Mary Barnes,
contrary to Section 58 of the Offences
Against the Person Act, 1861.
Sit down, Mrs Drake.
Inspector?
Detective Inspector Earnest Webster,
G-Division, Metropolitan Police.
I swear by almighty God
that the evidence I shall give
shall be the truth,
the whole truth and nothing but the truth.
As a result of a telephone call
from Ward Sister Coombes,
Detective Sergeant Vickers,
WPC Best and myself
went to the North London
General Hospital at 9:00pm...
"I know why you are here.
I help young girls who are in trouble.
I help them to start their bleeding."
I said, "You mean you perform abortions?"
She said, "That's not what I call it.
I just help them."
She admitted performing an illegal
operation on Pamela Barnes
and on hearing of the girl's critical
condition, became distressed.
I arrested and cautioned her
and at my request she produced
the equipment used in the operation,
which included a Higginson's
syringe and a cheese grater.
Mrs Drake accompanied us
to the police station,
where she made a voluntary
statement under caution.
Mrs Drake was cooperative throughout
and is not previously known to the police.
We will not be opposing bail
for this defendant.
Mr Lewis.
Thank you, sir.
My application for bail
is based on the grounds
that Mrs Drake is gainfully employed
as a domestic in several households.
Um, she has a permanent residence
and is married with two children,
in addition to which,
there is an aged mother,
all of whom rely upon her
for domestic duties.
I understand that she has cooperated fully
throughout the police investigations
and has not received, nor sought
to receive any remuneration
for performing this operation.
She has no previous convictions.
Um, however, she is unable
to provide a surety.
Yes, I shall grant bail.
Much obliged, Your Worship.
Stand up, Mrs Drake.
I shall admit you to bail
in your own recognisances
in the sum of fifty pounds
to appear in this court
three weeks from today...
On December the 18th, sir.
That is at 10:00am
on the 18th of December.
Thank you, inspector.
I don't think I can go to prison, Stan.
I'd better be getting off.
Gonna do a bit of work?
I think I should.
Let's get your coat off.
Sid?
Hello, Sid.
Didn't think you'd be here.
Come in and sit down, Sid.
I'm gonna go to me room.
I've known her since I was six.
She's been like a mum...
She was me mum.
The two of them...
- paid for me apprenticeship.
- Yes, I know all that, Frank.
All their savings.
When I left on me own,
I spent all me time round there.
She taught me how to waltz
in the front room.
She always made us laugh.
Stupid cow.
How can she be so selfish?
So now you both know what we know.
I wish I didn't know any of it, Dad.
Well, we all wish that, Sid.
I'm ever so sorry.
How could you do those things, Mum?
I don't understand it.
I don't expect you do, Sid.
Why'd you do it?
I had to.
It's wrong though, ain't it? Eh?
- I don't think so.
- Well, course it is!
It's little babies.
I mean, you hear about these things,
you read about it in the papers,
but you don't expect to come home to it
on your own doorstep with your own mum!
- You ain't got no right!
- That's enough, Sid.
Oh, what?
So what are we supposed to do then, eh?
Sit round, playing happy families,
- pretending like nothing's happened?
- I said that's enough!
- You lied to us!
- No, she never.
- She did!
- She never told us, but she never lied.
- It's the same thing!
- No, it ain't!
It's dirty.
- All right?
- Come on in.
It don't seem fair.
Look at my old mum.
Six of us in two rooms.
It's all right if you're rich.
But if you can't feed 'em,
you can't love 'em, can you?
- Poor Sid.
- I know.
Everything's black and white for Sid.
He's young.
I can't blame him.
He'll come round.
- I don't know, Stan!
- Here, come here.
I don't think I can tell mother.
She don't need to know.
That's it. It's all right.
It's all gonna come out, Sid.
Everyone will know.
Some people won't be able
to look us in the eye,
- cross the road to avoid us.
- Can you blame 'em?
You wanna be one of them people?
Can't look your own mother in the eye? Eh?
You know when you went off into war,
you turned round to me, you said,
"Sid, you're the man of the house now,
you've got to look after things."
And I did.
I was only 13.
Me and Mum, we pulled together, and Ethel.
- She must've been doing it then.
- I know.
So how many has she done
over the years then, eh?
Dozens? Hundreds?
And all right, fair enough,
she's kept it from me and Ethel,
but she didn't even tell you.
If she'd told me, I'd have put
a stop to it, wouldn't I?
I don't get it, ain't you angry?
Of course I'm bloody angry,
you silly bugger.
- You're asking me to forgive her.
- Yes.
You can forgive her, Sid.
She's your mother.
She'd forgive you anything,
wouldn't she?
I know you think she done a bad thing.
But God knows, she's going to get
punished enough for what she done.
We can't let her down.
I don't know what to say to you, Mum.
You don't have to say nothing, Sid.
I'm scared for you, that's all.
You'll have to look after your dad.
Course I will.
I love you, Mum.
Stand up.
Vera Rose Drake.
I commit you for trial
at the Central Criminal Court
of the next session commencing
the 10th of January, 1951.
I shall admit you to bail
in your own recognisances
in the sum of fifty pounds
and I shall grant a defence certificate.
Much obliged, Your Worship.
I don't want to see that woman, Frank.
- I can't be near her.
- It's Christmas.
I won't sit round the dinner table
with her, eating food.
- I'm sorry, I can't help it.
- He's me brother.
- What am I supposed to say to him?
- I don't know.
We ain't never going
to have a Christmas by ourselves!
Just you and me.
All right, I'll go.
For you.
I ain't staying though.
We'll have a quick drink
and then we'll leave.
All right?
Now I have received a reply from
three of Mrs Drake's four employers.
Mrs Wells has not even had the decency
to respond to my second letter,
I'm afraid to say,
and whilst they all speak
very highly of Mrs Drake,
I'm afraid that none of them,
under the circumstances,
feel able to appear as a character
witness on your behalf.
A, Miss, uh, Miss Kitchener does,
however, send her blessing.
On a more positive note,
I have secured the services
of Mr Hampton Ward,
who is an excellent barrister,
and will present our case
in the best possible light.
Now, the judge may see fit to
give us the minimum sentence,
which could be as little as 18 months.
I'm afraid I'm unable to offer you
any more hope than that.
I'm sorry.
- You been feeling all right, Joyce?
- Yes, thank you.
You gonna have one of your chocolates?
Oh, yes.
I'll have one of these.
Frank?
No.
Ethel?
No, you're all right, mate.
This is the best Christmas
I've had in a long time.
Thank you very much, Vera.
Smashing.
Is your name Vera Rose Drake?
Yes.
Prisoner at the bar,
you are charged with using an instrument
with intent to procure miscarriage,
contrary to Section 58 of
the Offences Against the Person Act, 1861.
The particulars of the offence,
are that on the 17th day of November 1950,
in the county of London,
you did unlawfully use an instrument
with intent to procure
the miscarriage of a woman
named Pamela Mary Barnes.
How say you?
Are you guilty, or not guilty?
I'm guilty.
Could you please speak up, Mrs Drake,
that the court might hear you?
- I'm guilty.
- Thank you.
Please be seated.
The inspector then arrested the defendant
and cautioned her.
On being asked to surrender
the equipment used for the abortion,
the defendant produced nine objects
from the top of a cupboard in the bedroom.
My Lord, they were
a Higginson's syringe.
That is exhibit EW-1.
A cheese grater. Exhibit EW-2.
A nail brush.
Exhibit EW-3.
A bottle of disinfectant.
Exhibit EW-4,
Wrapped in a towel. Exhibit EW-5.
A piece of carbolic soap
wrapped in a dishcloth.
They are exhibits EW-6 and EW-7.
Those last two objects
were both enclosed in a tin.
Which is exhibit EW-8.
All the aforementioned items
were kept in a cloth bag,
which, as Your Lordship will see,
is exhibit EW-9.
Vera Drake is not concerned with riches.
She simply helps people,
as and when she's asked.
She's always helped people.
Her solicitude for others
has led her to commit
one of the most serious offences
in the calendar,
but her intention
was to help the young girl
and not to harm her.
Um, I may assure Your Lordship that
Vera Drake is more relieved than anyone
at the recovery of Pamela Barnes.
And I submit that Your Lordship
would have little doubt that this...
uh, unfortunate woman is now ever likely
to reoffend.
And that is the case
for the defence, My Lord.
Thank you, Mr Hampton Ward.
Prisoner at the bar, please rise.
Prisoner at the bar,
you stand convicted of felony.
Have you anything to say
why the court should not give you
judgment according to law?
No.
Please remain standing.
Vera Rose Drake,
you have committed a crime, the gravity
of which cannot be overestimated.
The law is very clear
and you have wilfully broken that law.
And furthermore,
in so doing,
you have put at risk
the life of a vulnerable young woman.
And but for the timely intervention
of the medical profession,
you might have been before me
on an even more serious charge
than the one that has
brought you here today.
Now...
I have heard your plea of guilty,
and I have taken that into account...
and I have listened very carefully
to the submissions of your council.
But nothing has been advanced me today
on your behalf
which would persuade me
to take any course
other than to impose a custodial sentence.
Indeed...
the extreme seriousness of your crime
is bound to be reflected
in the sentence that I am about to pass.
And that must serve
as a deterrent to others.
I therefore sentence you
to a term of imprisonment...
which will be two years and six months.
Take her down.
All rise.
She won't be able to come round
and see you.
Not for a while.
Why not?
Ethel will come over.
- She ain't dead, is she?
- No.
No, she ain't dead.
How long did you say you got?
Two years and six months.
First offence?
Oh, yes.
- Did she die?
- No, dear.
I don't know what I'd
have done if she had.
My girl died.
- Did she?
- So did mine.
Oh, dear.
What'd you use?
- A syringe.
- There you are.
Hundreds of times, safe as houses.
Yes, I don't know what happened.
We just do our best, love.
- How long you in here for then?
- Three years.
- Four.
- Second time for us.
Oh.
- Cheer up. You'll only do half.
- You'll be out before you know it.
Yes.
See you later, then.
Mind where you're going, Drake.