Replacement team's here, sir.
Right.
Come on through.
Another 20 minutes,
we were gonna start looking for you guys.
God, it's really something out there.
You look a mess, sir.
Yeah?
Your turn next, Ginsberg.
Okay, I'll see you in 24.
See you tomorrow.
What was that you were saying now?
Oh, so I used to hear her chant
all night long.
Over the plants?
Yeah, she'd cup her hands over those seeds
and she'd chant by the hour.
She grew the most
beautiful wandoos you ever saw, man.
Primo stuff. Resin city.
Stand clear.
Your mother's been
very worried about you guys.
The roads must be a bear, huh?
- What roads?
- Visibility.
Visibility? Bullshit.
You guys haven't been on
time for the last six months.
Well, I wrote you guys up in the log book.
Yeah, you're a prince, Bevan.
Good night, gentlemen.
So that was, like, sensimillia, right?
Sinsemilla.
This grass made Thai
stick taste like oregano.
Lay you out flat, man.
- Got a red light, sir.
- What on?
Number eight. Warhead alarm.
Give it a thump with your finger.
Alarm reset.
Skybird, this is Dropkick
with a Red Dash Alpha
message in two parts.
Break, break.
Red Dash Alpha.
- Stand by to copy message.
- Red Dash Alpha.
Standing by.
Romeo, Oscar, November,
Charlie, Tango, Tango, Lima, Alpha.
Authentication, two, two, zero, zero,
four, zero, Delta, Lima.
I have a valid message.
Stand by to authenticate.
I agree with authentication also, sir.
- Enter launch code.
- Entering launch code.
- Launch order confirmed.
- Holy shit!
Target selection complete.
Time on target sequence complete.
Yield selection complete.
Begin countdown T-minus 60.
All right, let's do it. Insert launch key.
Stand by.
Launch key inserted.
Roger.
On my mark, rotate launch key to set.
Three,
two,
one,
mark.
T-minus 50.
Roger, at set.
- Sir.
- T-minus 40.
Uh, enable missiles.
Number one enabled, two enabled,
three enabled, four, five...
Let's try to get
somebody on the goddamn phone!
Seven, eight...
...nine.
- Ten. All missiles enabled.
- T-minus 30.
Get me Wing Command
post on your direct line.
That's not the correct procedure, Captain.
SAC. Try SAC headquarters on the HF.
That's not the correct procedure.
Screw the procedure.
I want somebody on the goddamn phone
before I kill 20 million people.
T-minus 20.
I got nothing here.
They might have been knocked out already.
All right.
On my mark, rotate launch keys to launch.
- Roger. Ready to go launch.
- 15, 14...
13, 12, 11.
Seven, six, five...
- Sir, we have a launch order.
- ...four, three...
Put your hand on the key, sir.
- I'm sorry.
- ...two, one, launch.
Sir, we are at launch. Turn your key!
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
Turn your key, sir!
They're cleared.
You can go ahead and open it up.
- Hello, I'm Pat Healy.
- How do you do?
- I'm Lyle Watson.
- Oh, we've met before.
This is Arthur Cabot.
Yes,
I'm Pat Healy, Dr. McKittrick's assistant.
- How do you do?
- We've got some passes
for you here.
We have scheduled
a meeting pending your arrival.
If you have any questions,
please feel free to ask me.
I'd be happy to fill
you in, in any way I can.
I've read the briefing.
They're here.
Good.
Let's go.
Cabot and Watson came alone.
No senators. No congressmen.
I wish they had
brought a couple of senators.
What?
I'd like to tell them
what's going on around here.
Oh, John, please,
don't start that right away.
I've had them on
the phone and they're calmed down.
Well, look, now, are we positive
that these men had no way
of knowing this was only a test?
Lyle, for God's sakes,
how many times are
we gonna go through this?
It doesn't make any difference anymore.
I've spoken to each of these men,
they all believed it is the real deal.
Now, look, we gotta be on
a plane in less than an hour.
I'm the one that has
to explain to the President
why 22 percent of his missile commanders
failed to launch their missiles.
What am I supposed to tell him?
"22 percent isn't so bad"?
The President knows
that I am fully responsible
for the men in my command, sir.
I've ordered a complete re-evaluation
of our psychological screening procedure.
What? Wait a minute.
Excuse me, General.
We can't ask these men to go back
to the President of the United States
with a lot of headshrinker horseshit!
Besides, you can't
screen out human response.
Those men in the silos
know what it means to turn the keys,
and some of them are just not up to it!
Now, it's as simple as that!
I think we ought to
take the men out of the loop.
Mr. McKittrick, you're out of line, sir.
- Why am I out of line?
- Wait a minute.
What are you talking about, out of line?
Excuse me.
I'm sorry. I don't understand.
What do you mean?
Take them out of the loop?
Gentlemen, we've had men in these silos
since before any of
you were watching Howdy Doody.
Now, for myself,
I sleep pretty well at night
knowing those boys are down there.
General, we all know they're fine men,
but in a nuclear war,
we can't afford to have our missiles
lying dormant in those silos
because those men refuse to turn the keys
when the computers tell them to!
You mean when
the President orders them to.
The President will
probably follow the computer war plan.
Now, that's a fact!
Well, I imagine
the Joint Chiefs will have some input.
You're damned tooting!
Well, hell, the Soviets
launch a surprise attack,
there's no time.
23 minutes from warning to impact.
Six minutes if it's sub-launched.
Six minutes. Six minutes.
That's barely enough time
for the President to make a decision.
Now, once he makes that decision,
the computer should take over.
Now, sir, I know
that you've got a plane waiting for you,
but if you could
indulge me for five minutes,
I'd like to show you something.
These computers give us instant access
to the state of the world.
Troop movements, Soviet missile tests,
shifting weather patterns.
It all flows into this room,
and then into what
we call the WOPR computer.
WOPR. What is that?
It's the War Operation Plan Response.
This is Mr. Richter.
Paul, would you like to tell
these gentlemen about the WOPR?
Well,
the WOPR spends all its time
thinking about World War III.
24 hours a day, 365 days a year,
it plays an endless series of war games,
using all available
information on the state of the world.
The WOPR has already fought World War III
as a game time and time again.
It estimates Soviet
responses to our responses,
to their responses, and so on.
Estimates damage, counts the dead,
then it looks for ways to improve...
Well, but the point
is that the key decisions
of every conceivable
option in a nuclear crisis
have already been made by the WOPR.
So, what you're telling me
is that all this trillion-dollar hardware
is really at the mercy of those men
with the little brass keys?
That's exactly right.
Whose only problem is
that they're human beings.
But in, what, 30 days,
we could replace
them with electronic relays.
Get the men out of the loop.
Gentlemen, I wouldn't
trust this overgrown pile
of microchips any
further than I can throw it.
And I don't know if you wanna trust
the safety of
our country to some silicone diode.
General, nobody is
talking about entrusting
the safety of the nation
to a machine, for God's sake.
We'll keep control, but we'll keep it here
at the top, where it belongs.
All right, gentlemen,
I think I'm gonna recommend
McKittrick's idea to the President,
and I'll get back to you on this.
Thank you.
You won't... you won't regret this.
Okay, you had fries and a Coke, right?
Damn!
- Hi, David.
- Hey, Howie.
- How's it going?
- Pretty good.
You wanna take this over?
- I gotta go.
- Sure.
- Go ahead.
- Thanks.
- Bye, David.
- Bye.
All right, question number two.
Seeds that are germinated in water
before they are planted will...
What?
Rudwick.
- Sprout roots.
- Oh, David!
Nice of you to join us.
Oh, David, I have
a little present for you up here.
Question number four.
In the history of science,
novel and innovative concepts
occasionally arise from
sudden left-field inspiration.
Miss Mack.
Could you tell us
your answer to question number four?
Why do nitrogen nodules
cling to the roots of plants?
Um...
Love?
Love.
Jennifer, what do you know
about nitrogen nodules that we don't?
Some bit of salacious info
to which you alone are privy?
- No.
- I see.
No, you didn't know
the correct answer, symbiosis,
because you don't pay attention in class.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Now, there seems to be a lot of confusion
on this next question.
Asexual reproduction.
Could someone tell me, please,
who first suggested
the idea of reproduction without sex?
Miss Mack?
- Yes?
- What is so amusing?
I...
Come on.
All right, Lightman.
Maybe you could tell
us who first suggested
the idea of reproduction without sex.
Um...
Your wife?
Get out, Lightman. Get out.
Mr. Liggett wants me to discuss
my attitude problem with Mr. Kessler.
I think Mr. Kessler is getting tired
of discussing your attitude problem.
Me, too.
Lightman. What a surprise.
- Won't you come in?
- Yes.
Hi.
Whoa!
I'm sorry if I got you in trouble today.
I just couldn't stop laughing.
Oh, that's okay. You were perfect.
- I was?
- Yeah.
You want a ride home?
Yeah.
Hop on.
Whoa!
So you got an F on
that test today, too, huh?
Yep.
I guess we're both gonna
be stuck in summer school.
- Not me.
- Oh, why not?
You have to make up Biology.
I don't think so.
Why not?
Why not? Come on, tell me!
Make a left.
Why don't you come up to
my house and I'll show you?
What are you gonna show me?
I'm gonna show you.
I'll show you how to... How to do it.
Hi, Beau.
- Hey, Beau.
- Oh, hi, Beau.
- Hey, Beau. How you doing?
- Oh!
- Beau, Beau, Beau, Beau, Beau!
- Come here, little baby.
Beau! Beau!
Beau.
My room's upstairs.
- Your parents aren't home?
- No. They both work.
Ooh.
Oh.
Little mess.
That's okay. You should see my room.
You're really into computers, huh?
Yeah.
What are you doing?
Dialing into the school's computer.
They change
the password every couple of weeks,
but I know where they write it down.
Are those your grades?
Yep.
I don't think
that I deserved an F. Do you?
You can't do that!
Already done.
Do you have a middle initial?
K. Katherine.
Those are my grades.
How can anybody get a D in Home Ec?
That's none of your business.
- Can you erase this, please?
- No, it's too late.
What are you doing?
I'm changing your Biology grade.
No, I don't want you to do that.
You're gonna get me in trouble.
No, nobody can find out.
There, you just got a C.
Now you don't have to go to summer school.
- Change it back.
- Why? They can't possibly...
I said change it back.
Okay, okay.
I guess I better get going.
Thanks for the ride.
Yeah, okay. Bye.
Bye.
- Get down, get down. Come on.
- It's my favorite...
You've already had your dinner.
Now, just sit.
Sit. Stay.
Don't forget you have
to take out the garbage.
- Yeah.
- David, David, put that lid on real tight
so Beau doesn't dump over the trash.
- I know, Ma.
- Shh.
Yes, they will carry back on the second.
Sure, I think we can really work out
some creative financing.
Oh, but you've gotta see it.
There's a Jacuzzi in the master bedroom,
and, honey, you know what that means.
I mean, those jets, they really work.
You know?
You are so naughty.
Oh, sure.
We can work that out.
Well, now, that is true.
You're gonna have a balloon payment
at the end of five years,
but that's nothing.
The economy is gonna be great then.
Beau. Come here, Beau.
He who dances must pay the piper.
- See you, Dad.
- Well, that's wonderful.
I'll meet you tomorrow at 9:30. Bye.
You know, I worry about that kid.
Why?
I don't know. Sometimes I think
we're all gonna get electrocuted.
This corn is raw!
I know, isn't it wonderful? It's so crisp!
Of course it's crisp.
- It's raw!
- No, it's terrific.
You can just taste
the vitamin A and D in here.
It's great.
Could we have pills and cook the corn?
What city, please?
Yeah, for Sunnyvale, California.
- The number for Protovision.
- Yes. That's 555-8632.
Thank you, and could you also tell me
what other prefixes cover that area?
There's 399, 437, 767, 936.
Thanks.
Protovision, I have you now.
Hello?
Saul's Fish Market.
- Hi.
- Oh, hi.
What?
Well, I've been thinking,
that thing with my grade,
can you still change it?
- Oh, I don't know.
- I can't believe I was so stupid.
I should have just let you do it.
I don't know.
It might be kind of rough.
- Why?
"Cause they might've changed the password.
Well, maybe they didn't.
Can't we at least try?
Damn!
Please?
- Okay.
- You owe me a quarter.
- Yeah. Come on.
Sorry you lost your game.
What's it doing?
Oh, it's dialing numbers.
- Don't touch the keys!
- I'm not touching the keys.
Excuse me.
This computer company is coming out
with these amazing new
games in a couple of months.
The programs for them are
probably still in their computer,
so I told my system to
search for other computers
in Sunnyvale, California.
They answer with a tone
that other computers can recognize.
Hear?
You're calling every number in Sunnyvale?
Isn't that expensive?
There's ways around that.
You can go to jail for that.
Only if you're over 18.
Is this gonna take a long time?
I'd like to get my grade changed.
That's funny, actually,
"cause I already changed it.
I told you not to do that.
Yeah, I know, but
I figured you'd change your mind.
I didn't want you to flunk.
Well, what did I get?
You got a D.
You gave me a D?
No, you got an A.
I was kidding.
Oh, well, that's okay.
Here, let's see what we have so far.
Excuse me.
- Did you really give me an A?
- Yeah.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
Oh, hey, you got a bank.
Gotta make a note of that one.
Might come in handy some day.
Pan Am.
Where should we go?
- Anywhere?
- Anywhere.
New York?
- New York, okay.
- No, Paris!
- Paris.
Okay.
Will you be traveling alone?
Yeah.
No. You wanna go with me?
Okay.
All right.
Smoking or nonsmoking?
- Nonsmoking.
All right, Miss Mack,
you're confirmed on Pan Am's flight 114,
leaving Chicago's O'Hare
airport at 8:15 AM on 18 August.
Do we need a rental car? No.
We really have tickets to Paris?
No. You have a reservation, though.
It doesn't identify itself. Huh.
Try anything.
"Connection terminated."
How rude.
- I'll ask it for help.
- Can you do that?
Yeah, on some systems.
See, the more complicated they are,
the more they have to help you out.
Now what?
Help games.
"Games refers to models,
simulations, and games, which have..."
- That must be them.
- "...tactical and strategic
- applications.” What does that mean?
- I don't know,
but that's gotta be them.
Turn on the printer, will you?
I wanna get a printout of this.
List games.
Oh, my God.
So, these guys can tell
you what that printout means?
Yeah, they probably
invented it in the first place.
- Can you wait here?
- Why?
"Cause these guys
can get a little nervous.
Jim.
Oh. Lightman.
Hi, Lightman.
I want you to take a look at this.
- Hey, what's that?
- I wanted Jim to see that.
Wow! Where'd you get this?
I was trying to break into Protovision.
I wanted to see
the program for their new games.
- Can I have this, please?
- Hey, wait, Jim. I'm not through yet.
Remember you told me to tell you when
you were acting rudely and insensitively?
Remember that?
You're doing it right now.
"Theater-wide
biotoxic and chemical warfare."
This didn't come from Protovision.
You bet it didn't!
Ask him where it did come from, Jim.
- Go ahead, ask him.
- I told you already.
Looks military to me. Definitely military.
Probably classified, too.
Yeah, but if it's military,
why does it have games
like checkers and backgammon?
Maybe because those are games
that teach basic strategy.
Jim, how do I get into that system?
I wanna play those games.
You're not supposed
to see any of that stuff.
That system probably contains
the new data encryption algorithm.
You'll never get in there.
Hey, I don't believe
that any system is totally secure.
- I bet you Jim could get in.
- Yeah, I bet you he couldn't!
- I bet you he could.
- Well, you'll never get in
through the front-line security,
but you might look for a back door.
- What's that?
- I can't believe it, Jim.
That girl's standing over there listening,
and you're telling
him about our back doors?
Mr. Potato Head. Mr. Potato Head!
Back doors are not secrets!
Yeah, but, Jim, you're
giving away all our best tricks.
They're not tricks.
What's a back door?
Well, whenever I design a system,
I always put in a simple
password that only I know about.
That way, whenever I wanna get back in,
I can bypass whatever
security they've added on.
That's basically what it is.
Yeah?
Okay. You really wanna get in,
find out as much as you can
about the guy who designed the system.
Oh, come on, I don't
even know the guy's name.
Boy, are you guys dumb!
You guys are so dumb.
I got this thing all figured out.
I figured it out all by myself.
Oh, yeah, Malvin?
How would you do it?
The first game in the list.
Go right through Falken's Maze.
Oh, baby, hi.
Hi, I'm Jennifer. Is David here?
How do you do?
Yeah. He's up in his room.
Thanks.
Have you ever heard of the word tumulus?
Tumulus? No, I haven't, sorry.
Neither have I.
Yeah?
Hi.
- Where have you been?
- What?
I haven't seen you all week in school.
Are you sick?
Oh.
Oh, no, no.
I was, uh, I was doing things.
You wanna sit down?
How are you?
No, I'm gonna get some water, okay?
- Okay.
- What is all that stuff?
Oh, it's nothing.
I was just...
Well, I was trying to find out more
about the guy
who designed those game programs
so I could get his secret password.
- Why?
- Why? Because...
What's so special about
playing games with some machine?
Oh, no.
No, it's not just some machine.
Here, look at this.
This is a tape
that I got from the library.
It's about this guy named Falken.
He was into games as well as computers.
He designed them so that they could play
checkers, or poker, chess.
What's so great about that?
Everybody's doing that now.
Oh, no, no, no. What he did was great.
He designed his computer
so that it could learn
from its own mistakes,
so they'd be better
the next time they played.
The system actually learned how to learn.
It could teach itself.
If I could just get that damn password,
I could play the computer.
That's him. That's Falken.
That's him?
Wow.
He's amazing-looking.
Can't you write to him
or call him somehow?
No. He's dead.
He's dead?
Yeah.
Here, look. Here's his obituary.
He wasn't very old.
Well, he was pretty old. He was 41.
Oh, yeah? Oh, that's old.
That's his little boy.
Oh, yeah?
This is really sad.
Did you know the child and his mother
were killed in a car crash?
- Yeah, I know.
- "In the years that followed
the tragic loss of his family,
Dr. Falken's health deteriorated.”
My dad is 45.
I remember once he was
really sick, and we thought...
What was his name?
My father?
No, no, no. No. Falken's kid.
Joshua.
It can't be that simple.
- Wow.
- What?
We got something.
We're in!
It thinks I'm Falken.
Hello.
How can it ask you that?
It'll ask you whatever
it's programmed to ask you.
- You wanna hear it talk?
- Yeah.
I'll ask it how it feels.
I'm fine.
How are you?
Excellent. It's been a long time.
Can you explain
the removal of your user account
on June 23rd, 19737?
They must have told it he died.
People sometimes make mistakes.
- Yes, they do.
- How can it talk?
It's not a real voice.
Uh, this box just interprets
signals from the computer
and turns them into sound.
Shall we play a game?
Oh.
- I think it missed him.
- Yeah.
Weird, isn't it?
Love to.
How about Global Thermonuclear War?
Wouldn't you prefer a good game of chess?
Later.
Let's play Global Thermonuclear War.
Fine.
All right!
Wow.
Which side do you want?
I'll be the Russians.
Please list primary targets.
Who should we nuke first?
Um. Oh, let's see.
How about Las Vegas?
Las Vegas. Great.
What next?
- Seattle!
- Yeah!
Kill them.
I have seven... Correction, eight.
That's eight Redbirds,
two degrees past apogee.
Better get the old man down here.
Cobra Dane,
we have Soviet missile warning.
Check for malfunction
and report confidence.
Projected target areas.
NORAD regions 2-5, 2-6.
All stations, this is Crystal Palace.
Initiating emergency conference. Stand by.
19 degrees past apogee.
Possible 18 targets in track.
Estimate re-entry at 19:23 Zulu.
What you got up here, Joe?
Sir, we have a radar tracking.
Eight inbound
Soviet ICBMs already over the Pole.
Estimated impact, 11 minutes.
Confirmed target area,
Western United States.
Why didn't we get a launch detection?
I'm not sure, sir. We're
checking for DSP malfunction.
BMEWS has continuous
radar tracking on inbounds.
Confidence is high.
I repeat, confidence is high.
- What is all that stuff?
- I don't know.
They're trajectory headings
for Multiple Impact Reentry Vehicles.
- What does that mean?
- I don't know, but it's great.
Are those bombs? Which is the bombs?
- Subs.
- Can you blow them up?
- Blow them out of the water.
- What's a "tra-jec-tory” heading?
- I have no idea.
- What's this?
The President's in his limousine.
They're diverting to Andrews.
The Vice President is out of position,
and the Chairman of
the Joint Chiefs is on his way.
Missile warning reports no malfunction.
Confidence remains high.
Take us to DEFCON 3.
Get on the SAC.
Tell them to flush the bombers.
Yes, sir.
SAC, this is Crystal Palace.
CINCNORAD has declared DEFCON 3.
Scramble all alert aircraft.
I repeat, scramble all alert aircraft.
Inbounds presently MIRVing.
We now have approximately
24 possible targets in track.
Sir, new time to impact, eight minutes.
Sir, SAC is launching the bombers.
General Powers is on the line.
Beringer.
God damn it!
We didn't get a launch
detection from our satellite.
No. No, radar picked them up
already out of the atmosphere.
That's the first we heard of it.
Get the ICBMs in
the bullpen warmed up and ready to fly.
Get me the President on the horn.
Yes, sir.
Mr. President, this is Beringer at NORAD.
Oh, attack!
I wonder if I should use my subs.
Yeah, sure. Give them the works.
David?
Excuse me.
David!
How many times have I told you
to fasten these lids on tight?
Would you look at this mess?
I'll be down in a few
minutes, all right, Dad?
Now! You'll come down now!
- I want this cleared up right away.
- Honey, you come down here
- and do what your father asks you to.
- Beau, why would you do this?
Pronto, David.
We're gonna barbecue tonight.
You wanna invite your little friend?
Please!
David?
Shit.
"Little friend"?
Yes, sir.
Mr. President, something's happening.
We don't know exactly what it is, sir.
I'll get back to you as soon as I know.
Reconfirm.
What's happening, Joe?
General, BMEWS and Cobra Dane now report
negative confirmation
on all the inbound tracking.
Get on to SAC, tell them to hold steady.
Sir, stop! It's a simulation!
There's an attack simulation running!
What the hell's he yelling about?
I didn't order any simulation.
We're not being attacked.
It's a simulation!
Whoa, now. Hold it!
You're not supposed to be running here.
Somebody could get hurt.
I'm sorry, sir.
We don't know how it happened.
But someone on the outside
fed an attack simulation to the...
It's a simulation!
Conley, take us off full alert.
Hold at DEFCON 4 till we find out exactly
what in the hell's happening here!
I didn't tell you to cut the line!
Did I tell you to cut the line?
You've cut the line!
Sir, they shut down before
we could complete our trace.
We did manage to locate the general area
where the transmission originated.
- Where?
- Seattle, Washington.
Shut it down!
Somebody's playing a game with us.
The flames began
in a prophylactic recycling center...
Hi, Dad!
David! David, come in here.
- What did I do?
- Plenty, mister. Plenty.
You have just passed all
of your classes this semester.
- Congratulations, dear!
- Oh.
Show this to your dad.
- Honey, David has something to show you.
- What's that?
- Here, Dad.
Uh-oh.
Oh!
- Hey, this is good.
- I'm so proud of you.
...Forces of the United States
went on a full-scale nuclear alert,
believing that the Soviet Union
had launched a surprise missile attack.
A Pentagon spokesman
places blame for the error
on a computer malfunction,
emphasizing that
the problem has been corrected.
For more on the story, let's go live,
via satellite, to Washington, DC
and News 4's Tim Hillard.
Oh, that's your phone.
Yeah.
Seriously, David, congratulations.
- Thank you.
- This one will be a pleasure to sign.
- Hello.
- David?
Are you watching the news?
Jennifer. Yeah, I'm watching.
David, is that us on TV?
- Did we do that?
- It could be.
Oh, Jesus, Jennifer!
What am I gonna do?
They're gonna come get me.
I'm really screwed.
- I'm screwed.
- What? No, shh.
Calm down!
Calm down. Calm down.
No, listen.
If they were so smart,
they would've found you already, right?
Yeah.
Okay, so all you have to
do is throw the number away
and don't call it again.
- That's all.
- Yeah.
Maybe they didn't trace the call, huh?
Right. Maybe they didn't trace the call.
I'm sure they didn't trace the call.
And listen, all you have
to do is act normal, okay?
We'll both act normal and
everything is gonna be fine.
Okay?
Okay.
Oh, God, this is so unbelievable.
Listen, do you think maybe
I can call Michelle and tell her?
No, Jennifer, don't call her!
Sorry. All right, I won't.
I'll talk to you tomorrow, okay?
Okay.
Good night, Jennifer.
Greetings, Professor Falken.
Oh, my God!
Incorrect identification.
I am not Falken.
Falken is dead.
I'm sorry to hear that, Professor.
Yesterday's game was interrupted.
Although primary goal
has not yet been achieved,
solution is near.
Game time elapsed,
31 hours, 12 minutes, 50 seconds.
Estimated time remaining,
52 hours, 17 minutes, ten seconds.
What is the primary goal?
You should know, Professor.
You programmed me.
Oh, come on.
What is the primary goal?
To win the game.
David Lightman,
hold it right there, please. FBI.
- What?
- I'm here to read you your rights.
Step over to the van, please.
You have the absolute right
to remain silent.
- For what?
- Hands on the van, please.
- What did I do?
- ...against you in a court of law.
- Step back.
- You have the right
to consult with an attorney
and to have an attorney
present during questioning.
If you cannot afford an attorney,
one will be appointed to you by the court.
- Left hand please.
- Do you understand
the rights I've just explained to you?
- Yeah.
- With these rights in mind,
are you willing to talk to me
about the charges against you?
All right, let's move.
This rather large room here
is the command center for NORAD.
No picture taking.
The screens you see in front of you
are connected to our satellites
and missile tracking
stations throughout the country.
This is the commander's desk.
Colonel Conley's in charge.
Colonel Conley, would you mind
relinquishing your command, sir?
Miss Dealy, would you come forward
and sit in this rather important chair?
These buttons you see here, and switches,
are connected with
the Strategic Air Command,
missile launching stations, et cetera,
and other things that are classified.
Miss Dealy, would
you press this button right here, please?
- The red one.
- The one in the middle?
Yes, ma'am, the one in the middle.
Oh, my God,
that's the wrong one, Miss Dealy!
That's a joke.
You didn't blow up anything.
But look what you did do.
Distinguished visitors from Birmingham.
You know...
Just last week,
I had the governor of New Jersey
right in this chair, and he asked me.
He said, "Colonel Thomas,
why are we at DEFCON 4?"
As we are right now.
Why are we at DEFCON 4?
The Soviets saw our bombers scramble,
and so they went on alert.
We told them it was just an exercise,
but we're waiting for them to relax
their posture before we do.
Wait, wait.
- Give me that. Here.
- Oh, Christ, another tour group.
Just what we need today.
Why don't they go to
Disneyland where they belong?
Well, I think they're going to tomorrow.
- Okay. All set?
- Yeah.
Oh, here.
Mr. Cabot, it was a one-in-a-million shot.
There was an open line in
our space division in Sunnyvale.
The phone company screwed up!
John.
John McKittrick, George Wigan.
- How are you?
- George is with the FBI.
He brought the kid in for questioning.
Well, it looks like we've got
a high school prank on our hands here.
- Paul, what happened?
- Well, the kid broke into
the war games subsystem,
all right, using a password
left by the original programmer.
- Password?
- Yes, sir.
Now, none of my team
even knew it was in there.
The kid claims he was
looking for a toy company.
That's great.
Anybody in here buy that one?
Well, we can find
the password and take it out,
but it might help to beef
up security around the WOPR.
Oh, beef up, huh?
How about screwed up?
We did all that and he broke in again.
The kid says your computer called him.
What the hell is going on, John?
I woke up the President, I told him
we were under attack by the Russians.
You have any idea what kind of an idiot
that makes me look like?
Not to mention the General.
Wait. Wait a minute, gentlemen.
I think we're being a little naive here.
There's no way that a high school punk
can put a dime in
a telephone and break into our system.
He's got to be working with
somebody else. He's got to be!
Well, he does fit the profile perfectly.
He's intelligent but an underachiever.
Alienated from
his parents, has few friends.
A classic case for
recruitment by the Soviets.
Now, what does this say
about the state of our country, hmm?
I mean, have you gotten any insight
as to why a bright boy like this
would jeopardize the lives of millions?
No, sir. He says
he does this sort of thing for fun.
- What?
- Damn it, John,
I want some answers, and I want them now!
Let me talk to this little prick.
I don't wanna talk anymore. Just do it!
Come on, Paul.
Who do they belong to? Do you know?
No idea.
- Good morning, sir.
- Where's the Lightman kid?
In the infirmary, sir.
Hello, David. John McKittrick.
I run the computer facility here.
Sergeant, these aren't
necessary, the handcuffs?
- No, sir.
- Yeah.
Well, David, we called your parents.
You know, we told them everything's fine.
No charge has been filed, yet.
But I think we are
gonna need a little time
to sort things out here.
How mu... how much time?
Well, that depends on
how willing you are to cooperate.
Oh, of course.
I tell you what.
Sergeant, would you tell the OD
I'm gonna take David for a little walk?
- Let's go down to my office.
- Yes, sir.
We'll be more comfortable there.
Go ahead.
You used to work with
Stephen Falken, didn't you?
Yeah, started out as his assistant.
How'd you know that?
Oh, I read an article you wrote
with him on poker and nuclear war.
Bluffing.
Yeah, that shook a few people up.
He must have been pretty amazing, huh?
Well, he's a brilliant man.
A little flaky.
He never understood
the practical uses of his work.
This machine over here
runs his game programs.
Joshua.
Come here a minute, David.
See the sign up here? Up here?
- Yeah.
- DEFCON.
That indicates
our current defense condition.
It should read DEFCON 5,
which means peace.
It's still on a four because of
that little stunt you pulled.
Actually, if we hadn't caught it in time,
it might have gone to DEFCON 1.
You know what that means, David?
No. What does that mean?
World War III.
- Wow.
- You say you broke into our system
just to... just to play a game, right?
Right. That's right.
That's exactly right.
Yeah, but when you heard it on the news,
you must've realized how serious it was.
Why'd you do it again?
I didn't do it again.
I even threw the number away.
Yeah, they found it in the trash. I know.
Joshua called me.
Hey, look at that.
That's some setup.
What did you say?
This is some setup.
- No, no. Before that.
- Joshua called me.
David,
machines don't call people.
Yours did.
Who are you, uh,
who are you going to Paris with?
Pari...? Oh, no, no, you don't understand.
Now, you had
reservations for two to Paris.
Who are you working with?
Nobody!
Why don't I believe you?
I don't think I should say anything else
until I talk to a lawyer.
I think we better
forget about the lawyer crap
until I get a few
answers out of you myself.
You gonna answer the phone?
Hello.
Yeah.
What?
All right, I'll be right down.
You stay here. Don't move.
What's going on?
There's just been
a very serious penetration
into our WOPR execution order file.
- What the hell is he saying?
- Let's have it in English.
I'll give it to you in English.
Somebody got into
Mr. McKittrick's well-known system
and stole the codes
that'll launch our missiles.
- That right, Mr. McKittrick?
- There's no cause for alarm.
The system won't accept a launch code
unless we're at DEFCON 1.
I can change those codes
in less than an hour.
Well, who did this?
I think the kid's gotta be working
with somebody on the outside.
I don't know what they're up to,
but I sure as hell don't
want our bombers on the ground
when it happens.
Take us to DEFCON 3
and get SAC on the line.
- Where are you?
- Sir.
Oh, get me an update on those subs.
I wanna know what
those bastards are up to.
Yes, sir.
Joshua.
Greetings, Professor Falken.
Hi.
Hello,
are you still playing the game?
Of course.
I should reach DEFCON 1
and launch my missiles in 28 hours.
Would you like to see
some projected kill ratios?
69 percent of the housing destroyed.
72 million people dead.
Is this a game
or is it real?
What's the difference?
Oh, wow.
You are a hard man to reach.
Could not find you in Seattle
and no terminal is in
operation at your classified address.
What classified address?
DOD pension files
indicate current mailing as...
Dr. Robert Hume, AKA Stephen W. Falken.
5 Tall Cedar Road,
Goose Island, Oregon, 97...
Can I just talk to Mr. McKittrick?
I think I know what's going...
Can I talk to Mr. McKittrick, please?
David Lightman, I'll be escorting you
to federal authorities in Denver,
where you'll be placed under arrest
pending indictment for espionage.
Espionage? No, wait a minute!
Let me talk to him! He's right over there.
Get that little bastard
out of the war room!
No. It's Joshua!
He's still playing the game!
He's gonna start a war!
Hold him where you had him before.
We'll be ready to leave in a few minutes.
Call Falken! He'll tell you!
Please, call him!
Please, call him! Call him!
What the hell's he doing in here, anyway?
Some of the men told me
that you're quite a tennis player.
Patient's eyes are dilated,
consistent with use of
marijuana and possibly PCP.
Depending on what information you want,
you have to know which button to press.
Oh, well, let's say I wanted to find out
how to hit a backhand.
I don't think... I don't think
I have the right program.
Excuse me. What do you want?
The bathroom. It's a long ride to Denver.
Excuse me.
Please! Let me talk to Mr. McKittrick.
- I gotta talk to him!
- Look, you're not supposed
to talk to anybody.
The FBI will be here any minute.
Now, do you have to take a leak or not?
No.
- I'm working here.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- Stop it.
- This right here...
- Oh, you have pretty eyes.
- That's original.
I'll get the elevator.
- Sign in here?
- Yeah, get us all.
I heard they voted you Miss Fine in 1979.
Is that true?
- Will you stop it?
- Am I bothering you?
- Yes.
- Do you want me to leave?
Yes.
All right, I want
this door open right now.
- How about getting on a phone...
- Is there a connection?
Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
I don't believe it.
Hey, Scooter. Wait up.
Come on, hurry it up. I'm late.
Okay. I'll be right with you.
I think it's jammed from inside.
- Come on.
- David!
Come on, David.
You're just making it harder on yourself.
Okay.
Let's go.
Right this way, folks.
I've just been informed
that they're cleaning
the floors in the computer center.
Don't want anyone to
slip and hurt themselves,
so we'll have to end the tour here.
Now, if I can ask you to board the bus
as quickly as possible,
we'll have a complimentary beverage
waiting for each one of you
down the hill at the officer's center.
- Hold it!
- Ah!
Now, what do you think you're doing?
Got it. Here it comes.
So what, you kids
think you own this place?
Oh, I was, uh, I was...
I was just looking around.
You know you're not supposed
to leave the group, don't you?
- Yes.
- So why don't you get back there?
Okay, excuse me. Thank you very much, sir.
- Get out of the way!
- Come on!
Hey, be careful there.
Take care. Watch your step.
- Bye.
- Bye, now.
Watch your step.
Thanks again.
Quick, check everywhere.
He can't be far. Let's go.
Come on, move it, will you?
- Thanks, pal.
- Take care.
One, five, two...
What city, please?
Goose Island, Oregon, please.
The number for Dr. Robert Hume,
H-U-M-E, on Tall Cedar Road.
Checking under Dr. Robert Hume,
H-U-M-E, on Tall Cedar Road,
I find no listing.
What does that mean?
He doesn't have a phone?
I'm sorry. I have no listing.
Oh, wait. Uh...
Falken. Dr. Stephen Falken.
F-A-L-K-E-N, at the same address.
I find no listing for
a Dr. Stephen Falken,
F-A-L-K-E-N,
on Tall Cedar Road, Goose Island.
Thank you.
Yeah?
Jennifer? It's me, David.
- David?
- Yeah.
Listen, I'm in Colorado,
and I need a really big favor.
Can you lend me some money?
What?
I need an airline ticket.
I'll pay you back as soon as I can.
But I need a ticket from
Grand Junction, Colorado,
- to Salem, Oregon.
- Why? What's going on?
I'll tell you all about it later.
David, what are you doing in Colorado?
You know, I went by your house
and your parents were just freaked,
and there are men around from the FBI
asking all these questions.
I can't talk about it right now!
Listen, when you buy the ticket,
will you tell them that I'll pick it up
in... in Grand Junction airport?
David, what's happening?
I can't talk right now.
I gotta get off the phone.
But, please, will you just
do this for me, please?
Punch up number five.
- Let me see what you have.
- Yes, sir.
22 typhoon-class
submarines departing Petropavlovsk,
turning southbound at Nordkapp,
bearing 095 degrees.
Sergeant, I hope you like vodka.
Yes, sir.
I just hope they don't make me eat
none of them damn fish eggs.
Sir, the Soviets are denying
any increase in
their submarine deployment.
They wanna know what
the hell we're doing provoking them.
They're full of shit.
We know they're down there.
I'm gonna blow their ass out of the water.
Surprise!
What are you doing here?
Well, you didn't
sound too good on the phone.
It was only a three-hour drive down here.
You shouldn't have come here.
I'm in real trouble.
Why?
David, is this because of
what you did with my grade?
Hey, you kids better hustle.
The ferry's gonna leave any second.
Thanks. Come on, we gotta run.
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
- Wait! Oh, wait!
- Hold it, hold it.
David, if he's still alive,
why did the obituary say he's dead?
No, he's not dead. He left.
When they know too much,
they give them new identities.
Anyway, the computer said so.
Oh, the computer said so.
Is that the computer
that's still playing the games?
It's the military's computer.
Why wouldn't they know about it?
They don't know about Joshua!
Falken knows about Joshua!
He's the only one
who knows what it can do!
That computer is trying to win the game
that we asked it to play.
For real!
You don't even believe me!
David.
David. David.
He's not dead.
I'm sorry.
I believe you.
Oh, shit!
What was that?
I don't know.
Did you see that?
Do you know there are still people
who won't believe they could fly?
I tell you, the sky
was once filled with them!
I'm looking for Dr. Robert Hume.
Oh, is either of you a paleontologist?
I desperately need a paleontologist.
No, we're high school students.
Oh, pity.
Well, high school students,
you're on my land and I didn't invite you.
But aren't you Stephen Falken?
Now, listen carefully.
Path. Follow path.
Gate.
Open gate, through gate, close gate.
Last ferry, 6:30.
So run, run, run.
Wait! Wait!
I came because of Joshua.
Radar reports two unknown tracks
are penetrating
the Alaskan Air Defense zone.
Confidence is high.
Flight profile
suggests Soviet backfire bombers.
I want a visual confirmation on that.
Scramble two F-16s out of Galena.
Yes, sir.
Go to DEFCON 2.
Crystal Palace, this is Delta Foxtrot 27.
I have negative radar contact.
Repeat, negative Soviet aircraft.
27, this is Brass Hat.
They're right in front of you!
You're almost on top of them.
Brass Hat, we got nothing on radar
and 40 miles visibility.
There's nothing out there,
General. Just blue skies.
What the hell?
You really haven't
been listening, have you?
Yes, I have.
I loved it when you nuked Las Vegas.
A suitably biblical ending
to the place, don't you think?
You gonna call them up and
tell them what Joshua's doing?
Now, children, come on over here.
I'm gonna tell you a bedtime story.
Are you sitting comfortably?
Then I'll begin.
Once upon a time,
there lived a magnificent race of animals.
They dominated
the world through age after age.
They ran and they swam
and they fought and
they flew until suddenly,
quite recently, they disappeared.
Nature just gave up and started again.
We weren't even apes then.
We were just these smart
little rodents hiding in the rocks.
And when we go, nature will start again
with the bees, probably.
Nature knows when to give up, David.
I'm not giving up.
If Joshua tricks them
into launching an attack,
it'll be your fault.
My fault?
The whole point was to find a way
to practice nuclear war
without destroying ourselves,
to get the computers to learn
from mistakes we couldn't afford to make.
Except that I never could get Joshua
to learn the most important lesson.
What's that?
Futility.
That there's a time
when you should just give up.
What kind of a lesson is that?
Did you ever play tic-tac-toe?
Yeah. Of course.
- But you don't anymore.
- No.
Why?
Because it's a boring game.
It's always a tie.
Exactly. There's no way to win.
The game itself is pointless.
But back at the war room,
they believe you can win a nuclear war,
that there can be acceptable losses.
So you gave up? Decided to play dead?
For security reasons,
they graciously arranged my death.
Did you know that no land animal
with a body weight of over
50 pounds survived that age?
Extinction is part of the natural order.
Bullshit!
If we're extinguished,
there's nothing natural about that.
It's just stupid!
Oh, it's all right. I've planned ahead.
We're just three
miles from a primary target.
A millisecond of
brilliant light and we're vaporized.
Much more fortunate than the millions
who'll wander sightless
through the smoldering aftermath.
We'll be spared the horror of survival.
I'm only 17 years old.
I'm not ready to die yet.
You won't make a simple phone call?
If the real Joshua was still alive,
your Joshua, you'd do it, wouldn't you?
Look, we might gain a few years.
Perhaps time enough for
you to have a son and watch him die.
But humanity planning its own destruction,
that, a phone call won't stop.
This is unreal!
You don't care about death
'cause you're already dead.
I know a lot about you.
I know you weren't always like this.
What was the last thing you cared about?
You've missed the last ferry.
You're welcome to stay.
You wanna sleep on the floor?
Good night.
Let's get out of here.
Come on, we'll find a boat.
There's gotta be a boat.
Mr. President, we've got 48 nuclear subs
closing on the United States,
and we've got 100,000 Soviet
troops massing in East Germany.
We're monitoring
their bombers that are on alert.
Yes, sir.
Well, that's a load of shit!
No, no, sir. Not you.
Yes, sir, we'll be in touch
as soon as the information changes.
Intelligence reports
rumors of a new Soviet bomber
with stealth capabilities.
It can project a false radar image
600 miles away from the real aircraft.
Christ, now they got us chasing shadows.
I think I saw one.
What kind of an asshole lives on an island
and he doesn't even have a boat?
Maybe we can swim for it.
How far do you think it is?
No, it's two or three miles, at least.
Maybe more.
Well, what do you say?
Let's go for it.
- No.
- Come on.
No. I can't swim.
You can't swim?
No, I can't. Okay, Wonder Woman?
I can't swim.
Well, what kind of
an asshole grows up in Seattle
and doesn't even know how to swim?
I never got around to it, okay?
I always thought there
was gonna be plenty of time.
I'm sorry.
I wish I didn't know about any of this.
I wish I was like
everybody else in the world
and tomorrow it would just be over.
There wouldn't be any
time to be sorry about anything.
Oh, Jesus.
I really wanted to learn how to swim.
I swear to God I did.
Did I tell you that next week
I was gonna be on TV?
- You're kidding.
- No.
It's on an aerobics
show that's on in the afternoon
with some girls from my dance class.
A movie star.
Yeah.
I know, it's kind of stupid, huh?
I mean, nobody would have
been watching me, anyway, I guess.
I would have.
Oh, Jesus!
The bastard turned us in!
It's all right. Get in.
We have a launch detection.
We have a Soviet launch detection.
BMEWS confirmed a massive attack.
- Missile warning. No malfunction.
- Confidence is high.
I repeat, confidence is high.
Cobra Dane, is this an exercise?
Negative, this is not an exercise.
General, DBS is tracking
300 inbound Soviet ICBMs.
Tell me this is one of your simulations,
- Mr. McKittrick.
- It's not, Jack.
All right. Flush the bombers.
Get the subs in launch mode.
We are at DEFCON 1.
DEFCON 1.
Better look at this.
Major Lem, get me a report on the WOPR.
Initial attack profile is
a full-scale Soviet strike.
WOPR is putting our losses
at 85 to 95 percent
of the strategic forces.
What does WOPR recommend, Mr. McKittrick?
Full-scale retaliatory strike.
I need some
machine to tell me that?
President's on his way to Andrews
to join Airborne Command.
Sir, we have to give launch option.
Has he been in touch with the premier?
Russians are still
denying everything, sir.
We have a Soviet
submarine launch detection.
Let's go into a launch mode.
Close up the mountain.
This is Crystal Palace.
We're closing up the mountain.
You'll have to hurry.
After the gates are closed,
nobody gets in or out.
Initiate internal power.
Generators on and functioning.
External power disconnected.
Seal off ventilation shafts.
Shaft locks sealed.
The gate's closed!
Oh, Jesus!
- David!
- Everybody okay?
Are you all right? Are you all right?
Yeah, yeah. Run for it!
Move it! Get inside!
Come on! Come on!
Come on!
Hold the door! Hold the door!
Hold the goddamn door!
Come on, come on! Hurry!
They're clear! They're clear!
All units confirm
weapons targeted and ready.
Awaiting launch codes.
We are in a launch mode.
Major Lem, lock out changes.
Roger, lock out enabled.
All right, I'll call you back.
Here!
I don't know what
you think you could do here, Stephen.
John. Good to see you.
I see the wife still picks your ties.
What has this kid been telling you?
How far has it gone?
The President's about
ready to order a counter-strike.
That's what we're recommending he do.
It's a bluff, John. Call it off.
No, it's not a bluff. It's real.
Hello, General Beringer. Stephen Falken.
Mr. Falken, you picked
a hell of a day for a visit!
General, what you see
on these screens up here
is a fantasy,
a computer-enhanced hallucination.
Those blips are not real missiles.
They're phantoms.
Jack, there's nothing to
indicate a simulation at all.
Everything's working perfectly.
But does it make any sense?
Does what make any sense?
That.
Look, I don't have time
for a conversation right now!
General, are you prepared
to destroy the enemy?
- You betcha!
- Do you think they know that?
I believe we've made that clear enough.
Then don't.
Tell the President to ride out the attack.
Sir, they need a decision.
General, do you really believe
that the enemy would
attack without provocation,
using so many missiles, bombers and subs,
so that we would have no choice
but to totally annihilate them?
One minute and 30 seconds to impact.
General, you are listening to a machine.
Do the world a favor
and don't act like one.
One minute and 20 seconds to impact.
- Yes, Mr. President.
- One minute and ten seconds.
Sir, at this point in time,
we cannot positively confirm the inbounds.
We have reason to
believe they may not exist.
Yes, sir. That's affirmative.
Yes, sir.
- I do, too.
- One minute to impact.
Who's first and how soon?
Sir, initial impact
points at the 43rd Bomb Wing
at Loring, 319th at Grand Forks,
and Alaskan Air Command Headquarters
at Ellmendorf.
50 seconds to impact.
Get me the senior controllers
at each of those stations.
I wanna talk to them myself.
All stations, this is Crystal Palace.
Stand by for a message
from Brass Hat. Acknowledge?
Eimendorf Air Force Base Operations.
Lieutenant Colonel Bowers.
319th Bomb Wing Operations. Colonel Chase.
This is Loring Air Force Base.
The senior controller
isn't here right now.
That's all right. Who are you?
Sir, this is Airman Doherty, sir.
This is General Beringer at NORAD.
- 40 seconds to impact.
- Our current situation...
Men, we're currently tracking
approximately 2,400
inbound Soviet warheads.
But at the moment, we cannot confirm this.
I repeat, we cannot confirm this.
30 seconds to impact.
We're right there with you guys.
We've taken all the steps we can.
Stand by to launch missiles at my command.
Stay on this channel as long as you can.
We'll be standing by.
20 seconds to impact.
Ten,
nine,
eight,
seven,
six,
five,
four,
three,
two,
one, impact.
This is Crystal Palace.
You still on?
Anyone there?
That's affirmative, sir.
Yeah, we're here!
- Jesus H. Christ! We're still here!
- Report is showing impact.
No, sir, no impact.
We're alive and well.
All right!
Yeah! Yeah!
- That's right!
- Yeah!
All right!
All right! Recall the bombers!
Stand down the missiles!
Joshua, what are you doing?
COC, I need Dr. McKittrick right away.
Yeah, this is McKittrick.
Sir, we got a problem.
WOPR's not letting me log back on.
I can't get in to stand down the missiles.
All right, stand by.
Yeah, Paul, this is McKittrick.
The WOPR is not letting us back in.
I know. No one can get back on.
We're trying everything.
It's like the entire
password file has been wiped out.
I tried that.
Don't you think I would've tried that?
What are those?
Those are launch codes.
What are they for?
Joshua's trying to find the right codes
so he can launch the missiles himself.
Yeah, Paul, what's happening?
I checked the random number generators,
they're not even running.
Got anything?
- No, sir. I'm still looking.
- Keep going.
All right, look, I got no idea.
It could be coming from anywhere.
Sir, you better get on the headset.
Yeah.
General, the machine has locked us out.
It's sending random numbers to the silos.
It's trying to get
the codes to launch the missiles.
Just unplug the goddamn thing.
Jesus Christ.
That won't work, General.
It would interpret a shutdown
as the destruction of NORAD.
The computers in the silos
would carry out their last instructions.
They'd launch.
Well, can't we disarm the missiles?
Over 1,000 of them? There's no time.
At this rate, it'll hit
the launch codes in 5.3 minutes.
Mr. McKittrick,
after very careful consideration, sir,
I've come to the conclusion
that your new defense system sucks.
I don't have to take that,
you pig-eyed sack of shit.
Oh, I was hoping for something
a little better than that from you, sir.
A man of your education.
General, it's the President.
Well, what do you...
What are you gonna tell him?
That I'm ordering
our bombers back to failsafe.
We might have to go
through this thing after all.
Yes, sir.
He's got one.
When he gets all ten,
he'll launch the missiles.
Well, can't they get in and stop it?
No, they can't.
They've taken out my password.
Well, what are we gonna do?
I don't know. Do you?
I told you not to start
playing games with that thing.
It's games.
- Games!
- Try it.
John, let's feed it a tapeworm.
No, it's too risky.
It might smash the system.
How'd the kid get in?
Through the back door?
- We took it out.
- Can we invade the deep logic?
We keep hitting a damn firewall.
If it wants to play a game, then play it!
- Have it list games.
- Stephen, for Christ's sake.
No, let him. He's played it before.
He can hardly do
worse than you have, John.
- Two numbers.
- God damn it, I'd piss on a spark plug
if I thought it'd do any good.
Let the boy in there, Major.
List games.
Chess.
Three numbers locked in.
Poker.
The security system's
not gonna let anything through.
Global Thermonuclear War.
Four numbers.
Stephen, for Christ's sake, do something.
- Come on, kid, let's go.
- No. Try again.
- Put the list back up.
- Yeah, we already tried that.
- Put it up!
- Yes, put it up.
It's not on the list!
What's not on the list?
Go ahead. It's gotta
be in there somewhere.
Tic-tac-toe.
You're in.
Order it to disarm the missiles.
No, no!
Five numbers. It's got half the code.
One.
- Put X in the center square.
- I know.
- Six up.
- There's no way
- you can win that game!
- I know that. It doesn't.
It hasn't learned.
Is there any way to make it play itself?
Yes. Number of players, zero.
Seven.
Come on.
Learn, Goddamn it!
Eight.
It must be caught in a loop.
It's drawing more and more power
from the rest of the system.
Nine numbers.
Ten. It's got the code.
It's gonna launch.
General!
Colonel Conley, call SAC.
Get me a launch status report.
- Major Davis, get me the President.
- Yes, sir.
How you doing, Colonel?
Sir, all land lines out
of the mountain are dead.
I'm trying to break through on satellites.
Okay, keep trying.
- What's it doing?
- It's learning.
Greetings, Professor Falken.
Hello, Joshua.
A strange game.
The only winning move is not to play.
How about a nice game of chess?
Colonel Conley, take us to DEFCON 5.
Yes, sir.