(OVERTURE PLAYING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(PLANE ENGINE RATTLING)
(CROWD JEERING AND BOOING)
- (AIR-RAID SIRENS WAILING)
- (BOMBS EXPLODING)
(PLANE ENGINE WHIRRING)
(EXPLOSIONS)
(SHIP'S HORN SOUNDING)
MAN
fool on the grey?
noticed, I should imagine.
MAN
Get his head blown off.
(HORSES' HOOVES)
OLD CHURCHILL:
My Early Life
by Winston Spencer Churchill.
On the 16th of September, 1897,
at the age of 22,
I found myself taking part
in a punitive expedition
of the Malakand Field Force
on the northwest frontier of India.
CHURCHILL: In a sense, I had arranged for
my participation in this action myself.
YOUNG WINSTON:
August the 5th, 1897.
A letter to General Sir Bindon Blood:
"Sir, I do hope you will not
be annoyed if I remind you
"that you once promised me that
when you had your next command,
"you would try to find
a place for me."
BLOOD:
"Very difficult. No vacancies.
"Come up as a correspondent.
Will try to fit you in. Blood."
WINSTON: Now, which of these
gallant chaps will lead me
to something really exciting,
an adventure I can write about?
That column there?
Or that one? It's all a lottery, isn't it?
Just luck.
God, I hope I'm lucky today.
The joke of it all is that I never
really wanted to be a soldier.
No. Politics, parliament,
that's my arena.
But how am I to get there?
I have no reputation,
no family in the government.
And worst of all, no money.
CHURCHILL: Ah, money. My darling mother
wrote to me often on that tiresome subject:
JENNIE: "Really, Winston, you are
simply irresponsible about money.
"I am sending the man
the eleven pounds he asks,
"but why will you write cheques
when you have no money in the bank?
"Actually, in America,
you know, it's illegal.
"And they sentence people
to long terms in jail for doing it.
"My dear, do be careful.
And do write when you can.
"Please, please, don't take
any unnecessary risks.
"Your loving mother,
Jennie Randolph Churchill."
Who's that bloody
fool on the grey?
ADJUTANT:
Can't tell.
Someone who wants to get noticed,
I should imagine.
He'll be noticed.
Get his head blown off.
(CHATTERING)
Sir!
Lieutenant Churchill, sir.
4th Hussars.
Actually, I'm here as a correspondent.
Pioneer and Daily Telegraph.
I wonder, if you're going
to that village up there,
would you mind awfully
if I came along with you?
Ah yes. Churchill,
4th Hussars.
Actually, we don't care much
for correspondents out here, Churchill.
Or white horses, either.
Where'd you get him?
Ah, in the auction last week, sir.
Malakand Pass.
- Previous owner killed?
- I believe so, yes, sir.
Didn't that teach
you anything?
Sir?
Well, come along if you like.
But keep out of the way.
Thank you very much, sir.
Oh, one more thing.
We do try to bring our wounded back.
These chaps can be very nasty.
But as you're only an onlooker,
I can't guarantee anything. Understood?
Yes, sir.
Thank you very much, sir.
WINSTON:
The truth is, I'm not at all brave.
In fact, the truth is, I've often felt myself
a coward, especially at school.
But if I could win a reputation
for courage and daring,
if I could be mentioned
in despatches,
that would help me
to get started in politics.
In short, I need medals.
Lots and lots of medals.
And I have to learn so much,
and there's so little time.
I have to read all the books
I should have read before.
I must become my own university.
And I must overcome my speech
impediment when I speak in public.
The Spanish ships
I cannot shee... see.
For they are not in shite... sight.
Damn!
OFFICER:
Move it!
SIKH SERGEANT:
Everybody gone, sir.
All gone, sir.
Very well, then.
- Carry on.
- ADJUTANT: Carry on!
OFFICER:
Number three section, follow me!
WINSTON: Wouldn't you know it?
All this way for nothing.
Talk about rotten luck.
(CHATTERING)
(FLAMES ROARING)
(SHOUTING)
Right, we'll start back now.
Keep a dozen men, will you, and cover us
till we get halfway down, will you?
- Then we'll cover you.
- Right.
Come along, Mr Cartlidge,
we're going back now.
Very well, sir.
Come along, bring them down.
(OFFICER BARKING ORDERS)
WINSTON:
Not bad at that.
Could be worth two
or three hundred words.
(MAN SHOUTING)
- (SCREAMING)
- (GUNSHOTS)
OFFICER:
Get back. Get back!
(VILLAGERS SHOUTING)
(GUNSHOT)
(MULTIPLE GUNSHOTS)
Willy! Come on, get out of there.
Come down!
We'll cover you!
Fall back!
(GUNSHOT)
No, sahib, leave me.
Oh, sahib, you're hurting me!
Ooh, sahib, let me go!
Oh, please, on my knees,
I am begging you.
(MULTIPLE GUNSHOTS)
(MASSED SHOUTING)
(GUNSHOT)
(GRUNTING)
(MULTIPLE GUNSHOTS)
(GUN CLICKING)
CAPTAIN: Come on, you idiot,
get out of it!
Get out of it!
(SHOUTING)
(MULTIPLE GUNSHOTS)
BLOOD:
"And to conclude these despatches,
"the general in the field
wishes to mention and commend
"the courage of
Lieutenant W L S Churchill,
"who made himself useful
at a critical moment."
(BUGLE PLAYING)
(SHOUTING)
(GUNSHOT)
CHURCHILL: And thereupon,
I sat down and wrote a book.
And the literary critics
were most kind to me:
CRITIC: "If General Kitchener
should ever find time
"to read Mr Winston Churchill's
new book, The Malakand Field Force,
"it's fascinating to imagine
the great warrior's reaction to it.
"The book is excellent for a first effort,
but perhaps its title should have been:
"Some Helpful Hints for Generals
From a Young Lieutenant."
SIKH: Hurry up now, sahib,
the train is about to leave.
CHURCHILL:
For some reason unknown to me,
I have always been charged
with being unpunctual.
But then, in my lifetime,
I have constantly been accused
of many wicked things.
(CHATTERING)
- (GUARD'S WHISTLE BLOWING)
- (TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
CHURCHILL:
Perhaps I paid for all those sins,
real or imaginary, in advance,
for when I was but seven,
I was cast out of my happy home,
- and sent away to school.
- (GUARD'S WHISTLE BLOWING)
I left behind me
all who were dear to me,
especially my nurse,
Mrs Everest...
Winnie, bye-bye!
CHURCHILL:...who looked after me
and tended all my wants,
and to whom I poured out
all my troubles.
And for some reason
I cannot now remember,
I called her "Womany".
And when I went away,
I think I missed her most of all.
WINSTON: "Dearest Mother, my white horse
has been a marvellous investment.
"Everyone noticed me.
"The news here is that Kitchener is going
to fight the dervishes in the Sudan.
"Mother, darling, you must use
all your influence and charm
"to get me into his command."
CHURCHILL:
My American mother
always seemed to me
a fairy princess.
A radiant being,
possessed of limitless
riches and power.
She shone for me
like the evening star.
I loved her dearly.
But at a distance.
Nevertheless, it was my father
who was the greatest and most
powerful influence on my early life.
He was the second son
of the Duke of Marlborough
and a Tory member
of the House of Commons.
Good morning,
good morning.
CHURCHILL: Unfortunately, if my mother
had little time for me in those days,
I saw and spoke to my father
even less.
He numbered among his friends
some of the most important
men in Parliament,
and indeed in all England.
Men like Lord Salisbury,
the leader of the Tory Party,
which was then in opposition,
his nephew, Arthur Balfour,
and Joseph Chamberlain.
And even I knew that one day,
when the people
came to their senses
and swept the Conservatives
back into power,
it would be these men who,
together with my father,
would form the government.
No Lord Rothschild?
Are none of your Jewish friends
to be with us today, Randolph?
No, I didn't think
it would be fair to them.
You know how
easily bored they are.
(LAUGHING)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
Winston.
Thank you, sir.
Now, we enter
this in your name.
So.
And then you can purchase anything you
like from the school shop.
Up to the limit of
your credit, of course.
I'm afraid Winston doesn't quite
understand about money yet.
We shall teach him.
This young man will be very happy here,
Lady Randolph, I assure you.
I am certain he will.
But you'll take tea,
Lady Randolph?
Oh, I'm afraid I can't.
I shall miss my train.
Another time perhaps,
when I come again.
You will be good, darling.
And you will write,
won't you?
Yes, Mama.
And so, young Churchill,
here we are.
Come along.
Yes, sir.
HEADMASTER:
I am going to tell you something
I shall want you
to remember always.
Your school days are the most
important days of your life.
How you get on here
will determine precisely
how you get on in the world.
Succeed here,
and you will succeed as a man.
Fail here...
and you will be a failure
to the end of your days.
- Do you understand?
- Yes, sir.
Good.
Your father is a great man.
Be like him in all things.
Now, you wait here while I see about
getting you settled in.
Have you had any Latin?
Latin? No, sir.
Hmm.
While I am gone, learn this.
This, on the right-hand page.
When I return...
we shall see
how well you have done.
(WINSTON MUMBLING)
They are ready for you.
Come along.
Now, then,
have you learnt it?
- I think I can say it, sir.
- Then please do so.
Mensa: a table.
Mensa: o table.
Mensam: a table.
Mensae: of table.
Mensae: to or for a table.
Mensa: by, with or from a table.
Very good. Come along.
Excuse me, sir,
but what does it mean?
It means what it says.
Mensa: a table.
Mensa is a noun
of the first declension.
There are five declensions.
You have learnt the singular
of the first declension.
Yes, sir.
But what does it mean?
I have told you.
Mensa in Latin means "a table".
But it means
"o table" too, sir.
And what does "o table" mean?
"Mensa: o table"
is the vocative case.
O table.
You would use that in addressing a table,
in invoking a table.
You would use it
in speaking to a table.
But I never do, sir.
Churchill,
in this school, if you are impertinent,
you will be punished
and punished, let me
tell you, very severely.
Come along.
MacSweeney, P J M W.
"He exhibits rather
too relaxed an attitude
"towards the disciplines
of academic life.
"Gamma."
Stand forward, MacSweeney.
Mr MacSweeney, I shall be obliged if,
after this assembly,
you will take your customary
step through my study door.
WINSTON:
"Dear Mama, I hope you are well.
"I'm very happy at school.
"I do wish you could come
and visit me one day soon."
HEADMASTER: "He gabbles his translations
and is dirty with his written work."
Step forward,
Stuart Mackenzie.
May, A C W.
Stand forward, Mr May.
Mr Belcher tells me in this report
that you suppose noise to be
an effective camouflage for inattention.
You will shortly give me
your attention in the study,
where we will explore
your capacity for making noise.
Mr May, you're first.
(DOOR CLOSING)
(CANING AUDIBLE)
(CHATTERING)
LABOUCHÈRE:
...which is, in my view, essential.
Oh, come, come, it really is time
the Honourable Member
stopped trying
to introduce bogus bills
in order to prevent action
on bona fide ones.
(ANGRY SHOUTING)
Mr Speaker!
Mr Speaker, I protest!
- Those words should be taken down.
- MPs: Hear, hear!
Mr Speaker, I agree.
I wholeheartedly agree.
Those words
should be taken down.
Will the gentlemen of the press
please take these words down?
(ENUNCIATING CLEARLY)
It really is...
time the Honourable Member
stopped trying
to introduce bogus bills!
(LAUGHTER)
(CANING CONTINUES)
WINSTON:
"Dear Papa, how are you? I am well."
- HEADMASTER: Mr Churchill!
- WINSTON: "I am very happy at school.
"I had a nice birthday. Thank you
ever so much for the present.
"I know you're ever so busy,
"but it would be ever so nice
if you could come one Sunday."
(DOOR CLOSING)
(CANING AUDIBLE)
(CHATTERING)
CHURCHILL:
And when the next election came,
my mother married an American
flavour to the proceedings.
WOMAN:
Mind your skirts, dearie.
BUTCHER: Good morning!
Good morning.
Are we new in the neighbourhood, ma'am?
I must say, I don't recall the pleasure.
Well, you've come to the right place
to save a bit of money.
It never hurts to do a little
shopping yourself, I always say.
And learn your way about, in effect, ma'am.
What can I do for you, ma'am?
Actually, I want to talk to you
about the election.
My husband, Lord Randolph Churchill,
is standing for this constituency.
And I'm helping him to get elected.
Oh, er...
Ma'am, in this constituency,
in effect, we vote as we please.
And we don't like people coming round
asking us for our votes.
Furthermore, I never discuss
politics with women.
Even ladies, ma'am,
begging your pardon.
In... in... in... in effect.
But I want your vote.
How am I to get it if I don't ask for it?
Indeed.
Well, that's a point.
Quite so. You...
you have a point there, ma'am.
It is a point, but it's no use.
I'm a life-long Liberal.
Besides, I don't hold with lordships lolling
about the House of Commons.
No. Horses for courses, I say.
Lords for lords, commons in
the Commons, in effect, ma'am.
But my husband doesn't loll.
He never lolls.
He works very hard.
That's why he isn't here
and I am, in his place.
In effect.
Oh, and what time, may I ask,
does His Lordship arise in the morning?
Most days, about eleven.
You see, the House sits at night.
- Sometimes very late.
- He st... he stays in bed till eleven?
Well, I'm sorry, ma'am
I could never vote for a man
who lies abed until eleven o'clock!
That is the end of it, ma'am.
Good day.
- (BELL JANGLING)
- Just a moment.
Doesn't get out of bed
till eleven, does he?
Well, ma'am, looking at you now,
it's a wonder to me
he bothers to get out at all.
Good day to you, ma'am.
- JENNIE: Good evening.
- Welcome home, my lady.
JENNIE: Thank you, Evans. Betty,
Marlene. Is Lord Randolph in?
- No, my lady.
- Oh. Where's Everest?
I'm here, Lady Randolph.
If I might speak to you?
Now, please.
When did this happen?
Have you called the doctor?
We shall be taking him
out of that place.
Won't we, m'lady?
INTERVIEWER: Ladies and gentlemen,
Lord Randolph Churchill,
Secretary of State for India.
Lord Randolph. Many people
give you the major credit
for the return of the
Conservative Party to power.
Yet there is a rumour that recently
you tendered your resignation
to the Prime Minister,
Lord Salisbury.
I trust I am not here to exchange gossip
or to encourage a rumour.
INTERVIEWER: But you will not deny there
is friction between yourself and Lord Salisbury?
I refuse to discuss that any further.
To put an end to it, let me say
that I have never run away from a fight
when I believed it necessary.
But I am and always will be
loyal to the Tory Party.
Mind you...
some of my friends in my own party
have a great lesson to learn.
The Tory Party
will never remain in power
until it gains the confidence of
the minorities and the working classes.
Because the working classes are quite
determined to govern themselves.
INTERVIEWER: Ah, yes.
Your theory of Tory democracy.
It is said that there are
few who take it seriously.
Really?
Yes. After all, as an aristocrat
it's difficult to accept you
as an advocate of democracy.
Many people think
you use it as a device
to make yourself Prime Minister
in Lord Salisbury's place.
Do you?
- Not at all.
- Good.
Recently, you've expressed strong views
on the state of the Irish question.
Ah, well... the Irish question...
That, I'm afraid,
will never be solved.
Quite.
Now, Lord Randolph,
on a more personal note,
you and Lady Randolph, the former
American heiress Jennie Jerome,
are leaders of society.
Your racehorses are most
successful, you entertain lavishly,
and His Royal Highness the Prince of Wales
attends your dinners frequently.
And Lady Randolph and you
are identified with all that is new
and fashionable.
Your splendid home
here in Connaught Place
is one of the few
to have electric lighting.
How do you find it?
Do you prefer it to gas?
Well, it's all rather
up-to-date, I suppose.
That thing in the cellar,
I think you call it the dynamo,
is rather noisy.
The lights will keep going out
always at the wrong times.
No, I don't think that electric light
will ever replace gas.
- At least, not in private houses.
- No, no.
I believe, Lord Randolph,
you have a son.
What? Yes. Actually, two.
Two sons, Winston and Jack.
No doubt, they're very
proud of their father.
Well...
(CHUCKLING)
That thought
had never occurred to me.
(BELL RINGING)
CHURCHILL: I had scarcely
passed my twelfth birthday
when I entered the inhospitable
regions of examinations,
through which,
for the next seven years,
I was destined to journey.
These examinations
were a great trial to me.
I should have liked to be asked
to say what I knew.
They always contrived
to ask what I did not know.
This sort of treatment
had only one result:
I did not do well in examinations.
Begin.
CHURCHILL:
This was especially true
of my entrance examination to Harrow.
I wrote my name
at the top of the page.
I wrote the number
of the question: "1."
And, after much reflection,
I put a bracket around it.
But thereafter, I could not think
of anything connected with it
that was either relevant or true.
Incidentally, there arrived
from nowhere in particular
a blot and several smudges.
I gazed for two whole hours
at this sad spectacle.
Then, merciful ushers
collected my piece of foolscap
with all the others and carried it
up to the headmaster's table.
Whose is this?
The blond-haired boy
in the second row, sir.
CHURCHILL: It was from these slender
indications of scholarship
that Mr Welldon, the headmaster,
drew the conclusion that I was worthy
to pass into Harrow.
It is very much to his credit.
It showed that he was a man
capable of looking
beneath the surface.
A man not dependent
upon paper manifestations.
I have always had
the greatest regard for him.
- Happy Christmas, Lord Randolph.
- Thank you.
And to you, my boy.
RANDOLPH: Well, Mr Buckle, a visit from me
to The Times at this hour
must be somewhat of a surprise to you.
Oh, The Times has learnt never to be
surprised by Lord Randolph Churchill.
Then, perhaps, this will surprise you.
This is a letter from you
to the Prime Minister.
That is correct.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
But it's a letter of resignation
from the Cabinet.
That is also correct.
Lord Randolph,
you have taken me into your confidence
by showing me this letter.
I ask you...
I beg you not to send it
to Lord Salisbury.
I already have. That's a copy.
Then I urge you to withdraw it.
That's not possible.
Lord Randolph, once before
you threatened to resign
and the Prime Minister retreated.
This time, he will stand firm.
Really?
Forgive me if I seem
to be taking a liberty,
but for you to resign now,
to leave the government at this time,
on this issue of the budgets for the
Army and Navy would be a tragic error.
You must not do it.
I have no choice.
I'm pledged to economy
up to my eyes.
I gave my word.
How can I accept this flagrant misuse
of public money?
May I say that public money
has been wasted before
and the nation has survived.
As I understand it, every one of
your colleagues in the Cabinet
is willing to accept this bill.
Then why do you feel it
necessary to resign?
Because, in addition to being
Leader of the House of Commons,
I'm also Chancellor of the Exchequer.
I am responsible
for the country's money.
Why resign?
In protest?
The country will not
be grateful. After all,
isn't this a matter
of national defence?
Withdraw this resignation.
At once. Now.
The Prime Minister
has already accepted it.
I have his letter here.
Mr Buckle, I came to you,
rather than any other editor
in the hope that you, of all people,
would give me your support.
I see.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
The Times has criticised
the government
when we have thought it necessary.
But we will not lend a hand
toward bringing it down.
Will you, at least,
publish both my letter and
the Prime Minister's reply?
No.
Both letters are private communications
between you and Lord Salisbury.
To publish his letter,
I would have to have
the Prime Minister's permission.
That you will never get.
I presume I shall see the news
in tomorrow's edition of The Times?
Yes. Tomorrow.
JENNIE:
Randolph!
Randolph.
Quite a surprise for you.
It is true.
It must be.
It's in The Times, isn't it?
(BELL RINGING)
Last night, you knew.
You knew then,
and you didn't tell me.
When you said you were going to the club,
you were going to The Times.
I saw no reason
to spoil your evening.
But you've worked so hard.
Yes, I'm very tired.
Why don't we take a holiday?
We've arranged to be home at Christmas.
We have engagements.
Mr Moore, my lord.
Oh, dear, yes.
Show him in, will you?
- Good morning, Lady Randolph.
- Good morning, Mr Moore.
- Lord Randolph?
- Yes, it's quite true, Moore.
Now, be a good fellow,
have a cup of coffee with us.
No, thank you. I...
I just came to tell you that
if I can ever serve you
in a private capacity,
I would be honoured.
Very kind of you.
- Do sit down.
- Thank you, no. I...
I really must go.
I'll see you to the door.
I'll see myself out, Lady Randolph.
In all my twenty years
in Her Majesty's government,
I have never served a more able
or more brilliant minister.
He has flung himself
from the top of the ladder.
And he will never reach it again.
Winston, hurry up.
CHURCHILL: The devoted Mr Moore
had a heart attack
and died shortly thereafter.
I can see my father now
in a somewhat different light
than I did in those days.
I have long since passed
the age when he died,
and I understand very clearly
the suicidal nature
of his resignation.
My mother remained, as always,
loyal and steadfast.
(CHOIR SINGING)
BOY:
"A light on Marmion's visage spread,
"And fired his glazing eye:
"With dying hand, above his head,
"He shook the fragment
of his blade,
"And shouted, 'Victory!
"'Charge, Chester, charge!
"'On, Stanley, on!'
"Were the last words of Marmion."
(APPLAUSE)
WINSTON:
"Dearest Mother and Father.
"Two weeks from Monday,
"there is to be prize-giving
in the Speech Room.
"I have memorised six hundred lines
from Macaulay's Lays of Ancient Rome,
"and if I can get
a thousand lines by heart,
"which I will do,
I am bound to get a prize.
"So will you please
both come down?
"Everyone will be there,
and it would make me so happy
"if you were there
to see me win a prize.
"You have never been down
to see me at Harrow. Either of you.
"And this would be a perfect time.
"So, dearest Mummy and Papa,
"please, please, please,
do, do, do come.
"Your loving son,
Winston S Churchill."
WINSTON:
"And under that great battle,
"The earth with blood was red,
"And, like the Pomptine fog at morn,
"The dust hung overhead,
"And louder still and louder,
"Rose from the darkened field,
"The braying of the war-horns,
"The clang of sword and shield..."
(KNOCKING)
Come in.
Oh, Dr Roose, do come in.
- Thank you.
- He is better, isn't he?
Oh, do sit down.
I shan't be a moment.
Will you have a cup
of coffee with me?
Lady Randolph, I should
like you to meet Dr Buzzard,
whom I have consulted.
But I thought he
was getting better.
I am sorry to have to tell you, madam,
that your husband is very ill.
You must, I fear,
prepare yourself for the worst.
- Dr Buzzard...
- We agreed to be frank
with Lady Randolph, did we not?
ROOSE: Frank, yes.
But I see no necessity to be brutal.
What is it?
What are you talking about?
Lady Randolph,
it is my sad duty to tell you
that Lord Randolph is suffering
from an incurable disease.
From which, at the most,
he will die within five or six years.
Stop!
What are you telling me?
You're talking about a man
who is only 38 years old!
Lady Randolph, please believe
this is extremely painful for us.
Do sit down.
May we?
Lady Randolph, I am a specialist,
and what I have to tell you is,
I am sorry to say,
beyond question.
But what is the cure?
There is no cure.
But what is it?
Why don't you tell me?
Let us call it...
an inflammation of the brain.
In the years to come,
although he will seem to recover,
although he will seem from time to time
to be perfectly normal,
in fact, he will
deteriorate consistently.
He will suffer paralysis
in his limbs,
and his speech will become
impaired. As will his mind.
There will be periods of violence.
I am sorry, believe me.
But it is necessary for you to know.
Is it true?
It can't be.
It isn't true, is it?
Yes.
Yes, I'm afraid it is.
(SOBBING)
Oh, my God.
Randolph.
Does he know?
No. And in our opinion,
he should never know.
Lady Randolph?
Yes?
How recently have you had
physical relations
with your husband?
Why do you ask?
Forgive me, but it is a matter
of some importance.
I beg you.
Well...
Not for a considerable period.
If it is necessary for you to know,
perhaps not for...
a considerable time.
- Thank God.
- Yes. Thank God.
Neither you nor the two boys
are in any way affected.
But I'm afraid there must be
no further physical relations,
between you and your husband,
ever again.
WINSTON: Good morning, Mother.
Good morning, Father.
JENNIE:
Good morning, Winston.
(CLATTERING)
Winston!
Go to your room and stay there
until you learn how to
behave in a civilised manner!
Yes, Father.
Don't you think
that was a little excessive?
His manners are atrocious.
I know.
But most boys are
ugly and tiresome at his age.
To the best of my memory,
I was always fairly presentable.
I do not recall grunting at table
like a pig on heat.
Randolph, we haven't seen much
of Winston this past year.
And he does worship you.
You were right, of course.
- But you were a bit harsh.
- Nonsense.
You don't really think
that, do you?
Well, if you ever spoke
to me like that,
I'd feel as if you didn't
care about me at all.
Of course.
Perhaps I should
have a chat with him.
Oh, that would be nice.
- Yes, I think I'll do it now.
- Why don't you finish your breakfast?
No. Now would be best.
(DOOR CLOSING)
(KNOCKING)
Father.
I'm awfully sorry, Father.
I'll be better. I promise you, truly.
I'm sure you will be.
- We won't talk about it any more.
- Thank you, Father.
You know, Winston...
the world of politics can be
very difficult sometimes.
And I have my share
of problems these days.
The things I do are misjudged.
Things I say are often distorted.
Perhaps that's why
I'm so often bad-tempered.
Oh, no, Father. You're a great man.
Everyone knows that.
Everyone knows Lord Salisbury
treated you very badly.
And you'll show him.
All of them.
Thank you.
Thank you, my boy.
Anyway, I think...
older people aren't always
particularly considerate
to younger people, to children.
They forget what it was like
when they were children.
And sometimes,
when they're bad-tempered,
they speak more harshly
than they think they are or mean to.
Yes, I know, Father.
Well, I think there have been
times when I've done that.
Perhaps this morning.
But I would never...
wish you to feel
that I don't care
for you very much.
Because I do.
Thank you, Papa.
I mean, Father.
I say, Winston,
your collection has become
most impressive, hasn't it?
You're rather short
of artillery, aren't you?
Yes, Father.
Only five field guns.
Yes, well.
Now, that's not really...
CHURCHILL:
It was one of the three or four
long, intimate conversations with him,
which are all I can boast.
He spoke in the most wonderful
and captivating manner,
and, when he inspected my troops,
he displayed such a
knowledge of military affairs
that it would
have astounded me
had I not already been aware
of his breadth of mind.
Winston?
When you grow up,
would you like to go into the army?
Would you like me to, Father?
No, it's what you would like
that counts.
Well...
I'm awfully good at history.
Especially about wars and
battles and generals and...
Yes, Father,
I'd like to very much.
- Very much.
- Good.
We'll talk about that again later.
There's an army class
at Harrow, isn't there?
I'll have a chat with Welldon,
see what he thinks.
Yes.
Goodbye, Winston.
Goodbye, Father.
Womany.
- Womany!
- What is it, for heaven's sake?
Father talked to me!
He talked to me for the longest time,
and he was so kind,
and I'm going into the army!
The army?
Jennie, he's our son, but we mustn't
blind ourselves, must we?
He's no scholar.
Can you imagine him
qualifying for the Bar
or cutting any kind
of figure in politics?
So unless you see
him in the Church...
No, you see, the army's all that's left.
I think it's an inspiration.
We have to get him into Sandhurst,
and that, of course,
means passing the examination.
The army.
Well, that's three or four
years off, anyway, isn't it?
CHURCHILL:
Unfortunately, it took not one,
but three examinations
to get me into Sandhurst.
(HESITANT KNOCKING)
Come in.
Did my letter come, Father?
I've been accepted.
I passed.
You seem very pleased
with yourself, Winston.
I'm afraid I don't share
your satisfaction.
But I passed.
Yes, you passed.
(COUGHING)
There are two ways of passing
an examination, Winston,
one that does you credit
and one that does not.
As usual,
you have chosen the latter.
Seventh from the bottom
of the entire class.
But I did pass.
Yes. You passed...
but you failed
to get into the infantry.
You merely
scraped into the cavalry,
which everybody knows
is the mark of a third-rate pass.
Now, that will cost
me an extra...
two hundred pounds a year
to get you a horse.
And this after all those
months of cramming,
and all the trouble I went to with the Duke
of Cambridge to get you into 60th Rifles,
one of the finest regiments
in the British army.
But I only failed the infantry
by 18 marks, Father.
- I'm sorry.
- Sorry?
You are sorry?
Winston, how many times
have I heard that word from you before?
You've had
every possible advantage.
Your mother and I have
done everything possible
to make life easy for you.
Remember how you behaved at Eton?
- Eton? You mean at Harrow...
- Your reports.
They've been nothing
but an embarrassment to me.
"Untidy, slovenly, bad, lazy."
You're my greatest
disappointment.
You lie, you shirk, you boast!
You care nothing for anyone
but yourself, Winston.
Ever since you were a child,
you've been...
a problem to me.
Nothing but trouble
and heartache.
What's to become of you, boy?
No, you're no longer a boy,
you're 20. You'll be 21...
- No, Father, I... I'm 19.
- Don't interrupt me, Winston, please!
Winston,
if you do not change
your ways at Sandhurst,
if you do not face up
to your responsibilities like a man,
if you don't buckle down, Winston,
I can accept no further responsibility
for you after your 21st birthday.
If you don't change,
you'll become just another...
public-school failure, social wastrel,
living out a shabby and a miserable life
to the end of your days.
Do you understand me,
Winston?
Yes, Father.
(CHATTERING)
(HORSE WHINNYING)
CHURCHILL: Nevertheless,
once I became a gentleman cadet,
I acquired a new status
in my father's eyes.
And, when I was on leave,
I was sometimes allowed
to go about with him.
I dearly loved these outings.
I had no idea that he had
less than eighteen months to live.
Lord Randolph.
- General.
- Good afternoon, sir.
- This your boy?
- Yes. Winston.
Winston, you have the privilege of
meeting General Bindon Blood.
How do you do, sir.
Sandhurst, eh?
Good, good.
See you in India one day, right?
I hope so, sir.
I'd like to serve under you some day, sir.
I mean, in the field, sir.
You like a bit of gunpowder,
do you? Good, good.
Well, young fellow,
you do well at Sandhurst,
and if ever there's another war,
which I doubt, worst luck,
I'll find a place for you.
Give you my word.
RANDOLPH: Ambition's a good thing
in a young man, Winston, but...
one mustn't be too pushy, you know?
Yes, Father.
RANDOLPH:
Hello, Joe.
Randolph.
I was going to write to you
to congratulate you
on this young man's
maiden speech.
Excellent, Austen. Excellent.
Made a fine impression on the House.
Thank you, sir.
I should be
very proud of him, Joe.
Yes, I thought it was
a reasonable effort.
You've grown, Winston.
- Be an officer soon, eh?
- Hope so, sir.
Hmm.
- Father, I... I've been thinking.
- Yes?
Arthur Balfour is
Lord Salisbury's nephew.
They're very close,
and he helps Lord Salisbury a lot.
And now that Austen
Chamberlain's an MP,
he must be a great
help to his father.
I was just wondering...
I mean, when I have some leave,
couldn't I help your secretary?
I mean, you were your father's
secretary for a while and...
They fancy Rosebery's
gelding in this race.
He's a handsome enough fellow.
The breeding's there, but there's
something lacking in the stamina.
You know? Character.
No, I don't see him
winning the race.
RANDOLPH:
It was not...
so long ago...
(WHISPERING)
Excuse me.
RANDOLPH:
...in terms of the calendar.
- Excuse me. Hello.
- RANDOLPH: Honourable Members...
- Hello, how are you?
- RANDOLPH:...may recall I made
a previous statement.
A previous statement...
made by me...
on a previous occasion.
Honourable Members may recall.
And so I repeat,
if I may.
On that...
On that o...
On that o... occasion...
(RANDOLPH COUGHING)
On that occasion...
Honourable Members
may recall I...
Her Majesty's government...
(COUGHING)
are spending
huge amounts of money...
on army and naval operations.
They are doing so...
They are...
They are doing so
without regard to the pledges
they made to the country.
Without regard...
They are doing so...
without regard to the pledges
they made to the country.
Without regard...
to the will or voice of Parliament.
That's what I...
said.
Must have...
had a reason.
Come along, old friend.
CHURCHILL:
He was only 46.
Had he lived
another four or five years,
he could not have
done without me.
But all my dreams
of comradeship with him,
of entering parliament
at his side and in his support,
were ended.
We buried him near Blenheim,
where both he and I were born.
His friend Lord Rosebery
wrote of him:
"He was human, eminently human,
"full of faults, as he himself knew.
"But not base or unpardonable faults.
"Pugnacious, outrageous,
"fitful, petulant,
"but eminently lovable and winning."
Not a bad epitaph, at that.
Nor one I should mind
having for myself.
Now, there remained for me
only to pursue his aims,
and vindicate his memory.
OFFICER:
Parade...
present arms!
(BAND PLAYING LIVELY MARCH)
Colour parties, halt!
OFFICER:
Parade...
shoulder arms!
(BAND PLAYING "THE BRITISH GRENADIER")
CHURCHILL:
I passed out of Sandhurst with honours.
Eighth out of 150.
I mention this
only because it shows
that I could learn quickly enough
the things that mattered.
QUEEN VICTORIA:
"Victoria, by the grace of God,
"Queen, Defender of the Faith,
Empress of India,
"to our trusty and well-beloved
Winston Leonard Spencer Churchill,
"gentleman, greeting.
"We, reposing a special
trust and confidence
"in your loyalty,
courage and good conduct,
"constitute and appoint you
"to be an officer in our land forces
with the rank of 2nd Lieutenant."
CHURCHILL:
Four months later,
I lost the one person
who had never failed me.
Elizabeth. Elizabeth!
It's Winston.
Do come in.
(WEAKLY)
Winston...
What a good boy you are,
to come and see your old Everest.
You've grown.
It's the army.
Do you think they'd take me?
I'm afraid I'm not
much good anymore.
Oh, you'll get better,
Womany. You'll see.
(SIGHING)
I was thinking this
afternoon about your father.
Do you know what he did?
When I retired,
I gave him my savings,
and he made a special
trip to the City
to talk to Lord Rothschild
about investing them for me.
Now, wasn't that kind?
And he, with
so many cares of his own.
Oh, they were cruel to him.
Lord Salisbury,
that Arthur Balfour
and Mr Chamberlain.
Supposed to be his friends.
Broke his heart.
You're wet.
- You're soaked through.
- It's raining.
You came in the rain? You must
take that off. You'll catch cold.
- No. It's all right.
- No, no. You must take that jacket off
and you must dry it.
Please, dearie.
All right, Womany.
In just a moment.
Your boots aren't damp,
are they?
No. No, they're dry.
Oh, good.
It's what gives you
toothache, you know.
Sitting in damp boots.
I know.
Are you enjoying
the cavalry, dearie?
Very much, Womany.
Very much.
SERGEANT MAJOR:
Next! Arms up.
Next!
Arms up. Next!
Walk on!
Outward turn.
Both rides outward circle!
Sit up! Look up!
Two! Forward! One!
Back to your riding position.
One! Two!
Three! Four!
And one! And two!
And three! And four!
Down the centre.
Walk on.
Come along, Mr Churchill, sir.
You'll have to do better than that
if you want to go to India.
WINSTON: "Mother, darling, India has
nothing more to offer me.
"And now that you, unfortunately,
have lost most of our money
"in that American
stock market swindle,
"I really must go
to the Sudan with Kitchener.
"I could write another book
or sell some articles.
"So, please, please,
talk to everyone you can.
"By the way, I have met the most
beautiful girl I have ever seen.
"Her name is Pamela Plowden.
"We are going to do a tour
of Hyderabad tomorrow
"on an elephant.
You have to ride on an elephant
"because if you walk about,
"the natives have a habit
of spitting at you
"and crowding you into the gutter.
"Mother, darling, you won't forget
about Kitchener, will you?"
JENNIE:
"Darling, as you asked,
"I have written
to General Kitchener,
"and I should be getting
his reply soon.
"You will be pleased
to learn, I know,
"that the Prince of Wales
is reading your book."
I cannot resist writing
you these two lines
to congratulate you
on the success of your book.
Everyone is reading it.
But your dear mother tells me
you are thinking of
resigning your commission
and standing for parliament.
I hope you will not do so.
You have plenty of time
before you
to make your name
and your friends in the army.
(DOOR CLOSING)
And now to Sir Ian Hamilton,
Lord Roberts, Lord Curzon,
Sir Evelyn Wood,
Lord Cromer,
the Prince of Wales,
the Prime Minister
and Lady Randolph Churchill.
Say that I insist on the privilege
of selecting my own officers.
Say, as I've already said
not once but many times before,
I have no room for Churchill.
None!
- Say that...
- Just arrived, sir.
Say that time grows short
and I have a great many
more important things to think about
and that the matter is closed
finally, definitely and forever.
And I don't want to hear
any more about it.
You'll, er...
you'll dress it up, of course.
Certainly, sir.
(LIVELY CLASSICAL PIECE)
INTERVIEWER:
Lady Randolph Churchill,
widow of
Lord Randolph Churchill,
formerly Miss Jennie Jerome
of New York and Paris.
You play, if I may say so,
Lady Randolph, most beautifully.
It has been said that you could appear
on the professional concert stage,
if you desired,
and you've given us
ample proof of that skill.
Thank you.
It has also been said,
no doubt with malice,
that you interest yourself a great
deal in your son Winston's affairs,
and in his advancement.
But I should be a most
unnatural mother if I didn't.
Of course.
But there are those who
find an interesting contrast
between your efforts
on his behalf now
and your neglect of him
when he was a child.
Neglect?
But that was never the case.
That is vicious and hurtful.
My son never lacked
a mother's love.
Naturally, when he was a child, he went off
to school. The very best of schools.
At home, he had my attention
and a marvellous nanny
who was with us almost
from the time he was born.
Naturally, I was at the same time
devoted to my husband's career,
as any wife would be.
I see.
You do, on occasion,
entertain or act as hostess
for the Prince of Wales.
His Royal Highness finds you
charming, gracious, amusing.
You are at liberty to think so.
But if you are insinuating
the slightest impropriety...
Not at all, dear lady. Not at all.
Please be calm.
I am perfectly calm.
Then we can proceed.
You are aware, of course, that your name
has been linked with another royal personage,
Count Charles Kinsky,
the well-known sportsman.
I don't know what
you mean by "linked".
We are friends.
We have been friends
for many years.
Yes, friends. Exactly. Friends.
Yet, at one time, there was gossip,
malicious, of course,
that your marriage to Lord Randolph was,
shall we say, pro forma,
and that in the event
of a divorce, you and Count...
There was never
a possibility of a divorce.
But you and Count Kinsky
are still friends?
Yes.
Charles was married shortly
before my husband died.
Three weeks before,
in his own country, in Austria.
He has remained there ever since.
He has great responsibilities there.
One last question.
What precisely was the nature
of your husband's last illness?
It is well known.
It was caused by overwork.
Ah, yes. But the symptoms were
most curious, were they not?
I don't know what you mean.
But surely you were aware
of your husband's symptoms?
I think this has gone far enough.
But this is of great
interest to the public.
Is it? Why should it be?
Why should it be of any concern
to what you call the public?
The public is everyone.
And the public has a right to know.
Why? What right?
I don't know anything
about such a right.
I only know about the right
to some decent privacy!
Oh, come, come, Lady Randolph.
We live in modern times.
Surely the word "syphilis"
need hold no terrors for us?
Are you content?
Have you heard?
We've had a death.
Young Chapman.
21st Lancers.
- Really?
- Mmm.
Pity. Just when he was
going out to the Sudan too.
Yes.
So we have a vacancy, don't we?
You know, I was wondering...
- What?
- What about young Churchill?
- Are you mad?
- Well, why not?
Well, firstly,
if the general twigged,
he'd have our balls for breakfast.
And secondly, why?
Surely you don't have any use
for that little publicity hunter.
None at all.
- But his mother's a smasher.
- Yes, I know.
(CHUCKLING)
I say, you dog!
- Do you know her?
- No.
But I'd give
anything to meet her.
So, come on,
what do you say, hmm?
There's not a chance
in the world the old boy will ever...
(INTERMISSION MUSIC)
(ASSORTED ANIMAL CRIES)
(HORSES WHINNYING)
OFFICER: War Office to
Lieutenant Churchill:
"You will proceed to the 21st Lancers
at your own expense.
"In the event of injury
to yourself or your horse,
"no charge will be made
against army funds.
"Sign here, please.
Three copies."
MAN: "I say, Churchill, we at the
Psychical Research Society
"have an interesting
experiment in mind,
"which, as a journalist,
should interest you, too.
"If you should,
unfortunately, get killed
"will you try to
communicate with us?"
FINN:
Forward, halt!
Er... Chapman!
I say, Chapman?
Chapman, are you deaf?
Oh, sorry, sir.
It's Churchill, sir.
Oh, yes, of course, Churchill.
Chapman's the one who's dead.
Hmm. Sorry about that.
What condition's your horse in?
First-rate, sir. Not tired,
if that's that you mean.
Oh, good. Now, you're the one who
wants to see a show, aren't you?
Well, report up forward to Colonel Martin.
He'll tell you what to do.
Yes, sir.
Thank you very much, sir.
Oh, and Chapman...
I mean, Churchill,
my compliments to the colonel.
Yes, of course, sir.
Sir. Lieutenant Chapman re... Churchill.
Sorry, sir. Um...
Lieutenant Churchill reporting
from Major Finn, sir.
- Come with me.
- Sir.
- Your horse reasonably fit?
- Yes, sir.
I have a message
I want you to deliver.
But I want you to see
the situation for yourself
so that you can describe
what you've seen.
Sir.
Now, our estimate is something
approaching close on 60,000,
and, though it may not seem like it,
they're coming on pretty fast.
I want you to report on what
I've told you and what you've seen
personally to General Kitchener.
Oh, God!
Oh, I'm sorry.
I mean, yes, sir.
- You all right, Chapman?
- Yes, sir.
WINSTON:
What do I say?
"Lieutenant Churchill reporting to
General Kitchener"? He'll kill me!
He'll send me home.
He'll have me court-martialled.
He'll skin me alive
before the entire army.
I'll be ruined.
Oh, my God!
Oh, well. I died for my country.
(MASSED BAGPIPES PLAYING)
(BAND PLAYING "THE BRITISH GRENADIER")
(BAGPIPES DROWNING OUT BAND)
Sir, I come with a report
from the 21st Lancers.
The Dervish army is advancing
between yourself and
the city of Omdurman.
Colonel Martin estimates their strength
in the region of 60,000.
I saw them 40 minutes ago.
They're moving rapidly.
- They're moving rapidly, you say?
- Yes, sir.
How long do you think I've got?
I would say an hour, sir.
Possibly an hour and a half.
WINSTON: An hour and a half
should be about right.
I hope.
(HOOVES THUNDERING)
(HORSES WHINNYING)
(MEN SHOUTING)
(SHOUTING)
MAN:
Allahu akbar!
CROWD:
Fire!
(MASSED EXPLOSIONS)
(HORSES WHINNYING)
OFFICER: They're breaking, sir!
They're breaking!
(SHOUTING)
CHURCHILL: During the mopping-up
operations the next day,
I took part in
what was destined to become
the last full charge ever
of British cavalry.
(DISTANT EXPLOSIONS)
Sound the trot.
(BUGLE PLAYING)
Sound troop to the right.
Sound the charge!
Charge!
(SHOUTING)
(HORSES WHINNYING)
Charge!
(GUNSHOTS)
(SHOUTING)
Bloody hell!
(SCREAMING)
- (GUNSHOTS)
- (HORSES WHINNYING)
(GUNSHOT)
(SCREAMING)
INTERVIEWER:
Mr Winston Churchill
war correspondent, author,
recently resigned from the army
and candidate for parliament
for Oldham at the age of twenty-three.
Twenty-four, actually.
In November.
Thank you, Mr Churchill.
There is gossip that you were
detested in the army,
where it is said that you were
known as a medal hunter,
a publicity seeker,
and a social climber,
pushing, aggressive, and scheming.
Forgive me. I'm sorry.
I was wondering why
a certain kind of person
always seems to believe
the worst about me.
At Sandhurst, for example,
I was accused of being
everything from a horse thief
to a homosexual.
And I had to sue for libel, and win,
to prove my innocence on both counts.
As to what you have just said,
I'm sorry to hear it.
I thought I had served
my country faithfully,
- at some danger to myself.
- Yes.
Some officers have stated that
your criticism of General Kitchener
in your new book, The River War,
was inexcusable.
- Have you read the book?
- No.
Then perhaps you should read it.
My statements concerning
his atrocious treatment of enemy wounded
were entirely factual.
As to our victory, although
the enemy had superior numbers,
they were no match
for a modern army.
I see.
Your father also had
a weakness for offending
people, did he not?
I wouldn't call it a weakness.
I would describe
it as his strength.
And I would attribute it to the
strength of his convictions.
My father was a brilliant man.
He had no time for fools.
Yes. Actually,
you were not very well acquainted
with your father, were you?
Not as well as I should
have liked to have been.
However, solitary trees,
if they grow at all,
grow strong.
Indeed.
Something you've read?
No. Something I have written.
In my new book, The River War.
You really should read it.
There are some good things in it.
Reverting to your father's enemies,
do you imagine they will
welcome you into politics?
I don't know what you
mean by "enemies".
Oh, come now! Lord Salisbury,
who kept him out of government.
Mr Balfour, who supported
Lord Salisbury. Mr Chamberlain,
who destroyed your father's
last chance of returning to power.
- And the others.
- They were never enemies.
They may have disagreed at times,
but that's the nature
of politics, isn't it?
Lord Salisbury has been very kind to me.
I dedicated my book to him.
Then you feel you have no cause
to fight for in your father's name?
No wrong to right?
No vendetta to keep alive?
Vendetta?
That's an Italian word, isn't it?
Nothing like that in England, is there?
Why are you so friendly with
David Lloyd George, who is a Liberal?
- I like people.
- People who can help you?
A young man starting out
in life needs help.
But don't you think in these times,
politics has little room
for wealthy and privileged
young men?
I am not wealthy.
I live on what I earn.
And I support my mother
and my younger brother.
But why exactly do you wish to stand
for parliament, Mr Churchill?
- To serve my country.
- And to advance yourself?
- Yes. Is there anything wrong in that?
- Is there anything right in it?
Who are you to aspire to the
greatest parliament in the world?
What do you have to offer,
other than your ego and your ambitions?
Only myself.
I believe in myself.
I believe in my destiny.
Really?
Have you consulted
a fortune-teller recently?
As a matter of fact, I have.
She agrees with me.
- Is it a crime to be twenty-four?
- No, no. Not at all.
What would you like me to do?
Play games?
Be seen but not heard?
Close my eyes and ears?
Be a child forever?
Must we always be ruled by old men?
Doesn't every old man in politics
betray the wonderful things
he believed in when he was young?
And, by doing that,
betray his country?
I think there is room for a young man,
many young men, in government.
If I could, I would say this
to young men all over the world:
"Come on. You are needed
more than ever now.
"You must take your places
in life's fighting line.
"Twenty to twenty-five,
those are the years.
"Don't be content
with things as they are.
"Yes, you will make mistakes.
"But as long as you
are generous and true,
"you cannot hurt the world.
Nor even seriously distress her.
"She was made to be wooed
and won by youth.
"She has lived and thrived
only by repeated subjugations."
Well...
- Something else you have written?
- No.
No, it's something
I'm going to write, I think.
Really?
In your autobiography, no doubt?
Yes.
Yes, I think I will write
an autobiography someday.
I think I'll have
something to write about.
Yes. Well...
MANCUNIAN VOICE:
The Oldham Evening Chronicle:
"Young Mr Winston Churchill's
first attempt to enter politics
"has met with defeat.
He has left for South Africa,
"as a correspondent to write about
our war with the Boers."
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
CHURCHILL: In South Africa,
I had the good luck
to encounter
a Captain Aylmer Haldane,
whom I had met in India,
and who had befriended me there.
He invited me to go out
on a reconnaissance with him
in an armoured train.
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
Going back?
This is as far as
our orders take us.
Seems quiet enough.
Let's go and have a spot
of breakfast, shall we?
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
You know, Haldane,
I've been thinking.
After the Malakand Field Force,
I went on to the Tirah expedition.
- Do you remember?
- Yes.
Well, I never did
get my medal for that.
Now, if you were to write
to the War Office...
A medal for the Tirah?
(LAUGHING)
Winston, don't you ever relax?
I can't. I'm almost twenty-five.
- Down!
- (EXPLOSION)
Look out!
On the left!
- Carry on, Sarge!
- Enemy left!
(GUNSHOTS AND EXPLOSIONS)
(MAN SHOUTING IN AFRIKAANS)
Steady now, lads. Take aim.
Take aim! Good.
ENGINEER:
Brakes!
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
(RUMBLING)
(GUNSHOTS)
HALDANE: Come on, lads.
On your feet! On your feet!
WINSTON:
Take it easy.
SERGEANT:
Get up! Take posts!
WINSTON:
Haldane, we're off the rails!
Shall I go up front
and see what I can do?
Good idea!
SERGEANT:
Set up, boys!
- OFFICER
(MULTIPLE GUNSHOTS)
(COUGHING)
Hey, where are you going?
I'm a civilian.
I don't get paid for being shot at!
WINSTON:
Come back here!
- Come here! Listen!
- Let go!
Listen! You've got more chance
of being hit if you run.
Now listen to me, I'm a soldier.
No one ever gets shot twice
on the same day. That's a fact.
Now you get back in there!
It's the safest place there is.
And when this is over,
you'll get a medal.
That's a promise.
Come on! I'll go with you.
- Can this engine still run?
- Well, it might.
But the track's blocked.
We can't move.
Unless we get uncoupled
from that truck in front of us.
Come on, get in.
- And get it over on its side.
- I see.
And there's no way of doing that.
We can try.
Is there an officer here?
Yes! What is it?
We have to uncouple that truck there
and push it over on its side!
- Sergeant, bring a dozen men.
- SERGEANT: Very good, sir!
Who was that? A Boer?
Worse than that.
He's crazy!
(EXTENSIVE GUNFIRE)
- Come on. Give him a hand.
- Heave it up from underneath.
Right.
It's moving.
(MULTIPLE GUNSHOTS)
Come on! Out you come!
Outside!
Come on, that's it, lads!
Move it now! Move it! Come on!
You men, over here!
Right, come on.
Get your shoulders under here.
Come on, men!
Come on down!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Come on, there! Heave!
Come on! Heave!
Heave!
(EXPLOSION)
And again. Come on!
Hold it! Hold it!
Keep it up!
Hold it up!
Heave!
Get it up, men!
Push it!
OFFICER:
Right, take cover!
Come on!
(MULTIPLE GUNSHOTS)
(GUNSHOT)
- Did it, by God!
- You didn't get it off the track.
You said all we had to do was get
it uncoupled and push it over.
Anyway, it was too heavy
to get it off the track.
- Well, I'll have to ram it off now.
- Well, ram it off!
- I don't know if the engine'll run.
- Well, try it!
(STEAM WHISTLING)
Good. Now, go ahead.
I'll have to back her up first.
Well, then bloody well
back her up, you idiot!
Well, you don't have to get excited.
(EXPLOSION)
ENGINEER: Get out of the way!
Get out of the way!
(MULTIPLE EXPLOSIONS)
(STEAM HISSING)
Right. Now, go ahead.
- And you, keep shovelling.
- Yes, sir.
- We could go off the rails, you know.
- Go on!
- Here.
- Sorry.
But go on!
(METAL SCRAPING AND SCREECHING)
Oh, Christ!
Haldane!
Move, Fusilier!
Move, move, move!
The track up ahead's clear,
but we can't get back to you.
And anyway, the
couplings are smashed.
Yes, I know.
I know, I know.
Can we load the wounded
onto the engine?
Yes.
Well, that's something, I suppose.
The rest of us have to go on foot.
Thanks very much,
Winston. I'll remember this.
So shall I.
(MULTIPLE GUNSHOTS)
Wounded onto...
onto the engine!
The rest of us go on foot,
using it as cover.
Come on,
everyone out now!
Wounded on the engine!
Get the wounded onto the engine!
(MAN SHOUTING IN AFRIKAANS)
Come on, move along! Move along!
(GROANING)
Easy, easy!
OFFICER: Move around!
Move around!
(MULTIPLE EXPLOSIONS)
- All right?
- I think so.
All right, go ahead!
Go ahead!
As slow as you can.
HALDANE:
Slow down, Winston!
Slow down.
Slow down!
- You're getting ahead of them.
- Yes, all right. All right.
(RAPID GUNFIRE)
Winston!
Slower!
Slow down, you damn fool!
HALDANE:
For God's sake, Winston!
- Hey, slow down.
- Oh, shut up!
Slow down, you damned idiot!
I can't, you silly arse.
We're on the downgrade.
I'll kill you!
I can't help it.
The brakes are gone.
(GRUNTING)
(MULTIPLE EXPLOSIONS)
(MULTIPLE GUNSHOTS)
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
- Now what?
- I must go back and get Haldane.
What, back there?
What do I do?
You wait!
You wait ten minutes. And then if you
don't see us coming, you can go.
(GROANING)
(GUNS COCKING)
(GUNSHOTS)
(SHOUTING IN AFRIKAANS)
(NEWS WIRE BEEPING)
BOER: Pretoria.
"We have captured Lord Churchill,
"who claims to be
a war correspondent.
"But from our intelligence,
we know that he was responsible
"for one part of the
armoured train getting away."
WINSTON:
Sir, I am a special correspondent.
I was unarmed, and I took no part
in the fighting when I was captured.
I respectfully submit that I should
be released as soon as possible.
BOER: On no account is he to be released,
for the duration of the war.
I've been watching you two.
You're working on an escape.
- You're out of your mind.
- I am not.
But I will be if you won't
take me with you.
- Never.
- Be quiet, Brockie.
We can't use you, Winston.
You don't know the country,
you don't know the language.
If we got separated,
you wouldn't have a chance.
Anyway, you'd be the first
to be missed from here.
BROCKIE:
Play.
Haldane, I'm going mad in here.
And tomorrow's my birthday.
- Congratulations.
- Oh, shut up. You don't understand.
I'll be twenty-five.
I can't stay cooped up in here
for the rest of the war.
Please, Haldane.
You said you'd remember
what I did that day.
Do you remember now?
I wouldn't have been caught
if I hadn't gone back for you.
No.
Do shut up, Brockie.
I can't think.
HALDANE: What's for dinner tonight?
Any idea?
They're too close.
You're afraid.
Well, see for yourself.
- I'll go and look, too.
- No, no, wait...
(INDISTINCT VOICES)
CHURCHILL:
It was maddening.
And, besides, normally there was
only one guard on duty here.
The thought crossed my mind
that we were suspected.
Suddenly, I felt it was now or never.
And the impulse was
too overpowering to resist.
But how was I to inform my comrades?
Then I heard a heavenly sound.
(TOILET FLUSHING)
Psst!
Who's there?
(WHISPERING)
It's Churchill. Keep quiet.
Churchill? Where are you?
- What are you doing out there?
- Never mind.
Just go and tell Haldane
and Brockie right away.
Oh, I get it. Good show!
(NEWS WIRE BEEPING)
REPORTER:
London, the Morning Post.
"Our special correspondent,
Winston Churchill,
"who distinguished himself
before his capture,
"has, in a fashion as yet
undisclosed, escaped."
BOER:
Johannesburg.
"A reward of 25 pounds is offered
for the capture of Winston Churchill.
"Dead or alive."
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
Pretoria.
"Although Mr Churchill's escape
was cleverly executed,
"there is little chance of his
being able to cross the border.
"When he is recaptured,
it is probable that he will be shot."
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
(DOG BARKING)
(MAN SHOUTING IN AFRIKAANS)
(WEARY THUMPING)
Wie is daar?
My name is Dr Bentinck.
I've had an accident.
Bly daar.
(DOOR OPENING)
Now, what did you say?
- Are you English?
- Never mind.
What do you want?
Oh, I've had an accident. I...
I fell off a train.
Well, the truth is,
I'm afraid I'm lost.
All right.
Come in.
Now, then,
I think you'd better
tell me the real truth.
I think so, too.
My name is Winston Churchill.
The correspondent for the Morning Post.
I escaped from Pretoria last night,
and I'm making for the border.
I have 75 pounds.
Will you help me?
By God, it's lucky you came here.
It's the only house for twenty miles
where you wouldn't be handed in.
My name's Howard.
I'm British.
I'm the manager of this mine.
There are three more of us
keeping the place going.
The Boers keep an eye on us.
There were some
here this afternoon.
Looking for you.
- Well, then, perhaps I'd better go.
- Nonsense.
We'll just have to be extremely careful.
Have a drink, Mr Churchill.
Thank you, Mr Howard.
HOWARD:
This is our engine man, Mr Dewsnap.
Stay with him for a moment, will you?
While I get the food and blankets.
- Are the others ready?
- Waiting down below, sir.
(SIGHING)
I know who you are.
You're young
Winston bloody Churchill.
Don't worry.
I'm from Oldham, you see.
Me wife writes to me regular.
She told me how you
got beat at last election.
Don't worry, lad.
You'll get all their votes next time.
HOWARD:
Right. Come on, now.
Watch your step here.
Don't trip over the tracks.
Round the other side.
I couldn't bring much food.
The housemaids are all Boers.
Can't take the risk.
Take one of these, lad.
Ever been down a coal mine before?
- I think you'll find it an experience.
- (RATTLING)
Not very comfortable,
I'm afraid.
But you mustn't move away
from here, whatever happens.
I'll try to bring you some
more food tomorrow.
You'll be all right, won't you?
Of course. It's very cosy.
Just like home.
(CHUCKLING)
Oh, Mr Howard, gentlemen,
- thank you very much.
- Our pleasure.
RANDOLPH: You've been shamefully
careless with this watch, Winston.
The repair bill was very expensive.
If you can't take proper care
of a fine watch,
you don't deserve to have one.
WINSTON:
Yes, Father.
CHURCHILL: I remained underground
for three days and nights,
while the brave Mr Howard planned
how to spirit me across the border
to Portuguese East Africa,
from whence I could take
ship to British territory.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(CHATTERING IN AFRIKAANS)
Psst!
Thank you, Mr Dewsnap.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(NEWS WIRE BEEPING)
BOER REPORTER
"Mr Winston Churchill has given himself up."
Johannesburg.
"It is announced here that Winston
Churchill has been recaptured,
"dressed as a woman."
BOER REPORTER
Pretoria.
"Although Mr Churchill
is still at liberty,
"there is no doubt that he will
soon be a prisoner again."
BOER REPORTER
Johannesburg.
"It is reported that Mr Churchill
has been captured,
"disguised as a policeman."
ITALIAN REPORTER:
Rome."So far as is known
"Mr Winston Churchill
is still at liberty.
"The entire world watches
the progress of his escape."
FRENCH REPORTER:
Paris."There is no confirmation
"that Mr Churchill has been captured.
"At the same time, however,
no-one knows his whereabouts,
"or if he is alive and well."
CHURCHILL:
I was not yet aware
that I had leapt from a latrine
into world celebrity.
BRITISH REPORTER:
London.
"Young Mr Winston Churchill continues
to give the Boers a run for their money.
"Everyone in Britain
is cheering him on."
AMERICAN REPORTER:
New York.
"Winston Churchill, who is American
on his mother's side, is still free.
"The whole world is praying for him."
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(MAN SPEAKING PORTUGUESE)
- I'm free!
- (FIRING GUN)
I'm Winston bloody Churchill!
And I'm free!
(CROWD CHEERING)
Ladies and gentlemen!
A man who, after his daring escape,
rejoined the army of his country,
distinguished himself
again and again in battle,
helped to free his fellow officers
from the very same
prison he escaped from.
I give you...
(PROLONGED CHEERING)
Ladies...
Ladies and gentlemen
of Oldham.
Friends,
I promised Mr Daniel Dewsnap,
without whose wonderful help
I should not be here tonight,
that the first time
I returned to Oldham,
I would give his love to his wife.
She's here!
She's right there!
(CROWD CHEERING AND APPLAUDING)
CHURCHILL:
And thus, at my second attempt,
the Tory electors of Oldham
sent me victorious
into the Mother of Parliaments.
MAN: The Times.
"In raising his amendment
"against the government's bill
on military expenditure,
"young Mr Winston Churchill,
in his first major speech,
"seems bent, after one short
and promising year in the House
"on repeating the most disastrous
mistake of his father's career."
(SIGHING)
I don't understand.
- I wish I could understand.
- Does it really matter?
Yes, it does matter.
It matters very much to me.
I never understood your father
when he did what he did,
throwing his life away.
And now you're doing the same thing.
Only this time, I know in advance.
You're being dramatic.
I'm not throwing my life away.
But you are, my darling.
Everything you've worked so hard for.
I've had a note from Arthur Balfour.
No, thank you.
He says the Prime Minister's
very angry with you.
Winston, you can't attack
the three most important men
in your party, in the government,
and think that they'll
forgive and forget.
You'll be finished after tonight.
We'll see.
Oh, Winston.
- It isn't Pamela, is it? Because...
- Pamela?
No, of course not.
Of course I loved Pamela.
Still do.
I'll never love another woman.
But she had every right
and reason to marry an earl.
A "belted" earl, as you Americans say.
(BIG BEN CHIMING)
I do wish you weren't so friendly
with Lloyd George.
Such an odious little man.
He has the most annoying
way of looking at women.
I'm sorry, darling, I must go.
Sign for me, will you, please?
Winston...
for my sake.
I'm begging you.
Don't move your amendment.
Don't speak tonight.
Please.
Good evening.
Are you prepared to face these savage beasts
who even now are lying in wait for you?
As prepared as I'll ever be.
- WOMAN: Excuse me, sir.
- Oh, I'll deal with this, Mother.
I intend to escort
your son to the arena.
You're very kind.
Winston speaks of you often.
Oh, we are great friends, I trust,
despite our political differences.
Your presence in the House tonight
makes it a special occasion.
I am sure it will inspire
all the speakers.
And are you speaking tonight?
No, no. I shall be listening
with great interest to your son.
Well, now, Winston, I said
I would escort you, so let us go.
I hope one day to escort him
to the other side of the floor.
Heaven forbid.
(CHUCKLING)
Lovely lady, your mother.
- Has she talked you out of it?
- No.
He'll have your head. Lord Salisbury
never forgets, as you should know.
Well, there'll always be room
for you in the Liberal Party.
Why don't you quit the Tories
and come over to us?
Never.
Good luck.
Excuse me.
DILKE:
...to a thorough, sweeping
and almost revolutionary
reconstruction of the army,
we have failed to rise
to the hopes of the country.
MPs:
Hear, hear.
DILKE: Is there any
competent authority
who really believes that
the right honourable gentleman
has made the best
of his opportunities?
MPs:
Hear, hear.
Hear, hear! Hear, hear!
Hear, hear!
Mr Churchill.
(CHATTERING)
Mr Speaker,
I stand here tonight
to plead the cause of economy.
It may be, at some other time,
and under other circumstances,
I may take a directly
opposite position.
But tonight, I speak on behalf
of military economy
- and retrenchment.
- MPs: Hear, hear!
WINSTON:
The Secretary of State for War is asking,
indeed, demanding,
a great deal of money.
I do not think he should have it.
(MURMURING)
WINSTON:
I say it humbly,
but with, I hope, becoming pride,
no-one has a better right
to this position than I have.
For it is a cause
I have inherited.
And it is a cause for which
the late Lord Randolph Churchill
made the greatest sacrifice
of any minister of modern times.
I am glad the House
has allowed me,
after an interval of fifteen years,
to lift again the tattered flag
that I found lying
on a stricken field.
It is quite recent history.
Lord Randolph was
Chancellor of the Exchequer.
Lord Salisbury was Prime Minister,
as he is now.
And, on this same issue of economy,
Lord Randolph Churchill went down.
Forever.
But wise words, sir,
stand the test of time.
And his words were wise.
I have frequently been surprised,
since I have been in this House,
to hear with what composure,
and how glibly,
members, and even ministers,
talk of a European war.
I say, sir,
we must not regard modern war
as a kind of game
in which we may take a hand
and with good luck
and good management
play adroitly for an evening.
And when we have had enough,
come safely home with our winnings.
MPs:
Hear, hear!
WINSTON:
Oh, no, sir.
It is no longer a game.
A European war
cannot be anything but
a cruel and heart-rending struggle
which, if we are ever to enjoy
the bitter fruits of victory,
must demand, perhaps for years,
the whole manhood of the nation,
the entire suspension
of peaceful industries,
and the concentrating
to only one end
of every vital agency
in the community.
- MPs: Hear, hear!
- Ah, yes.
It may be that
the human race is doomed
never to learn from its mistakes.
We are the only animals
on this globe
who periodically set out
to slaughter each other
for the best, the noblest,
the most inescapable of reasons.
We know better,
but we do it again and again,
in generation after generation.
It may be that our
empire, too, is doomed,
like all those that
have gone before it
to continue to spill and waste
its best blood on foreign soil,
no matter what we say
or do in this place,
or think, or believe,
or have learned from history.
But, thank God for us,
there is still such a thing
as moral force.
And in spite of
every calumny and lie,
it is known that, upon the whole,
and it is upon the whole that
such things must be judged,
British influence is a healthy
and a kindly influence.
And so I say, sir,
at this particular
moment in history,
we would make a fatal bargain
if we allow the moral force
which this country
has for so long exerted
to become diminished,
or perhaps destroyed,
for the sake of the costly, trumpery,
dangerous military playthings
upon which the Secretary of State for War
has set his heart.
(MPs ACCLAIMING)
Hear, hear!
REPORTER
The Times.
"Mr Winston Churchill's outburst
brought forth some cheers,
"but not, it should be noted,
from his own party."
- Congratulations.
- Thank you very much.
REPORTER
The Morning Post, London.
"Mr Winston Churchill,
last night served notice
"that there is a young lion
loose in the House
"and the lion has sharp claws."
Well, well. Hmm.
I deeply suspect what you've
done tonight, and yet...
I have to believe you were
completely sincere.
And very brave.
You know, Churchill,
you're a child of your class,
and you may never outgrow it.
But you've got something.
(INAUDIBLE)
- (PLAYING MUSICAL PHRASE)
- (KNOCKING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
Congratulations.
Thank you.
I looked for you, but,
when I couldn't find you,
I thought you might be here.
Well...
do you think I still have a career?
We shall have to wait
and see, won't we?
Hmm.
How do you feel?
Tired.
Tired, but free.
It's odd. I feel free.
Sorry, darling, a brandy?
No.
I don't know.
It's like when I escaped.
When I first knew I was really free.
It's odd.
Oh, Mother...
I saw a girl tonight.
Tall, fair-haired.
Rather lovely, I thought.
Dressed in pale yellow, I think.
You didn't see anyone like that
in the gallery, did you?
Yes.
There was one young woman
who more or less fits that description.
Oh?
Well, you know everyone.
You wouldn't, um...?
Well, yes.
As a matter of fact, I do.
You must mean
Clementine Hozier.
Your Uncle Jack Leslie almost dropped her
in the font when she was christened.
Oh.
- Did he, now?
- Yes.
CHURCHILL:
It was an end,
and a beginning.
My darling mother
continued on her headlong,
headstrong, but always
gallant and courageous way
whilst, seven years later,
Clementine Hozier and I were married,
and lived happily ever afterwards.
SUBTITLES BY POWERHOUSE FILMS LTD