♪ It's been
a hard day's night ♪
♪ And I've been workin'
like a dog ♪
♪ It's been
a hard day's night ♪
♪ I should be sleepin'
like a log ♪
♪ But when I get home to you ♪
♪ I find
the things that you do ♪
♪ Will make me feel
all right ♪
♪ You know I work all day ♪
♪ To get you money
to buy you things ♪
♪ And it's worth it
just to hear you say ♪
♪ You're gonna give me
everything ♪
♪ So why on earth
should I moan?  ♪
♪ 'Cause when
I get you alone ♪
♪ You know I feel OK ♪
♪ When I'm home ♪
♪ Everything
seems to be right ♪
♪ When I'm home ♪
♪ Feeling you
holding me tight ♪
♪ Tight, yeah ♪
♪ It's been
a hard day's night ♪
♪ And I've been workin'
like a dog ♪
♪ It's been
a hard day's night ♪
♪ I should be sleepin'
like a log ♪
♪ But when I get home to you ♪
♪ I find
the things that you do ♪
♪ Will make me
feel all right ♪
Aah!
♪ So why on earth
should I moan?  ♪
♪ 'Cause when
I get you alone ♪
♪ You know I feel OK ♪
♪ When I'm home ♪
♪ Everything
seems to be right ♪
♪ When I'm home ♪
♪ Feeling you
holding me tight ♪
♪ Tight, yeah ♪
♪ It's been
a hard day's night ♪
♪ And I've been workin'
like a dog ♪
♪ It's been
a hard day's night ♪
♪ I should be sleepin'
like a log ♪
♪ But when
I get home to you ♪
♪ I find
the things that you do ♪
♪ Will make me
feel all right ♪
♪ You know I feel all right ♪
[Crowd screaming]
Hey, pardon me for askin',
but who's that little old man?
- What little old man?
- That little old man.
Oh, that one.
That's my grandfather.
- Your grandfather?
- Yeah.
- That's not your grandfather.
- It is, you know.
But I've seen your grandfather.
He lives in your house.
Oh, that's my other grandfather,
but he's my grandfather as well.
How do you reckon that one out?
Well, everyone's entitled
to two, aren't they?
And this is my other one.
We know that,
but what's he doin' here?
Well, my mother thought
the trip would do him good.
- How's that?
- He's nursin' a broken heart.
JOHN:
Ah, poor old thing.
Hey, mister,
are you nursin' a broken heart?
He's a nice old man, isn't he?
He's very clean.
- Hello, grandfather.
- Hello.
He can talk then, can he?
Of course he can talk.
He's a human being, isn't he?
Well, if he's your grandfather,
who knows? Ha ha ha.
And we're lookin' after him,
are we?
- I look after meself.
- That's what I'm afraid of.
He's got you worried, then?
Him, he's a villain,
a real mixer...
and he costs you a fortune
in breach of promise cases.
- GEORGE: Get on.
- No, straight up.
Hiya.
- Hello, Shake.
- You got on all right, then?
- No.
Oh? Well, we're here.
SHAKE: Norm'll be along
in a minute with the tickets.
Hey, who's the little old man?
It's Paul's grandfather.
- Oh, aye, but I thought...
- No, that's his other one.
Oh, that's all right, then.
Clean, though, isn't he?
Oh, aye. He's very clean.
- NORM: Mornin', lads.
- Hi, Norm.
Thank God you've all got here.
Look, I've had a marvelous idea.
Just for once,
let's all try to behave...
like ordinary
respectable citizens.
Let's not cause any trouble,
pull any strokes...
or do anything
I'm gonna be sorry for...
especially tomorrow in that
television theater, because...
Are you listening to me,
Lennon?
You're a swine.
Isn't he, George?
Yeah, a swine.
Thanks. Hey!
ALL:
Who's that little old man?
- Well, who is he?
- He belongs to Paul.
Oh, well. I'm going down
for a cup of coffee.
- Anyone coming?
- We'll follow you down.
I want me coffee.
You can come with Shake and me,
if you like.
PAUL: Look after him. I don't
want to find you've lost him.
Don't be cheeky. I'll bind him
to me with promises.
Very clean, isn't he?
Come out, granddad.
Make up your mind, will you?
Hello. Morning.
All right?
Whoa.
Do you mind if we have it open?
Yes, I do.
Well, there are four of us,
and we'd like it open...
not if it's
all the same to you, that is.
It isn't. I travel
on this train regularly...
twice a week, so I suppose
I have some rights.
So have we.
[Playing rock and roll]
And we'll have that thing
off as well. Thank you.
- [Turns off]
- But...
An elementary knowledge
of the Railway Acts...
would tell you that I am
perfectly within my rights.
Yeah, but we want to hear it.
There's more of us than you.
We're a community,
a majority vote.
Up the workers
and all that stuff.
Then I suggest
you take that damn thing...
into the corridor, or
some other part of the train...
where you obviously belong.
Give us a kiss.
Look, mister, we paid
for our seats, too, you know.
I travel on this train
regularly, twice a week.
Knock it off, Paul.
You can't win with his sort.
After all, it's his train,
isn't it, mister?
And don't take that tone
with me, young man.
I fought the war for your sort.
I bet you're sorry you won.
- I shall call the guard.
- Ah, but what?
They don't take kindly
to insults, you know.
Let's go have some coffee
and leave the kennel to Lassie.
[Door closes]
PAUL: Hey, mister,
can we have our ball back?
PAUL: Look, mister! Mister!
Can we have our ball back?
- JOHN: Hey!
- PAUL: Please, mister!
- You want to watch it.
- Well, it's not my fault.
You stick to that story, son.
I can't help it.
I'm just taller than you are.
They always say that.
Well, I've got me eye on ya.
I'm sorry, Norm. I can't help
being taller than you.
Well, don't rub it in! I've
a good mind to thump you, Shake.
If you're gonna have a barney,
can I hold your coat?
- He started it.
- I did not. You did.
Well, what happened?
The old fella said that...
could he have these pictures,
and Norm said, "No."
And all I said was,
"Well, why not be big about it?"
- And?
- Your grandfather pointed out...
that Shake was always being
taller than me just to spite me.
I knew it. He started it.
- PAUL: I should've known.
- NORM: You what?
You two have never had
an argument in your life...
and in two minutes flat,
he's got you at it.
He's a king mixer.
He hates group unity,
so he gets everyone at it.
Well, I suggest
you just give him the photos...
and have done with it.
Oh, all right, you old devil.
Here you are.
Hey, Pauly, would you ever
sign one of them for us?
Ah, come out, Shake.
JOHN: Hey, look at the talent.
Let's give 'em a pull.
- Should I?
- Aye, but don't rush.
None of your five bar gate
jumps and over sort of stuff.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- I don't know.
I thought it just sounded
distinguished-like.
JOHN: George Harrison,
the scouse of distinction.
Excuse me, madame.
Excuse me, but these young men
I'm sitting with...
wondered if two of us
could come over and join you.
I'd ask you myself,
only I'm shy.
I'm sorry, miss. You mustn't
fraternize with me prisoners.
- Prisoners?
- Convict in transit.
Typical old lads,
the lot of them.
Get out, ladies!
Get out while you can!
He's been gone a long time.
- Who?
- Paul's grandfather.
Oh, I didn't notice.
Where'd he go?
- Down the, uh...
- Oh, down the, uh...
Yeah, down the, uh...
Oh, well, give him
a couple of minutes, then.
Hey, have you seen
Paul's grandfather?
Of course.
He's concealed about me person.
Now, he must've slipped off
somewhere.
- Have you lost him?
- Now, don't exaggerate.
You've lost him!
Look, put it this way, Pauly...
he's mislaid him.
Honest, you can't trust you
with anything, Norm.
If you've lost him,
I'll cripple ya.
- He can't have got far.
- Let's look up the sharp end.
What's the matter
with you, then?
It's his grandfather.
I can tell he doesn't like me.
It's 'cause I'm little.
You've got an inferiority
complex, you have.
Yeah, I know.
That's why I play the drums.
It's me active
compensatory factor.
Goin' in, then?
No, she'll only
reject me in the end...
and I'll be frustrated.
You never know.
You may be lucky this time.
No, I know
the psychological pattern.
It plays havoc
with me drum skins.
Excuse me. Have you seen that
little old man we were with?
We've broken out...
the blessed freedom of it all.
Have you got a nail file?
These handcuffs are killing me.
I was framed! I'm innocent!
I don't want to go!
Sorry for disturbing you,
girls.
I bet you can't guess
what I was in for.
Should we go in here?
No, it's probably
a honeymoon couple...
or a company director
or something.
Well, I don't care.
I'm gonna broaden my outlook.
Congratulate me, boys.
I'm engaged.
PAUL: Oh, no, you're not.
Not this time.
And to think me own grandson...
would've let them
put me behind bars.
Don't dramatize. Let's face it,
you're lucky to be here.
If they'd have had
their own way...
you would have been
dropped off already.
Well, you've got to admit
you upset a lot of people.
PAUL: At least I can
keep my eye on you...
while you're stuck in here.
Shove up.
- Odds or evens?
- Odds.
JOHN: Don't worry, son.
We'll get you the best lawyer
green stamps can buy.
PAUL: Oh! It's
a laugh a line with Lennon.
Anyway, it's your fault.
- RINGO: Why me?
- Why not you?
JOHN: God, it's depressing
in here, isn't it?
Funny. They usually reckon dogs
more than people in England.
You'd expect something
more palatial.
- Let's do somethin', then.
- Like what?
Hmm.
OK.
[Girls laughing]
GEORGE:
Cor, there's the girls.
RINGO: I'll deal 'em.
JOHN: Aye aye,
the Liverpool shuffle.
Two for you, two for me,
three for them.
Cheat.
♪ I...  ♪
♪ Should have known better
with a girl like you ♪
♪ That I would love
everything that you do ♪
♪ And I do ♪
♪ Hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ Whoa, whoa, I...  ♪
♪ Never realized
what a kiss could be ♪
♪ This could only
happen to me ♪
♪ Can't you see,
can't you see ♪
♪ That when I tell you
that I love you ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ You're gonna say
you love me, too ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ And when I ask you
to be mine ♪
♪ You're gonna say
you love me, too ♪
♪ So, oh, I...  ♪
♪ Should have realized
a lot of things before ♪
♪ If this is love,
you gotta give me more ♪
♪ Give me more,
hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ Give me more ♪
♪ Whoa, whoa, I...  ♪
♪ Never realized
what a kiss could be ♪
♪ This could only
happen to me ♪
♪ Can't you see,
can't you see ♪
♪ That when I tell you
that I love you ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ You're gonna say
you love me, too ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ And when I ask you
to be mine ♪
♪ You're gonna say
you love me, too ♪
♪ You love me, too ♪
GEORGE:
He's wearin' his lucky rings.
All mine.
JOHN: It won't buy you
happiness, my son.
[Screaming]
Hey, don't move, any of you.
They've gone potty out there.
The place is surging with girls.
Please, sir, can I have one
to surge me, sir, please, sir?
No, you can't. Now listen.
As soon as I tell you, get out
through this door there...
into that big car
that's waiting.
[Girls screaming]
[Screaming]
Come on, lads. Come on, then!
[Train whistle blows]
[Screaming]
[Piano playing]
- I don't snore.
- You do, repeatedly.
Do I snore, John?
Yeah, you're
a window rattler, son.
That's just your opinion.
Do I snore, Paul?
With a trombone hooter
like yours...
it would be unnatural
if you didn't.
Now, Pauly,
don't mock the afflicted.
Oh, come off it.
It's only a joke.
Ah, it may be a joke,
but it's his nose.
He can't help havin'
a hideous great hooter...
the poor little head tremblin'
under the weight of it.
John, Paul, George, come here.
Get at it.
Hello, the income tax have
caught up with us at last.
- None for me, then?
- Sorry.
This'll keep you busy.
It's your nose, you know.
Fans are funny that way.
They take a dislike to things.
They'll pick on a nose.
- Ah, you pick on your own.
- Hey, here.
- Are those yours?
- No, they're for Ringo.
Must've cost you a fortune
in stamps, Ringo.
He comes from a large family.
Well...
What's Le Cirque Club?
"The management
of Le Cirque Club...
"takes pleasure
in requesting the company...
"of Mr. Richard Starkey..."
That's you.
"To their gaming rooms...
"chemin de fer, baccarat,
and champagne buffet."
- They want me?
- JOHN: You're a big spender.
- Well, you're not goin'.
- Aw.
Quite right.
Invites to gamblin' dens...
full of easy money
and fast women...
chicken sandwiches
and cornets of caviar.
Disgustin'.
- That's mine.
- Come on, you lot.
- Get your pens out.
- Why?
It's homework time for
you load of college puddings.
I want this lot
answered tonight.
- Yeah, right.
- I want to go out.
NORM:
Now, I'll brook no denial.
You couldn't get a pen
in your foot, you swine.
Oh, chatter on, son.
Chatter on.
A touch of the writer's cramp
will soon sort you out.
Come on, Shake.
- Ta ta, then.
- See ya.
[John humming and chuckling]
- Where are you goin', then?
- He told us to stay, didn't he?
- Come, men!
- Right.
[All mumbling]
Couldn't we get a taxi?
PAUL AND RINGO:
No, we couldn't get a taxi.
[Laughing]
- [Knock knock]
- Come in.
- I'll clear up, sir.
- Yeah.
♪ I wanna be your man ♪
♪ Tell me
that you love me, baby ♪
♪ Let me understand ♪
♪ Tell me
that you love me, baby ♪
♪ I wanna be your man ♪
♪ I wanna be your lover,
baby ♪
♪ I wanna be your man ♪
♪ I wanna be your lover,
baby ♪
♪ I wanna be your man ♪
Wow! Wow!
DEALER: Banco.
MAN: Banco. Suivais.
Banco.
WOMAN: Suivais.
Alors, monsieur.
Soufflé.
I bet you're a great swimmer.
My turn?
Bingo.
Pas bingo, monsieur.
Banco.
Ah, I'll take
the little darlings, anyway.
Two and one is three,
carry one is four.
Huit...
et sept.
♪ I can't believe that
she would leave me on my own ♪
♪ It's just not right when
every night I'm all alone ♪
♪ I've got no time
for you right now ♪
♪ Don't bother me ♪
♪ I know
I'll never be the same ♪
♪ If I don't
get her back again ♪
♪ Because I know
she'll always be ♪
♪ The only girl for me ♪
Bingo.
♪ Close your eyes,
and I'll kiss you ♪
♪ Tomorrow, I'll miss you ♪
♪ Remember
I'll always be true ♪
♪ And then while I'm away ♪
♪ I'll write home every day ♪
♪ And I'll send
all my lovin' to you ♪
♪ I'll pretend
that I'm kissing ♪
♪ The lips I am missing ♪
♪ And hope that my dreams
will come true ♪
♪ And then while I'm away ♪
♪ I'll write home every day ♪
♪ And I'll send
all my lovin' to you ♪
♪ All my lovin' ♪
♪ I will send to you ♪
♪ All my lovin',
darlin', I'll be true ♪
[No audio]
♪ Close your eyes,
and I'll kiss you ♪
♪ Tomorrow, I'll miss you ♪
♪ Remember
I'll always be true ♪
♪ And then while I'm away ♪
♪ I'll write home every day ♪
♪ And I'll send
all my lovin' to you ♪
[Voices in hallway]
The manager.
[All talking at once]
Now, come on, you lot.
Get on with it.
- We were gonna do 'em, but...
- Aye. Well, now, now, now.
Hey, any of you lot
put a man in the cupboard?
- A man?
- Don't be soft.
Well, somebody did.
He's right, you know.
There you go.
Hey, uh...
Hey, what's all this?
PAUL:
Oh, him. He's been lurking.
He looks a right lurker,
doesn't he?
You're undressed.
Where are your clothes?
The old gentleman.
He borrowed them to go gambling
at Le Cirque.
He's gone to my club, has he?
- Yeah! It's all your fault.
- RINGO: What?
Gettin' invites
to gambling clubs and all that.
He's probably in the middle
of some orgy by now.
JOHN:
An orgy? Orgy! Ha ha ha!
- But what about me?
- You're too old.
Encore de champagne, monsieur?
Oh, yeah. And I'll have
some more champagne, as well.
Lord John McCartney,
millionaire Irish peer.
Filthy rich, of course.
Well, I don't know.
He looks quite clean to me.
Come on, you lot. Try to act
with a bit of decorum.
This is a posh place.
JOHN: We know how to behave.
We've had lessons.
I'm sorry, sir.
Members and invited guests only.
- Aye. Well, uh...
- Oh, yes.
I'm with them.
I'm Ringo's sister.
Excuse me. Have you got
a little old man here?
Do you mean Lord McCartney?
Oh, he's at it again.
Look, I'm his grandfather.
I mean...
WOMAN: Oh, it must be
the dolly floor show.
GRANDFATHER:
Put me down!
Who are these ruffians?
I never saw them before.
MANAGER:
Before you go, gentlemen...
there's a little matter
of the bill.
I'll take care of that.
A hundred and eighty pounds?
I beg your pardon... guineas.
WAITER:
Your winnings, my lord... £190.
Ha!
- What about me change?
- Cloak room charge.
Ah, well, easy come, easy go.
Well?
Guten morgen, mein herr.
[Speaking German]
[Imitates engine rewing]
Ah, ze filthy Englander.
Guten morgen.
Keep Britain tidy.
- Aw, go on, George.
- Don't be ridiculous.
But you said I could.
Honestly, me mind boggles
at the very idea.
A grown man, and you haven't
shaved with a safety razor.
It's not my fault. I come from
a long line of electricians.
Well, you're not practicing
on me.
All right, then. But show us.
Oh, come on, then.
Aah hee hee ho!
Ooh.
[Gasps]
♪ Rule, Britannia,
Britannia rules the...  ♪
Put your tongue away.
It looks disgusting...
hanging there
all pink and naked.
- One slip of the razor, and...
- Ooh!
[John humming
Deutschland Uber Alles]
Help! Ich! Headphones! Help me!
[Blows bubbles] Help!
Torpedoed again, eh?
Come on, lads.
There's a car waiting
to take you to the studio.
- Hey, where's John?
- In the bath.
All right, Lennon,
let's have you.
Come on, John.
Stop larking about.
John? John?
What are you messing around
with that boat for?
There's a car waiting.
Come on.
Ready, John?
As soon as we draw up...
open that door and straight in.
[Shrieking]
We can't keep them waiting
much longer.
- I knew they'd be late.
- Oh, here they are.
- Boys, come on.
- Where have you been?
It's your press conference
we're arranging.
NORM: All right.
Give us a couple of shakes...
to get our breath, will you?
JOHN: Hey, I've got a suit
just like him, you know.
MAN: Ringo. Yeah.
I don't like the handkerchief.
I always have the handkerchief
in me trouser pocket.
You can't blow your nose on it
up there, can you, mister?
MAN: No, you can't.
[Crowd chattering]
REPORTER:
How about highbrow music?
GEORGE: I've always liked
that question.
JOHN: I never noted his nose
till about six months ago.
GEORGE: And me mother asked me
before we left for America...
if we wanted any sandwiches.
JOHN: And when I plugged her
in, she just blew up.
Tell me...
how did you find America?
Turn left at Greenland.
- Has success changed your life?
- Yes.
I'd like to keep Britain tidy.
- Are you a mod or a rocker?
- Um, no, I'm a mocker.
[Laughs] Oh.
Have you any hobbies?
No. Actually,
we're just good friends.
Do you think these haircuts
have come to stay?
Well, this one has, you know.
It's stuck on
good and proper now.
Frightfully nice.
What would you call
that hairstyle you're wearing?
Arthur.
No. Actually,
we're just good friends.
No, they're brown, aren't they?
What do you call that collar?
- Oh. A collar.
- Oh.
Do you often see your father?
No. Actually,
we're just good friends.
How do you like
your girlfriends to dress?
Ha ha!
- JOHN: What a drag that was.
- GEORGE: I'm starving.
Didn't even get
a jam butty, did you?
Anything left?
We've just finished, Pauly.
Hey, George, give us
your John Henry on that picture.
Hey, look at that.
Is that our set down there?
- Shall we go down, have a go?
- RINGO: Yeah.
- Trees and everything.
- A lot of fellas for one set.
Look, it's a bird.
Just passing through, like.
- Where are they?
- On the stage, down here.
[Chattering]
[Hits cymbal]
Leave them drums alone.
MAN: Oh, surely I could
just have a little touch.
You so much as
breathe heavy on them...
and I'm out on strike.
Aren't you being
rather arbitrary?
There you go,
hiding behind a smoke screen...
of bourgeois cliches.
I don't go messing about
with your earphones, do I?
- Spoilsport.
- Well?
He's very fussy
about his drums, you know.
They loom large in his legend.
- What's up?
- Oh, he's sulking again.
JOHN:
Ha ha ha! I'll show him.
♪ If I fell in love with you ♪
♪ Would you promise
to be true ♪
♪ And help me ♪
♪ Understand ♪
♪ 'Cause I've been in love
before ♪
♪ And I found
that love was more ♪
♪ Than just holding hands ♪
♪ If I give my heart ♪
♪ To you ♪
♪ I must be sure ♪
♪ From the very start ♪
♪ That you ♪
♪ Would love me more than her ♪
♪ If I trust in you ♪
♪ Oh, please ♪
♪ Don't run and hide ♪
♪ If I love you, too ♪
♪ Oh, please ♪
♪ Don't hurt my pride
like her ♪
♪ 'Cause I couldn't stand
the pain ♪
♪ And l ♪
♪ Would be sad
if our new love ♪
♪ Was in vain ♪
♪ So I hope you'll see ♪
♪ That l ♪
♪ Would love to love you ♪
♪ And that she ♪
♪ Will cry ♪
♪ When she learns we are two ♪
♪ 'Cause I couldn't stand
the pain ♪
♪ And l ♪
♪ Would be sad
if our new love ♪
♪ Was in vain ♪
♪ So I hope you see ♪
♪ That l ♪
♪ Would love to love you ♪
♪ And that she ♪
♪ Will cry ♪
♪ When she learns we are two ♪
♪ If I fell in love with you ♪
Pardon me. Excuse me. Pardon me.
More... I'd like more drums there.
- No. I think it's on that...
- It sounds like a...
On the third bit.
You know, on the third bit.
Third bit, more bang.
[Plays]
Right. Let's hear no more
about it. You're probably right.
Now, look...
if you think I'm unsuitable,
let's have it out in the open.
I can't stand
these backstage politics.
Aren't you tending to black and
white the situation somewhat?
Well, quite honestly, I wasn't
expecting a musical arranger...
to question my ability
picture-wise.
I could listen to him for hours.
What's all this
about a musical arranger?
Mr. McCartney Senior.
Hey, Paulie,
they're trying to fob you off...
with this musical charlatan,
but I gave him the test.
DIRECTOR: I'm quite happy
to be replaced.
GRANDFATHER:
He's a typical buck-passer.
- I won an award.
- JOHN: A likely story.
It's on the wall in my office.
Hello, our lot.
Everybody happy?
NORM: All right, all right.
If you don't need them...
I'll lock them up
in the dressing room.
Please do. I'll not need them
for half an hour.
Thank you.
Get me a bottle of milk
and some tranquilizers.
I see it all now.
It's a plot... a plot.
Tranquilizers.
Come back, you lot.
I've got the key.
Come back, Ringo.
Uhh.
- Hello.
- Come on.
Leslie Jackson?
I saw your father...
in the old empire
in nineteen hundred and nine.
Ah, if you're as good as him,
son, you're all right.
Gear costume.
- Swap?
- Cheeky.
NORM: Come, lads. First door,
and no messing about.
Lennon, put them girls down,
or I'll tell your mother of you.
NORM:
And stop messing about.
Stay in here
until that rehearsal.
I'm going to keep you in,
even if I have to put...
the lock in the key
and turn it.
We're out!
♪ Can't buy me love ♪
♪ Love ♪
♪ I'll buy you
a diamond ring, my friend ♪
♪ If it makes you feel
all right ♪
♪ I'll get you anything,
my friend ♪
♪ If it makes you feel
all right ♪
♪ 'Cause I don't care
too much for money ♪
♪ Money can't buy me love ♪
♪ I'll give you
all I've got to give ♪
♪ If you say
you love me, too ♪
♪ I may not have
a lot to give ♪
♪ But what I got
I'll give to you ♪
♪ I don't care too much
for money ♪
♪ Money can't buy me love ♪
♪ Can't buy me love ♪
♪ Everybody tells me so ♪
♪ No, no, no, no ♪
♪ Say you don't need
no diamond rings ♪
♪ And I'll be satisfied ♪
♪ Tell me that you want
the kind of things ♪
♪ That money just can't buy ♪
♪ I don't care too much
for money ♪
♪ Money can't buy me love ♪
♪ Ow!  ♪
♪ Can't buy me love ♪
♪ Everybody tells me so ♪
♪ No, no, no, no ♪
♪ Say you don't need
no diamond rings ♪
♪ And I'll be satisfied ♪
♪ Tell me that you want
the kind of things ♪
♪ That money just can't buy ♪
♪ I don't care too much
for money ♪
♪ Money can't buy me love ♪
♪ Can't buy me love ♪
♪ Love ♪
MAN: I suppose you realize
this is private property.
Sorry we hurt your field,
mister.
Not here. Hello, Dicky.
Probably gone to the canteen...
cup of tea, like.
No, that's too easy for Lennon.
He's out there somewhere...
causing trouble
just to upset me.
You're imagining it, Norm.
You're letting it
prey on your mind.
No. This is a battle of nerves
between John and me.
But John hasn't got any.
- What?
- Nerves.
No.
That's just the trouble.
I've toyed with the idea
of a ball and chain...
but he'd just rattle them
at me... and in public, too.
Sometimes I think he enjoys
seeing me suffer.
- Hello.
- Wait a minute. Don't tell me...
- No, I'm not.
- Oh, you are.
- I'm not.
- Oh, you are. I know you are.
- I'm not. No.
- You look just like him.
- Do I?
You're the first one
that's said that ever.
Yes, you do. Look.
- No. Me eyes are lighter.
- Excuse me.
All right, noddy.
- Oh, yes. Your nose is, very.
- Me nose.
- Is it?
- Well, I would've said so.
Oh, you know him better, though.
I do not.
He's only a casual acquaintance.
- That's what you say.
- What have you heard?
- It's all over the place.
- Is it? Is it really?
Mmm, but I wouldn't have it.
I stuck up for you.
- I knew I could rely on you.
- Thanks.
You don't look like him at all.
She looks more like him
than I do.
P.A. ; There will be
a full rehearsal...
in ten minutes time.
Ten minutes from now,
a full rehearsal.
DOLLY:
Oh, there you are.
Oh, sorry.
Must've made a mistake.
No, you haven't.
You're just late.
I am?
Actually, I think he'll be
very pleased with you.
Will he?
DOLLY: Yes. You're quite
a feather in the cap.
Hello?
I've got one.
Oh, I think so.
Yes, he can talk.
DOLLY: Well, I think
you ought to see him.
Yes. All right.
Come on.
GEORGE: Sorry.
You don't see many of these
nowadays, do you?
[Rattles]
DOLLY: Come on.
Simon, will this do?
Oh, not bad, Dolly...
not really bad.
Turn around, chickie baby.
SIMON:
Oh, yes, he's a definite poss.
He'll look good
alongside Susan.
All right, Sonny Jim, this is
all going to be quite painless.
Don't breathe on me, Adrian.
GEORGE:
I'm terribly sorry...
but there seems to be
some sort of misunderstanding.
Oh, you can come off it
with us.
You don't have to do the old
adenoidal glottal stop...
and carry on for our benefit.
I'm afraid I don't understand.
Oh, my God. He's a natural.
Well, I did tell them
not to send us real ones.
They ought to know the phonies
are much easier to handle.
Still, he's a good type.
We'd like you to give us
your opinion...
on some clothes for teenagers.
Oh, by all means.
I'd be quite prepared
for that eventuality.
Well, not your real opinion,
naturally.
It'll be written out,
and you'll learn it.
- Can he read?
- Of course I can.
I mean lines, ducky.
Can you handle lines?
- Well, I'll have a bash.
- Good.
Give him whatever it is
they drink. A coke-a-rama?
Ta.
Well, at least he's polite.
Show him the shirts, Adrian.
SIMON:
Now, you'll like these.
You'll really dig them.
They're fab and
all the other pimply hyperboles.
I wouldn't be seen dead in them.
They're dead grotty.
- Grotty?
- Yeah, grotesque.
Make a note of that word
and give it to Susan.
It's rather touching, really.
Here's this kid...
trying to give me
his utterly valueless opinion...
when I know for a fact
that within a month...
he'll be suffering from
a violent inferiority complex...
and loss of status...
because he isn't wearing
one of these nasty things.
Of course they're grotty,
you wretched nit.
That's why they were designed,
but that's what you'll want.
I won't.
You can be replaced,
chickie baby.
I don't care.
And that pose is out, too,
Sonny Jim.
The new thing is to care
passionately and be right wing.
Anyway, if you don't cooperate,
you won't meet Susan.
And who's this Susan
when she's at home?
Only Susan Campy
our resident teenager.
You'll have to love her.
She's your symbol.
Oh, you mean that posh bird
who gets everything wrong?
I beg your pardon.
Oh, yeah, the lads frequently
sit round the television...
and watch her for a giggle.
In fact, once we all sat down
and wrote these letters...
saying how gear she was
and all that rubbish.
She's a trendsetter.
It's her profession.
She's a drag...
a well-known drag.
We turn the sound down on her
and say rude things.
- Get him out of here.
- Have I said something amiss?
Get him out. He's knocking
the program's image.
- Sorry about the shirts.
- Get him out!
You don't think
he's a new phenomenon, do you?
You mean an early clue
to the new direction?
[Snaps fingers]
Where's the calendar?
Oh, no, no, no. It's all right.
He's just a troublemaker.
The change isn't due
for three weeks yet.
All the same, make a note
not to extend Susan's contract.
And let's not take
any unnecessary chances, hmm?
[Singing in German]
[Singing continues]
So I explained to my mother
that he was a very clean man.
She was quite pleased.
[Chorus singing in German]
[Footsteps]
- NORM: There's no one here.
- SHAKE: No one here?
SHAKE:
Well, where have they gone?
[Motor revs]
[Man and woman singing
long high note]
[Both sing and stop]
That's wrong, isn't it?
Surely, that's wrong.
No, not you.
DIRECTOR OVER P.A. ;
Get him out!
[Voices in corridor]
There's someone coming.
Quick, hide.
Stop being taller than me.
- It's not my fault...
- Shh!
JOHN: Ha ha ha ha!
- What are you doing here?
- Hiding.
You must be soft or something.
Well, we weren't hiding.
We were resting.
I thought I told you lot
to stop here.
RINGO: Well?
When I say stay put,
I mean stay put.
Don't cane me, sir.
I was led astray.
Oh, shut up, John. They're
waiting for you in the studio.
Gear.
I'm dying to do a bit of work.
NORM:
Well, God bless you, Ringo.
- Oh, listen to teacher's pet.
- Crawler.
- Betrayed the class, eh?
- Aw, lay off.
- Temper, temper.
- Well?
Will you get a move on?
They're waiting for you.
Sorry.
[Woman's voice] I now declare
this bridge open.
DIRECTOR:
Where are they, hmm?
Where are they?
- They're coming.
- Hmm?
They're coming, I promise you.
Ah, yes, well...
if they aren't on this floor
in thirty seconds...
there'll be trouble,
understand me?
Trouble.
Standing about, eh?
Some people have it dead easy.
Once you're over thirty,
you're past it.
It's a young man's medium.
I just can't stand the pace.
- Oh, you're as young as that?
- I was.
JOHN: Ah, there he goes.
Look at him.
I bet his wife
doesn't know about her.
He hasn't even got a wife.
Look at his sweater.
PAUL: [Laughs] You never know.
She might've knitted it.
JOHN:
She's knitted him.
DIRECTOR: Right. Standby.
Run through a number...
and try not to jiggle
out of position.
Hello, three? Coming to you.
Three.
Three, coming to you. Three.
- MAN: We're on three.
- What?
- We're on three.
- Oh, yes.
DIRECTOR: Uh, music.
♪ I give her all my love ♪
♪ That's all I do ♪
♪ And if you saw my love ♪
♪ You'd love her, too ♪
♪ I love her ♪
♪ She gives me everything ♪
♪ And tenderly ♪
♪ The kiss my lover brings ♪
♪ She brings to me ♪
♪ And I love her ♪
♪ A love like ours ♪
♪ Could never die ♪
♪ As long as l ♪
♪ Have you near me ♪
♪ Bright are the stars
that shine ♪
♪ Dark is the sky ♪
♪ I know this love of mine ♪
♪ Will never die ♪
♪ And I love her ♪
♪ Bright are the stars
that shine ♪
♪ Dark is the sky ♪
♪ I know this love of mine ♪
♪ Will never die ♪
♪ And I love her ♪
DIRECTOR:
Thank you. Very nice.
Makeup?
No, not really.
They don't need any.
They'll just powder them off
for the shine.
Oh, well, yes. Norm, would
you take them down to makeup...
and powder them off...
the shine.
Sure.
You blinked.
- NORM: Come on. Come in.
- Hello, lads.
Hey, your grandfather's
not talking to me.
I think he's got a sulk on.
It must be catching on.
He's given it to Ringo here.
Stop picking on him, George.
I don't need you to protect me,
you know, Norm.
Got a touch of the swine fever,
haven't you?
- No. Come on, lads. Sit down.
- This is impossible.
- We'll never get them all done.
- Then do us first.
It doesn't matter to them
whether they're made up or not.
By the way, what's that?
My name's Betty.
Do you want a punch
up your frogged tunic?
No.
John, behave yourself,
or I'll murder you.
Shake, take that wig off.
It suits you.
- Ringo, what are you up to?
- Page five.
You always fancied yourself
as a guardsman, didn't you?
Oh, that this too, too solid
flesh would melt.
Zap!
Hey, you won't interfere with
the basic rugged concept...
of me personality,
will you, madam?
Hey, he's reading the Queen.
That's an in-joke, you know.
Shazam!
It's my considered opinion
that you're a bunch of sissies.
- You're just jealous.
- Leave him alone, Lennon...
or I'll tell them all
the truth about you.
- You wouldn't.
- Oh, I would, though.
I thought I was supposed to be
getting a change of scenery...
and so far, I've been
in a train and a room...
and a car and a room
and a room and a room.
Well, maybe
that's all right...
for a bunch of powdered
geegaws like you lot...
but I'm feeling decidedly
straight-jacketed.
What a clean old man.
Ah, don't press your luck.
JOHN:
He's sex obsessed.
The older generation
are leading this country...
to galloping ruin.
What's a pretty girl like you
doing in a place like this?
They're nearly ready for you.
Just finishing the band call.
[Piano music playing]
I say, did you go to Harrods?
I was there in '58, you know.
- I can get you on the stage.
- Oh, how?
You turn right here
at the corridor...
and go past the fireplace.
Ah, I don't like yours.
[Piano playing I'm Happy
Just to Dance With You]
[Plays along]
JOHN:
Hey, kids, I got an idea.
Well, why don't we do
the show right here? Yeah!
[Laughs]
JOHN: Two, three, four.
♪ Before
this dance is through ♪
♪ I think I'll love you, too ♪
♪ I'm so happy
when you dance with me ♪
♪ I don't want to kiss
or hold your hand ♪
♪ If it's funny,
try and understand ♪
♪ There is really
nothing else I'd rather do ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm happy
just to dance with you ♪
♪ I don't need to hug
or hold you tight ♪
♪ I just want to dance
with you all night ♪
♪ In this world there's nothing
I would rather do ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm happy
just to dance with you ♪
♪ Just to dance with you ♪
♪ Is everything I need ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ Before this dance
is through ♪
♪ I think I'll love you, too ♪
♪ I'm so happy
when you dance with me ♪
♪ If somebody tries
to take my place ♪
♪ Let's pretend
we just can't see his face ♪
♪ In this world there's
nothing I would rather do ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm happy
just to dance with you ♪
♪ Just to dance with you ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Is everything I need ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ Before this dance
is through ♪
♪ I think I'll love you, too ♪
♪ I'm so happy
when you dance with me ♪
♪ If somebody tries
to take my place ♪
♪ Let's pretend
we just can't see his face ♪
♪ In this world there's nothing
I would rather do ♪
♪ I've discovered
I'm in love with you ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm happy
just to dance with you ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh ♪
JOHN: Oh.
Very good, that, George.
- Oh.
Well, we're trying.
JOHN: Yeah, keep trying.
Let's go. Come on.
NORM:
That was great, lads.
Now, you've got about an hour,
but don't leave the theater.
Where are you going, John?
She's going to show me
her stamp collection.
PAUL: So's mine.
NORM:
John, I'm talking to you.
This final run-through
is important, understand?
Important.
[Oink oink]
- I want a cup of tea.
- Uh, Shake?
I've got to adjust the decibels
on the inbalance, Norm.
Clever. George?
Ringo,
look after him, will you?
- Oh, hey, Norm.
- Do I have to raise my voice?
All right. Come on, granddad.
I'm a drummer,
not a wet nurse, you know.
GRANDFATHER:
Would you look at him...
sitting there with his hooter
scraping away at that book.
Well, what's the matter
with that?
Have you no natural resources
of your own?
Have they even robbed you
of that?
- You can learn from books.
- You can, can you?
Ahh. Sheeps' heads.
You could learn more by
getting out there and living.
- Out where?
- Any old where.
But not our little Richard.
Oh, no.
When you're not thumping
them pagan skins...
you're tormenting your eyes
with that rubbish.
- Books are good.
- Parading's better.
Parading?
Parading the streets...
trailing your coat,
bowling along... living!
- Well, I am living.
- You? Living?
When was the last time
you gave a girl...
a pink-edged daisy?
When did you last
embarrass a Sheila...
with your cool
appraising stare?
You're a bit old for
that sort of chat, aren't you?
Well, at least
I've got a backlog of memories.
All you've got is that book.
Ah, stop picking on me. You're
as bad as the rest of them.
Ah, so you are a man
after all.
What's that mean?
Do you think I haven't noticed?
Do you think I wasn't aware
of the drift?
You poor, unfortunate scruff.
They've driven you
into books...
with their cruel,
unnatural treatment...
exploiting your good nature.
I don't know.
Ah, that lot's never happier
unless they're jeering you.
And where would they be...
without the steady support
of your drum beat?
That's what I'd like to know.
Yeah. That's right.
And what's it all come to
in the end?
Yeah.
What's in it for me?
A book.
Yeah, a bloomin' book.
When you could be out there...
betraying
a rich American widow...
or sipping palm wine in Tahiti
before you're too old like me.
Yeah, funny, really,
'cause I never thought...
but being
middle-aged and old...
takes up most of your time,
doesn't it?
You're only right.
Where are you going?
I'm going parading
before it's too late.
Hey, Ringo, you know
what just happened to me?
No, I don't.
You ought to stop
looking so scornful.
It's twisting your face.
Tell him of the story about...
Hello, here he is,
the middle-aged boy wonder.
I thought you were
looking after the old man.
We've only got half an hour
to the final run-through.
He can't walk out on us now.
Can't he?
He's done it, son.
- Hey, you know what happened?
- We know.
Your grandfather.
He's stirred him up.
He hasn't.
Yeah, he... he filled his head
with notions seemingly.
The old mixer. Come on,
we'll have to put him right.
P.A. ; Coming up, all dancers
onstage for rehearsal, please.
JOHN:
Split up and look for him.
We've become a limited company.
I'll look in here again.
[This Boy playing]
- Aah!
- Hello there.
- Get out of it, shorty.
Hey, you should
have more sense...
than to go around
chucking bricks about.
Southerner.
Here, mate. That's my hoop.
Stop playing with it.
Hoop? That isn't a hoop.
It's a lethal weapon.
- Have you got a license for it?
- Oh, don't be so stroppy.
Well, a boy your age
rolling hoops at people.
- How old are you, anyway?
- Eleven.
- I bet you're only 101/2.
- 102/3.
There you are, then,
and don't be rolling at people.
Oh, you can have it. I'm
packing it in. It depresses me.
- Y'what?
- You heard. It gets on my wick.
That's lovely talk, that is.
And why aren't you at school?
- I'm a deserter.
- Are you now?
- Yeah, I've blown school out.
- Just you?
No, Ginger, Eddy Fallon,
and Ding Dong.
- Oh, Ding Dong bell, eh?
- Yeah, that's right.
They was supposed to come
with us, but they chickened.
RINGO: Yeah? And they're
your mates, are they?
Yeah.
RINGO: Not much cop
without 'em, is it?
- Oh, it's all right.
- Yeah? What are they like?
BOY: Ginger's mad.
He says things all the time.
And Eddy's good
at spitting and punching.
Yeah?
How about Ding Dong?
Oh, he's a big head.
He fancies himself, you know.
He's all right, though,
'cause he's one of the gang.
Hmm.
- Why aren't you at work?
- I'm a deserter, too.
- Oh.
- Hey, Charlie!
See ya!
MAN: Come in, number seven.
Your time's up.
I'm sorry, boys.
I didn't mean it, honest.
If he says that again,
I'll strike him.
Oh, don't worry. They're
good lads. They'll be back.
Well, we've only twenty minutes
to the final run-through.
I meant no harm.
I was only trying to encourage
little Ringo to enjoy himself.
God knows what you've unleashed
on the unsuspecting south.
It'll be wine, women, and song
all the way with Ringo...
when he gets the taste for it.
That was fresh this morning.
Two and nine.
[Parrot screeching]
- Right. On your way.
- You what?
You heard. On your way.
Troublemaker!
Hey, watch it!
- Shake.
- What?
Worry, will you?
Well, that's it. Two minutes
to the final run-through.
- They're bound to miss it now.
- I'll murder that Lennon.
We could survive a missed
run-through as long as they...
SHAKE: As long as
they end up for the show?
Oh, you're right there.
I mean, it wouldn't do...
to miss the show,
like, would it?
NORM: Shut up, cheerful.
You don't think...
Oh, oh, oh no.
- Now, look, don't worry.
- They can't do this to me, no.
It's all your fault.
Oh, yes, it is.
If they don't turn up
I wouldn't be in your shoes...
For all the tea in China.
Oh, you're right there.
Neither would it.
- You dirty traitor.
- Well, of course.
Yes, of course.
BEATLES:? I have been working
like a dog ♪
- Hello.
- Hi, John. John!
- Did you want something?
- I could eat the lot of you.
You'd look great
with an apple in your gob.
Do you realize you could have
missed the final run-through?
Oh, we're sorry about that.
Norm?
There's only three of 'em.
Oh, we were
looking for Ringo...
but we realized
he must've come back here.
Well, do you realize
that we are on the air live...
in front of an audience
in forty-five minutes...
and you're one short?
JOHN: Control yourself,
or you'll spurt.
He must be here somewhere.
Aye, well, we'll look
in the dressing room.
- Shake.
- Yes, the dressing room.
Hey, where's my grandfather?
Don't worry about him, Paul.
He can look after himself.
I suppose so.
Personally signed
and handwritten...
by your own sweet boys.
- The chance of a lifetime!
- [Fans screaming]
Be the envy
of your less fortunate sisters!
GRANDFATHER: Oh, me bones.
All right, break it up.
Break it up. Move on.
Hey, what's going on here?
Right, move over. Move over.
- Come on, move along.
- Here you are.
Why don't you go back home?
You're making a disturbance.
Will you just move along now?
[Indistinct arguing]
Come on, ya. Aah! Yeahh!
[Ringo humming]
Thank you.
[Humming]
- [Whistles]
- Gotcha!
You nasty little person, you.
RINGO:
Come on! Ooh, yeah.
I'm Ringo Starr.
I've got a show to do.
I'm on in a few minutes.
You've got to let me go.
I'm Ringo.
Yeah, that's what
they all say these days.
Look, I don't care who you are.
You can save that
for the stipendiary.
- Here you are, sarge.
- All right. What is he?
Yeah, I got a little list here.
Wandering abroad,
malicious intent...
acting
in a suspicious manner...
conduct liable to cause
a breach of the peace.
OFFICER:
You name it, he's done it.
Oh, a little savage, is he?
Yeah, a proper
little aborigine.
- I demand to see my solicitor.
- What's his name?
Well, if you're gonna
get technical about it.
GRANDFATHER: Dragging me
through the streets...
Hello, it's gonna be
one of those nights, is it?
Sit Charlie Peace down
over there, will you?
Well, you got me here,
so do your worst...
but, by God,
I'll take one of you with me.
- Ow!
- I know your game!
Get me into that tiled room and
then out come the rubber hoses.
Oh, there's a fire, is there?
You ugly great brute.
You have sadism...
stamped all over
your bloated British kisser.
- Eh?
- I'll go on hunger strike.
I know your caper.
The kidney punch
and the rabbit clout.
The third degree and
the size twelve boot ankle tap.
What's he on about?
GRANDFATHER: I'm a soldier
of the republic.
You'll need the mahogany
truncheon on this boyo.
♪ A nation once again ♪
Get Lloyd George over there...
next to the mechanic
in the cloth cap...
while I sort this lot out,
will you?
OFFICER: Come on, dad.
Sit down over here.
Ringo, me old scout!
So they grabbed your leg
for the iron, too, have they?
I'm not exactly
a voluntary patient.
Shh, shh.
Have they roughed you up yet?
What?
Oh, they're a desperate crew
of drippings...
and they've fists
like matured hams...
for pounding poor
defenseless lads like you.
Right, that's it, then.
GRANDFATHER:
One of us has got to escape.
I'll get the boys.
- Hold on. I'll be back for you.
- For me?
If they get you on the floor,
watch out for your brisket.
They seem all right to me.
Ah, sure, that's what
they want you to think.
All coppers are villains.
SERGEANT: Would you two
like a cup of tea?
See? Sly villains.
Um, no, thank you,
Mr. Sergeant, sir.
No, not for me. Please don't.
So you just
brought the old chap...
out of the crowd
for his own good, eh?
Well, he was getting
a bit nasty, you see...
so we had to bring him in.
Well, he can't stop here.
This is the stuff
he's been hawking around, eh?
- Yes, sergeant... photographs.
- Photographs.
Well, son, it's now or never.
All right, you paid assassins!
Johnny McCartney...
will give you a run
for your thruppence halfpenny.
Hey, you forgot
your photographs.
Only half an hour,
and you're on.
- Can I say something?
- Yes. Anything.
It seems highly unlikely
we'll be on.
I mean, the law of averages
are against it.
I think if you could
get the juggler on...
with a couple more clubs...
that would fill in
a bit of time.
Come on, let's go!
I'll have the hides
off of you lot.
[Laughing]
You ought to be ashamed
of yourself. Go home.
I must see Pauly.
Go home, then,
and see him on the telly.
- Can you fix him for me?
- Yeah.
Sixpence.
- Each.
- In advance.
Mercenaries.
[Laughing]
It's all right.
Leave him alone.
P.A. ; What's up, Richard?
GRANDFATHER:
Paul? Where are you? I'm...
PAUL:
Granddad. Where's Ringo?
The police have the poor lad
in the bridewell.
- The police station.
- He'll be pulp by now.
- NORM: Go get him!
- PAUL: We'll get him out.
- JOHN: We'll fix it, Norm.
- [Beatles barking]
We've only got twenty minutes.
♪ Can't buy me love ♪
♪ Love ♪
♪ I'll buy you a diamond ring,
my friend ♪
♪ If it makes you feel
all right ♪
♪ I'll get you anything,
my friend ♪
♪ If it makes you feel
all right ♪
♪ 'Cause I don't care
too much for money ♪
♪ Money can't buy me love ♪
♪ I'll give you
all I've got to give ♪
♪ If you say
you'll love me, too ♪
♪ I may not have
a lot to give ♪
♪ But what I got
I'll give to you ♪
♪ I don't care too much
for money ♪
♪ Money can't buy me love ♪
♪ Can't buy me love ♪
♪ Everybody tells me so ♪
♪ No, no, no, no ♪
♪ Say you don't need
no diamond rings ♪
♪ And I'll be satisfied ♪
♪ Tell me that you want
the kind of things ♪
♪ That money just can't buy ♪
♪ I don't care too much
for money ♪
♪ Money can't buy me love ♪
What is all this?
[Panting] Hold on
till we catch our breath.
Fine.
Are you all right now?
[Pants] Yeah.
- Huh?
- See.
♪ Can't buy me love ♪
♪ Everybody tells me so ♪
♪ No, no, no, no ♪
♪ Say you don't need
no diamond rings ♪
♪ And I'll be satisfied ♪
♪ Tell me that you want
the kind of things ♪
Quick! Follow them!
♪ That money just can't buy ♪
♪ I don't care too much
for money ♪
♪ Money can't buy me love ♪
♪ Can't buy me love ♪
♪ Love ♪
♪ Oh ♪
[Screaming]
I had to laugh even when
they kick the stool away.
[Giggles]
Lads. Lads! You're back!
Thank goodness. Where's Ringo?
- There he is. We got him.
- Great, great, great.
You don't know
what this means to me.
If you hadn't come back,
it would have meant...
the epilogue
or news in Welsh for life.
Hey, aren't you
supposed to be in that box?
- Yeah, where's the old mixer?
- Here, Pauly.
Got a few words to say to you,
two-faced John McCartney.
Aw, leave him alone.
He's back, isn't he?
- It's not his fault he's old.
- What's old got to do with it?
He's a troublemaker and a mixer.
That's good enough for me.
You're right. He's only asking
for attention, aren't you?
You see, you know your trouble.
You should've gone west
to America.
You would've been
a senior citizen of Boston.
But you took a wrong turn,
and what happened?
You're a lonely old man
from Liverpool.
- But I'm clean.
- Are you?
- Hey, Norm.
- What?
I've been thinking.
- It's not my fault.
- What isn't?
I'm not taller than you are.
You're smaller than I am.
Anyone at home?
Hey, Shake, where's me boot?
Will you get us some tea
while you're there?
- All right, George.
- Ta.
- Come on, lads. Get changed.
- Come on, get some tea.
[Overlapping conversation]
[Screaming]
♪ Tell me why you cried ♪
♪ And why you lied to me ♪
♪ Well, I gave you
everything I had ♪
♪ But you left me
sitting on my own ♪
♪ Did you have to treat me,
oh, so bad?  ♪
♪ All I do is hang my head
and moan ♪
♪ Tell me why you cried ♪
♪ And why you lied to me ♪
♪ If it's something
that I've said or done ♪
♪ Tell me what
and I'll apologize ♪
♪ If you don't
I really can't go on ♪
♪ Holding back
these tears in my eyes ♪
♪ Tell me why you cried ♪
♪ And why you lied to me ♪
♪ Well, I'm begging
on my bended knees ♪
♪ If you'll only
listen to my pleas ♪
♪ If there's anything
I can do ♪
♪ 'Cause
I really can't stand it ♪
♪ I'm so in love with you ♪
♪ If I give my heart ♪
♪ To you ♪
♪ I must be sure ♪
♪ From the very start ♪
♪ That you ♪
♪ Would love me more than her ♪
♪ If I trust in you ♪
♪ Oh, please ♪
♪ Don't run and hide ♪
♪ If I love you, too ♪
♪ Oh, please ♪
♪ Don't hurt my pride
like her ♪
♪ 'Cause I couldn't stand
the pain ♪
♪ And l ♪
♪ Would be sad
if our new love ♪
♪ Was in vain ♪
♪ So I hope you see ♪
♪ That l ♪
♪ Would love to love you ♪
♪ And that she ♪
♪ Will cry ♪
♪ When she learns we are two ♪
♪ 'Cause I couldn't stand
the pain ♪
♪ And l ♪
♪ Would be sad
if our new love ♪
♪ Was in vain ♪
♪ So I hope you see ♪
♪ That l ♪
♪ Would love to love you ♪
♪ And that she ♪
♪ Will cry ♪
♪ When she learns we are two ♪
♪ I...  ♪
♪ Should have known better
with a girl like you ♪
♪ That I would love
everything that you do ♪
♪ And I do ♪
♪ Hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ Whoa, whoa, I...  ♪
♪ Never realized
what a kiss could be ♪
♪ This could only
happen to me ♪
♪ Can't you see ♪
♪ That when I tell you
that I love you ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ You're gonna say
you love me, too ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ And when I ask you
to be mine ♪
♪ You're gonna say
you love me, too ♪
♪ So, oh, I...  ♪
♪ Should have realized
a lot of things before ♪
♪ If this is love
you gotta give me more ♪
♪ Give me more ♪
♪ Hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ Whoa, whoa, I...  ♪
♪ Never realized
what a kiss could be ♪
♪ This could only
happen to me ♪
♪ Can't you see ♪
♪ That when I tell you
that I love you ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ You're gonna say
you love me, too ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ And when I ask you
to be mine ♪
♪ You're gonna say
you love me, too ♪
♪ You love me, too ♪
[Screaming]
♪ She loves you,
yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ You think
you've lost your love ♪
♪ Well, I saw her yesterday ♪
♪ It's you she's thinking of?
♪ And she told me
what to say ♪
♪ She said she loves you ♪
♪ And you know
that can't be bad ♪
♪ Yeah, she loves you ♪
♪ And you know
you should be glad ♪
♪ She said you hurt her so ♪
♪ She almost lost her mind ♪
♪ But now she says she knows ♪
♪ You're not the hurting kind ♪
♪ She said she loves you ♪
♪ And you know
that can't be bad ♪
♪ Yeah, she loves you ♪
♪ And you know
you should be glad ♪
♪ Whoo ♪
♪ She loves you,
yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ With a love like that ♪
♪ You know you should be glad ♪
♪ You know it's up to you ♪
♪ I think it's only fair ♪
♪ Pride can hurt you, too ♪
♪ Apologize to her ♪
♪ Because she loves you ♪
♪ And you know
that can't be bad ♪
♪ She loves you ♪
♪ And you know
you should be glad ♪
♪ Whoo ♪
♪ She loves you,
yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ With a love like that ♪
♪ You know
you should be glad ♪
♪ With a love like that ♪
♪ You know
you should be glad ♪
♪ With a love like that ♪
♪ You know you should ♪
♪ Be glad ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
[Audience screaming]
Now, I've got the stuff.
Come here, lads.
- Aren't we going...
- No, we're not.
The office has been on
the phone and think it's best...
if we push on to Wolverhampton
straight away.
- Tonight? We'll never make it.
- You've got a midnight matinee.
Aye, Norm!
There's only one thing I've got
to say to you, John Lennon.
- What?
- You're a swine.
♪ It's been
a hard day's night ♪
♪ And I've been working
like a dog ♪
♪ It's been
a hard day's night ♪
♪ I should be sleeping
like a log ♪
♪ But when I get home to you ♪
Come on,
you're hanging up the parade!
Get rid of those things!
♪ You know I work all day ♪
♪ To get you money
to buy you things ♪
♪ And it's worth it
just to hear you say ♪
♪ You're gonna give me
everything ♪
♪ So why on earth
should I moan ♪
♪ 'Cause
when I get you alone ♪
♪ You know I feel OK ♪
♪ When I'm home ♪
♪ Everything
seems to be right ♪
♪ When I'm home ♪
♪ Feeling you
holding me tight ♪
♪ Tight, yeah ♪
♪ It's been
a hard day's night ♪
♪ And I've been working
like a dog ♪
♪ It's been
a hard day's night ♪
♪ I should be sleeping
like a log ♪
♪ But when I get home to you ♪
♪ I find
the things that you do ♪
♪ Will make me
feel all right ♪
♪ Aah ♪
♪ So why on earth
should I moan ♪
♪ 'Cause
when I get you alone ♪
♪ You know I feel OK ♪
♪ When I'm home ♪
♪ Everything
seems to be right ♪
♪ When I'm home ♪
♪ Feeling you
holding me tight ♪
♪ Tight, yeah ♪
♪ It's been
a hard day's night ♪
♪ And I've been working
like a dog ♪
♪ It's been
a hard day's night ♪
♪ I should be sleeping
like a log ♪
♪ But when I get home to you ♪
♪ I find
the things that you do ♪
♪ Will make me feel
all right ♪
♪ You know I feel all right ♪