- Code message, sir.
- Thanks.
- Harper, code message.
- Yes, sir.
All right, fellas, everything
clear now to the pilots?
- Major Roberts.
- Yes, Quincannon?
- Gonna use the radio beam all the way, sir?
- Yes.
To keep a double check, flight
leaders will work Hickam radio control...
while the other planes work the
home station. How about the navigators?
- One question, sir.
- How soon...?
- Sorry.
- Hauser?
How soon will we get our maps
and tracks from Group Operation, sir?
Anytime you want them. You'll
be given the route weather
forecast soon as it's finished.
- Wendell?
- That's what I wanted to know, sir.
Are there any questions
from the bombardiers?
- Major Roberts, sir.
- Parker.
- What about ammunition?
- No ammunition.
- Yes, McMartin?
- Are we taking bombsights along, sir?
We're ferrying them fully
equipped, except for ammunition.
The maintenance crews are
working on them now, so you pilots
can check with them to be
sure everything's in shape.
- And Harper, you'll check for us.
- Yes, sir.
I guess that's all for now.
Oh, yes. The crews haven't been told yet
what the destination is, so keep it quiet.
- Anything else?
- How about phoning our wives, sir?
Evidently your copilot doesn't
take you into his confidence.
He got permission this morning
to send a radiogram to Lt.
McMartin's sister in Honolulu.
I thought that might interest you,
McMartin.
- Yes, sir.
- Well, I guess that's about all.
We'll meet here 30 minutes before
takeoff time for final instructions.
- How's everything, sergeant?
- Everything's going fine, sir.
Gotta put a new magneto on number two.
Gear's shot.
They told me to get her ready
for a long trip.
- They didn't tell me where.
- They didn't, huh?
- No, sir.
- Can you keep a secret, sergeant?
- Yes, sir.
- That's good.
Captain Quincannon?
Private Chester reporting, sir.
Second radio.
Sergeant White, your crew chief.
- How are you?
- How do you do?
- Glad to have you with us.
- I'm glad to be assigned to your airplane.
I've been hoping to get on a Flying Fortress
since radio school.
- How long ago was that?
- Three months ago.
I've had experience.
I've been in light bombers.
That's fine.
Better turn him over to Peterson, sergeant.
He can look over the radio set
and get the hang of things.
- I'll be in Operations if you want me.
- Yes, sir.
You'll find Peterson inside, son.
- Must be a big flight. Nine Fortresses.
- So they say.
Do you know...?
I mean, can you tell me where we're going?
- Can... Can you keep a secret?
- Oh, yes, sir.
That's good.
- Hello.
- Hello. Are you the new gunner?
- No, second radio.
- Yeah?
- My name's Weinberg, second engineer.
- Chester's my name. Glad to know you.
- Glad to know you.
- Hey, is that what they call her, Mary-Ann?
That's her.
And she's the best ship in the outfit.
Hey, Peterson,
here's your new static chaser.
- My name's Chester.
- How are you?
Come on, I'll show you around.
- Hey, you the crew chief?
- Yeah.
My name's White.
Are you the new gunner?
Yeah, Winocki. Joe Winocki.
We've been expecting you.
Put your stuff inside.
- Okay.
- You're lucky.
- Our regular gunner's on furlough.
- I wouldn't say I'm lucky.
- Looks like everything's okay, sergeant.
- I think so, sir.
- How about coffee and sandwiches?
- Got them, sir.
- I wish we could get ahold of extra oxygen.
- Already inside the plane, sir.
- How'd you do that?
- Six bottles.
- You haven't got an extra engine, have you?
- Almost enough parts to build one, I guess.
I'm getting sort of worried about my wife.
She should be here by now.
Oh, Winocki.
- Yeah?
- This is our new gunner, sir.
Captain Quincannon.
- Don't I know you, sergeant?
- I think you do, sir.
- You were at Randolph Field?
- That's right.
- About two years ago?
- Two and a half, sir.
- While I was instructing there.
- That's right.
- Oh, I remem...
- I think you remember.
- Anything else, sir?
- Not now, no.
Anyhow, I guess that new radioman
of ours is a pretty good kid.
- Yeah, I guess he is.
- We're getting them right off the bottle.
We were all pretty young
when we started out.
How old is that kid of yours
you talk about?
- Twenty-one.
- Where is he stationed?
Clark Field, Manila.
They got him in one of those Peashooters.
Just got a boost too.
If he gets another bar on his shoulders,
you're gonna have to have a bigger head.
- Imagine me saluting my own kid.
- You'd pin his ears down if he didn't take it.
Excuse me, sir. Would you mind if...?
Well, my mother would like to meet you.
Sure.
Mother, this is Captain Quincannon.
- How do you do?
Mighty nice of you to turn out
at this time of night to see us off.
I wanted to meet you, captain, because...
well, I couldn't help wondering
what kind of a...
- You'll take good care of him, won't you?
- In a way, he'll be looking after me.
That's the way
the crew of a bomber functions.
- I wouldn't worry any.
- I won't.
We haven't much time left, Chester.
Don't worry about our radioman.
It's a routine flight.
- He'll be back in a couple of weeks.
- Thank you.
- Goodbye, Mrs. Chester.
- Goodbye.
I'll write to you, Mom,
so you'll know where I am.
Did you bring this for me?
Take care of yourself, Mom.
Don't worry about me. I'll be all right.
Goodbye, son.
Goodbye, Mom.
Haven't seen Mrs. Quincannon, have you?
- I haven't. I've been watching, sir.
- Well, I guess I've been ditched.
- You better get aboard, Chester.
- Yes, sir.
Irish!
- Irish.
- It's about time, Mrs. Quincannon.
- Did you have another date?
- Flat tire. You ever try to get a taxi here?
- I was scared I wouldn't make it.
- So was I.
And I couldn't bring Michael. It's a little
too late for him, but he sent you this.
And this.
Thanks.
- Darling, couldn't I stow away?
- Do you wanna get me court-martialed?
I'll be back in a couple weeks.
We'll take time off for that honeymoon.
I remember every honeymoon
we didn't have. Even the first one.
So do I.
You haven't got much chance
to be bored with me.
Oh, I'll never get bored with you, Irish.
It's been fun, every minute of it.
Such good fun.
- I guess I'm just lucky.
- Me too.
Irish, when you go out in the rain, you'll
remember to wear your rubbers, won't you?
Sure, I will.
I'll be waiting.
So long, kid.
- Better stow this stuff over there, sergeant.
- Yes, sir.
Excuse me, sir.
- Get that ladder aboard, will you, Weinberg?
- Okay.
- Hey, what's that thing for?
- You never know where your luck is.
That's from
Michael Aloysius Quincannon, Jr.
- Everybody in?
- Yes, sir.
- Doors closed?
- Lockpins out?
- Yes, sir.
- Check controls for free movement.
- Check.
- Roberts to flight, check-in in order.
- Two ready.
- Three okay.
- Four okay.
- Five okay.
- Eight ready.
- Nine okay.
- Okay, start engines.
All set here, sir.
- Only need one shot, sir. Kind of warm.
- Okay.
Number one.
Number two.
01104 to control tower.
Take-off instructions
for flight of nine B-17s.
- Sir, is this a local flight?
- No, this is not a local flight.
Okay to taxi up to north end of ramp.
Use runway two-eight.
Wind west, one-five. Go ahead.
Roger.
Roberts to flight, all planes follow me.
Use runway 28. Wind west, 15 miles.
Take off at 30-second intervals.
Let's go.
- Looks like they're gonna run all right.
- Thank you, sir.
- Check the tail wheel, will you, Robbie?
- Yes, sir.
- I'm going upstairs.
- Okay, Tommy.
Don't get us lost.
Want any help running this thing?
- Hi, Tommy. How's Monk doing?
- Knee-deep in maps.
Well, looks like you got your date,
all right.
They say that Hawaiian moon's awful big.
Better watch out, Tommy,
or he'll be your brother-in-law.
No, Susan's a smart girl.
She won't marry beneath herself.
Go on, you can't make me mad.
Take a last look.
- Goodbye, San Francisco.
- Hello, Honolulu.
Hey, there's the Golden Gate.
Christmas crackers.
That's an awful big town, San Francisco.
Strictly a one-whistle stop.
There's only one city in the U.S.A.
And that's New York.
Oh, you're just another hometown hick,
Weinberg.
- What's wrong with California?
- California?
The sun shines and nothing ever happens.
Before you know it you're 60 years old.
It's no different from New York.
My sister's been trying to get out
of Brooklyn for 40 years.
Brooklyn? That ain't New York.
Once you cross that Brooklyn Bridge,
you're out of this world.
The only noise you hear
is the hardening of your arteries.
When I used to drive a hack...
I had a pal who crossed that bridge
back in 1929.
- I ain't heard from him since.
- Me, I'll take Minneapolis.
Minneapolis?
Why, the grass still grows in the streets.
Besides, that ain't your hometown,
Peterson.
The hayseed's still sticking out
of your hair.
Yeah, but I can still milk a cow.
I bet you can't.
I'll get mine out of a bottle. That's
the closest I ever wanna be to a cow.
You're handy with the old bull.
Gee. Gee, we're sure lucky.
- Why? What do you mean?
- Oh, this whole trip.
Well, what about it?
Oh, a million fellas would give anything
to be in our shoes right now.
Why?
I don't mean just this flight.
I mean, well...
Everything we've got to look forward to.
How far do you think you'll get
as an enlisted man?
A lot of enlisted men get commissions.
Look at the training you get,
and the experience too.
Look, if you don't go through flying school,
you don't rate.
- I don't believe that.
- I know.
- Well, what are you in it for?
- Not for long.
I've had enough.
I'm getting out next month.
- You're getting out, huh?
- Yup.
- Well, I'm not.
- That's right, stay with it.
You stick to what you believe in, kid.
Don't listen to guys like him.
What are you gonna be in another 20 years,
sergeant? A brigadier?
No. But my boy is.
Him and me sort of like the old Air Corps.
You stay in the box, son,
and keep right on pitching.
Yeah.
Coming up forward, kid?
Yeah. Keep right on pitching.
- Everybody all right?
- Fine, sir.
- Good.
- Coffee, captain?
Yeah, please.
- Thanks, sergeant.
- Yes, sir.
- You want some coffee, Winocki?
- No, thanks.
- How's it going?
- All right, sir.
- I want to talk with you.
- Sure. Can I talk too?
Sure, go ahead. Get it off your chest.
- I want to get things straight with you.
- I think I'm straight.
- I don't know if you are, sir.
- I think I know what's bothering you.
- Do you?
- Yeah. And in a way, I don't blame you.
- You wanted to fly, be a pilot, didn't you?
- Who doesn't?
- You had your chance.
- Did I?
- Yeah. You blew it.
- That's what you think.
You couldn't make it. You scraped around
a while. When the going got tough...
Yeah, and you threw me up for grabs.
I didn't run you into Driscoll's plane
and cut his tail off.
- Oh, I know it was an accident, but...
- For which you washed me out of school.
I could have been flying one of these
if it hadn't been for that.
I didn't wash you out,
the board washed you out.
- On your recommendation.
- You lacked flying ability.
You should have been eliminated sooner.
I want you to know that nobody
held you responsible for Driscoll's death.
- Except you, sir.
- Not me either.
Get that out of your head.
Now, look, Winocki...
there are two other men on this ship
who washed out as pilots.
McMartin's a bombardier, Hauser went in
for navigation. They're both good.
You're a good gunner
or you wouldn't have the rating.
We need you
like we need the whole gang.
It takes all of us
to make this ship function.
Now, get this into your head:
We all belong to this airplane.
Every man has got to rely on every other
man to do the right thing at the right time.
You played football, Winocki.
You know how one man
can gum up the whole works.
You gotta play ball with us, play the game,
or I'm gonna get rid of you.
Nice speech.
But my enlistment runs out in three weeks.
- You're quitting, huh?
- Yes, sir.
Well, that's your privilege.
But until that time, you're still in the Army.
Don't you forget it.
- Yes, sir.
- I'm sorry for you, Winocki.
- Anything else, sir?
- No, that's all.
Oh, Peterson, if you want entertainment,
tune in on the broadcast frequencies.
- I'll stay on the command set.
- Yes, sir. Thank you.
San Francisco. Mr. Litvinoff, the new
Russian ambassador to the United States...
arrived yesterday
on the China Clipper...
and departed immediately for the capital
to confer with the president.
Washington, D.C.
Tension in the Pacific and the Far East
has relaxed...
as a result of the peaceful mission of
Japan's special envoy, Mr. Saburo Kurusu.
Mr. Kurusu and Admiral Nomura
have assured the press...
that Japan's intentions
are wholly peaceful.
They will meet again tomorrow
with Secretary of State Cordell Hull.
Seattle, Washington.
A final labor conference
was held here this morning...
Weather report from Hickam Field, sir.
- Did you get a good sleep, Chester?
- Not much, sir.
I didn't wanna miss anything.
- How's the kid doing, sergeant?
- Fine, sir.
He likes the ship
and I guess Mary-Ann likes him.
Good. How about Winocki?
I can't make him out.
No, sir.
Thanks, Chester.
Beg pardon, sir. Isn't that
a picture of Captain Monk Hauser?
Yeah.
- Well, that's...
- My father.
Gosh, I'm pretty dumb.
I should have realized.
- Well, there's not much resemblance.
- Oh, sure there is. I can see it now.
I've seen him in a book I got
about the Lafayette Escadrille.
- Yeah, he was in it.
- Yeah, he sure was.
- Gee, he could sure fly.
- Yeah.
I wish I could fly like him.
Yes, sir.
Well, it won't be long now
before you see Diamond Head...
sticking out of that ocean.
Suits Weinberg.
I used to dream
about getting out of traffic jams...
and going someplace
where a guy would have elbow room.
But this is overdoing it.
Two thousand miles and I ain't seen a fish.
I kind of like it.
- Like being on the prairies when I was a kid.
- Funny thing.
I never thought there was nothing
west of Manhattan except Jersey.
- I can use some of that coffee.
- I was just talking to the navigator.
- You know who his father was?
- Sure. Monk Hauser.
- Who's that?
- How old were you in the last war?
Older than you.
I was over on the other side.
And you never heard of Monk Hauser
with Eddie Rickenbacker's squadron?
Well, what do you know?
Was that Lieutenant Hauser's old man?
That's him. I knew him. He was plenty good
till they knocked him down.
Yeah, he sure was.
- Well, why ain't this kid of his a pilot?
- Tried too hard.
Yeah, like a lot of others.
- That's funny.
- What?
Hickam radio went off
right in the middle of a weather report.
- Maybe it faded out.
- It didn't sound like it.
- What is it? What is it?
- Wait.
Hey, Peterson, who you got tuned in,
Orson Welles?
- Shut up.
- Now...
Shut up.
Better tell the captain.
Radio operator to pilot.
- Go ahead.
- Sir, Hickam Field's off the air.
I don't know what I've picked up.
You can listen in on R-2.
- What's that?
- I don't know.
- Chinese?
- No, Japs.
Number four to Major Roberts.
Stand by, Irish. I hear it.
Keep off the air.
01104 to Hickam radio.
Hickam radio, answer.
Hickam radio, answer, please.
01104 to Hickam radio.
A flight of B- 17s to Hickam
want landing instructions.
Hickam radio, answer, please.
Give me landing instructions
for a flight of B- 17s.
Hickam radio, give me a call, please.
01104 to Hickam radio.
Silence your radio!
Keep away from the field!
We're being attacked by enemy aircraft.
Land elsewhere. Land elsewhere.
Roberts to flight.
We're going into emergency fields.
You know where they are.
I'll take the one furthest north,
number nine, furthest south...
the rest of you, in between.
Get on the ground
and stay there till you're clear.
You're on your own.
Peterson, send the crew chief up here
right away.
Get the rubber boats ready.
Pass out.45s and ammunition.
- Where do we go, Monk?
- Turn 120 degrees until I figure it out.
Okay, 120 degrees she is.
- I wish we were there.
- Yeah.
- If we only had machine-gun loads.
- I still got a throwing arm.
I'll heave a wrench
if any of them come our way.
Get the rubber boats ready.
- Pass out side arms.
- I've done that.
- Tell everybody to keep their eyes open.
- Yes, sir.
Put your life vests on.
Keep an eye out upstairs, kid.
- Put your life vests on, boys.
- Hey, sarge, is this really on the level?
You guess.
Winocki,
I told you to put your life vest on.
Relax, sergeant.
This is some kind of drill, and you know it.
Personally, I wouldn't care
if you left it off. Here.
Thanks, brigadier.
- Navigator to pilot.
- Go ahead.
Change course to 135. We ought to be
on the ground at Maui in 22 minutes.
Right, 135.
This one really is smaller
than a postage stamp.
Little more. That's about it.
- Looks like it here.
- Hold it there.
- Think it'll work, sergeant?
- It'll hold all right, sir.
- We gotta see if she'll retract.
- Because I made a mess out of the landing.
A wonder you got her in at all, sir.
This field wasn't built for the Mary-Ann.
Hey, captain, something's moving
over there in the brush.
Why, it's the lieutenants.
- You fellas look like you've had a trip.
- We did.
- Yeah, where's the water?
- Right here.
- You find the other field?
- Yeah, but no ammunition.
- How many of our flight there?
- Two. Both of them okay.
- Hi, there, Tommy.
- Hi.
- That accounts for everybody.
- Yeah.
Two more landed at Molokai,
and Roberts and the rest made Hickam.
- Cracked-up landing. Nobody was hurt.
- What have you heard?
- Nothing since noon.
- Sound bad at Hickam?
Doesn't sound good.
We had a little trouble ourselves
on the way back.
- What?
- Somebody took a crack at us.
- What do you mean?
- Just that.
We saw men in a cane field
and headed for them.
- They started popping away with rifles.
- Local Japs. Friendly fellas.
We lost them back there,
three or four miles.
I hope you did.
- Better get back to your bombsight, Tommy.
- Yeah.
Step on it, sergeant.
- Douse that light! Let's get out of here!
- Knock those wedges out.
Winocki, cut it out.
Knock this one out first.
Got this one.
- All right, shove!
- Shove.
Everybody in the ship!
- How do we get out of this chicken yard?
- We got in, didn't we?
Hey, they ain't kidding.
Did you see that bumblebee?
- Lock it.
- Locked.
Check the tanks
and see if they've been hit.
Yes, sir.
All right, all right. Let me alone.
- All right, all right.
- How are you feeling, Winocki?
- I owe you one for this.
- Yeah?
How far do you think you'd have gotten
in that brush?
They'd have cut you down
before you got to first base.
- Instead, you did it.
- Don't you know this is just a drill?
We could've had a fine scrap
with them snipers.
Couple of shots in the right place
could have set this ship afire.
Use your head, Winocki,
and stop trying to prove something.
My job is tail gunner.
What's yours, lecturing?
No. My job is to keep this thing flying.
05564 to Hickam Field.
Shut off your radio. Stay where you are.
Don't get off the ground.
05564 to Hickam.
Just cleared emergency field on Maui.
- Have to come down.
- Okay.
- Give me a call just before you come in.
- Roger.
Pilot to crew.
Take a good look at Pearl Harbor.
Maybe it's something
you'll want to remember.
Damn them. Damn them.
Now ain't you glad
you're getting out of the Army?
05564 to Hickam.
- Go ahead.
- Approaching the field from the south.
- Coming in for a landing.
- We won't be able to give you any lights.
- I can get in without them.
- Take the west side near the hangars.
Watch out for bomb craters
on the runway.
- Good luck to you.
- Roger.
Pilot to crew. Fasten your safety belts.
- Might be a rough landing.
- All set, sir.
All checked for landing.
- Give me full flaps.
- Flaps coming down.
- Landing lights.
- Lights.
Air speed 110.
One hundred.
- Captain Quincannon, sir.
- How are you, captain?
You made a good landing.
You were told to stay where you were.
- Yes, but we had to get out.
- Why?
- We were being shot at by snipers.
- At Maui?
- We didn't wanna lose the airplane.
- No, no, of course you didn't.
Didn't know about that.
You did the right thing, then.
Well, we've had our troubles around here
too, as you can see.
Yes, sir.
They certainly did a complete job of it.
What happened to those P-40s?
Three trucks arrived from Honolulu
this morning.
When the first Jap plane showed up,
the trucks went down the field...
smashed the tails off every ship
on the land.
They sure had a field day.
Took the first round, but there'll be others.
- Yes, sir.
- Which one of you is McMartin?
- Me, sir.
- I have some bad news for you.
- You're wanted over at the hospital.
- My sister?
Sorry, I didn't get any details except that
she asked for Williams and Quincannon too.
Captain, we'll want your ship serviced
right away.
- Full gas load, ammunition for guns.
- Yes, sir.
Any repairs needed?
There's a wheel to be checked.
Everything else seems okay.
These men will give you everything.
- Sergeant?
- Yes, sir?
You heard what the colonel said.
Anything else?
- This car will take you to the hospital.
- Thank you.
- Who's your navigator?
- I am, sir.
- Come with me. I have a job for you.
- Oh, colonel.
Beg your pardon, sir.
- Glad to see you again, sergeant.
- Thank you, sir.
Did they attack Clark Field, Manila, sir?
- I've got a boy there.
- Yes, they hit it all right.
Hit everything in the Pacific.
Guam, Wake, Midway.
I remember your boy, sergeant.
- Twenty-seventh group.
- Yes, sir.
He's a first lieutenant now.
Flight commander.
He's a good pilot, then.
Don't worry. He'll take care of himself.
Thank you, sir. All right, fellas.
We got a job of work to do.
Let's get with it.
- Miss McMartin?
- Right down that way.
Thank you.
I can't see. Why is it so dark?
Hush, child. It's going to be all right.
But I can't see.
I can't see.
- Lieutenant McMartin?
- Yes, nurse.
You can only stay a few minutes.
She needs all the rest she can get.
Sure.
Sue.
Hello, kids.
Why, it's good to see you boys.
I was kind of scared.
I acted like a ninny.
We didn't know whether you had
a flat tire or something...
or couldn't find the place.
Or...
Tommy, Bill, I'm so glad you're here.
- Kind of hurts when I cry.
- Don't, Sue.
I wanted to tell you about...
But I guess I'm kind of tired.
- He'll tell you.
- Who?
Tex.
- Tex Rader.
- What?
Please don't get mad at him.
It was all my fault.
He tried to make me
get out of the car, but...
- I guess he'd better tell you.
- Sure.
- Will you come in the morning?
- You bet.
Good night.
Sergeant, do you know
where we can find Lieutenant Rader?
Yes, sir. Right this way.
Rader. Rader.
Oh, hello, Tommy.
- Quincannon. How are you, Bill?
- I've been waiting for you. I went to sleep.
We just came from the hospital.
- How is she?
- Not so good.
That's what we came
to talk to you about.
- Suppose you do a little explaining.
- Yeah, go on, start.
- Say, what is this, the third degree?
- All right, she said it wasn't his fault.
Don't believe what she said.
It was my fault.
- Should've made her get out of the car.
- What car?
- The one I borrowed for the party.
- What party?
Give him a chance.
We were starting out
when the first planes came.
- Couldn't figure it out.
- Up early, weren't you?
- Or out late.
- Listen, will you?
- Say, I don't get...
- Never mind, Rader. Go ahead.
We spotted the planes, and
at the same time heard the bombs.
All I could think of
was getting to the field.
I told Susan to hop out and get under cover,
but she only laughed at me.
- You know how she is.
- Yeah, we know. Go on.
We got near the field, a truck pulled
across, blocking the road ahead of us.
It was a delivery truck from Honolulu.
I remember thinking as I jumped out
that the driver had been hit.
I was just dumb.
First thing I knew,
there was an explosion right in my face.
There was a Jap behind the wheel
with a shotgun.
It was a rotten shot. Sloughed him
over the head with his own gun.
Got the truck off the road.
Other cars were coming along,
trying to get to the field.
Was Susan all right then?
Yeah, but that's when
I should've made her get out.
She took the wheel and went carting off
toward the hangars with me hanging on.
Last time I saw her,
she was standing up in the car...
yelling and rooting
like she was at a football game.
- How'd she get hurt, then?
- Machine gun.
The soldier who ran out
to drag her in was killed.
- What were you doing all that time?
- What do you think?
I notice you're not hurt any.
- Listen, wait a minute.
- Wait a minute, Tommy.
If I stay here, I'll...
Let's go.
- Say, you guys don't think...?
- See you later, Rader.
You wanted to see me, colonel?
- You find something to eat?
- Yes.
- How's your sister, McMartin?
- Pretty weak, sir.
The surgeon says it's hard to tell yet.
I'm going over again
when he makes another examination.
No, you aren't. We want this airplane
out of here before daylight.
- You're sending us back to the mainland?
- No, Manila.
We're safe here for the moment,
and the Philippines are in bad shape.
Our orders are to send them as many B-17s
as we can. Can you make it?
- Where do we stop to refuel, sir?
- Wake Island.
I can't promise you how long it'll hold out
or what you'll find there.
- Got the charts there, Monk?
- Yes, sir.
- Sergeant White.
- Yes, sir?
- How'd the engines rev up, sergeant?
- Number-three engine's a little rough, sir.
The men are pretty tired.
We'll overhaul it in the morning.
- We're taking off in two hours.
- Sir?
I think you're gonna see
that son of yours soon.
- Manila?
- Can you get that engine running?
We'll have her hitting home runs
in 90 minutes.
Tell the crew they can sleep
in the next world.
- We'll make it all right, sir.
- Good luck. Take off when you're ready.
By the way, tell your passenger
I'll have some papers for him.
- What passenger, sir?
- Hasn't he reported yet?
- Manila needs pilots. You're taking one.
- Who, sir?
Lieutenant Rader.
- Did you say Rader?
- Yes, and he's a good man too.
Three fighters got off the ground
this morning, and he was one.
Knocked off four Jap Zeros
before they shot him down.
He'll be recommended for a DFC.
Well, good luck again.
Thank you, sir.
Well...
looks like you two fellas
talked out of turn a while ago.
Maybe you better go
and rustle up some grub for the crew.
- Yes, sir.
- Java, lieutenant?
- No, I've been living on it.
You fellas must have a plantation
in Brazil.
I'll leave it here.
Maybe you'll want some later on.
- Is this here Wake Island?
- Yeah.
- How far is it?
- Oh, it's about 2300 miles from Honolulu.
- And we're gonna land on that dot?
- Yeah. It's not very big, is it?
Like trying to find a buckshot
in Central Park.
Gee, I wish there were
some traffic signs around.
- There are, but you can't see them.
- I mean like numbers and streets.
Yeah, but I call them latitudes
and longitudes.
- And they're just like signs, huh?
- Yeah, if the wind doesn't change them.
Say, lieutenant, how we doing?
Now, look, you're the fifth guy
that's been down here asking that.
- We'll hit Wake all right.
- Yes, sir.
I was just asking.
- Time to relieve the kid, Minnesota.
- Okay.
You want anything, lieutenant?
Yeah, I'd like to get out
of this flying boxcar.
Sure a long way to Manila.
Mary-Ann ain't no boxcar, sir.
She's a good airplane.
- Mary-Ann?
- That's what we call her.
There ain't a better airplane in the Army.
- Maybe, if you're talking about bombers.
- Any airplane, sir.
- I'll take a pursuit ship for mine, sergeant.
- Well, you can take pursuit and...
Yes, sir.
Oh, chief, that's my last apple.
I'm saving it.
Don't leave it laying around, then.
There's a pursuit pilot back there.
Morning, sir. How we doing?
You too? Every 15 minutes, somebody
wakes up and comes here to find out...
if I know where we are or if I'm gonna
get this airplane lost. I'm getting sick...
- Yes, sir.
- Oh, I'm sorry, sergeant.
- I guess I'm a little on edge.
- Oh, that's all right, sir.
That's the way
your old man would've told me off.
Except he'd have done it
with a four-star cussing.
- Yeah, I guess he would.
- Tell me, sir, how are we doing?
We're all right. I think we're gonna
hit Wake right on the nose.
Sure we will, sir.
Say, chief, what happens if the Japs
have took Wake Island before we get there?
I wish you'd learn
to control that imagination of yours.
- I was just asking.
- Don't you know we're not at war?
- Ain't we in the war yet?
- Hasn't been declared.
- I don't get it.
- Them Japs.
They smear Pearl Harbor, smack Manila,
raid Wake, Guam and Midway...
and still there ain't no war.
They send a couple of oily gents
to Washington...
with a olive wreath for the president...
while the boys back home slough
Uncle Sam over the head with a crowbar.
Your Uncle Sam
is a pretty tough old gentleman.
You just wait till he gets mad.
I hope you don't mind
if I get slightly annoyed in the meantime.
- No. But I didn't expect it of you.
- I still don't get it.
Message coming through, sir.
And good news.
Thanks, Peterson.
Hey, you guys, take a look at this.
That's wonderful.
If the head surgeon says that,
she must be okay.
- Sure she is.
- Boy, I feel a lot better.
Oh, me too.
It was mighty swell of the CO
to think of sending this.
Better show it to our passenger.
Poor guy must be worrying.
- Let him worry. He's got it coming.
- You're being a little tough with Rader.
- I haven't kicked him in the face yet.
- You couldn't be jealous, could you, Bill?
Well, maybe I am.
Peterson, ask Lieutenant Rader
to come up front, will you?
That's the stuff.
Now, look, stay out of arguments.
- We never...
- You can't outtalk that guy.
He's been shooting off his face against
big airplanes since they gave him wings.
But he doesn't know any better.
Just quit arguing.
- You'll be a lot better off.
- Okay, captain.
- Somebody up here wanna see me?
- Yeah.
- We got some good news for you, Tex.
- Yeah?
Boy, that is good news.
She's a swell kid.
You know, Tex,
we were all pretty upset last night.
If we said anything out of line...
Oh, forget it, I know how you felt.
I don't blame you.
Thanks, Tex. After all,
we've known each other a long time.
We've had our arguments about these
big bombers and your Peashooters, but...
Forget it, Tommy.
Just a matter of opinion.
You know, Tex, we were wondering,
what was it like yesterday at Hickam?
- Oh, an awful mess. We just weren't ready.
- How good are those Japs?
They're pretty good
when they got the edge, 10 or 12 to one.
They don't like an even fight.
Every time you get one alone,
he lights out like a scared sage hen.
- We heard you did a swell job.
- Thanks.
Hope you get a decoration.
I'd still like to know
how all their carriers got away.
We didn't even get a bomber off.
- Caught them on the ground.
- You make it sound like the bombers' fault.
Okay, you two, quit it.
You guys are awful touchy
about these crates.
- Oh, it's not that...
- Hold it.
- Go ahead, Monk.
- The wind shifted again.
Give me three degrees to the left.
You'd better make it 2.44.
Okay, two-four-four.
- That's the new flight control?
- You know the old type?
- Yeah.
- Well, this is a whole lot better.
Why don't you fly her
and find out what a B-17 will do?
Oh, no, not me. Looks to me
like she's flying herself anyway.
Well, she is right now, yeah.
She seems to be getting us there,
not very fast though.
She'll out-fly your pursuit ships
up high.
- Will she?
- Yeah, she will.
- You can't sell me.
- What'll a P-40 do at 30,000?
- We'd have to tow it to get it up there.
- We'd run away and hide on you.
- Well, that's all you could do.
- Oh, sure, no arguments.
If you guys will give me a chance,
I'll prove something.
- All right, go ahead.
- Three minutes and no interruptions.
- Anything to get this settled.
- Let him talk.
Irish, the navigator gave you a course.
You reach down and turn a knob
and you're on it, right?
Tommy, that gadget there is almost as good
as your bombsight, isn't it?
- Well, not quite...
- Well, almost.
- And you call the sight the brain, don't you?
- Yeah.
- Then this is a sort of mechanical brain too.
- It does everything but think.
It seems to be doing the thinking
right now.
- Well, I don't...
- Watch out for him.
- Did you hear about it too?
- Hear what?
- I got it pretty straight.
- What?
Why, they're gonna give commissions
to these mechanical brains in bombers.
Put them in uniform and teach them to talk,
turn out bomber pilots on the assembly line.
We pursuit pilots
will be upstairs fighting.
We'll look down and see
a flock of these freight trains coming.
Press a button: "Lieutenant."
"Yes, sir?" says that thing.
"Drop a load of potatoes on the enemy."
"I'll tell Captain Bombsight right away."
"Very well. Where's your pilot?"
"We left him on the ground.
We don't need them.
Their heads take up too much room."
- Very funny.
- Did you ever think...?
- Keep them quiet, Irish.
- Shut up, you guys. Give him a chance.
Now, seriously, guys,
these big crates are all right.
I just don't wanna fight in any airplane
that more than one man can ride in.
I don't wanna be responsible
for eight or 10 guys.
Or depending on them,
the way you're on Hauser now.
What do you mean, depending on him?
In a pursuit ship, you're a one-man army,
not a taxi driver.
You're on your own.
You don't wait for orders
from a guy who can't fly, a bombardier.
Hey, that's enough.
You give orders to these taxi drivers
when you go to lay eggs.
"Where to?" says the Irishman.
You say, "Go a few blocks and turn right.
Give me change for a nickel, conductor."
When you get to 33rd and Broadway,
throw an egg out the window and run.
Very exciting. I wouldn't fly this crate
if they made me a brigadier for it.
Bill, pipe down. Shut up, Rader.
Go ahead, Peterson.
I've picked up Washington
on the short wave, sir.
- The president's on.
- Thanks.
Washington's on short wave.
Get below and grab some headphones.
Yeah, and take that
pursuit pilot with you.
- Do I have to?
- Take him.
- Come on, lone eagle.
- Drop him out if you get a chance.
The attack yesterday...
on the Hawaiian Islands...
has caused severe damage
to American naval and military forces.
I regret to tell you that
very many American lives have been lost.
But always will our whole nation...
remember the character
of the onslaught against us.
I hope he tells us something
about the Philippines.
My boy's at Clark Field.
No matter how long it may take us...
to overcome
this premeditated invasion...
the American people,
in their righteous might...
will win through to absolute victory.
We will not only defend ourselves
to the uttermost...
but will make it very certain...
that this form of treachery
shall never again endanger us.
With confidence in our armed forces...
with the unbounding determination
of our people...
we will gain the inevitable triumph...
so help us God.
I ask that the Congress declare...
a state of war.
Pick up anything from Wake Island?
- Pilot to navigator.
- Go ahead.
- What do you think, Monk?
- I don't know, Irish.
We ought to be there now.
Go another 10 minutes, then turn east.
Okay.
- There she is, Irish, dead ahead.
- Good guessing, Monk.
- Oh, shut up, will you?
- Magellan!
Pilot to crew. Wake Island, dead ahead.
- Hey, Wake Island in sight.
- Boy, what a navigator.
- There's nothing here but Marines.
- What'd you expect to see?
- Where'd you guys come from?
- Hickam Field.
- Any more coming?
- I don't know.
- Where are you going?
- Manila.
Gangway, men. Coming in.
Good work, captain.
Major Daniels, commanding.
Quincannon. Thank you, sir.
These are Lieutenants Williams,
McMartin and Rader.
And this is Lieutenant Hauser,
our navigator.
We're gonna put him
in a glass case in a museum.
- Did a good job, Hauser.
- The island looked pretty good to me, sir.
- Me too.
- Yes, I guess it did at that.
- Looks better than anytime since Monday.
- You mean Sunday, don't you?
Monday here was Sunday in Honolulu.
You've crossed the date line.
He's a pursuit pilot, major.
They don't get around very much.
Could we bunk down
for five or six hours, sir?
We haven't had much sleep.
In six hours, you better be
five and a half hours out.
With the beacons, Japs don't have
to wait till daylight to call.
- My orders are to get you out in 20 minutes.
- Twenty minutes?
That's right.
- What do you say, sergeant?
- Well, we're halfway to Manila now, sir.
Don't see any reason
we can't make it the rest of the way.
- Could use some help.
- Take all the men you need, sergeant.
All right.
You first five men come with me.
Get the cowling off number 3 engine.
Quincannon, our commander,
Major Bagley, wants to talk to you.
Yes, sir.
- So they really got the Arizona?
- Yes, sir.
Hickam Field was hit
just as bad as Pearl Harbor.
A lot of fifth column work.
We got practically nothing
off the ground, sir.
I've studied all the wars of history,
gentlemen.
I've never come across
any dirty treachery like that.
How many airplanes have you got, sir?
A week ago, we didn't have any.
A few days ago, they flew in 12 fighters
from one of the carriers.
Eight were destroyed
after they came in from patrol.
Only four left, sir?
Only two. And one of those can't fly.
But those four Grummans
took on 60 Nips this afternoon.
Shot down plenty of them too.
Hogan and Ingersol got theirs.
I think you knew them.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, I did.
I suppose the Japs will be back, major.
What are you gonna do then?
We got a lad catching a few winks of sleep
that will take them all on single-handed.
- Lieutenant Rose.
- Bertie Rose?
- That's him.
- You guys remember Rose, don't you?
- Sure.
- Everybody kidded him about his size.
- Little bitty squirt about that high.
- Sure, we knew him.
I'd like to stand up and salute him.
Could we talk to him before we take off?
I'll tell him you wanted to see him.
He needs rest.
We have to roust him out any minute...
and he hasn't had
much of a chance to sleep lately.
- Ship's ready, sir.
- All right, sergeant.
And good luck to you.
It's been nice seeing you boys.
Go out and blast the Japs.
Teach them that treachery can't win
no matter how much of a head start it has.
You young fellows will have to do that.
We're only fighting a delaying action here.
You can't hold out, sir?
I've got 400 Marines
and they're fighting mad.
There's gonna be some Jap tail feathers
flying around this island or I'm crazy.
Major Bagley, can't we fly you out, sir?
You and the rest of the wounded?
No, thanks, I'm fine here.
I'm not worth my weight in gasoline.
Me or anybody else.
They need that ship of yours in Manila.
Get it there.
- Yes, sir.
- Oh, by the way...
if you see my old boss,
General MacArthur...
tell him, no matter what the news is...
we'll be in here pitching
till they strike us out.
All right, sir, we will.
- I'll see you all somewhere.
- So long.
- Best of luck to you.
- Thanks.
- You think we ought to take him with us?
- He wouldn't leave this island...
if you got him a lower berth
in a Pullman.
- There you go.
- One for the wife, one for the kid.
He'll be old enough to read
by the time I get back.
- Don't lose them, soldier.
- Don't worry.
I was gonna leave a letter here
for the Clipper.
She got away yesterday.
Twenty-six bullet holes in her.
- Crew so mad they wanted to stay and fight.
- The old man got tough with them.
- Take care of this one.
- This one too.
Come on.
We don't want Tripoli to get hurt.
- Gave him the rank of top sergeant.
- No pedigree, but he sure can fight.
- He'd tackle a Jap three times his size.
- Anything.
No, I wish I could,
but I'd get in an awful jam.
Give him to the Marines in Manila.
We gotta get him out of here.
- Come on, soldier.
- It's against regulations, pal.
- I can't take that dog onboard with me.
- You can.
- Wanna get me busted?
- You're not...
He's trained too. Look.
Tripoli, do you like Mr. Moto?
- See?
- Ain't that cute, Winocki?
- He's smart.
- What do you say, Brooklyn?
- Come on, soldier.
- Give him a kiss.
Gee, I'd like to, honest, but...
Gee, here goes my promotion.
- That's a good fellow.
- Duck. Here they come.
- Well, goodbye, sir. And luck.
- Same to you, boys.
- Anything we can do for you in Manila?
- You might send us more Japs.
- We'll try to.
- So long.
- Good luck, men.
- Good luck, sir.
Bye, sir.
What's the matter, Bill, can't you sleep?
No, I keep thinking of those marines
back there on Wake.
- They haven't got a prayer, Irish.
- No, I know they haven't.
But they're gonna have some fun
before anybody gets on that island.
Yeah.
How are things, sergeant?
Oh, I'm kind of...
What the...?
Why, it's a dog.
Who belongs to this?
Look at that. Is that your dog, chief?
It ain't my dog. What kind
of a crew chief do you think I am?
- I was just asking.
- Who brought him onboard?
- Well, maybe he just walked on.
- And tied himself in a sack?
- Come on, who did it?
- I didn't.
You, Weinberg?
- Maybe the Marines done it.
- Sure.
- If I'm not mistaken, they had a dog.
- His name was Rover.
- No, his name was Tripoli.
- Talk fast.
- He had a cute trick.
- What?
Let's see if this is him. Look here, Tripoli.
What do you think of this Mr. Moto?
Moto. There you are. It's the same dog.
I know the dog came from Wake Island
and I know you brought him onboard.
- Me?
- You can get busted for this.
Why don't you ask me, sergeant?
- I did it.
- You?
- Yeah, me. Shut up.
- Listen, Joe.
You ought to know better
than do a trick like that.
- Why?
- Because it's against regulations.
Makes no difference. Regulations...
You know why this dog is here.
We know what chance those Marines have
on that island, so they gave us this dog.
Go on up front and report me.
I've been busted out.
- Now, Joe, I did it. I don't...
- Shut up. I'm getting sore.
We got chased out
before we can even light...
got kicked all over the place
by sneaking Nips...
and you're yapping about regulations.
- You're changing your tune, ain't you?
- So, what if I am?
- I'd like to do a little chasing myself.
- Me too.
- Go on, tell them.
- I'm a half a mind to...
- I'd like to...
- Come here. Come here.
- Come here.
- Why'd you wanna do that for?
Pipe down.
Hey, look what's here.
What is this, sergeant? Noah's Ark?
- I'm sorry, sir.
- Who brought him on this airplane?
- He could have jumped on.
- Or flown in the window...
but he didn't.
- No, sir.
- You know it's against regulations.
- Yes, sir.
And you don't know who did it?
You didn't see anybody do it?
No, sir, I didn't.
We can't very well throw him out now,
can we?
- We could take care of him, sir.
- We can?
- Yes, sir.
- Who back there likes dogs, sergeant?
Why, I think Winocki and Weinberg
like dogs.
- You think they'd like to take care of him?
- Yes, sir. I think they would.
- All right, sergeant, you tell them.
- Yes, sir. I'll tell them.
It'll be pretty tough on you
if we gotta fly over that stuff ahead.
We can fix that.
He's a cute little pooch.
- What's his name?
- I think they call him "Tripoli."
- Tripoli?
- Yes. He don't like Japs.
Tripoli, what do you think
of that guy Moto?
So you don't like Moto, huh?
Well, what is this, a flying doghouse?
Look out.
He doesn't like pursuit pilots.
- What's his name?
- Moto.
Hi, Moto.
- Didn't we tell you?
- That dog's a judge of character.
Here, Moto. Be nice, Moto.
Hello, Moto.
He doesn't like me.
I'm getting out of here.
Tripoli, you're gonna be
very useful around here.
- Take good care of him, sergeant.
- Yes, sir.
Well, did you tell him
how the pup got aboard?
- No.
- You didn't?
But I'm telling you to take care of him.
If he don't behave himself,
you can take care of that too.
Pilot to crew.
We're going up to 20,000.
Better check your oxygen.
There you are, Tripoli.
He seems to like it all right.
He ain't putting up no kick.
Just like a baby on a bottle.
05564 to Clark Field.
- Here they are, sir.
- 05564 to Clark.
Clark Field to 05564.
What's your position? Go ahead.
We're about four miles
northeast of the field.
Two thousand.
What are your landing instructions?
We've only got one runway.
North to south.
It's pretty rough.
The Japs just had a picnic.
Someday we're gonna find a field
that's flat.
Hold him off a while.
Those tractors are still working out there.
Do not land. Keep your altitude.
Do not land.
Sorry, have to come straight in.
Running out of fuel.
Sergeant, get those tractors
off that runway.
- Tell him to come in low over the fence.
- Come in low over the fence. South end.
Cut close to the wire,
you haven't much room.
Tractors working down
the middle of the runway.
We've got the fence with us.
- Take a look, Robby.
- Yes, sir.
- Hi there, Irish.
- Hi, major.
Say, when we were at Kelly Field,
didn't I teach you how to get over a fence?
That's one way to stop quick.
I just cut her too fine.
Not bad, anyway.
After 7000 consecutive miles...
you did a great job, all of you.
- Hi there, Rader.
- Hi you, sir.
- Don't tell me you've joined the bombers.
- No, I still belong to the opposition.
He doesn't appreciate
a good airplane, major.
It ain't that.
It's just that I don't like them big.
- Tail wheel clear, sir. No damage.
- Okay.
Take her down the end
and get her a full load of gas...
drop your extra tanks
and get ready for action, Irish.
- Okay, major.
- The Japs been hitting us...
with 60 bombers at a clip.
You gotta be ready to take off at any time.
You can see yourself,
you're wide open on the ground.
Colonel Blake wants to see you.
I'll pick you up in a while.
All right, sir.
Hold it.
You got any sectional maps
for around here?
- Yeah, but I haven't got enough.
- Grab as many as you can get.
Find out what size bombs
they'll give us and load them.
- Okay.
- I'll go with you.
- Thanks for the buggy ride, Irish.
- Okay, Tex.
- Weinberg, open the bomb bay.
- Right.
Peterson, check your radio.
You and Chester, give him a hand
with the loading.
Winocki, find the line chief
and see if they'll give you a transfer.
We'll get somebody to replace you.
All right, get going.
- Okay.
- Winocki.
You wanna get out of this crew?
- That's what you want me to do?
- Not necessarily.
You'd take that stuff
I've been handing you?
- We all make mistakes.
- I'm beginning to realize that myself. I...
Turn that dog over to the nearest Marine
and get back and check those guns.
- Give them a good going over.
- Yes, sir.
Be ready as quick as you can, sergeant.
- Okay, Bill, let's go.
- Oh, captain.
Excuse me, sir.
Would you see if you could find out
something about my boy?
Sure, I will, sergeant.
- Hey, buddy, any Marines around here?
- If so, the place would be in better shape.
- You a Marine?
- What's it to you?
- You're one all right. Got this for you.
- What's this?
You outfit on Wake gave it to us to deliver.
His name is Tripoli. Feed him good.
- He'll eat like a company commander.
- What's your name?
Callahan. Thanks.
- You all ready up there?
- All ready.
Let it go. Watch her, boys.
Steady. Keep her level.
Now turn her, fellows.
Turn her.
Hurry it up, boys. Make it snappy.
That's about it.
Take the strain off.
Take it away.
That's the situation as it stands
right now.
- I've given the facts to you straight.
- Yes, sir.
We've taken a licking
because we were caught on the ground.
Since then,
they've outnumbered us 10-to-1.
Yet every time we've been up against them,
they've lost five to our one.
In other words, if we were anywhere
near equal, we could lick them.
The record proves it.
From now on, our job's
to keep fighting with what we've got...
till we get enough airplanes
to blast them off the earth.
How long since you had
any sleep, captain?
- We haven't had much time.
- When did you leave the mainland?
- Saturday night.
- Three days and three nights flying.
You've done a good job.
- I've got a good crew, sir.
- Yeah, I can believe it.
- Excuse me, sir.
- What'd you find, Moran?
That PT boat was right.
Looks like an invasion fleet.
- What's in it?
- There's a transport and a tanker.
- Got a battleship or cruiser and destroyers.
- Where?
Forty miles off Lingayen
last time I saw them.
I didn't have much time to stick around.
Sky suddenly got full of Zeros.
So I headed for home.
I marked their position
and course on this chart.
Right here. A flight of Boeing B-17s
could give them a nice party, sir.
- We haven't got a flight of B-17s.
- You've got one, sir, loading up now.
- You wanna tackle it?
- Yes, sir.
All right, study this first.
Take your time, don't take any chances.
Moran will give you the dope
and good luck.
Excuse me, sir. There's one thing more.
I told our crew chief I'd find out
about his son, Lt. White.
Danny White. Can you tell me
anything about him, sir?
Yeah, I can. He was killed the first day.
That's a shame.
Give these to old Robbie, will you?
I've known him for a long time.
How did it happen, sir?
Capt. Anderson in the other office
can tell you more than I can.
He saw the whole thing happen.
Yes, sir.
Did you find out anything, sir?
How'd it happen?
He was trying to take his flight off
during the first raid.
Before he could get off...
they hit the runway
right in front of him with a big one.
Didn't even get into the air.
It's not much to show for 20 years,
is it, sir?
Get that airplane off the ground.
- All right, sergeant, let's go.
- Yes, sir.
Pull that dolly out.
- Close the bomb bay.
- How many loaded?
- Three, sir. All big ones.
- Thousand pounders?
- Yes, sir.
- Good.
Come on, let's get this thing out of here.
Take it away.
Doors are closed. Everything all set, sir.
Wheels up.
- Wheels up.
- Monk?
- Go ahead.
- What do you make it?
Three-thirty-one, Irish.
Okay, 331.
- You better put on your chute, Robbie.
- Yes, sir.
Navigator to pilot.
- Go ahead.
- We're about 30 miles off the coast.
You better go down
and take a look.
Okay. Going down.
Fighters.
Pilot to crew.
There's a flock of Zeros ahead.
Two o'clock at about 3000 feet above us.
There's another bunch at 10 o'clock.
Take your time.
Sing out if they get on our tail
and I'll kick her around.
Make it count.
We've got a lot to get even for.
Here they come.
Coming over.
Did you see that?
They break up in little pieces.
Winocki, one at 9 o'clock even.
Coming down.
Coming over.
Great.
Kick it left.
Take it to the right.
Hey, Joe. Fried Jap going down.
Gas line on two.
- Oil line's burning.
- Yeah.
It looks like we'll have to bail out.
Pilot to crew.
Are you hurt, Irish?
Yeah.
Pilot to crew. Abandon ship.
All right, come on, kids.
Tommy, get rid of your sight. You and Monk
go out through the bomb bay.
- I know...
- I'll use the escape hatch.
- But you're hurt.
- Go on.
They'll have to drag
the bottom of the ocean to get this.
- Open the escape hatch. I'll throw it out.
- Right.
- Irish, you...
- Go on, get out.
You're about 15 or 20 miles
northwest of the field. Get out.
Yes, sir. Go ahead, Peterson.
- Weinberg.
- I don't think I'm gonna like this.
Go on.
All right, kid.
- Winocki.
- Go ahead, I'm coming.
Okay.
05564 to Clark Field.
Emergency landing. Emergency landing.
- There she is, sir. One engine's burning.
- Get your wheels down.
I can't do it. Gear's jammed.
It won't come down.
- Well, Joe?
- I just had a look at that B-17, sir.
What about her?
I counted over a hundred
bullet holes in her.
Two motors hit, props are bent,
controls in a mess, wheels damaged...
fuel tanks are punctured,
one wing's gone.
At least the tip.
- I don't see how they brought her down.
- Neither do I.
I suppose if we had 10 days
and plenty of spare parts...
we might make her fly again.
I don't know that we'll have 24 hours.
- We'll have to write off the Mary Ann.
- All right, we'll destroy her.
No use lighting any fires tonight.
They'd only hit us again.
Joe, send out a demolition squad
in the morning.
- All right, sir.
- So long.
- What about the crew?
- They all got back all right, sir.
- Where are they now?
- Over at the hospital.
- Quincannon asked to see them.
- How's he?
That's too bad.
Yeah.
It's good to see you.
What are you...?
What are you doing with that rifle, Tex?
Picked up too many slugs
in the P-39, Irish.
I'm a foot soldier now.
They finally got him where he belongs.
Anyway, we was using up
Japs so fast...
they was afraid
there wouldn't be none left to surrender.
- Winocki?
- Yes, sir.
- They told me you brought her in.
- He did, sir.
She came in herself. I just sat there.
It was a good job.
She's all right, huh?
She's all right, isn't she?
- Robbie.
- Yes, sir?
- She's all right, she'll fly again?
- Sure she will, skipper.
What's wrong with her?
- She's gonna be all right.
- Tell me.
- Props, gear, wing tip.
- Just a tip?
It's a wing tip, sir.
Couple of days...
- Two days?
- Two days. Yes, sir.
But she will fly again?
- Yeah.
- That's fine.
Get as many men as you need, Robbie.
The colonel will give them to you.
I'll get a clearance.
We'll leave right away.
- We gotta hurry.
- Nurse.
Easy, easy, Irish.
- Get the doctor right away.
- Oh, no. No, the doctor can't go.
Regulations.
Besides, we already got one passenger.
Is he here, that pursuit pilot?
- Here, sir.
- Okay, start them, Bill.
Sure, Irish.
Everybody in, chief?
All in, sir.
- Doors closed?
- Yes, sir.
Here we go.
- Lock them.
- Locked.
Wheels up.
- Coming up.
- They sound like they're gonna run all right.
- Robbie?
- Yes, sir.
- Pilot to navigator.
- Go ahead.
Monk.
- Monk, what's our course?
- Due east, skipper.
That's right into the sunrise.
- Right into the sunrise.
- Over here, major.
That's all, boys.
Well, let's get going, fellas.
We got a lot to do.
- Corporal?
- There's something wrong.
- Yeah? What?
- I don't know.
But there's something wrong.
- What are you talking about?
- We was to burn them airplanes.
- Well, did you?
- No, not all of them, sir.
- Why not?
- They're being stolen.
- What?
- Japs are stealing it.
Don't talk nonsense, man.
There have been Japanese
through but they're snipers.
- They're not stealing.
- But...
Now, wait a minute, Mallory.
Let's get this straight.
- You had five B-17s to demolish.
- Yes, sir.
- What is it you wanna tell us?
- They're missing.
- You mean parts of them?
- Sure. I mean, yes, sir.
- Why on earth would anybody...?
- Now, look.
There's a B-17,
the one that came in yesterday.
- The Mary Ann.
- Have you burned it?
- No, sir.
- Why not?
We was, but I told the boys
I ought to report them Japs.
Well, you've reported.
You better burn it.
Yes, sir.
What was he talking about?
I don't know, sir,
but I'd better go out and have a look.
I'll go with you.
There's the stuff we've been missing.
- How's it coming, chief?
- All right.
- All right, Weinberg, lower away.
- Okay.
- Hey, sarge, your guns loaded?
- Sure they are. Keep a coming.
- Any bombs in?
- No, not yet. Come on.
- Get down, sarge.
- Get away from here.
- Get down. We're gonna burn this junk.
- What?
A couple of you get in there
and get the live ammunition out.
Hey, wait a minute.
You said you gonna burn this plane?
The colonel said to burn it so she's gonna.
Get your stuff out.
Okay, boys. Bring in the gas.
Wait a minute.
Get this gasoline away from that airplane.
- Hey, Butch.
- Weinberg.
I thought you still was
on a streetcar in Jersey.
- I wished I was.
- Lieutenant Williams.
- You ain't gonna burn that airplane?
- I got orders.
- I never enlisted to be no fireman.
- Go on.
If you know this firebug,
get him out of here before he gets hurt.
I don't wanna, but orders is orders.
- What orders?
- To burn the plane.
- Who gave them to you?
- The CO.
Yeah? Well, you tell that CO to take a...
Take a look at this airplane.
- I am.
- Sorry, I didn't see you.
- Apparently not.
- There's no reason to burn this airplane.
- She's gonna be good as new.
- We're gonna rig a tail gun.
- Been working all night.
- She'll fly when we get through.
- We'll have her in the air in 24 hours.
- We won't have this field.
- I know, but...
- Now, look.
I appreciate what you're trying to do.
But our job's to destroy everything
that'll be of use to those Japs.
Excuse me, but we can't move any gas.
- The trucks have all been wrecked.
- Scare up drums. Get it here.
- You can't get that ready in time to...
- We can.
- The bomb sight still in this airplane?
- Yes, sir. The one we "borrowed."
- We won't let...
- Give us a chance.
- I'd like to, but...
- Excuse me, sir.
I've been in this Army 20 years.
I've never asked a favor.
- We'll get her out. I give you my word.
- We'll burn her ourselves if we can't.
You're crazy. You know what'll happen
if the Japs move in?
- We do, sir.
- All the rest?
- Yes, sir.
- You'll burn her?
Yes, sir.
All right. It's your funeral.
Forget it, corporal.
- Yes, sir.
- Thank you, sir.
- Come on, boys. Let's...
- Excuse me, sir.
That observation plane is patched up
and ready to go.
But I'm gonna need a gunner.
- Lieutenant.
- Yes?
I'll need one of your gunners.
Which one can you spare?
- Well...
- I can go.
- Wait a minute.
- He shouldn't go.
- He's more useful here.
- He's right, sir.
- All right. Go ahead.
- Yes, sir.
- That kid's awfully green, lieutenant.
- I know.
- Come on, give us a hand.
- Okay.
Don't like him leaving Mary Ann
this way. Ain't good luck.
Be back in a couple of hours.
Swing it wide.
- Put some muscle into it.
- Will I!
Where'd you find
that little beast, sergeant?
Beast?
He's a Marine Corps dog, lieutenant.
Yeah, I know. Hiya, Moto.
Hey, Moto, cut it out.
Cut it out.
Get him away, sergeant.
I've had enough trouble with Jap snipers
without getting hydrophobia.
- His name ain't Moto, it's Tripoli.
- What?
Yeah, Tripoli. Maybe he don't
like to be called Moto.
That's it. Cute trick, ain't it?
Yeah, very cute.
- How's it going, Rader?
- Not good. They're withdrawing to Bataan.
All I could get was a foxhole view
with my face in six inches of dirt.
I thought if I came back
I could get an airplane.
You've got a fat chance for that.
We got one 0-47 left.
We might get you to Batavia
or Port Darwin.
- They've got airplanes.
- We're getting out too.
- How about that B-17 I came in with?
- What? That crazy outfit?
They're working on it.
They've been up all night.
- Robbing the other wrecks for spare parts.
- Haven't got a chance getting it to fly.
- Forget it.
- But can I help them?
What kind of lunatics have we got
in this Air Corps?
- Don't you know what's impossible?
- Thank you, sir.
- Hey.
- Excuse me, colonel.
- What?
- Can't I lend a hand too?
- You can go straight to...
- Help, sir? Thank you, sir.
Come on, stay with me. Come on.
- Hello, Weinberg.
- Gee, it's the pursuit pilot.
- We thought you was in the infantry.
- It's too hard on the feet.
- Hi, fellas.
- Hi, Tex.
- Things get too tough for you?
- I came to see if I could give you a hand.
How you making out with Moto there?
I'm getting along fine, Tommy,
with Tripoli.
- I knew it all along, you morons.
- Sure, sure.
Looks like you guys got yourself a job.
- How about me and the Marine Corps?
- Listen to who's talking.
You asking to join this crew?
I'd rather fly than walk.
Even in this crate.
- Changed your mind, haven't you?
- No, but I'm willing to work my way.
Stop grinning and tell me what to do.
- Are you serious?
- Why, sure.
What we need is gas. I don't know
how you're gonna get it, but get it.
Take the Marine with you
so you can find your way back.
Okay, Callahan.
- Watch it now. Watch it.
- Pick up. Pick up the end.
All right. That's got her. Now, give me that.
Where's Weinberg?
- Left for oil. He'll be back.
- Okay.
Hey, those are Jap planes.
Get going, men.
Get on the guns.
Bring some more ammunition.
Good work, Robbie.
- Don't talk. Shoot.
- There's another one for you.
You dog!
Look, they're after the kid.
- They're gonna get him on the way down.
- Look out, kid.
Stay here, Weinberg.
Dirty...
I guess we'd better get him back now.
Yeah.
All right, now, boys, get on this lift.
Come on now.
Let's go. All together. Come on, heave.
- Well, there she is, sir.
- Think there's room in there to work a gun?
I'll show you.
Hand me the gun when I get in.
Okay.
It looks like it'll work all right.
The Japs are gonna get a surprise
when they come on the tail of this B-17.
What about the tail wheel?
- I can get through if you leave it down.
- Okay.
Got a full bomb load?
To the gills. Don't know
what we're gonna do with them.
Well, we can always drop them out.
- Hey, lieutenant?
- Yeah?
- Hand me a can of ammunition, will you?
- Coming up.
- Lieutenant, give us a hand here.
- Sure, let's go.
- Pull it in again. Here we go.
- How's that?
That's got her.
Now, get a couple of planks
across here, will you?
- Sounds like they're getting closer.
- We'll have to be out by daylight.
- We will.
- It's almost 5 now.
Weinberg just finished Number 3.
Yeah, but if Rader doesn't get back
with that gasoline soon we might as well...
- Who is it?
- Me, sir, Peterson and Callahan.
We got your gas, plenty.
- A whole truckload.
- Good.
- How we gonna get it out?
- Cans and buckets.
- Rader's bringing a bunch of soldiers.
- Here they are now.
- Where do you want it?
- Right where it is.
- Okay, men, let's get these drums out.
- Come on, snap into it.
Some of you get around behind.
Get around behind.
Good work, boys. Keep them going.
Step on it. Don't slop it.
Handle those cans careful.
Don't slop it around the plane.
Keep them level, keep them level.
Come on up here.
Okay, sarge. Number 4 will run.
- Fitter, get the cowling on.
- It's going on.
- Lieutenant, lieutenant.
- Yeah?
- Engines are ready.
- Good work. Thanks, kid.
- It's getting too close.
- Come on. Hurry it up.
- Don't spill it, don't spill it.
- Faster, men, with these buckets.
- Lieutenant Williams?
- Right here.
- They're coming. Through there.
- That'll have to be enough.
- Get everything clear to take her off.
- Yes. Hold that gas.
- Hold that gas.
- Drop those pails.
Give us a hand moving that shaft.
Come on. Get this stuff out of here.
Some get around to the front wheels.
Start her up
as soon as we're turned around.
- Winocki, get on the guns.
- Come on, Peterson.
Try and hold them off.
Get in, in the bomb sight.
Monk. You and Callahan,
siphon this gasoline.
If it won't start, we'll burn her.
Come on, get on this tail.
Come on now, shove her.
Straight back. Shove her.
- Hey!
- Hold it there!
That's all right.
Go ahead. Go ahead.
Keep going.
Okay.
Weinberg, get inside to help Rader.
Okay, that's far enough. Turn her around.
That's enough. Hold it.
Now, take her around. Come on.
Hard, now. Push. Everybody.
Come on. Take her around.
That's enough. That's enough.
That's far enough.
All right, soldiers.
Get going, soldiers. Run.
Keep clear of the props.
All clear. Start it, lieutenant.
Okay, stay clear.
- Get everybody out.
- Lieutenant.
But we've got to. Go on.
All right, bring over that gasoline.
Come on.
Don't burn it.
Hold it, hold it, hold it!
Get out of there. Get out.
Keep clear. Get away.
Go ahead, Tex.
Give it to her.
- Wheels up.
- Coming up.
That's all right, sir.
It's this one here, Robbie.
That's easy.
How are we doing, sir?
For a plane they said
would never fly again, we're fine.
- How's our fuel consumption?
- Nothing to worry about.
We'll make Australia all right.
- Peterson picked up news on the radio.
- What's that?
There's a Jap invasion fleet
headed for Australia.
That's what they think.
Our Pacific fleet's hunting for them.
I wish them luck.
You know, Tex...
you're a funny-looking thing
to be flying a B-17.
Yeah? I hope they got P-40s in Darwin.
If they haven't, I'm gonna take up knitting.
I think he's the guy that shot me in the arm
just so he could get in that seat.
Don't do me an injustice, Bill.
I'd only shoot you to get out this seat.
Why don't you fellas sleep
while you can?
We kind of got out of the habit.
How about it, Joe?
Is that tail gun of yours gonna work?
Just wait and see.
Hey, sergeant,
we gonna stop at Mindanao?
- No, we've already passed there.
- Yeah?
You look like you know
how to work that gun, Callahan.
What do you think a Marine uses,
a bow and arrow?
I wouldn't put it past them.
Navigator to pilot.
Take a look down below.
On the left, right under us.
- Holy smoke.
- Boy, look at that.
Looks like we hit the jackpot.
- Here we go again.
- Start shooting.
- Those are Japs.
- What'll we do?
- Pull up through the clouds.
- Going up.
Where we going?
Give me a crack at them.
Hold your horses. Get below.
We're gonna start a war, not a fight.
Four degrees north, 124 degrees east.
Okay. Pilot to radio.
Did you hear that, Peterson?
Write it down.
Four north, 124 east. Got it?
Four north, 124 east.
Contact all air bases in this area.
Army, Navy, carriers,
everyone you can reach.
Tell them we sighted
a big Jap task force headed south.
- Give them that position.
- Yes, sir.
We're gonna play hide-and-seek
until they get here.
- Radio to pilot.
- Go ahead, Peterson.
Army bombers and Navy torpedo planes
have reached the approximate position.
Their formation leader's calling you
on the command set.
Okay.
Williams in 05564 talking. Go ahead.
Hello, Bill. This is Jack Harper.
We're looking for you. Where are you?
Hiya, Jack. We're at 14,000.
There they are.
Where are those Japs
you're worrying about, Bill?
We're roosting right over them.
Just make a turn and follow us.
Turning now.
Pilot to crew. Get ready, fellas.
This ought to be fun.
- Let's go calling, Tex.
- Yeah, man.
Now you're gonna see
what an Air Force can do.
- How do you want it?
- The cruiser third from the right.
Take her in line,
I'll pour them down their funnels.
- Don't waste any eggs, Popeye.
- You watch the basket, I'll lay the eggs.
Bomb bay doors opening.
Hold it.
- Ready to bomb.
- Hold it.
Slide right.
Left a little.
To the left.
Steady.
Bombs away.
Here they come. Weinberg to pilot.
About nine Japs a little above us,
around 4 o'clock.
Wait for them and make them count.
Monk, coming down, straight ahead.
- Did you get hit?
- Sure, I got hit.
- Do you need some...?
- Watch out.
- Did you see that?
- What do you want, a cigar?
They're coming in on our tail.
Wait for them. They don't know
we got a stinger in our tail.
- Which one now, Tommy?
- Let's take that carrier straight ahead.
Okay.
- What do you think of our bomber now?
- Boy, I'll take it for mine.
We gotta get out of here.
We just lost half our gas.
Attention.
All right, men. At ease.
Turn that thing off, Henson.
Well, gentlemen...
this is it.
This is what we've been waiting for.
Tonight, your target is Tokyo.
You're gonna play them the "Star
Spangled Banner" with two-ton bombs.
You've got to remember
what you've learned...
and follow your squadron leaders.
They'll get you in
and they'll get you out too.
Williams, you lead the first section.
Rader, the second.
Hauser will navigate
for the entire squadron...
and McMartin will talk to you
bombardiers before taking off.
Any questions?
All right, that's all.
Good luck to you and give them hell.
We shall carry the attack
against the enemy.
We shall hit him and hit him again...
wherever and whenever
we can reach him.
For we intend to bring
this battle to him...
on his own home grounds.