Passengers arriving
on Philippine Airlines
flight 118,
welcome to Manila
International Airport.
Those passengers flying on...
Hey.
Hey, kid!
Are you Zack?
Yes, sir.
I'm Byron. Nice to meet you.
Come on. Let's get
your bags, okay?
Yes, sir.
Take your jacket off, kid.
It's hot as hell here.
This is the P. I. It's what
we call the Philippine Islands.
I'm sorry about what
happened to your mom.
It must have been
pretty rough, huh?
I would have called
you a lot sooner,
but I was out at sea.
But I've been calling
you for four months.
That's what I'm
trying to tell you.
I was out at sea
for four months.
All right, kid.
These are your mama-sans,
Tiki and Maria.
Hello, Byron.
I want you to meet somebody.
This is my son,
Zack. Tiki, say hello.
Zack, Tiki and Maria.
Hi, Zack.
Hi.
I'm out at sea three
weeks out of every month.
When I'm back in port,
I don't have time for this daddy
stuff, because that's not who I am.
That's okay, sir.
Wait a second, kid,
you don't understand.
I'm too old for this.
I don't care what the Navy says,
this is no place to bring up a kid.
Like I told you on
the telephone...
you're better off in that
state school back in Virginia.
I'm never going back!
They treat me like shit.
Maybe that's not for you to say!
Goddamn it! Don't
look at me that way!
What happened to your mother
had nothing to do with me.
It did! You said
you'd come back!
Is that what she said? That's
a female lie. That's bullshit!
That's a lie!
I found your letters,
and I read them
after she did it!
You said you were going to come
back for us. You said you loved her,
and she believed you!
You're a liar!
Grow up, boy. I'll wait
for you. Cherry boy.
Want to go to school?
I'll teach you nice.
Whoo! Whoo! Whoo!
Chicken feet, monkey
meat. Come on, you buy.
You buy. Monkey
meat. You buy. You buy.
Hey, sailor. What
ship are you from?
Hey! What are you doing?
Big spender, give us money.
I don't have any.
Bullshit!
No!
Leave me alone!
Leave me alone.
Holy shit.
Watch it. I got to heave.
Jesus Christ.
Give me a towel.
Pretty fuckin' wild.
Holy shit.
Not as wild as that night
we banged those three
stewardesses in Manila.
Bet you didn't
get it on like that
in that jerkwater college
you graduated from.
How long are you going
to hang around Seattle?
Get ready, man. This one
is going to blow you away.
Nothing you do is ever
going to surprise me.
Tell me.
I joined the Navy.
You joined the Navy.
That's right. I joined the Navy.
I'm on my way to
Port Rainier now,
this officer's training
school over there.
What for?
Jets. I want to fly jets.
It's only a couple
of hours from here.
Maybe you'll want to
come visit me sometime.
Who put that idea in your head?
Nobody. It just come to me.
What's so funny?
You, man.
It's like saying you're
running for fuckin' president.
Christ, look at yourself.
Officers don't have tattoos.
Look, I'll see you,
man, all right?
Hey.
Zack, come on.
Don't be pissed off.
I'm not pissed off.
You are pissed off.
Come on, I'm on your side.
Don't do something
you'll regret.
You got to give up six
fucking years to the Navy
if you want to fly.
Six fucking years
with the most uptight
assholes God put on this Earth.
Officers, man, they're
not like you and me.
They're a different breed.
You're afraid you might have
to salute me someday, Chief.
Bullshit! Why the
fuck would I be afraid?
I don't know. It kind
of sounds that way.
You want some fatherly
bullshit, a pat on the back.
From you? No.
No.
Thanks for my
graduation present.
I'll see you around.
Don't go away mad.
Hey, baby.
Zack, come on.
Zack!
Fall in!
I said fall in, you slimy worms!
Put your toes
on that chalk line!
I said put your toes on the
chalk line, you slimy worms!
A-ten-hut!
I don't believe what I'm seeing.
Where you been all
your lives... At an orgy?
Listening to Mick Jagger music
and bad-mouthing
your country, I'll bet.
You better stop
eyeballing me, boy.
You're not worthy enough
to look your
superiors in the eye.
Use your peripheral
vision. Understand?
Yes, sir.
Every time I say "Understand,"
everyone says, "Yes,
sir!" Understand?
Yes, sir!
Understand?
I know why most of you are here.
I'm not stupid.
Before you get to
sell what we teach you
over at United Airlines,
you'll give the Navy
six years of your life.
Lots of things can
happen in six years.
Another war could come up.
If you're too peaceful to
napalm an enemy village
where there might be
women and children,
I'm going to find that out.
Understand?
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir!
Hi, son.
How you doing, Sarge?
What did you call me?
Beg your pardon?
What did you call me, boy?
- Sarge.
- Before that.
I didn't call you
anything before that.
You said, "How are you?"
A ewe is a female sheep.
You think that's what I am?
No.
No, sir!
No, sir.
Louder, sweet pea!
No, sir!
Hey. You want to
fuck me up the ass?
You a queer?
Hell no, sir!
Where are you from, boy?
Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, sir.
Ah!
Only two things come
out of Oklahoma...
Steers and queers.
Which one are you, boy?
I don't see no horns.
You must be a queer.
No, sir.
Stop whispering, sweet pea.
You're giving me a hard-on.
No, sir!
You laughing at me, dickbrain?
Stop eyeballing me, boy,
or I'll rip your eyeballs out
and skullfuck you to death.
Yes, sir!
What's your name, boy?
Mayo. Zack Mayo, sir!
How did you slip
into this program?
I didn't know the
Navy was so hard up.
You got an injury there, Mayo?
Not exactly, sir.
Hey, this is really
wonderful work.
Where did you get this?
Subic Base, Philippines, sir.
Ah. Thought I
recognized the work.
Be proud of them wings.
They're the only ones
you'll leave here with,
Mayo-nnaise!
What's your name, boy?
Emiliano Santos
Della Serra, sir.
Mmm-hmm. You don't say?
You a college boy?
Yes, sir! Math major, sir.
Graduated from Texas
Tech with honors, sir!
I see.
You see this cane, Della Serra?
See the notches near the handle?
There's a notch for
every college puke like you
that I got to D.O.R...
Drop on request...
From this program.
The first one I'm
carving out of this class
is you, Emiliano.
I expect to lose half of
you before I'm finished.
I will use every means
necessary, fair and unfair,
to trip you up,
to expose your weaknesses
as an aviator and as a
human being. Understand?
Yes, sir!
The prize at the other end
is a flight education
worth $1 million!
But first, you got
to get past me!
Hey, Paula!
It's 5:00!
Where's the goddamn whistle?
Oh, shit!
Whoo!
Come on, Paula. Let's go!
Next!
Oh, shit.
This is my idea
of an ass bandit.
Wait till the girls see
you, scrotumhead.
Ha ha ha! Scrotumhead.
Think that's funny, Worley?
Not all the obstacles
are on this base.
Let me tell you
about the local girls.
Ever since there's
been a naval base here,
there's been the
Puget Sound debs.
Poor girls come across
the Sound every weekend
with just one thing in mind,
and that's to marry
themselves a naval aviator.
♪ You want me to leave
You want me to stay ♪
A Puget deb will tell you,
"Don't worry about
contraceptives.
I've got that taken care of."
Don't believe it, sweet pea.
A Puget deb will do anything
and say anything to trap you.
I know this sounds silly to you,
especially in this so-called modern age,
but you scuzzy college
pukes had better watch out
'cause they're out there.
And you, sweet peas, are
the answer to their dreams!
♪ Treat me right ♪
♪ Open your eyes
Maybe you'll see the light ♪
♪ Oh, treat me right ♪
Hurry up! On the double!
You lard asses, I'll fix you!
Get up in there!
On the double, Mayonnaise!
Little girl poopies to the left,
little boy poopies, right!
Come on, let's go!
What a motley bunch!
Get in there!
All right, quick! On the double!
How's it going?
They've got to be kidding.
How do they expect
me to get down there?
One of you guys
want to switch bunks?
Those are assigned bunks, man.
I don't think we can.
Hey, Daniels, you're in there.
Who the hell is that guy?
Your mom and dad
for the next 13 weeks.
All right, fall out!
Get outside! On the double!
Come on out here!
Quick! Out the door!
On the double!
Quick!
More! More! More!
Give me 50.
Count them for me!
Think it's true
about those girls,
Puget debs?
Sure.
Should have warned
you female types
about the Puget dudes.
They say they're
wearing rubbers,
but there's really a hole
bitten in the bottom.
Very funny.
Seeger, Mayo, Worley! Got
enough energy to run them sewers,
give me 50! On the double!
Right now!
Poopie asses, get your
faces on down there!
You women better not
expect special privileges!
You think flying a plane
is just sitting on a
chair pushing buttons?
You need more upper-body
strength, See-gar!
Ugh!
All right, get up.
Get up!
Step out!
Back in line! You watch!
The pilots off the Lexington
ought to be at
the officers club.
You sure got the timetable down.
After three years,
you learn all the tricks.
You see that
bodacious set of tatas?
Hi. The social committee
wanted these records.
You're pissing me off, boys!
38...
39...
The Blue Angels are coming.
If you need an
introduction, let me know.
Far fucking out!
Shh!
I've always wanted
to meet a Blue Angel.
Look at those poor poopies.
See you during your liberty!
It grows an inch by then!
You ain't going to be
liberty for you boys.
You'll be home before then.
Start from one again!
1...
- 2...
- 3...
Flyin' low and feelin' mean.
Spot a family by a stream.
Pickle a pair and
hear 'em scream.
'Cause napalm sticks to kids.
That's disgusting!
What are you doing here, Seeger?
Am I threatening you?
You'll get your ass shot down.
I wouldn't mind being the
first woman combat flier.
Go in my place.
Jets?
Uh-huh.
Mayo?
Jets.
Only two go to jets.
Who's going with me?
- Me!
Talking in the ranks again.
You three just added 2 miles
to this little hike
for everybody.
Family of gooks
all sittin' in a ditch!
Little baby suckin'
on his mama's tit!
Chemical firms
don't give a shit!
That napalm sticks to kids!
Get up here! Up those stairs!
Let's go! Come on!
Go!
Move! Move! Move!
Go! Get up here!
Move it up here!
Come on, let's go!
Come on, let's go! Go!
Get up here! Move!
Get up here!
All right, everybody,
on your feet!
I don't want to see nothing
coming out of your mouths either!
Let's get in shape around here!
Stand straight up!
All right, get out of the way!
Lift your head and hold it high.
Lift your head and hold it high!
The best in the
regiment is runnin' on by.
regiment is runnin' on by!
That could be you
after 13 weeks...
Those who might survive!
You don't deserve
to look at them!
Della Serra, turn your back!
You are the most pathetic class
I've ever been assigned to!
You big chump.
Four weeks, and you
still can't shine a buckle.
Shoot me a Kotex, buddy.
Be careful where you stick that.
Five minutes to
inspection, Mayo.
Where's your money?
Boonies.
You better hope Foley
never finds out about that.
Hey, Perryman.
Look what I got here.
Ooh...
Look at that.
Look at them buckles.
Look good, huh?
10 bucks.
15 for the boonies.
Who the hell's got 10 bucks?
I spend every penny
keeping my family in that motel.
You're breaking
my heart, Perryman.
Who's doing this for you?
Some enlisted guy, right?
Hey, tell me something.
Watch the sheets.
Is that piss-ass
change you making
worth all of us getting
kicked out of here
on an honors violation, huh?
I don't see anybody else
complaining about it, Perryman.
Ready...
Go!
Look out, Worley,
coming through.
The hell you say, son.
Here I come.
My name's going on that wall.
Underneath mine.
Fuck!
Aahhh!
Give me the rope!
Shit!
Goddamn, Mayonnaise!
10:25. Not bad...
for a beginner.
Piece of cake.
Let's go! Come on, Schneider!
Come on, Schneider!
Let's go! Let's go!
Kick ass!
Let's go! You're
bringing up the rear!
You ain't getting out of here
till you get over
that wall, See-gar.
I'll make it, sir!
Hurry up.
Come on. Get over there!
You really want to
be a man, See-gar?
You didn't get enough
of your daddy's attention
'cause he really wanted a son?
That's what'll beat you
every time, See-gar.
The mental attitude of a
person of the female persuasion.
Deep down under
all that bullshit,
you're still thinking like
a second-class citizen!
You can never
give orders to men!
Aw, walk around.
Walk around... sugar britches.
Bernoulli's Equation gives
us the total amount of energy
contained in the air flow.
"P" is static pressure in
pounds per square foot.
"Rho" is air density
in slugs per cubic foot,
and velocity is in
feet per second.
2,000 pounds per square foot
for your static pressure.
Air density of 1,
which is sea level.
Let's see them.
What about the buckles?
Okay. All right.
20 bucks, right?
Hey, bud.
Beat it.
What are you laughing about?
I thought that's how you did it.
Did what?
Did what? Come on, Santy Claus.
You aren't going
to tell, are you?
Not if you make
it worth my while.
Free boonies for the duration.
That's fair.
Tell you what.
You get me through aerodynamics,
you can write your
own ticket, my friend.
You got a deal.
♪ I'm comin' home,
I've done my time ♪
♪ And I got to know
what is and isn't mine ♪
♪ If you received my letter ♪
♪ Tellin' you I'd soon be free ♪
♪ Then you know
just what to do ♪
♪ If you still want me ♪
♪ If you still want me... ♪
George Jones, where are
you when we need you?
♪ It's been three long years ♪
♪ Do you still want me? ♪
♪ If I don't see a ribbon ♪
♪ 'Round the old oak tree... ♪♪
Hey, 2:00. Moving
in. Della Serra.
Radar's up. Scoping
the target area.
Uh-oh, zero in.
Slick it back.
Who'll be the lucky deb?
Is it the blonde?
Is it the brunette?
Score! He got her.
Oh, my God, check Perryman.
Five years of
marriage, still in love.
That's what life's all about.
Aah-oooh!
- Hey, See-gar!
Hey, Zack,
remember those
bodacious tatas and her pal?
Right there they are, bud.
We ought to do
something about it.
So nice to meet you.
The boys speak highly of you.
Lynette, he has
several people to meet.
I'm so sorry.
Captain Rufferwell.
Mrs. Rufferwell!
Hello, Captain.
How are you?
Could you introduce
us to these ladies?
Paula, Lynette.
Miss Paula Pokrifki,
Miss Lynette Pomeroy,
may I present
Officer Candidate Sid Worley
and Officer Candidate
Zachary Mayo.
Well, I hope you
have a good time.
We already met.
We did?
Uh-huh.
You said it would
grow an inch by now.
That was you guys?
Yeah.
Would you like to dance?
Sure.
It's grown out more
than an inch, pal.
Would you like to get a drink?
Sure.
Let's go.
What kind of name is Pokrifki?
Polish. What kind
of a name is Mayo?
Italian. My mom was Irish.
No, thanks.
I think I got her ears.
The rest is all wop.
Where are you
from, Mayo the wop?
Everywhere, nowhere...
Paula the Polack.
Seriously.
My father's a rear
admiral, 7th Fleet.
You're kidding.
No. We lived in ports
all over the world.
Katmandu...
Moscow, Nairobi.
Really?
Hell, I've never been
out of Washington.
Wait a minute.
You're kidding me, right?
We don't have any
naval bases in Moscow.
No.
No, I didn't think so.
So, you got a girl,
Mayo the wop?
No.
I ain't looking for one either.
What are you looking for?
I've heard about these girls
who come here
looking for a husband.
Not me.
Yeah?
Why are you here?
To meet interesting people,
improve myself.
What do you do, go to school?
No, I got a job.
I work at National Paper.
It's a real good job.
I'm saving money to travel.
Think I'd like to go to Moscow.
You been through
the Dilbert Dunker yet?
My father and my
brother made it through.
I guess I can, too.
Oh, is your brother a flier?
He was. He got killed.
Vietnam?
Yeah.
My brother died over there, too.
He wasn't no flier, though.
I was only 12 when it happened.
I really don't remember
much about him.
I sure remember Tommy.
Mind if we talk about
something else?
We don't have to talk
about anything at all.
Think you'll make it
to getting your wings?
Who knows?
Guys a lot smarter than me
been dropping out like flies.
You've got to program yourself.
It'll happen.
You just got to see
yourself making it.
I read this article
in Cosmo about that.
I swear.
Paula...
you are a very,
very pretty girl.
Do you want to go
somewhere else?
Come on.
Fall out, Worley.
Something tells me you
girls have been here before.
Whatever gave you that idea?
Oh, stop it!
You're going to ruin it.
I'm sorry.
I'll do it.
You sure this is okay?
Don't worry. I'll respect
you in the morning.
You're crazy, girl.
You'll respect me.
Couldn't wait to
get out of there.
Didn't you like the band?
Not much.
You didn't like Tie
A Yellow Ribbon?
I thought their rendition was...
Let's go down to the beach.
That sounds good.
Halt!
Fall out!
Look at Foley.
Do you believe it?
Showboat.
All right, listen up.
I'm the base martial
arts instructor.
You must desist
in thinking of me
as the drill instructor.
Just think of me...
as the enemy.
Do you believe this guy?
May I have a volunteer, please?
Daniels.
Get up here.
Put him in the hospital.
He can't touch me.
It's against the law.
Come on, Topper!
Come on up here, son.
Hang tough, buddy!
Hello, pussy.
How bad do you want to survive?
This officer candidate doesn't
understand the question.
Let's see if I can
clarify it a little.
You want to stop me, pussy?
Are you relying on my generosity
to stop me from killing you?
I can't breathe.
Break loose.
Break loose!
I can't... breathe.
Get away from here!
You're not hurt.
I could have killed you.
Move off.
Get out of here!
Get back to your seat!
You think I was really
harsh on your classmate?
Wait until you get shot
down behind enemy lines.
The only thing between
you and a P.O.W. camp
is what you learn from me.
Now that I got your attention,
we shall proceed with the class.
God, I hope she shows.
She's going to show.
A rich, socialite Okie like you
ought to be a big catch here.
I ain't rich.
You're an officer's kid.
So what?
Man, I spent six years
living right on top of the
raunchiest whorehouse in the P.I.
"Oy! Oy, palequero!
You want numbah one fucky-fucky?
Long time, short time.
$10! Cheap-cheap!"
10 bucks?
"10 dollah. 10 dollah!"
Lynette, honey,
how's it hanging?
Don't drool on her, boy.
Hi.
Pansy-ass fly-boys.
I remember you.
Mayo the wop.
Yep, that's me.
It's good to see you.
I was looking forward to it.
Me, too.
Yeah.
Uh, excuse me.
You guys want to
just hang out here,
or can I suggest
an alternate plan?
Like pick up a bottle
and go to a motel?
Just like that. Yeah.
What do you think?
Huh?
I'll vote for a motel.
My kind of group.
Troy, here they come.
Well! Make way
for the warmongers.
What did you call us?
I called you a warmonger.
Ain't that what you are?
Yeah, right.
I'd like to ask you something.
What do you want?
You come up here,
you rich college boys.
You're strutting around
in your ice cream outfits
like you own the goddamn place.
Who do you think you are?
Man, I don't want to fight you.
Got that? I don't want to fight.
Go back inside and cool down.
I ain't finished
talking, sailor boy!
Oh, God.
That's enough, man.
Oh, shit! Check his nose.
He broke his nose, man.
You asshole! Faggot!
God, I never seen
anything like that in my life.
Did you see that guy's nose?
Lynette, will you
just shut up, please?
Well, excuse me for living.
Asshole!
I should have walked away.
Zack, he didn't
give you a choice.
A man's always got a choice.
Where did you learn
how to fight like that?
I don't want to talk
about it now, all right?
All right.
It wouldn't kill you
to open up to me.
What do you want,
you want to fuck?
Get on the bed.
Take your clothes off.
I'll give you a good fuck.
Where's that coming from?
I wouldn't fuck you now...
Then get the hell out!
Who do you think
you're talking to?
I'm not some whore
you brought in here.
I'm trying to be your friend.
Then be a friend.
Get out of here.
Fine.
Man, you ain't nothing special.
You got no manners. You
treat women like whores.
You got no chance
of being no officer.
Hey. Shh!
Shh!
It's okay.
It's all right.
Shh!
I'm sorry.
Are you hungry?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm starved.
Skivvies?
Pretty sexy, huh?
Sporty.
Control yourself, baby.
Ahh!
Mmm, good!
Look, Paula...
I try real hard not
to fool anybody
about who I am,
what I want.
I know who you are
and what you want.
And what do you want?
I want to have a good time
until you have to leave.
That's it?
Mm-hmm.
Hey!
Last night was incredible.
I thought so, too.
Zack, am I your fantasy?
What?
I dare you not to
fall in love with me.
How can you
resist? I'm like candy.
You're better than candy.
It's going to be hard to
get enough, very hard.
Very hard!
You're getting feisty on me,
you little cocky Polack!
What do you do with a girl
when you're through with her?
You say something
or just disappear, huh?
I never had a girl.
I forgot to thank
you for breakfast.
Anytime, sailor.
Heads up, Perryman.
When you hit the water,
you might get the wind
knocked out of you. Don't panic.
You've got a second and a half
before the cage
flips upside-down.
Go, Joe!
Now, the most important thing
is to watch your bubbles.
When that cage
flips upside-down,
you're going to be disoriented.
You won't have your bearings,
like Perryman down there.
The bubbles will
determine which way is up.
Holy shit.
All right, time's up.
Go down for him, Jason.
If you panic, you
can die down there,
and this is only
a swimming pool.
Out in the Pacific,
you won't have a
frogman to save your ass.
Totally unsatisfactory,
Perryman.
Do it again.
Two more chances to
make it, or you're out.
All right. Next!
Hold it. Change in order.
Mayo...
since you're
hotshot of the week,
you're next.
Aye, aye, sir.
Seeger, you're behind him.
Yes, sir.
You ought to be
good at this, Mayo.
Something you can do alone.
Take him up, Joe!
You never know when this program
will trip you up, huh, Mayo?
It could be the grade
or some little flaw
in your character
that comes out under stress.
Let it go, Joe!
All right, way to go!
Okay, Seeger. You're next.
Okay, Seeger, let's go.
Get a move on.
Joe, take her up!
Don't you cry now,
sugar britches!
Go, Joe!
All right, Seeger! Whoo!
All right.
Good girl.
Oh, gosh, that was great!
Think they'd let us do it again?
Not bad, Seeger.
But you still got to
get over that wall.
Next!
Daniels, move it.
Take it easy now.
Just a joyride.
Does this hit with
a plane's impact?
It's nothing
compared to a plane.
Don't forget to
watch the bubbles.
Okay, Joe, take him up!
All right, Daniels.
Let's have that thumbs up.
Come on. Where's
the thumbs up at?
All right. Go, Joe!
Hold it. Take it easy.
Pull it up!
Can't get it right now!
All right, let me through!
Grab him!
All right, pull him out!
Hold him!
Put him on his stomach!
Take his helmet off!
Goddamn!
Take it off.
Oh, Christ!
He killed himself.
Somebody get me a corpsman.
On the double!
Yes, sir!
Okay. Everybody just stand back.
Come on, Topper.
Oh, God!
Come on.
Come on, buddy.
Come on, man.
Come on, Topper.
Come on.
Breathe, man. Breathe.
Hey!
All right.
All right!
Is the corpsman on the way?
Yeah.
Stand back.
Give him room.
Get back.
Somebody go check
on that corpsman.
He's going to be all right.
Take it easy.
Prepare for inspection!
Shit.
I am not going to make it.
Help me out, Sid.
Got a spare, man?
My spare sucks.
You know where
the hardware store is.
Zack, I need a buckle, man.
I can't risk it.
You got time. He's up there.
Can't do it.
I got to see my
family this weekend.
Wouldn't want you to get
an honor violation, Perryman.
Okay.
Attention on deck!
In every class,
there's always one joker who
thinks he's smarter than me.
In this class, that
happens to be you,
isn't it, Mayonnaise?
Perryman, Worley...
let us have this room.
On the double.
Couldn't happen to a nicer guy.
Stow it.
Mayo...
I want your D.O.R.
No, sir.
You can kick me
out, but I ain't quitting.
Get into your fatigues, Mayo.
By the end of this weekend,
you'll quit.
Casey Jones was
a son of a bitch!
Drove his train
in a 30-foot ditch!
Came on out with
his dick in his hand.
Said, "Listen, ladies,
I'm a hell of a man."
Went to his room and
lined up a hundred.
Swore up and down
he'd fuck every one.
Fucked 98 till his
balls turned blue.
Then he backed off,
jacked off, and
fucked the other two!
He backed off,
jacked off, and
fucked the other two!
Wave good-bye to your buddies.
I forgot. You don't
have buddies.
Only customers.
You having fun, Mayonnaise?
Yes, sir!
Don't hear you!
98...
99...
Get your face all the
way down in there!
100.
You ready to quit now, Mayo?
No, sir!
Look over there, Mayo.
Look at her.
She decided to stay
instead of taking
liberty this weekend.
She may not make it,
but she's got more
heart and character
than you'll ever have!
Life's dealt you some
shitty cards, hasn't it?
I'm doing all right, sir!
6...
Bullshit.
I done some checking.
I looked through your files.
I know about your mama.
I know your
father's an alcoholic
and a whore chaser.
That's why you don't mesh,
because deep down...
Don't you eyeball me, boy!
Deep down inside...
you know the others
are better than you!
Isn't that right, Mayo?
No, sir!
What's the matter, Mayo?
You getting tired?
I'm not tired.
Move it, boy!
This is where the fun starts.
Move it!
You got all day tomorrow
to look forward to!
6 inches off the ground.
Give me 6 to 90.
Why don't we quit
this little charade
over a couple of beers at TJ's?
You're as close to
officer material as me.
This candidate believes
he'd make a good officer.
You only give a
shit about yourself.
All your classmates know it.
They wouldn't trust you
behind a plane's controls.
You'd probably steal my F-14
and sell it to the Cubans.
No, sir! I love my country.
Sell it to the Air Force, Mayo.
Talk to me.
Why would a slick
hustler like you
sign up for this abuse?
I want to fly jets.
So does my grandmama.
I've wanted to
since I was a kid.
We're not talking about flying.
We're talking about character.
I've changed since
I've been here.
The hell you have.
I've changed, sir!
You've just polished your act.
You've just shined it up!
Now, tell me what
I want to hear.
I want your D.O.R.
I ain't going to quit.
Spell it!
D-O-R.
Then you and your daddy
can go whore-chasing together!
No, sir! I ain't going to quit!
Then you can forget it.
You're out!
Don't you do it!
Don't... you...
I got nowhere else to go!
I ain't got nothing else.
I got nothing else.
All right, Mayo.
On your feet.
Let's get back to the barracks.
Hey, Foley!
Zack, don't give up!
You got that queer on the run!
Oh, no!
Kiss this, Foley!
Hang in there, Zack!
Those friends of yours?
Don't give up, Mayo!
Yes, sir.
We're with you, Zack!
Don't quit, Zack!
You can make it!
You got some urinals to clean.
Move out.
Hey, Foley's a queer!
He got his balls
shot off in the war!
You're still here, huh, Mayo?
Sid.
Yeah?
Thanks.
Sid.
Look at that.
That son of a bitch.
Want me to get a towel?
I'll get one.
I don't want you to move.
I don't want to move.
Somebody's got to move sometime.
Eventually.
"They found them
there weeks later,
shriveled from lack
of food and water."
Bye, Zachary.
I laughed all week,
thinking about you
guys on that boat.
We were so drunk.
That looks...
pretty sharp, Paula.
Pretty sharp.
I'd love to be
one of those girls
in the flight program.
I think it would
be a gas to fly.
So what's stopping you?
You know, those
magazines, what they say,
it's just... I don't know.
It's not so easy for a girl.
That's no excuse for
not getting what you want.
Just go get it.
Who says I'm not
going after what I want?
Not me.
My mama's 39 years old.
She still works
over at that factory.
Every time I look at her,
I know exactly
what I don't want.
My old lady...
took a bottle of pills one
day when I was at school.
Oh, God.
The thing that
got me about it...
she didn't leave a note.
Nothing. She just checked out.
I always hated her for that.
Oh, God.
That must really hurt.
Hurt? No.
You're all alone in the world.
Once you got that down,
nothing hurts anymore.
I bet most people
would buy that line
when you feed it to them.
Hmm?
Hey, are you really serious
about having him over?
I haven't made up my mind yet.
How far would
you go to get Zack?
What do you mean?
You know what I mean.
Would you let
yourself get pregnant?
No way, Lynette.
Come on. Would you?
I never used to think
I'd do something like that.
I don't know anymore.
Nine weeks ain't long enough
for a guy to fall in love.
That doesn't
justify trapping him.
Getting pregnant?
What a thought.
It's real backward.
It ain't any more backward
than the way these
hotshot assholes use us
till they've had enough,
then ditch us like we's trash.
Don't you ever feel used, Paula?
Don't you feel the son of
a bitch should pay for it?
No. I never feel like that.
Well, I do.
Thanks again for the flowers.
It was my pleasure.
Those are the most
beautiful things I ever saw.
Wipe that stuff off your mouth.
Zack?
This is great.
Sir?
How many more
weeks till graduation?
Oh, I've got three more.
Three more weeks.
Those are the
roughest, aren't they?
That's what they tell me.
Sir, why do you keep
staring at my food?
Or are you staring at me?
Not staring at you.
He doesn't mean anything by it.
Do you, Joe?
No. I don't mean anything by it.
Like some more chicken, Zack?
No. No, thanks.
I've had it.
I can't eat another bite.
I'm stuffed, too.
This is the best meal
I've had in a long time.
Let's go, Zack.
Thank you, Mama.
Thank you, Zack.
Thanks again, ma'am.
Go on and eat.
Mama, mama!
I'm sorry. I'm so
embarrassed, Zack.
I shouldn't have
brought you here.
That's okay. A great free meal.
A nice, relaxing meal.
Those people are so uptight.
I felt so sorry for you.
Don't feel sorry for me.
I'm used to it. It's hereditary.
After this, you go to basic
flight in Pensacola, right?
Yeah. Pensacola.
And, uh...
going to Beeville, Texas,
when I get jets.
So, after that...
don't you think about...
I mean, come on.
What's after that?
Family, kids...
Don't you think about all that?
No.
Is that what you think about?
Sometimes.
If I could do a
better job than them,
I'd love it.
What would you do different?
Everything.
First, I'd marry a
man I really loved.
So why did your
mom marry this guy
if she didn't love him?
My real father
wouldn't marry her.
Your real father?
My real father.
I want to show
you my real father.
Pop.
Your real father was an
officers candidate like me?
About 22 years ago.
Jesus.
No wonder this guy
was looking at me funny.
He always looks funny.
It's time I got
back to the wars.
I know, I know.
Thank your mom for dinner, okay?
Great chicken, huh?
I loved the chicken.
If you get a chance,
why don't you call me?
I have survival
training this week,
so I can't make any promises.
No promises.
I didn't have to
show you that picture
if I didn't want to.
I wanted to tell you that.
I know.
Be careful on that thing.
Yeah.
You and Paula still seeing
those flight candidates?
Any reason we wouldn't be?
3:40 in the afternoon.
You haven't said what
you're doing this weekend.
Hi. I'd like to speak
with Zack Mayo.
Could you look for him?
Tell him it's Paula.
Liberty time, boys and girls.
Fall out!
Aye, aye, sir!
Whoo-hoo!
Where's my bread?
Come on, Perryman. Come on.
Seeger, don't forget TJ's.
I won't.
Hey, Mayo, you got a call.
Somebody named Paula.
Tell her I already split.
Whoo!
I see.
Okay.
Right after survival training,
they start thinking they
can make it without you.
Suddenly, they stop calling.
Suddenly, they own
the goddamn world.
They said that he already left.
I don't think he did.
He hasn't called by
now, he won't call.
Bunny, just shut up!
You don't know so much.
Clock me out, Lynette.
Paula, what are you doing?
May they all crash and burn.
Paula, wait!
Where are you going?
Let me go, Mama.
You're going to look for Zack.
Don't do it.
I love him.
I can't let him run off.
How you going to stop him?
I'll think of a way.
No!
No?
I can't let you do this.
Don't go. Please don't go.
What are you crying about?
'Cause I know
what you're feeling!
What am I feeling?
Don't do it. Let him go.
Don't trick him or trap him.
I wouldn't do that.
I'd never try to trap him.
If you find him,
you'll say anything.
And God help you after that.
Mama, you're right.
Daddy, Zack's 2/10 of a second
off the obstacle course record.
He'll break it before he leaves.
Lucky you weren't
here when I was.
You couldn't quit
like you can now.
When I and my oldest
boy went through it,
you quit, you became a swabby.
That's interesting, sir.
How come you
haven't written Susan?
We haven't had time to write.
I've only written y'all once.
It's incredible.
Right?
Oh, yeah.
Who is this Susan?
That's my girl back home.
I'm marrying her
when I get out of here.
She was Tommy's girl.
They were supposed to get
married before he got killed.
I never told you
because I didn't want
you to think I was a shit
for fucking Lynette.
Man, I ain't your parents.
Do you love this girl?
Greatest chick you'll ever know.
She loves kids.
Works with handicapped
kids every afternoon.
That ain't what
I'm talking about.
I asked you if you loved her.
Everybody loves her.
I won't make that
reunion tonight.
Why not?
I'm meeting
Lynette at the Tides.
Best head in 52 states.
What can I do?
No, no, no.
You should've done what I did...
Break it off clean,
have it done with, over.
It's the best.
She was torn up
you didn't call her.
I'm not supposed
to tell you that.
Women. Women, women, women.
They say, "A good
time, a lot of laughs,
no problems."
Doesn't work that way, does it?
Look out, TJ's!
Here I come.
See you later, man.
What are you smiling about?
You're lucky you're here.
What are you talking about?
A toast.
We made it. To survival.
To survival.
In spite of Perryman.
Uh-uh. In spite of Foley.
Is that your deb over there?
She's pulling rank on you.
That's a flight
instructor she's with.
Back in a minute.
What are you doing here?
It was time for me to see TJ's
once before I left.
You come here a lot?
Once in a while.
I'm sorry I didn't call.
This week's been unbelievable.
It's okay.
How did survival training go?
I survived.
You survived. Obviously.
How was your week?
It was good.
I might get a raise next month.
That's great.
You guys are graduating
in a couple of weeks?
Yeah.
I'm starting to believe
I'll actually make it.
You'll make it.
I told you... You saw
it, and it happened.
Yeah, you told me.
I got to go.
I have a date.
Look, there's
something I wanted...
What?
I just... I wanted to thank you.
I wouldn't have
made it through this
if I didn't have something
to look forward to.
I had a good time.
Good luck in Pensacola, and...
get jets, huh?
See you, Zack.
Give me another one.
In fact, give me the bottle.
Come here, baby doll.
Come here.
Come over here.
Sit down for a second.
I'll tell you something.
Had to have one more taste.
That stuff come in
anything besides strawberry?
I'll bring some
coconut next time.
I've really got to go.
Mmm.
Shouldn't you have
got your period by now?
I'm a little late. That's all.
How late are you?
Why? What's the difference?
If anything happened,
it would be my responsibility.
Exactly how late are you?
What do you care?
Suppose I was pregnant.
I'd never make you do
something you didn't want to do.
Oh, I know.
But that's not the
only issue here.
There's more to it than that.
What other issue is there?
My responsibility as
its father, for one thing.
If I got you pregnant,
I'd want to do the
right thing by you.
I'll pay for the abortion,
be with you through
it, comfort you.
We'd go through it together.
So how late are you?
Let's just wait and
see what happens.
See you later.
I'll call you.
Fuck!
Last chance for the record!
Go for the record!
This is it, Mayonnaise. Go!
Go!
Come on!
Go for it, Mayo!
Go get it!
Go, Mayo! Push it!
Put your name on that wall!
Mike, let's catch that animal!
Let's do this together, Seeger.
Come on, Seeger.
Go for the record.
Come on!
Come on! You got it!
Come on, man!
Hey! Where you going?
Seeger, get up.
Forget it.
You want jets?
Then get up!
You're going over! Right here!
Three steps. Right, left, right.
Hand over hand.
Come on, See-gar.
Ready? Let's go!
Walk that wall, Seeger!
Walk that wall!
Hand over hand!
Walk it! Walk it!
Walk it, Seeger!
Seeger, walk!
Seeger!
Don't you let go!
You walk that wall!
Pull! Pull! Pull,
Candidate Seeger!
One leg! You got it!
Pull over! Pull over!
Pull yourself over!
Where's Sid?
What makes you
think she's not lying?
She went to a doctor.
She's pregnant.
So get an abortion.
I'd love to, believe me.
She won't even talk about it.
She's Catholic.
You're not marrying this girl.
If I don't,
she'll have the baby on her own.
Women do it all the time.
I can't let her have
a kid by herself.
It's my kid, too.
You sure?
It's mine.
I'm sorry, all right?
What if Foley was right?
She got knocked up to trap you.
Is it still your responsibility?
No matter how it happened,
the child would still be mine.
I wouldn't know where it was.
Is everything
your responsibility?
Sit.
Adjust.
Pray.
Attack.
It's like your
brother getting killed.
It's the same damn thing...
Him getting killed
instead of you.
Isn't that why you
promised to marry Susan?
You're acting out some
bullshit code of ethics.
It may be bullshit to you,
but I wasn't raised that way!
We're responsible for others.
It's the only thing that
separates us from animals!
I can't shit on people
and sleep at night.
You're responsible
to yourself first.
If you can't handle that,
you've got bigger problems
than making some girl pregnant.
Gentlemen, relax.
Without an oxygen
mask at 30,000 feet,
your insides will feel
like this rubber glove.
Your coordination
will deteriorate.
Look for the warning signs...
Giddiness, shortness
of breath, claustrophobia.
They can hit you at any moment.
The instant you feel
yourself losing control,
go back on oxygen.
Does everyone
understand the exercises?
Okay. Everybody set?
Let's see a thumbs up, please.
Very good. Everybody
remove your mask.
All right. Begin
the exercises now.
Queen of diamonds.
Nine of diamonds.
If you have any problems,
put your mask on.
If you can't, raise your hand.
The corpsman will assist you.
How you doing, Mayo and Seeger?
Having trouble?
Concentrate. Try to
make your palms meet.
Ace of spades.
How you doing, Worley?
Worley, are you all right?
Worley, can you hear me?
Ace of spades.
Worley, put your mask on!
Put your mask back on!
Sid, you okay?
I got to get out!
Worley, sit down!
Corpsman, we got a problem!
I want out!
Corpsman, get that mask on!
It's all right. Breathe.
Get out of here!
It's all right. Breathe!
Mayo, they're watching!
We'll stabilize the pressure!
It's okay. Everything's okay.
Everybody's watching you.
Hold on. Shh.
We'll stabilize
the pressure now!
Stay where you are.
Leave your masks on!
He's got it.
He's okay.
No problem. He's okay.
Colors!
Secure the halyard!
Charlie, take care of that.
Okay, Mayo.
What's going on?
You didn't kick him out?
Did he tell you what
he's been going through?
That doesn't matter.
What matters is he
freaked out at 25,000 feet.
That can't happen ever.
He's got a girl. She's pregnant.
That don't matter.
Don't matter?
You've got two weeks left!
That can happen to
you, too, Mayonnaise.
He ain't bullshitting you.
I'm talking to
you, motherfucker!
Don't fuck it up for you.
What did you call me?
I thought the D.I.s
were supposed to help.
What kind of a person are you?
Better lock it up,
or you'll go with him.
Go back to the barracks.
I don't get this.
He's the best
candidate in the class!
The best student,
the best leader,
the best friend to everybody.
Bend your goddamn rules!
He didn't drop
me. I went to him.
What are you talking about?
I'm glad it's over.
I was here for everybody but me.
I was here for my big brother.
Hey, buddy.
Sid, wait a minute.
Sid!
Request permission
to carry on...
sir!
Get the fuck out of here.
Yes, sir. Keep the change.
Thanks, pal.
Lynette!
Hi, baby.
Hi, Sid.
Come out here.
How come you're out of uniform?
I got something for you.
Wait. I'm a mess.
All right, if you don't want it.
All right.
What?
Well, if you don't want it.
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God. It's beautiful!
It cost me my whole savings.
Oh, God!
Oh, Sid! Oh...
So, does this mean...
Yes, ma'am, that's
what it means!
Oh, Sid!
Let's do it now!
I wonder where
we'll get stationed.
I've always wanted
to go to Hawaii.
We won't get stationed anywhere.
I D.O.R.'ed.
You what?
I wasn't cut out to be a pilot.
I was faking it.
I've been faking
everything up to now.
But... what'll we do?
Where would we go?
Oklahoma.
I'll get my old job
back at J.C. Penney's.
Hell, in two years,
I'll be floor manager.
You'll love Oklahoma.
You and Mama
will get along great.
Money might be tight,
so we'll live at home.
Sid.
There's no baby.
What?
I'm not pregnant.
I got my period this morning.
There's no baby, Sid.
I'll be goddamned.
What do you say we
get married anyway?
I love you.
I don't think I really knew that
till just now, just this second.
I have never been happier
than I have been in
the last seven weeks.
I've never felt so relaxed.
I've never felt so loved
for who I really am.
Lynette, marry me.
Make me the happiest
man in the world.
I'm sorry, Sid.
But I don't want to marry you.
I really like you,
and we've had ourselves
some really great times.
But I thought you understood.
I want to marry a pilot.
I want to live my
life overseas...
the wife of an aviator!
Damn you!
Goddamn you!
Nobody D.O.R.s after 11 weeks!
Nobody!
Hi, ma'am.
Have you seen Paula around?
Paula!
I'm looking for Sid.
He D.O.R.'ed and
split. Nobody's seen him.
I don't know where to look.
Same room?
Yes, sir.
Number three.
Yep.
That's the one.
What do you think of this?
That's nice.
Watch this.
I think you'll like it.
Damn it!
Oh, shit.
Lynette.
Has Sid been here?
Already come and gone.
What happened?
Can you believe it?
He D.O.R.'ed in the 12th week.
How can you win?
Lynette...
What did you tell
him about the baby?
That there isn't one...
as of today.
I got my period this morning.
I couldn't believe it.
He still wanted to marry me.
What did you say?
I said no, of course.
I don't want no
Okie from Muskogee.
I can get that right here.
You little bitch!
Who do you think you are,
playing with people like that?
He loves you!
You just shit on him!
You made up
everything, didn't you?
There wasn't any baby.
Of course there was a baby!
I'd never lie about
something like that!
Would I, Paula?
You little cunt!
God help you.
You're no different
than I am, Paula.
Oh, yes, I am.
Oh, no, you're not!
Let me see if he's here, okay?
Okay.
You seen Sid Worley around here?
Yeah, he's here.
Sid.
The guy said he just got here.
Sid?
Hey, man.
Sid, you okay?
Sid.
Shit! My God!
Oh, God.
Call an ambulance.
Oh, Sid.
Oh, God.
Call an ambulance.
You dumb, fucking Okie.
I was your friend.
Why didn't you come
and talk to me about it?
You didn't even try.
You didn't say good-bye to me.
The base chaplain said
he'd call Sid's parents.
Why can't I learn?
Just like her all over again.
Just like her.
Don't do this to yourself.
You didn't kill your mother.
You didn't kill Sid.
They killed themselves.
Yeah.
There's nothing you
could have done about it.
I got to get out of here.
Want some money for a cab?
I don't deserve that.
Okay. All right.
You're not the only
one who feels awful.
Maybe I had
something to do with it.
I knew what Lynette was doing.
Look, you got no problems!
Another class will be
coming through soon.
You and Lynette...
Right back into business.
That's not fair.
I never lied to you.
I never did what
Lynette's doing.
I'm not Lynette.
No.
I love you.
I've loved you since I met you.
Don't you understand?
No! I don't want you to love me!
I don't want anyone to love me.
I just want out!
I don't know,
but it's been said!
Air Force wings
are made of lead!
Left, right, left,
right, column right.
Hut!
I don't know,
but I've been told.
Navy wings are made of gold!
Platoon...
halt!
Sir, this officer candidate
requests permission
to see you in private, sir!
The whole class
knows about Worley.
We're sorry.
I bet you are.
I want to see
you in private, sir.
Not now.
Now!
Forward...
Sir, I request permission...
Left, right, left, right.
Left, right, left.
Sir, this officer candidate
requests permission
to see you in private!
Sir!
Not now. I'm busy.
Get cleaned up.
I don't need your shit!
I came back to quit! D.O.R.!
Platoon... halt!
I don't need you. I
don't need the Navy!
I don't need anybody.
Okay, Mayo. I see what you want.
You said you wanted
to meet me in private?
You got it!
The blimp hangar. Now!
Move it!
You move it.
We ain't going
there to talk, boy.
Move!
Fall out.
Fall out!
This is between me and him.
All right, Mayo.
Let's see what you got.
Shh! Shh! Shh!
Quiet.
I see you've had some
training, Mayonnaise.
Come on, Foley.
Lookie, lookie here.
Your blood's as red as mine,
isn't it, Mayo?
Come on, come on.
Get up!
You can quit now if you want to.
It's up to you.
Sir, the officers are present.
Guests, please rise.
Class 1581,
raise your right hand
and repeat after me.
"I do solemnly swear...
I do solemnly swear...
that I will support and defend
the Constitution of the
United States of America...
that I will support and defend
the Constitution of the
United States of America...
against all enemies,
foreign and domestic...
that I will bear true faith
and allegiance to the same...
that I take this
obligation freely...
without any mental reservation
or purpose of evasion...
that I will well and
faithfully discharge...
the duties of the office on
which I am about to enter...
so help me God."
so help me God.
Please be seated.
Gunnery Sergeant Foley.
Sir!
Well done, Sergeant.
Thank you, sir.
Class...
1-5-8-1...
Fall out!
Aye, aye, sir!
Foley's Fire-eaters
finally finished!
Daddy! What did you think?
Mayo, come and meet my family.
No. I'm going to
get my first salute.
Congratulations,
Ensign Chadwick.
Congratulations, Ensign Seeger.
Thank you, sir.
Gunnery Sergeant, Ensign Seeger.
Sir.
Congratulations, Ensign Mayo.
I won't ever forget
you, Sergeant.
I know.
I wouldn't have made
this if it weren't for you.
Get the hell out of here.
Thank you, Sergeant.
Congratulations,
Ensign Della Serra.
Thank you, Sergeant.
Every time I say, "Understand?"
the group will say, "Yes, sir!"
Understand?
Yes, sir!
I don't believe what I'm seeing!
Where you been all your lives?
Listening to punk rock
and bad-mouthing
your country, I'll bet!
Where you from, boy?
Tucson, Arizona, sir.
Where?
Tucson, Arizona, sir!
Only two things
come out of Arizona...
Steers and queers!
Which one are you, boy?
I don't see no horns,
so you must be queer!
No, sir!
What?
I will use every
means necessary,
fair and unfair,
to trip you up!
Turn it, Bunny.
No. Back the other way.
Keep going, keep going.
Way to go, Paula!
Way to go!
♪ Love, lift us up
where we belong ♪
♪ Where the eagles cry ♪
♪ On a mountain high ♪
♪ Love, lift us up
where we belong ♪
♪ Far from the world we know ♪
♪ Up where the
clear winds blow ♪
♪ Some ♪
♪ Hang on to used to be ♪
♪ Live their lives ♪
♪ Looking behind ♪
♪ All we have ♪
♪ Is here and now ♪
♪ All our life ♪
♪ Out there to find ♪
♪ The road ♪
♪ Is long ♪
♪ There are mountains ♪
♪ In our way ♪
♪ But we climb a step ♪
♪ Every day ♪
♪ Love, lift us up
where we belong ♪
♪ Far from the world we know ♪
♪ Where the clear winds blow ♪
♪ Time goes by ♪
♪ No time to cry ♪
♪ Life's you and I ♪
♪ Alive ♪
♪ Today ♪
♪ Love, lift us up
where we belong ♪
♪ Where the eagles cry ♪
♪ On a mountain high ♪
♪ Love, lift us up
where we belong ♪
♪ Whoa, whoa ♪
♪ Far from the world we know ♪
♪ Where the clear winds blow ♪♪