- Hello there.
- How are you, Frankie?
- Very well.
- Buddy!
- You all right, Paddy?
You
can't catch me.
I'm gonna
catch you, just wait.
All right?
Buddy!
I'm speedy, you're not. You're slow.
I'm gonna get you.
Hiya, Moira. How are you?
- Very good, thank you. How are you?
- I'm good.
And he's dribbling. Score now!
Buddy!!
No cheating. I did it fair
and square, I'm telling ya.
You nearly got me.
Yes! Dragon slayer!
Hey, Buddy!
I win! I slayed the dragon!
Your ma's calling
you! Your tea's ready!
All the rest of you too!
Yes!
I'll get you
next time, Buddy.
Yes!
- Get back here!
- You dirty bastard!
- Hiya, Buddy.
- Hello, Mrs. Ford.
- Have you been fighting any dragons?
- Only a couple.
I've got a couple in my house.
- Is that right, Mr. West?
- Aye.
And can you lend
us a shield, Buddy?
I'll see what I can do.
- Say hello to your daddy for me.
- Will do.
Buddy, your ma's calling you for your tea.
- Thanks, Mrs. Kavanagh.
- She says it's tripe and onions.
She did not.
- In a sandwich.
- She did not.
She says you're a terrible man.
And she's right.
Please. Please, we've done nothing.
Get the kids inside!
Get away from here. Go!
We don't want any trouble.
Come on! Get inside!
Mum!
Get out of here.
- You've been told.
- Buddy!
Ma!
Buddy!
'Mum! Mum! Mum!
Keep your head down and don't move.
Will!
- Mum!
- Will!
- Get in there. Come on.
- Danny, where are you?
Get down and don't move.
Say nothing to nobody.
- Catholics out!
- Easy, lads.
Get them upstairs!
Catholics out!
Get in the house. Mummy!
All right, come on!
Mummy! What's happening?
Keep him there and stay still.
- Mum, what are you doing?
- Will, stay where you are.
Mum!
You've been warned!
Get these fuckers out of your street!
And if you talk to the police,
we'll be back for you too!
Get the Catholics out!
Clear the street. Get out of it now.
Get down!
Get yourselves down!
Stand back!
Holy God.
Belfast was in shock this morning
as the impact of last night's rioting
was all too clear.
Small numbers of Catholics
still peacefully living
in Protestant areas were targeted.
Their houses were attacked and marked,
and intimidation may force them
to leave their homes completely.
Can these tightly knit neighborhoods
ever return to the peace
they shared together only 24 hours ago?
Further reports suggest...
Up front, Frank.
I'll show you where I put them.
Look, we need to get this barricade up
before those kids come back, okay?
Are we taking
all these paving stones to the barricade?
- Are we taking them all down?
- We need them all.
Right.
ls poor Jane okay? Is she all right?
Don't
you worry, Paddy.
We're not gonna let
them back here again.
You're as welcome on this street
as any of us.
All
right, Buddy?
We're
gonna have to get more.
We've got four more houses to do
and that's the last pane of glass.
Fergus didn't come home last night.
I'm gonna go see Mrs. McGuinness now.
I saw Fergus down the road.
He's coming now.
We have to do this.
The police aren't going to protect us,
so we have to do it ourselves.
Is that all you can
take in a barrow?
Kids,
please, go inside.
I don't want you out here
until it's all safe again. Come on.
Can you wheel that up to the front?
Frankie'|| show you
where we're putting it.
Tell Paddy I'll be there
in a minute to fix that.
I've got to nip into the house
and get my tools.
Watch yourself
getting up there, love.
Put them
pallets over here. Over here.
Get them kids to stay away
from them sharp edges.
- Everything on the floor.
- Put my washing machine in.
Bring them all round.
Keep it coming. We still need more.
Bring it up here. Come on. Keep it coming.
Come on, lads!
The likeliest move is
to bring troops into Belfast
in the hope of avoiding further clashes
between rioters and police,
particularly the B-Specials.
Stand to the side!
Another 600 troops
will be available this afternoon.
Off these streets now!
Get off the road. Stand back!
We're not stupid!
You can't keep us in our houses!
The men of the 3rd
Battalion of the Light Infantry
fly in from Plymouth to plug the gap
left by the use of troops.
A curfew is another possibility
which is being widely mentioned.
I've just come from the airport now.
I've literally just come from the airport.
I live in that street.
That's my kids there. I live in number 96.
- Get up there quick. Quick.
- Christ.
Stop.
Just let
him through. His kids...
Where do you think you're going, love?
To bring my husband home.
That's him on the other side there.
- Where's he been, then?
- None of your bloody business.
Not with you in your hour of need?
That's a bit off, isn't it?
- He works away in England.
- Does he? What kind of work is that?
- He's a joiner.
- I see.
Has he joined any of these groups
making all this mess in your street?
He knew nothing about
the whole bloody thing.
That's why he's here now. He's come home
from his work to see his family.
Glad to hear it, madam.
-All right?
All residents
in this street please stay indoors.
They nearly had you there, Steve McQueen.
- I'll have you in a second, Frankie.
- Come on, you two.
Hi, boys.
Stay in your homes tonight.
Thank you very much.
- Okay?
- Aye.
Space, the final frontier.
These ere the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise...
Did they attack you?
No. It was only the Catholic houses.
Them boyos want them out.
Them peoples don't give you any bother
in that street, do they?
Not at all. They're friends,
they're family, same as us.
- They just kick with the left foot.
- Exactly.
Sure, my best friend in the street
is Mrs. Ganjawala.
She's Indian.
She even comes to the wee mission with me.
Them curries. I tried one once.
I had to wear a nappy for a week.
- Will.
- Oh, Mum. Sorry, Granny.
She's well able to handle herself.
It's being so cheerful
keeps you going, isn't it?
I'm not gonna be running up
the Cave Hill anytime soon, am I?
- There's just no knowing...
- That's not easy.
...how it's gonna affect their schooling.
Will, would you turn that telly off
and talk to your granny?
- Hi, Pop.
- Hiya, Buddy.
Are you coming for your tea at mine?
Does the doctor wanna see you again?
Aye, he's given me a letter
for the hospital.
- And did you go?
- There's no point.
I think you've a few big decisions
to make, Son.
Did you clear up that wee bit of trouble
we were talking about?
Hey, wee fellas.
We're not deaf back here.
Yes, we've friends on the Protestant side.
They weren't
friends last night.
They weren't friends
last night, though.
Paddy Kavanagh told me
as long as Catholics keep confessing
everything bad that they do to a priest,
then they can do
whatever they want,
and God will forgive
them all the time.
Well, Paddy Kavanagh's family's
not gonna be living in this street
for much longer, so
you'd better check
he's not taking
the hand out of you.
I don't know how it works.
They get a lot of
water thrown on them
and then they're
okay. I think that's it.
Why aren't you going too?
'Cause me and your father
have business to discuss.
God understands. Now, come on.
- What are those?
- My little secret. Now, come on.
I've had too much God for one day.
Well, your granny says
you can never have too much God.
You might need him before too long.
Look, mind your nonsense for now
and I'll take youse all
to the pictures tomorrow.
Brilliant!
Robin and the 7 Hoods
is on in the afternoon at the Capitol.
Paddy saw it.
- Wait, is that gangsters?
- It's a blinking musical.
No, it's not. There's Little John
and swords and everything.
You can't go tomorrow afternoon.
Your cousins will be here.
Your aunties and uncles
wanna say goodbye
to your father before he goes back.
But, Daddy, are you not gonna be
a vigilante on our barricade?
No more talk
about bloody barricades.
That nonsense will stop soon enough.
I wouldn't be too sure about that.
Hey, less of the long face, Son.
These two can go and pray
for it to stop now,
and we'll all go to
the big picture house
in town tomorrow,
Daddy will pick the film,
and we'll forget about
this whole bunch of eejits
before I have to go back to work.
Was that our side that done all that
to them Catholic houses
in our street, Daddy?
There is no our side and their side
in our street.
Or there didn't used to be, anyway.
It's all bloody religion,
that's the problem.
Then why are you sending us to church?
Because your granny
would kill me if I didn't.
But, Daddy, if we were Catholics,
we could not go to church,
and then every once in a wee while
we could go in and confess,
and then they'd have to tell us
we were forgiven
and we wouldn't have
to go in again for ages.
I've nothing against Catholics,
but it's a religion of fear.
Protestants, you will die!
Agonizingly!
And where will you go
when you shuffle off
this pestilential mortal coil?
Where?
Well, I will tell you where.
Picture the scene.
A fork in the road.
In one direction,
a straight and narrow highway.
In the other, a long and winding road
which stretches down and away
into an unknowable distance.
One will take you
to the bosom of the Lord's grace,
forever and a day caress you
with beatific love.
And the other will spew you
into an eternal pit of sulfurous,
suffering, pustulating pain
from which you will
never, ever, through
the seven circles
of hell escape.
And I ask you here and now,
which road will you take?
Now, money.
- Thanks very much.
- Thanks very much. Really good.
Remember, one slice per sandwich.
I don't wanna be giving too much away.
With regard to the
explosive, I think
that's a fair word,
situation in Northern Ireland,
are we getting near to the point
where you,
as prime minister
of the United Kingdom government,
will feel it necessary to intervene
and use the supreme authority
which is yours in law,
either to remedy grievances
or to ensure order?
If that became necessary, of course,
I shouldn't shrink
from doing whatever was needed.
Ah, we have been deeply concerned
about the problem of civil rights
in Norfhern Ireland.
I've paid tribute...
Make an
orderly queue to be
allowed entrance
to the street, please.
Okay, yes, line up here
for admission to the street.
What
have we got left now?
One at a time.
Not doing a strip search this time,
eh, Frankie?
Who do you belong to?
You know full bloody well
who we belong to.
I'm taking my wife down to her sister's,
like I've been doing
all my bloody life.
House number?
There's no number. Just a name.
What's the name?
Arsehole.
Very funny, Mack.
Always the joker. On you go.
We won't worry about
their name and number now.
We know where they live.
Whoo! You like that?
How's that, then, Ginger Rogers, huh?
Whoo! Come on you, Fred Astaire.
Whoo!
VVhoo!
- You can tell them by their names.
- How?
Well, if he's a Patrick or a Sean,
he's a Catholic,
and if he's a Billy or a William,
he's a Protestant.
There's more names than that, though.
I know that.
I'm just saying, them's the obvious ones.
- What about Maurice?
- Ah... Dunno.
We've a wee fella down our street
called Thomas. What's he?
- Protestant definitely.
- He's not. He's a Catholic.
- No, he's not.
- He is.
They burnt his house out the other night
'cause his family is Catholic.
Sure, we've a cousin called Thomas.
I know. That's what I'm saying.
Well, how the hell
are you supposed to know, then?
- You have to get taught it.
- Who teaches you?
So the doctor says, "Listen, John,
I've got some bad news and worse."
And John says,
"Oh, no. What's the bad news?"
And he goes,
"Well, you've only got 24 hours to live."
John says, "That's awful.
What could be worse than that?"
Doctor says, "Well, I've been trying
to get a hold of you since yesterday."
Why do you even have to know?
In case they attack you.
- When?
- When you're out and about.
Well, if they're attacking you,
they're not going to stop
and tell you their name.
- It wouldn't get to that stage.
- Why?
'Cause you use your secret knowledge
to bluff them.
What are you talking about?
They can just come up to you when
you're not expecting it and ask you,
"Are you Protestant or Catholic?"
But it's a trick
question, you see,
because they don't
tell you what they are.
And what do you say then
to not get a dig in the gob?
- "I'm a Catholic"?
- Wrong.
That's exactly
what they think you will say.
They think you're trying to bluff them.
- But you've to double bluff them.
- How?
You say, "I'm a Protestant."
- But I am a Protestant.
- That's the point!
Blanchflower's now at the
halfway line. He looks up.
Is there nothing
this Spurs right half cannot do?
Perfect through-ball!
Nice pass, son.
Would you go on away in
and tell your pa I'd like to have
a wee chat with him, please?
Tell him it's Billy Clanton.
And McLaury.
What do you want?
We're looking to cleanse
the community a wee bit.
You wouldn't wanna be
the odd man out in this street.
You saw what happened
to your neighbors from the other side.
You touch my family and I'll kill you.
Calm down, fella.
I'm a Protestant like yourself.
- All all right?
- Aye, it's okay, Mackie.
Look, things get out of hand
pretty quick round these parts.
Cash or commitment.
The boys who cleaned up your street
have made me their new local chief.
So, you can report to me with either.
All right?
Have a wee think.
I'll be in touch.
Buddy, come on. Come and
show me how to play this game.
Come on. Let's have a look, huh?
All the big boys have left.
Buddy, give your brother a hand
there. Pick this sofa up, right?
- Here, can you give us a hand?
- Yes, ma'am.
Wanna put your gun down?
No, it's all right, thank you.
Don't you be scratching my walls
with that.
Got it? Right. Now, hold on.
This worked earlier.
I'll go in first.
- All right?
- Stewart.
- Frankie.
- All right?
All right, Frankie? Is that you
all this time at the barricades?
Somebody has to.
Better me than Billy Clanton.
- Aye.
- Not many people chose this.
There's a few men
hiding behind them barricades.
And they'll keep hiding
where they're afraid for their families.
It's a waiting game now.
When it's time for
that wall to come down,
I'll be first to swing
a hammer, but now?
"They also serve who stand and wait."
We can't all be acting the Lone Ranger.
This is a
story of long, long ago,
when the world was just beginning.
A young world.
A world early in the morning of time.
Well, no wonder you brought us to this.
It's educational for the boys.
Aye.
Raquel Welch is a hell of an education.
If people ask you to join anything,
deliver anything,
do messages for anybody,
you do nothing, okay?
You tell your ma, she'll tell me,
and I'll sort it. You understand me?
- Yes, Daddy.
- Very good.
I'm proud of you, Son.
Now get off to bed, the pair of you.
I'm up too early in the morning
to see you,
so make sure you get to
school all right. All right?
Don't mess your mother about,
and I'll see you in two weeks, okay?
- Yes, Daddy.
- Good boys.
A fork in the road.
In one direction,
a straight and narrow highway.
Which road will you take?
You're running round here
like the man in the big picture,
not paying your taxes
and spending all our money on horses.
It's the building trade.
I told you it doesn't work the normal way.
- I told you I had it covered.
- I was the one who had it covered.
No, you had us paying
three years of back tax.
To keep you out of bloody jail.
We're drowning in debt.
We're near done with the back tax.
Ten pound a month for three bloody years.
This is the time to think about
making a new start.
I know nothing else but Belfast.
Exactly.
There's a whole world out there.
We can give these boys
a better chance than we ever had.
There's Commonwealth countries
needing tradesmen.
The government
will give you assisted passage.
We can get the whole family to
the other side of the world for ten pound.
We're living in a civil war,
and I'm not here to protect my family.
What are those supposed to be?
An escape route.
Get this
street locked down.
Come on. Get a move on.
- We're gonna be late again.
- Come on!
Throughout the night,
sn/p/ng became the
tact/c of the r/oters.
As we drove past a side street,
three men on the corner dived for cover.
A young man with a revolver
asked us for a lift.
At 4:00 this morning,
RUC turned us back from the Falls area.
Snipers, they said, were still at work,
and in the distance, one heard
the ominous burst of machine-gun fire.
The scene terrified me,
but it reminded
an American colleague of Harlem,
but, he added,
it seems easier to get guns here.
One more left.
Dawn over Belfast today
showed a grim scene,
buildings scarred by fire,
thousands of pounds' worth
of damage caused,
and, of course, the tragic loss of life.
It's been a night of shame for Belfast,
one that will live on in the memories...
Come on, you two. School.
- Walking, please. No running.
- Good morning, miss.
Twelve elevens are 132.
Twelve twelves are 144.
Well, I'm pleased to say your times tables
were more impressive to hear
than your test scores were to read.
The whole point of these weekly tests
is to monitor your progress.
The best will sit directly by my desk,
the seat of learning,
and the rest of you
will view your Sisyphean struggles
from the distance
you have imposed upon yourself
by a lack of application.
Billy Clanton Junior, 17%.
Bottom row, seat 12.
Rachel, seat 11.
Martin to seat ten. Freddie, seat eight.
Karen to seat four.
And in the medal positions this week,
with 72%, in bronze, is Buddy, seat three.
And, of course, in silver again,
we have Ron,
and Catherine with the gold
yet again this week.
Congratulations, Catherine.
Very well done.
The wee girl
still showing some interest, yeah?
She looks at me sometimes,
but we're not allowed to talk
in the class,
so I can't say anything.
And then when we go
out to the playground,
she always goes off
with the other girls.
Anyways,
I think she loves that other fella.
You don't know that for sure.
Women are very mysterious.
And women
can smash your face in too, mister.
Your granny's become less mysterious
over the years.
So, you really like her?
When I grow up, I want to marry her.
Yeah, sounds like you really like her.
You know, she's not only at school.
You could see where she lives, maybe.
It's Reynolds Drive,
four houses in from the right,
the one with the wonky eight.
You've done your research.
I pass it every day on my way home.
I try to look in, but she never sees me.
She's always doing her bloody homework.
If she were a wee
bit more stupid like
me, we'd be sitting
together by now.
Ah. "A pity beyond all telling
is hid in the heart of love."
He's full of pretty answers, that one.
Come on. It's time to go.
I don't want your mammy
shouting at me because you're late.
- Cheerio, Son.
- Cheerio.
Here, take this threepenny bit.
Get yourself a wee sweetie.
I'm not allowed, Granny.
My da says you can't afford it.
I'm always saying to your man there,
"What's yours is mine
and what's mine's me own."
Thanks, Granny.
Try and find out how that wee girl thinks.
Good luck with that one, Son.
- Give me the ball!
- Pass it. Pass it. Goal!
Yes, mate. You just need to tell us
where you've been, all right?
Yeah, up against the wall.
Will.
What road do we take?
I can't remember.
What road did the minister say?
Shut up.
And in this already tense atmosphere,
concerns remain about intimidation
run rife in working-class areas.
Further reports suggest...
Get your arse up here.
Stop dragging your arse along there.
You're
hurting my arm.
Stop being
a crybaby now.
- You show me where he lives.
- Daddy, I'm sorry.
You tell me exactly what he said.
He
just said he couldn't
give any more
money to the streets.
He'll not
say that to my son.
Daddy, stop!
- Stewart! Stewart!
- Please!
Your blood's up there, Billy.
Would you go back to your house?
Billy, we've no call for fists here.
Aye? Well, what is it the man says?
A fist is only as good or bad
as the man using it.
Remember that.
Holy God. Billy!
Shut up, Frankie!
Come on, Billy. That's too much now.
We don't need more of this, Billy.
Billy, stop that.
You're settling old scores.
Regards to your pa.
Tell him I expect to hear from him soon,
or he'll be hearing from me.
Up them stairs.
23, 24, 25, 26! Whoo!
What are you doing?
It's, like, what my favorite holiday is.
What is your favorite holiday?
I don't know.
We haven't been on many, have we?
No, we haven't.
Unbelievable.
They're not getting away with this.
And it's due today as well,
so I can't do anything about it.
- Hello, Buddy.
- Hello, Mr. West.
- Right, on you go now.
- Thanks, Mr. West.
Will you ask your
da to drop down to
see us when he's
back at the weekend?
He's not back at the weekend.
That's a pity. Tell your ma
I was asking after him, will you?
- Aye.
- Tell your brother
I need another wee delivery with the milk.
Get him to come and see me
after school. All right?
Why is your da not coming home?
He can't come home every weekend.
It's too dear.
You won't get your wee Matchbox car then,
will you?
Come on.
Corning.
- Do you wanna join a gang?
- I'm not allowed.
- Why not?
- My mother said she'd kill me.
She doesn't have to know.
That's the whole point.
- Are you in one?
- Aye.
- What's it called?
- Doesn't have a name.
- Why not?
- Has to be secret.
That's what they tell you when you join.
What do you do?
I can't tell you till you're in the gang.
- How many of you are there?
- Not allowed to say.
- What do you have to do to join then?
- Whatever they tell you.
If your da's not home this
weekend, you could come with us.
I don't know.
I'm trying to practice my maths.
Then you're mental.
Come on.
If your da's not home anyway,
what else are you gonna do?
Ah, come on.
God. This takes ages.
No wonder they call it long division.
Patience. Patience with the sums.
Patience with the girl.
Is it 27?
It's close enough.
I'll just make sure
your numbers aren't very clear to read.
She might give you
the benefit of the doubt
if your seven looks like a one
with a fancy tail, right?
The same with a two and a six, right?
Keep her guessing.
That means you'll have
two or three horses in every race.
Isn't that cheating?
Well, I'd call it spread betting.
And if it gets you moved up by one seat
to bask in the light of her glory,
then you're off to the races.
But sure there's only one right answer.
If that were true, Son,
people wouldn't be
blowing themselves up all over this town.
I think my da wants us to leave Belfast.
What do you want?
Every night, before I go to sleep,
when I say my prayers,
I ask God if he'd fix it
so that when I wake up in the morning,
I'm the best footballer in the world.
And then I also ask him, as well,
that when I grow up,
can I marry Catherine?
Even if she loves Ronnie Boyd.
But she could still see him,
but she'd marry me.
That's what I want.
You looking for trouble, Doniphon?
You aim to help me find some?
What's the matter?
Everybody in this
country kill crazy? Here!
Show's over for now.
Try it, Liberty.
Just try it.
What right do you have
to interfere? It was me he tricked.
I have to keep those boys
where I can see 'em.
Well, I can't come home
every weekend, for God's sake.
If you can't be bothered, don't blame me
- for what them boys get up to.
- That's not what I'm saying.
You can't just throw that one...
Right,
that's 6:00 a.m., fellas.
That's youse done.
Housewives, it's thanks
to Sparkle biological washing powder
that their whites are whiter than ever.
What have I done?
As well as brightening,
it's the softest wash...
All right, Mummy?
Why do you always get sad
when a letter comes?
A mother's dream.
Remember, our washing powder
is biological.
Come on, Mr. Slow Coach. Get inside now.
And finally a switch
in the medal positions this week.
Well, Mr. Buddy, you may not have improved
your handwriting in maths,
for which, this once,
in lieu of your intensified efforts,
we will be willing to give you
the benefit of the doubt,
but you have improved your score.
So, in second position is Buddy.
Yay!
Be careful What you wish for.
That's what the minister
at the wee mission says.
When is your next chance?
We have to do a project
about the moon landing.
Did those boys not come back from that?
They did, and now we have to cut things
out of the papers
and explain how they got there.
If they did get there,
if they did get to the moon,
it's not what it says here.
God doesn't like it.
And I watched every night, too,
that they were up there,
and how did I never see Mike Collins
in the mother ship doing his orbit?
Surely you would've seen
the shape of Columbus
against the light of the moon.
That's 'cause mostly
he was on the dark side.
Exactly. It's the side that Lucifer
hangs his shillelagh.
No, he was on the dark side
of the moon most of the time
where we couldn't see him
while he was doing his orbit,
and then maybe just before he
was due to come round the corner,
you had to go in for your tea.
If I could come up
with something smart about that,
maybe I could stay up at the top desk
and wait till she gets back there.
Or you could say the moon's made of
green cheese and drop down a place.
Or you could do the project
together, you and the young lady.
You'd get the same marks and maybe
end up on the same seat together.
But how do I even talk to her?
Yeah, it's all rigmarole
with you, mister.
Walk, please.
No running, thank you.
Thanks.
Well done on your maths.
Have you gone to the moon yet?
Do you want to, with me?
It'll save you getting cold
waiting outside our house.
Hey, Romeo, come on!
We have work to do.
Operation Steal the Chocolate.
It's simple.
We go into the shop and keep
Mr. Singh talking down by the fridge.
He has to move the boxes round
at the bottom to get me a Lemon Mivvi.
His head will be down part of the time.
You stay at the front of the shop,
and when you see he's not looking,
you make a sweep.
What's a sweep?
A big grab for all the chocolate bars
on that low shelf near the till.
He'll know they've been nicked
if there's a big gap.
I thought you said we'd just do a couple,
so he'd never even notice.
- I don't want lifted by the police.
- All right, all right.
- All clear.
- No sweep. Just a small grab, okay?
I might be able to swipe you
a chocolate mousse at the same time.
Okay.
Hello,
Mr. Singh.
Moira. Hello, Buddy.
Good to see youse.
Please may I
have a Lemon Mivvi?
Lemon Mivvi coming right up.
Just need to move
a few wee boxes.
Hey!
He's seen us!
Come here, you wee buggers!
I know who you are!
No, he does not!
Well, your
woman will tell him anyway.
- You proud of yourself?
- It was Moira.
Get in there.
Get off that blinking road
or you'll kill somebody!
- She's gonna tell on us!
- She says anything, she's done for!
I know who youse are.
What have you got?
You're joking me.
- It's all I could see.
- Turkish Delight?
Who the hell eats Turkish Delight?
Do you eat Turkish Delight?
No. I don't like it.
Nobody likes it.
- It's all they had.
- Are you blind?
- I had to think quickly.
- Not quickly enough.
There was Flakes and Crunchies.
All you need is an in and out
with a fast hand
and then the Milkybars are on me.
I'm not sure you're cut out for this.
- Hey, Buddy, your da's home.
- It's only Wednesday.
He came in a taxi.
- And you too.
- What?
Keep your mouth shut.
- When did you write to them?
- None of your business.
Just tell me. When did you write
to them? It's a simple question.
- None of your business.
- Just give me a simple answer.
- I'm not getting interrogated.
- When did you write to them?
When the last receipt came through.
I knew it was the last one
'cause for three bloody years
I've been counting them envelopes
coming through that door,
and there wasn't so much
as a thank-you with this one.
It's the taxman, for God's sake.
Who do you expect, Father Christmas?
We've been scrimping and saving
and they hadn't the good grace as to say,
"That's it. You're done.
You're in the clear."
So what's you say to them in your letter?
I said I wanted
a full official declaration
that my husband was in the clear 100%
on all back taxes,
and that they acknowledged
that everything was shipshape
and aboveboard,
and that my family's good name
wasn't on some credit risk list.
- Christ. Christ the night.
- What?
No. No.
Yes, yes. Oh, yes.
They've decided...
Thanks to acting on your request,
they've decided to go back further
into my accounts
and say that I owe another £572,
which based on current earnings
should take another five years to pay off.
So that's a handy wee letter
you sent, wasn't it?
You bugger! You're a lying bugger!
That's right, believe the taxman
before you believe me.
'Cause I know you!
Your work won't be too pleased
with you skipping off in the week.
I'll work the weekend.
When's that job finish?
This one's nearly done.
What, there's another
one over there, is there?
Aye. Big one. A long one.
They're asking some of the boys
to move over permanent.
Offering accommodation
because of the time involved.
Couple of years. Building a hospital.
Your father has to go to the hospital.
You talk to him about it.
Won't talk to me about doctors.
- Is that right?
- It's just a couple of days.
A wee test for the lungs.
It's all that bloody time
over in Leicester.
- Where's that?
- In England.
Is that near where Daddy works?
Your daddy works near London,
the Big Smoke.
This was in the countryside.
- What were you doing?
- I was a coal miner.
You've done a lot of different jobs, Pop.
You can say that again.
Yeah, none of them lasted
more than a week.
My mother's worried about you.
Your mother's worried about you.
Granny's always worried
about something, isn't she?
Well, your granny's a very caring person.
Sometimes it affects her nerves.
Like your mummy.
Mummy's worried too, isn't she?
Daddy, are we gonna have to leave Belfast?
All right, Buddy,
that's me away, then.
I'll see you when I get back next week.
In you come,
girls. Catherine. Quinn.
Morning, girls.
You can help me put the pencils out.
Be good, Son.
And if you can't be good?
- Be careful.
Seems like only yesterday you and me
were in school together.
You're gonna need
to stay away from my family.
That's big talk
for a fella who's never here.
You can rely on me to be here
when it matters.
I hope your timing's good.
Things get out of hand pretty quick
around these parts.
Do you know the problem with men like you?
You think you're better
than the rest of us.
And the problem with men like you
is you know you're not.
We'll keep it simple.
You're with us or you're against us.
Clock's ticking.
You're a soft touch. Time
for real Protestants to step up.
You're no real Protestant.
You're a jumped-up gangster
and always were.
There's peelers about.
Watch it, youse two.
Quick.
Oh, look. There you are now, Son.
There he is now.
Hello, Son. The police officer here
just wants a wee word with you.
There seems to be a wee bit of confusion
about something that happened
at Mr. Singh's.
Go on, sit down there, now.
Do you know why I'm here, son?
Don't lie to me.
A very serious crime has been committed
down in Mr. Singh's shop.
Do you know what I'm talking about?
All the best, now,
and give my regards to Josie.
I will do.
I do like a man in a uniform.
Was he in there long?
Apples will grow again,
should they grow on a gooseberry tree.
I didn't even eat the chocolate!
No, I won't be here when it's over.
You're asking me to wait an hour
to find out if I'm going to be a wife
or a widow.
I say it's too long to wait.
I won't do it.
- Amy...
- I mean it.
If you won't go with me now,
I'll be on that train when it leaves here.
I've got to stay.
No, you're not listening to me.
I am listening. I am listening.
Would you listen to me for a change?
I'm trying to be practical about this.
Look, the police were here today,
but their father wasn't,
so, no, I'll not be having
any lectures from you, mister.
I know what you're gonna...
Clear the streets
and return to your homes.
Return to your homes.
Oi. Yes, I'm open.
- Catch it.
- Mine, mine, mine!
Pass to me, pass to me!
Mrs. Ford, how you doing?
All the better for seeing you, stranger.
- Welcome home.
- You're a silver-tongued charmer.
It takes one to know one.
- Hiya.
- All right?
Just the fella.
Have you got a horse for the 2:30 race?
I have, but if I tell you,
the odds will come down.
Christ, I'm not gonna bet the house.
Fancy Man, each way.
Should get you a pint.
- Is that Paddy moving out?
- Poor Catholics have no choice.
- It's a mad world.
- Well, get used to it.
We all live there now.
Prize capture was a tanker
laden with 2,500 gallons of petrol.
They'd also taken dozens of crates
of milk bottles from a passing truck
and dubbed the whole enterprise
the Petrol Bomb Factory...
All the kids in the street are going mad.
What do you want me to do?
You need to talk to them boys.
How many was there?
About ten of them.
And what did your mate do?
He said he wasn't joining
anything they belonged to.
Then he gave the big one a dig in the gob
and ran like hell.
So did I.
Did they chase you?
Aye, but we got a street ahead of them.
Then we ran into my uncle Tony's
and turned the corner
before they could see us.
We put the heart across my uncle Tony.
He was on the toilet, doing his horses,
and then he dropped his pencil
down the loo.
You've delivered
for these boys before, aye?
Mm-hmm.
And you know it's not milk they're
putting back in them empty bottles?
We do now, Daddy.
You were right to tell me.
Come here and hold this, Son.
Hold that there.
- You got that?
- Mm-hmm.
And amid more city-wide violence overnight,
government figures issued today
reveal that Northern Ireland now has
the highest rate of unemployment
in the UK.
Here it is. Planet Earth.
Do you know where that is?
- Sydney...
- Australia?
- Aye, that's right.
- Do you know about it?
- Aye.
They've got surfing and weird football.
And they have kangaroos on the barbecue.
And the weather's good.
Young Joe Turner's down there too.
That's right.
How do you fancy that?
- What?
- Moving over there for a wee while.
You're joking.
No. It's just down the side a wee bit.
It's 10,500 miles.
Right, school, you two. Now.
We might as well be going to the moon
if we went down there.
- Sure, you've already family there.
- One second cousin.
And you've the phone.
And a millionaire to pay the bills?
We could take trips back.
And pay for it with what? Scotch mist?
Family could come over for holidays.
I didn't come up the lough in a bubble.
There's no one from round here
can afford the fare to go down there,
or the time off work if they had any work.
- You just heard the bloody news.
- We have to do something.
This is our home.
I hope you're feeling confident, Daddy.
Don't worry.
He's away the night again?
Aye, he can't neglect his work.
- Sure, there's work here.
- Have you read the papers?
You'd break my heart to leave, but...
you have to think of them.
We can't all leave.
There'll be nobody left but the nutters.
Aye, and nobody to cook their tea,
run messages and wipe their arses.
That'd make the violence stop
in about ten minutes.
How could I leave Belfast?
I wouldn't worry about it.
The Irish were born for leaving.
Otherwise the rest of the world
would have no pubs.
It just needs half of us to stay,
so that the other half can get sentimental
about the ones that went.
All the Irish need to survive
is a phone, a Guinness
and the sheet music to "Danny Boy."
You're a terrible woman, you know that?
He shoots, he scores.
I'll see you soon, okay?
- Can you take her home?
- Take care of yourself, okay?
Come on, now, missus.
We must go as well. Come on, now.
- Violet, can I ask you a question?
- What?
- What did you do with the money?
- What money?
The money your ma gave you
for singing lessons.
All passengers
departing on the Heysham Ferry
should proceed to
the boarding area now.
Everybody's leaving home.
People have to move on.
"Too long a sacrifice
Can make a stone of the heart."
Is that what does it?
Yeah, well, you don't usually buy
your wisdom with a walk in the park.
Your heart has to explode.
Mr. Philosopher.
And when did your heart ever explode?
That time I saw you
in those brown stockings.
Holy God.
I remember that.
It took me half the day just staining
my legs brown with the tobacco water.
Then our Annie took half the night
to draw the seam
up the back of my legs with a pencil.
You couldn't understand why
you couldn't get your hands round them.
You thought it was magic.
It was magic.
When you've gray hair,
people think your heart never skipped.
Did yours ever skip?
Aye, it danced a bloody jig
every time you walked in the room.
You were full of it then
and you're full of it now.
Come on. We may get on.
Ah, Jimmy said he'd drive me
to the hospital in the morning.
And I told him he would not.
I'm taking you in on the bus.
I'm walking you in, and when they're done,
you can be bloody sure
I'm walking you back out again.
You hear me? I'm walking you home.
- Do you hear me?
- Yeah, I hear you, missus.
Sure, when did I not?
Aldergrove bus going
in three minutes. Last tickets now.
The boss has been in touch.
They want me to stay on.
A permanent job in England.
Wanting me to move into management.
It's more money.
There's a house that goes with it.
We get it rent-free,
with a chance to own it if things go well.
A wee bit bigger than what we have here,
a room for each of the boys.
There's a wee garden too.
Are you allowed to play football
in that garden, Daddy?
Aye, Son.
If I say yes,
there's more money straightaway.
We could start getting on top
of that back tax now.
This family's not gonna get another chance
like that in this town, not now.
Watch out for that traffic there.
I'm watching it now, Mammy. It's okay.
Come on, now. Two minutes.
Get on board if you're coming.
Last tickets now.
Sounds like they really want you.
What do you want?
I want my family with me.
I want you.
You and me, we've known each other
since we were toddlers.
We've known this street
and every street round it all our lives...
and every man, woman and child
that lives in every bloody house,
whether we like it or not.
I like it.
And you say you have a
wee garden for them boys?
But here they can play
wherever the hell they like,
because everybody knows them,
everybody likes them,
and everybody looks after them.
If we go over the water,
them people's not gonna understand
a word we say.
And half of them,
they'll take the hand out of us
for sounding different.
And the other half, they'll hate us,
'cause men here are killing
their young sons on our streets.
They'll think we don't give a shite.
And you think they're gonna
welcome us with open arms?
What, and say, "Come on in.
Well done for stealing
the house off of us"?
Things change.
Aye, they do.
We need to decide by Christmas.
You need to decide by Christmas.
You're coming back,
aren't you, Daddy?
You look after your mummy.
Be good.
If you can't be good...
And if you can't
be good, be careful.
Right, off we go.
Aldergrove Airport, ladies and gents.
We'll talk on the phone, okay?
Give me a ring.
Tell me when you've got there.
I caught you looking at Dr. Kildare.
You can talk.
Have you wrote to Santa?
He has, but Santa's explained
that money's a bit tight this year,
so he's not to expect too much.
Sure, Santa has plenty of surplus
if you talk to the people in the know.
Your health is all you need
for a Christmas present.
You've the right one to keep you
cheerful here, haven't you, Pop?
You tell your mammy to stop her cheek
or I'm not taking you to the show.
- What show's that?
- I don't know.
I think there's Christmas
carols in it, though.
That's my waterworks.
And you, behave yourself.
Don't be annoying your pop.
Don't be asking for
any Christmas presents.
He's no money either.
Taxman's got it, like ours.
Don't worry. Your mammy will persuade Santa
to bring some presents.
Don't think so, Pop.
I always know when there's no money.
Hello?
- It's the rent man.
- I'll get it, Mam.
Shut your mouth.
Is your mum in there, wee man?
Nobody's here...
{muffled shouting]
That puts me in mind
of a great wee system we had
in the old days for paying the rent.
The rent man would come round
and collect the money
for every house in the whole street.
And once he had done
and all the rent books
were marked up to date,
one of the boys would hold him up
at gunpoint in the back entry
and take all the money back off him.
And then he'd hand it straight back
to all the residents in the street,
with a little commission for the service.
Yeah, it was a very effective system.
And the rent man
was so good about it in the end
that eventually they cut him in
for a wee bit too and everybody was happy.
Except for the council, I suppose.
His work's giving my da a house
in England now if he wants one.
It's got a garden and everything,
and two toilets,
and they're both inside the house.
There's nothing wrong
with an outside toilet,
except on an aeroplane.
My ma says if we went across the water,
they wouldn't understand the way we talk.
That shouldn't be a problem, Son.
I've been married to your granny
for 50 years,
I've never understood a word she's said.
And if they can't understand you,
then they're not listening,
and that's their problem.
You know, when I was in Leicester,
they said the same thing about me.
So I put on a different bloody accent
every day just to annoy them.
They never knew who I was.
But I did, and that's the only one
who needs to know.
You know who you are, don't you?
Yes, Pop.
You're Buddy from Belfast 15...
where everybody knows you.
And your pop looks out for you,
and your mammy looks out for you,
your daddy looks out for you,
your granny looks out for you,
your brother looks out for you,
and the whole family looks out for you.
And wherever you go
and whatever you become,
that'll always be the truth.
And that thought'll keep you safe.
It'll keep you happy.
You remember that for me?
- Yes, Pop.
- Aye.
Fine man you are.
Now, forget about what your father
and your mother want.
What do you want?
I want you and my granny to come too.
Hear me.
I am here tonight to warn you
that you have yet a chance and hope
of escaping my fate.
Who wears chains that size?
Granny, you're not allowed to talk
in the theater.
It makes one heck of a necklace.
You were always a good friend to me.
Thank you.
You will be haunted.
Is this the chance and hope
you mentioned, Jacob?
It is.
I think I'd rather not.
I'm bloody well sure you wouldn't.
When will Pop get out of the hospital?
When the doctors say his lungs are fine.
When Pop went to England to be
a coal miner, did you go with him?
Did you want to?
Neither do I.
Has your father
said what he's doing?
He says it has to get decided
by Christmas.
- When's he coming back?
- At the weekend.
We're going to the pictures.
He's taking us to
Chitty Chitty Bang Bang.
- What in the name of God is that?
- It's a flying car.
Oh, God, I've heard it all.
It goes over a cliff
and you nearly fall out of your seat.
Do you wanna come?
It'll be company for you
till my pop's home.
If God had wanted
me to see flying cars,
I'd have been born
with blinking wings.
You love your films, don't you?
I was a great one for the pictures
when I was your age.
I used to think you could climb
right inside the screen
and visit all those
strange places you saw.
Like that one in that
film, what was that?
Ah... Lost Horizon.
Did you ever see that?
No. What was the name
of the place, Granny?
Shangri-La. That's what they called it.
Did you ever go there?
There were no roads to Shangri-La
from our part of Belfast.
So will you go one day?
- Where do they think they're going?
Look out!
What's happening?
Look! Look at that!
It's fantastic!
Oh!
You're a genius!
It's nothing, really.
Shut up. You'll get us thrown out.
- Darling. Thank you.
- Look at this!
Get Da, not me. Mummy.
Don't shoot me. No, Buddy, don't. Hey!
20-nil!
Ah, come on, here.
Sit down for a few minutes here.
We've a wee word to have with you.
Buddy, Mum and I want to talk to you
about something,
something that we might
have to do as a family.
You know the way your
dad's over in England
and he's been working over there
for quite a while?
Well, we were
thinking that, you know,
maybe we'd all go as a family
and go live there.
And, um...
your dad's seen a really nice wee house,
and it's got a lovely garden and...
- Play football, Buddy.
- Aye.
There's loads of room there.
More room than we have here.
- I don't wanna go to England!
- Switch that off.
I don't wanna go to England!
It's all right, darling.
I'll have no friends and no cousins
and I won't be able
to see Catherine at school.
Hey, listen, you'll make new friends,
and you're gonna have this big garden
to play football in.
I don't care about the garden.
I want my granny and my pop,
and I wanna do my project
on going to the moon
and get on the first desk,
and I don't wanna have to talk funny,
and I don't wanna forget what road
I have to go down when I'm dead.
- No one's asking you to talk funny.
- No decision's been made yet.
We were just trying to see
what everyone thought first.
- You're just overtired.
- Exactly, yeah.
I don't wanna leave Belfast!
Let's just leave it till Easter,
see where we are then.
Aye.
These boys are suffering.
I don't think we've got till Easter.
I don't think you and me
have got till Easter either.
Well, come home.
We'll fight this together.
Kids the same age as ours
are getting killed around the corner.
Well, we'll be careful.
You can't be with them 24 hours a day.
You can't take away
their childhood either.
You know, whatever happens...
what you've done with these two,
it's phenomenal.
What are you talking about?
You raised them.
Not me.
Not us.
You.
Thank you.
We'll see what happens by Easter.
I'll take the bins out, make a cuppa,
get these 'uns to bed.
Back to bed.
See you in two weeks.
Hey, you're gonna bring
the whole thing down.
- ...five...
- ...six...
- ...seven...
- ...eight...
There used to be 40 houses here
in this mainly Roman Catholic street.
That was before the trouble
in the middle of August.
Now the government are proposing
to rebuild this street,
but there are increased tensions
in the city,
and the move comes
amid warnings of renewed violence.
Moondance at seven to two.
It has to win, don't you think?
- What's going on in your comic?
- Well, he has to defeat the monster.
- What... They're my chips!
- What's yours is mine
- and what's mine's my own.
- Granny says that.
- What does that even mean?
- You'll find out.
Now, you go and wait at your granny's.
I'll come and pick you up
after I've seen my father, okay, Son?
All right, Daddy.
Right, wee fella? You did well
for not grassing us to the police.
- So you're in.
- What do you mean?
You're one of us now, and this is it.
- This is what?
- This is war.
Let's go, boys. Let's do this.
- What are we gonna do?
- Whatever the hell we want.
Our bloods up, lads. Our bloods up.
Authorities are urging citizens
to return to their homes immediately...
Take what you want!
...and to stay inside
and off the streets until further notice.
- Come on, let's just get home.
- Effective immediately.
They machine-gunned us.
Armored cars paving the way
for the hooligans to come in.
Everybody home now.
This doesn't look good.
Come on, let's go. Let's go.
I'm going home! I'm going home!
- No, you're not.
- I wanna go home!
- You're coming with us.
- I wanna go home.
Go on! Smash them!
- Come on. Get in here!
- Get in. Go on!
Take it easy, man.
We don't want any trouble.
- Oh, for God's sake, leave it.
- Come on. Let's go.
They've put the windows through.
This city belongs to the Protestants!
- Get yourself something.
- What?
Whatever you need.
Hey, get back, you Fenian!
- We're taking control.
- Washing powder!
Lock the doors. Lock the doors.
Mammy! Mammy!
- Here, what the hell's going on?
- Mammy!
- We're looting the supermarket.
- Where did you get that?
I told you, we're looting the supermarket.
You're what?
You wait right there, young man.
Why did you take that washing powder?
It's biological.
Oh, no. Get you now, get you now.
Here, grab everything you can.
Smash it in!
Come on.
Move! Move it!
Get the towel. Get the towel.
You watch yourselves.
- Clear the shelf!
- Take the lot of it.
Now, you put that back. Do you hear me?
And if you ever, ever do anything
like that again,
I will kill you, do you hear me?
And you, young madam,
if you ever drag my son
into something like this again,
I will beat you black and blue
until you never get home again,
do you hear me?
All right. Put it back, I said.
Hey, woman! We don't put things back.
That's not the statement
we're trying to make.
Billy, come on.
The army are coming. Come on!
Out! Go on, get out!
Come on. Grab it!
- Out!
- All right, all right.
- Come on.
- Come on!
Clear the street Clear the street now.
Tear gas and rubber bullets will be used.
We're clearing this area.
Move out the way now!
- Time to get out of here.
- Don't try anything.
So, you two are going to guarantee
safe passage for me and my men.
If you try to run,
I'll put a bullet in your son's head.
Ah, here he comes, the Lone Ranger.
Clear this area right now.
I can see your kind
needs a little discipline!
- Come on!
- You let them go now.
No, I think if I do, one of them soldiers
is gonna take my head off.
If they don't, I will.
Over their dead bodies.
Folks always have a problem with change.
But you better get used to it, mister.
People like me run this town now.
And it's people like you
that bring us all down.
Daddy!
This isn't the end, pal!
Thanks.
It's gonna be all right.
I'll talk to the committee,
get this fixed.
There'll be no more bother.
I caught sight of my face
in that shop window
when I was running down the street
and dragging them poor kids behind me.
And I was looking in the mirror just now...
at that same face.
And I asked myself...
what the hell am I doing?
And then I was sick...
like I am every morning now.
And I realized...
I don't think it really matters anymore.
So, tomorrow...
when Mack and Auntie Violet come round...
we're going to start packing.
You've no choice.
You know they're gonna
come for you, don't you?
And this time,
they'll send somebody serious.
Get yourselves to the moon.
London's only one small step for a man.
Belfast will still be here
when you get back.
Will you?
I'm going nowhere you won't find me.
And now to announce
the winners of our school moon project...
Well, how'd it go with this?
- We got a gold star.
Ah! Good on youse.
Now, tell me this,
seeing as you two will know.
How do I get to the moon
with only ten pound,
three leaky umbrellas and my bus pass?
See, there's an art to an Ulster fry, son.
Mind you, I'm glad your Aunt Violet's
away up the stairs there with your ma.
She keeps banging on now
about how Northern Ireland's
got the highest rates
of "chlomestremol" in the world.
Sure, I think it's great
that we're world champions at something.
Do you mind answering that for me, son,
while I've got this hot pan on?
Is your mother in, son?
Watch yourself, missus!
- Where's your white stick?
- Are you all right, son?
Will you ask in there
for my daddy, please?
Point out who he is.
The farmer says, "No,"
and he goes, "But do you have any bread?"
Excuse me. Your little lad's here.
What's that?
- He was a great fella.
- Heart breaks for them.
It was good to see him one last time.
There.
Oh, I'm done.
Here, you're all right. Will!
- You're all right.
- Yeah.
Take that note up to Mrs. Hewitt
and get the wee message for your granny.
For her nerves.
Come on.
That was a lot of people
that came to see him today.
Aye. He was very popular.
And he owed half of them money.
He used to help me with my maths.
He was a very deep thinker.
A very deep thinker.
Did he help you?
Yeah.
Yeah, he did help me.
He helped me a lot.
"For now we see through a glass, darkly,
For now I know in part,
but then I shall know as also I am known.
For when I was a child,
I spake as a child,
I understood as a child,
I thought as a child:
but then I became a man
and I put away childish things."
So do not say in grief
that you are sorry he is gone,
but rather say in thankfulness
you are grateful he was here.
- God love him.
- And that wee dote.
I'll miss him, now. I'll miss him.
And we'll be sure to toast him
down the club.
Will we head down now, will we?
I'm sure your man'|| have
a wee sing-along with the jukebox.
Top of the world, Ma!
Top of the world!
Buddy. Follow me.
- Hi, Buddy.
- Hello.
- Thanks.
- I'll come back.
- Make sure you do.
- Cheerio.
Daddy, do you think
me and that wee girl have a future?
Well, why the heck not?
You know she's a Catholic?
That wee girl can be a practicing Hindu
or a Southern Baptist
or a vegetarian Antichrist,
but if she's kind and she's fair
and you two respect each other,
she and her people are welcome
in our house any day of the week.
Agreed?
Mind you, does that mean you and me
have to start going to confession?
Probably.
That's us two in trouble, then.
Go.
Go now.
Don't look back.
I love you, Son.