Hey, boy!
What are you doing with my mama's car?
Wait there!
Ain't you ashamed?
Trying to steal an
old lady's automobile?
Oh, come on, now,
what are you talking about?
I've been thinking about buying me one.
Bull!
You ain't got money for dinner,
let alone buying a car.
Well, ma'am, I'll tell you something.
I've got enough money
for a Coca-Cola...
...and since it don't look like
you're going to invite me inside...
You'd steal the dining
room table if I did.
You want to go into town with me?
How would that be?
I'm going to work, anyway.
You're going to work?
What kind of work do you do?
None of your business.
I'll bet you're a movie star.
A lady mechanic.
A maid?
What do you think I am?
A waitress.
What line of work are you in?
When you're not stealing cars?
I tell you, I'm looking for suitable
employment right at the moment.
Oh, yes, but what did you do before?
I was in State Prison.
State Prison?
Well, I guess, some little
old lady wasn't so nice.
It was armed robbery.
The things that turn up in
the street these days.
What do you all do for a good time
around here? Listen to the grass grow?
I guess you had a lot more
fun up at State Prison.
I tell you. You see my right foot?
I chopped two toes off
that foot with an axe.
What! Why?
To get off of work detail.
You want to see it?
I surely don't intend to stand
here in the middle of Main Street...
...and look at your dirty feet!
Boy, did you really do that?
What's it like?
What do you mean, prison?
Armed robbery.
It ain't like anything.
Shoot. I knew you never
robbed any place, you faker.
Bet you wouldn't have
the gumption to use it.
You just wait right here and
you keep your eyes open.
What's your name?
Clyde Barrow.
Hi, I'm Bonnie Parker.
Pleased to meet you.
Hey, hey, slow down,
slow down.
Take it easy, you've
got my hand trapped.
Cut it out! Cut it out!
All right, now.
I might as well tell you right off.
I ain't much of a lover boy.
That don't mean nothing
personal about you.
I never saw no percentage in it.
Ain't nothing wrong with me.
I don't like boys.
Boy! Boy! Boy!
"Boy," what?
Your advertising is just dandy.
Folks would never guess
you don't have a thing to sell.
You'd better take me home now.
- Now, wait a minute.
- Now don't you touch me.
All right, all right...
...if all you want is a stud service,
you get on back to West Dallas,
...and you stay there,
the rest of your life.
You're worth more than that,
a lot more than that,
...and you know it, and that's why
you're comin' along with me.
You could find a lover boy on
every damn corner in town.
It don't make a damn to them if you're
waiting on tables or picking cotton,
...but it does make a damn to me.
Why?
Why, what do you mean why?
Because you're different, that's why.
You know, you're like me.
You want different things.
You've got something
better than being a waitress.
You and me traveling together, we could
cut a path clean across this state...
...and Kansas and Missouri and Oklahoma,
and everybody would know about it.
You listen to me, Miss Bonnie Parker.
You listen to me.
Now, how would you like to go
walking into the dining room...
...of the Adolphus Hotel in Dallas...
...wearing a nice silk dress and
have everybody waiting on you?
Would you like that?
That seem like a lot to ask?
That ain't enough for you.
You've got a right to that.
When did you figure all that up?
The minute I saw you.
Because you may be the
best damn girl in Texas.
You were born somewhere
around east Texas, right?
Come from a big old family.
You went to school, of course,
but you didn't take to it much...
...because you were a lot
smarter than everybody else...
...so you just up and quit one day.
Now, when you were 16... 17,
there was a guy who worked in a...
Cement plant.
Right, cement plant.
And you liked him,
...because he thought you were
just as nice as you could be.
You almost married that guy, but then you
thought no, you didn't think you would.
So then you got your job in a cafe.
And now you wake up every
morning and you hate it.
You just hate it. You get on down there
and you put on your white uniform...
It's pink.
And those truck drivers come in there
to eat your greasy burgers and...
...they kid you and you kid them back
but they're stupid and dumb boys...
...with their big old tattoos
on them, and you don't like it.
They ask you for dates and sometimes
you go, but you mostly don't because...
...all they're trying to do is get in your
pants, whether you want them to or not.
So you go on home and you
sit in your room and...
...you think, now when, and how...
...am I ever going to
get away from this?
And now you know.
Change that. I don't like it.
You're a knock-out!
That ain't ours.
No, but we came in this one.
That don't mean we
have to go home in it.
Where have you been keeping yourself?
I slept out by the car.
These accommodations ain't
particularly deluxe.
If they're after us,
I want the first shot.
Now, you come on out here.
We got some work to do.
Sheww! You're good.
I ain't good. I'm the best.
And modest.
Now, see that there now?
Set her spinning.
It's all right, all right.
Come on, now, try it again.
And try and get, now this
time come down slow.
How about that? Now, ain't
you something? I tell you.
Look, I'm going to get you a Smith &
Wesson. Go in your hand easier. Ok?
Now, I want you to try something now.
No, sir! No, sir!
You all go right ahead.
Used to be my place.
But it's not anymore.
Bank took it.
Yes, sir, they moved us off.
Now it belongs to them.
Why, that's a pitiful shame.
You're damn right, ma'am.
Me and him put in the years here.
You all go right ahead.
We just come by for a last look.
You all mind?
Hey, Davis!
Come on over here!
That's right.
Go on.
Much obliged.
My name is Otis Harris. This is Davis.
We worked this place.
How're you?
This here's Miss Bonnie Parker.
- Glad to meet you.
- I'm Clyde Barrow.
We rob banks.
Look, I don't want you
to worry about nothing.
This is going to be
the easiest thing in the world.
Your mama could take this bank.
You just be ready if I need you.
What are you waiting for?
This is a stick-up! Just take it easy
and nothing's going to happen to you.
Give me the money.
What money, mister?
There ain't no money here.
What are you talking about?
This here's a bank, ain't it?
Well, it was a bank, but
we failed three weeks ago.
All right, now, you get on out there.
You get on out there and tell my girl.
Come on, you tell her
what you told me.
We've got $1.98 and you're laughing!
Let's see now. A loaf of
bread, a dozen eggs...
...quart of milk, four fried pies.
Come on now, you sure you
ain't got no peach pies?
Get the hell out of here!
Go ahead! Go ahead!
He tried to kill me. Why'd he try to
kill me? I didn't want to hurt him.
Try to get something to eat around here,
...and some son-of-a-bitch
comes up on you with a meat-cleaver.
I ain't against him.
Now, you just tell me what
was wrong with that.
Dirt.
Dirt in the fuel line.
Just blowed it away.
Excuse me, ma'am, is there
anything else I could do for you?
Well, you're a smart feller.
You sure do know a lot about
automobiles, don't you?
Yes. I guess I do.
Would you know what kind of car this is?
This is a 4 cylinder Ford coupe.
Sure, sure is.
This is a stolen, four
cylinder Ford coupe.
Hey, you ain't scared, are you?
I believe he is.
That's a pity now. We sure could
have used a smart boy like that...
...who knows such a great
deal about automobiles.
Hey, you a good driver?
Yeah, reckon I am.
No, he's better off here.
What's your name, boy?
C.W. Moss.
I'm Miss Bonnie Parker and
this here is Mr. Clyde Barrow.
We rob banks.
There ain't nothing wrong
with that, is it?
Clyde, he ain't
the one. Let's go.
You think you got the guts
for our line of work?
What are you talking about?
I spent a year in reformatory.
A man with a record.
I know you got the nerve to short
change old ladies coming in for gas...
...what I'm asking you is have you got
what it takes to pull bank jobs with us?
Sure, I do. I ain't afraid,
if that's what you think.
Prove it.
You're gonna be all right.
I'm afraid we're overdrawn again.
This is a stick-up!
This here's a stick-up!
Leave it there.
Come on, everything.
Get it up here.
Clyde, where's the car?
What the hell you doing,
parking the car?
Stop that car!
Up ahead, cut left!
"We're in the money, the sky is sunny.
"Old man depression, you are
through, you done us wrong.
"We never see a headline,
about a bread line, today.
"And when we see the landlord, we
can look that guy right in the eye.
"Oh, we're in the money,
Come on, my honey."
You ain't got a brain in your skull.
On account of you, I killed a man.
And now we're all going to be wanted
for murder, and that's you too, boy.
Dumb head! Stupid!
What were you thinking about?
Do a dumb ass thing like that
again, I'm going to kill you.
If you boys want to talk,
why don't you all go outside?
Come on, I want to talk to you
for just a minute. Sit down.
This afternoon we killed
a man and we were seen.
So far, nobody
knows who you are...
...but they know who I am and
they're going to be running after me,
...and anybody who's running with me.
And that's murder.
Now it's going to get rough.
I can't get out, but
right now you still can.
I want you to say the word to me,
...and I'm going to put you on that bus
back to your mama...
...because you mean a lot to me, and
I ain't going to make you run with me.
Now, I ain't a rich man. You could
get a rich man if you tried.
I don't want no rich man!
You ain't going to
have a minute's peace.
You promise?
Least I'm not a liar.
I told you I wasn't no lover boy.
Let me look at you boy.
Oh, boy, you can do better than that.
Hey, how's mama?
Oh, fine, fine. Sister
sent her best to you.
Filling out there, boy.
Must be that prison food.
No, no, it's married life...
...you know what they say...
...it's the face powder that
gives a man interest...
...but it's the baking powder
that keeps him home.
I want you to meet my wife, Blanche.
This is my baby brother.
How're you doing?
It's really nice to know you.
How do you do?
I hear you're taking real good care
of the baby of the family...
I'm just so glad to meet you.
Come on over here.
I want you to meet my wife, Blanche.
Everybody, this is C.W. Moss.
My brother, Buck, and his wife, Blanche.
Howdy, everybody.
Howdy, you all.
Howdy, Mrs. Barrow, or may
I call you Blanche?
I sure am pleased to meet you.
How did you find us here
in this neck of the woods?
You sure picked a good day for it.
Is that a new Screenland Magazine?
Are there any new pictures of
Myrna Loy in there?
She's my favorite picture star.
Let me get the Kodak here.
We'll take some pictures.
Come on, put your pants on.
We're going to take some pictures.
Come on Blanche,
get out of there!
I'm a mess.
Been driving all day.
Did you take my picture? I declare.
I asked you not to take my picture.
Hey, Buck, get one of this.
Brother, I want to talk
to you later on.
You got that?
You take one of me and
my missus, here, Clyde.
I don't want a picture taken.
Be serious. Be serious.
Let me take one of Bonnie alone.
Come on, honey.
Hey, a little smile.
Don't want to smile?
Come on, I want to have a chat with
you. C.W., take the girls' pictures.
Why don't you step
in there with Bonnie?
What did you think of her?
She's a peach.
Now, tell me true.
Is she as good as she looks?
She's better.
Listen, it was, either you
or him, wasn't it?
The guy that you killed, you had
to do it, didn't you?
He put me on the spot. I had to.
You had to do it, right?
I know you did. Don't say
anything to Blanche about that.
That time you broke out of jail, that
true she talked you into going back?
You hear about that?
Well, I won't say nothing
to Bonnie about it.
I appreciate that.
We're going to have
ourselves a time, boy!
We surely are.
What are we going to do?
I figured we all drive up to Missouri.
They ain't looking for me up there.
We find a nice little place to hole up in.
We have us a regular vacation.
No trouble now.
I ain't looking to go back to no prison.
I heard in prison that you had
a little trouble there.
You were cutting on your toes.
You heard about that?
I did a little toe cutting.
That ain't but half of it.
I did it so I could get off
of work detail.
Breaking those rocks with a
sledge hammer night and day.
And you know what?
The very next week I got paroled.
I walk out of that God-
forsaken jail on crutches.
Ain't life grand?
You want to hear a story, about
this boy, he owned a dairy farm...
And his old ma, she was
kind of sick, you know.
And the doctor, he called
him over and said...
"...Listen, your ma, just lying there,
she's just so sick and she's weakly...
"...I want you to try to persuade
her to take a little brandy."
"Just to pick her spirits up."
"Ma's a teetotaler," he says,
"she wouldn't touch a drop."
"Well, I'll tell you what you do."
That's the doc.
"Now, I tell you what you do..."
"...you bring in a fresh quart
of milk every day..."
"...and you put some brandy in it, see.
And you try that."
So he did, and he doctored it all up
with the brandy, fresh milk...
...and gave it to his mama, and she drank
a little bit of it. She didn't, you know.
So next day he brought it in again,
and she drank a little more.
And so then, it went on that way,
the third day just a little more...
...and the fourth day she was, you
know, took a little bit more...
...and then finally, a week later,
he gave her the milk...
...and she just drank it down, she
swallowed the whole thing...
...and she called him
over and she said...
"...Son, whatever you do,
don't sell that cow."
All right, you got the
keys now, haven't you?
I gave him a month's rent in advance.
We're all set. Let's get inside.
Honey, I'm taking
you to our first home.
"Here comes the bride."
What do you think, honey?
Just perfect.
This is your first home.
He gave me the grocery number.
4-3-3-7, please.
Hi, there, Speedie's Groceries?
I want to order up a mess of groceries.
And a Frigidaire, not an ice-box.
Eight pounds of pork chops,
four pounds of red beans.
About eight bottles of Dr. Pepper.
You sure can play checkers.
You need a haircut. You're
looking just like a hillbilly boy.
You are just like an old man.
Playing checkers all the time, don't pay
any attention to your little old wife.
You ain't going to ever beat me,
but you just keep trying.
Oh, Daddy, you sure do need a haircut.
Why, you look like a little
old hillbilly, I do declare.
Oh, mercy me, don't.
Don't talk that way when she's
right there in the next room.
There is always somebody in
the next room, in this room,
...or in every other kind of room.
Don't you ever just want
to be alone with me?
I always feel like we're alone.
Do you, baby?
I'm hungry.
Groceries, ma'am.
- How much?
- Six dollars and 43 cents.
Here, ma'am, let me help you with...
those bags are heavy.
No, thanks, I'll get them.
Just get the door.
"But few of them really
are justified...
"...if you get right down to the point.
"You've heard of a woman's glory
being spent on a downright cur."
Did you write all that yourself?
Do you want to hear this or not?
"Still you can't always
judge the story as true...
"...being told by her.
"Now Sal was a gal of rare beauty...
"...though her features
were coarse and tough."
I knew that old gal.
She was cock-eyed and she
had a hare lip and no teeth.
"Now Sal was a gal of rare beauty...
"...though her features
were coarse and tough.
"She never once faltered from
duty, to play on the up and up.
"Sal told me this tale on the evening...
"...before she was turned out free.
"And I'll do my best to relate it,
just as she told it to me.
Hey! The laws are outside!
They're blocking the driveway.
- Please get us out of here.
- Shut up!
They got us blocked.
We've got to get the car out.
Where's Blanche?
You almost got us killed!
What did I do wrong? I thought
you'd be happy if I got shot!
Yeah! It would have saved
us all a lot of trouble!
Don't let that woman
talk to me like that!
You shouldn't have done that.
It was a dumb thing to do.
Oh, Buck, please, I didn't marry
you to see you get shot.
Let's leave. Let's get out
of here and leave.
Tell him to please stop
the car and let us out.
I killed a guy. Now we're in this.
Will you shut up!
Just shut up your big mouth!
At least do that much.
Cut it out, Bonnie!
Stop the car. I want to talk to you.
Get rid of her.
I can't, she's Buck's wife.
Then, get rid of them both.
Why? What's the matter
with you, anyway?
She is what's the matter with me.
She's nothing but a dumb,
stupid, back-country hick.
She ain't got a brain in her head.
What makes you any better?
What makes you so damn special?
You were just a West Dallas waitress.
Spent your time picking up truck drivers.
Oh, big Clyde Barrow!
You're just like your brother!
Ignorant, uneducated, hillbilly!
Listen, the only special thing about you
is your peculiar ideas about love-making,
...which is no love-making at all.
Oh, Clyde, please, I didn't mean that.
Listen, it, it was just all,
all that shooting...
...and all those guns. I got so scared.
Please, I didn't mean it.
"Law enforcement officers...
"...throughout the Southwest
are frankly amazed...
"...at the way in which the will
o' the wisp bandit Clyde Barrow...
"...and his yellow-haired
companion, Bonnie Parker...
"...continue to elude
their would-be captors!
"Since engaging in a police battle,
on the streets of Joplin, Missouri,
"...and slaying three of their number.
"The Barrow Gang has been reported as
far west as White City, New Mexico...
"...and as far north as Chicago.
"They have been credited with robbing...
...the Mesquite Bank in the
aforementioned White City...
"...and the J.J. Landry
Oil Refinery in Arp, Texas.
"The Sanger City National
Bank in Sanger, Indiana.
"And the Lancaster Bank in Denton,
Texas, on three different occasions.
"In addition to these robberies,
the fast traveling Barrows...
"...have been rumored to have a hand...
"...in the robbing of two
Piggly Wiggly stores...
"...in Texas, and one A&P
store in Missouri.
"Though Chief Percy Hammond, who first
identified Clyde Barrow's brother, Buck...
"...as a member of the gang..."
We ain't going to see another
toilet for another thirty miles.
Why don't you pull up
over here?
Here's something.
"Lone cop arrests two
officers in hunt for Barrow.
"Police Officer Anderson's heart
turned faster than his motorcycle...
"...when he forced to the side of the
road a roaring black V-8 sedan...
"...in which were 3 men and a yellow-
haired woman yesterday afternoon.
"He was certain he'd caught
Clyde Barrow, Bonnie Parker,
"...and maybe Buck Barrow...
"...and the third unidentified
member of the gang.
"It took a lot of telephoning and
explaining to convince...
"...the motorcycle cop that his captives
were two highway patrolmen...
"...and a blonde-haired stenographer
from the highway patrol."
I've never seen such shooting!
All right, now you just get
on right over to that car.
Look here. We're in the custody
of Captain Frank Hamer...
Frank here is a Texas Ranger.
Say, peace-maker, I believe you got
your spurs all tangled up there.
You're in Missouri, do you
know that, friend?
He's lost, this Texas Ranger.
I don't think he's lost.
Those banks have been offering
extra reward money for us...
...and I think Frank just
figured on some easy pickings.
You know, Texas Ranger, you
ain't hardly doing your job.
You ought to be home
protecting the rights of poor folk...
...not out chasing after us.
Why do you want to take
it so personal for?
We've got to discourage this bounty
hunting for the Barrow Gang.
What do you want to do
with him then?
Shoot him?
Hang him.
Take his picture.
Listen, we take his picture...
...we'll send it to all the newspapers.
And then everybody's going to
see Captain Frank Hamer...
...of the Texas Rangers
with the Barrow Gang...
...and all of us just
as friendly as pie.
We are just about the friendliest
folks you'd ever want to meet.
Big old Texas Ranger
waves his gun at us...
...and we just welcome him
like he was one of our own.
Buck, get the Kodak.
See what came of your
mischief not doing your job?
Down in Duncanville
last year...
...poor farmers kept you laws
away from us with shotguns.
Now you're supposed to be
protecting them from us...
...and they're protecting us from you.
That don't make sense, do it?
When his Texas Ranger friends see
this, he's going to wish he was dead.
I'm mighty proud to have a
Texas Ranger in the family.
How's this?
We're going to put that picture
in every paper in the country!
We got you!
You just stay there for a while.
Good afternoon.
This is the Barrow Gang.
If everybody will just take
it easy, nobody will get hurt.
Is that your money or the bank's?
Mine.
You keep it then.
Next time, I'll aim a
little lower.
Take a good look, Pop.
I'm Buck Barrow.
We're the Barrow boys.
Happy birthday, hon.
It was the Barrow Gang, Charlie.
They're headed for Oklahoma.
Load this!
There I was, staring square
into the face of death.
And all I can say is
they did right by me.
And I'm bringing me a mess
of flowers to their funeral.
Slow down, we're in Oklahoma now!
Come on, let's catch them, anyway.
I'm not going to risk
my life in Oklahoma.
Ain't much, is it?
Well, times are hard.
Let's get down to it.
I want my share.
If Bonnie gets a share,
I want a share, too.
What are you talking about?
Tell Clyde I want my share.
What about Blanche here?
Well, why not?
I earn my share same
as everybody.
I could have got killed
same as everybody,
...and I'm wanted by the law
same as everybody.
Besides I could have got snake-bit
sleeping in those woods every night.
I'm a nervous wreck and
that's the truth...
...and I have to take sass from
Miss Bonnie Parker all the time.
I deserve mine!
Hold on, Blanche, hold your horses,
you're going to get your share.
I married the preacher's daughter and she
thinks she's still taking up a collection.
Don't spend it
all in one place!
I guess I'm going to have
to keep saying this...
...Blanche is married to
Buck, and Buck is family.
My family could use some of that money.
Now you know how those laws...
...have been hanging around
your mama's house till all hours.
It's too risky to go up there now.
But where can we go now? We rob
the damn banks. What else do we do?
What do you want to do?
There's a hole in the pan.
We're losing oil. We've got to swipe
another car if we want to get anywhere.
C'mon and look.
Isn't that your car, Eugene?
That's my car!
That's my car.
- They're coming after us!
- Come on, kick it in the pants.
I'm going to tear them apart.
Those punks.
Stealing a man's car.
Wait till I get my hands
on those kids, Velma.
I'm going to tear them apart.
What if they have guns, Eugene?
Listen, we better get the police
and let them handle this.
All right, now, turn around.
Turn around and let's go back to town.
Then we'll go get the sheriff.
They stopped chasing us.
They're turning around there.
Let's take them.
Oh, my Lord, they're coming after us.
Step on it, Velma.
What do you want to do that for?
Step on it, Velma. Step on it.
What are you doing in there?
All right, get on out of there.
Come on.
You want to go for a
little ride in our new car?
Can we all fit in there?
There's not room for me in there.
What's your names?
I'm Eugene Griz- I'm Eugene Grizzard.
We're the Barrow Gang.
Now listen, now don't be scared.
It ain't like you was the law or anything.
I mean, you're just folks,
just like us. That's all.
That's the truth.
I expect you've been
reading about us.
We have, too.
You two must
be in love, I bet.
When are you going
to marry the girl?
He gave her the milk, and
she drank a little bit of it.
The next day, he gave her some more.
She drank some more till a week goes by.
And he brings her the milk and she
drinks down every drop of it.
And she looks at her son
and she calls him over and she says...
"...Son, whatever you do,
don't sell that cow."
I'm from Wisconsin originally.
Where the cheese comes from.
Oh, but he just loves Texas now.
Don't you, Eugene?
"Don't sell that cow."
How old are you?
I'm thirty-three.
Didn't I order some
French fries?
You did. Here you are.
Take it easy on those French fries.
Ain't that right, Eugene?
This isn't mine.
I ordered mine well done.
Who's got the other hamburger?
Is this supposed to be yours?
It's okay. Forget it.
I'm sure having a good time.
Aren't you glad we picked you up?
You're a grand host, Buck.
Maybe you all ought to join up with us.
They sure would be surprised
to hear that back home.
What would Bill and Martha
say if they heard that?
Lordy, they would have a fit!
What do you do, anyhow?
I'm an undertaker.
Get them out of here.
I don't see her, Clyde.
Bonnie, where are you?
Where do you think she
could have went, Buck?
I don't know. I just don't know.
There!
Leave me alone!
Where are you going?
Get away!
I want to see my mama.
Please, honey, don't ever leave me
without saying nothing.
Clyde, listen to me. Clyde, please.
Now, listen. I mean it.
I've been thinking about my mama...
...and she's getting so old,
and I want to see her.
You'll see her.
Would you look at him?
He just don't remember me.
He'll get used to me, won't he?
We've been cutting and pasting
everything we could find about you.
Clyde, there's the shot I took of you.
Came out real fine, didn't it?
"Horsey, get your tail up.
Why don't you make it rise?"
Oh, Lord, we thank you for
the safety of our loved ones.
And the food we are
about to receive. Amen.
Where you all headed
to from here, Clyde?
At this point we ain't heading to
nowhere. We're just running from.
Mama, why don't you stay
a little longer.
Listen, I want you to have this.
Listen, make mama stay a while yet?
Clyde, I read about
you all in the papers...
...and I just get scared.
Mrs. Parker, don't you believe what
you read in all those newspapers.
That's the laws talking there.
They want us to look big so they're
going to look big when they catch us.
And they ain't going to catch us.
Because I'm even better at running
than I am at robbing banks.
If we did half that stuff they
say we did in those papers,
...we'd be millionaires
by now, wouldn't we?
I ain't going to risk my little
girl here just to make money,
...uncertain as times are.
I knew, of a job...
You remember the time.
I could have...
...we could have got $2,000
just as easy as pie.
I pulled up outside there
and I saw them laws...
...and I said to myself,
"Bonnie could get hurt here."
So we just drove right on
and I let that money lay.
Maybe you know the way with her, then.
I'm just an old woman
and I don't know nothing.
But Mrs. Parker, this here is the
way we know best how to make money.
But we're going to be quitting all this
as soon as hard times are over,
I can tell you that.
Just the other night,
me and Bonnie were talking...
about the time we were going
to settle down and get a home.
She says, to me.
"You know, I couldn't bear...
...to live more than 3 miles
from my precious mother."
How do you like
that, Mother Parker?
I don't believe I would.
You try to live 3 miles from me
and you won't live long.
You best keep running, Clyde Barrow.
And you know it.
Bye, baby.
Look, who is this here,
is that your girlfriend?
"L, o, v, e."
Whose idea was
it to get bluebirds?
Bonnie's. Bonnie picked it out.
Day after we robbed the armory.
I want you to touch
something here. Ah...
I want you just to
touch it right there.
Why don't you all go
into your own cabin...
...if you want to play with C.W.?
What's the matter with you now,
besides your nasty disposition?
Wait now. Hold on!
I saw a chicken place a few miles back.
Who all wants to get some food?
I certainly do. I'm sick to
death of sitting around here.
Why, you can't even
drive the car.
Just get us 5 chicken dinners.
Get some dessert there, too. Some
peach ice cream or something.
I've got the blues so bad.
Is it what your mama said?
What mama?
She's just an old woman now.
I don't have no mama.
No family either.
I'm your family.
When we started out...
...I thought we were
really going somewhere.
But this is it.
We're just going.
I love you.
You sure are smoking a lot lately.
So what?
Why don't you go back
to your pa's house?
If I only could.
If I could only just do that one thing.
There's no telling
how all this happened.
I was a preacher's daughter.
What church was your pa affiliated with?
Baptist.
He thought the world
of Buck, my daddy did.
Even though Buck was
serving time in jail.
He forgave him because he
paid his debt to society.
We were Disciples of Christ.
I have no money.
Give me some.
Get me Sheriff Smoot on the phone.
"I love to spend...
"...each Sunday with you.
"As friend to friend...
"...l'm sorry it's through."
That's more like it.
Look how much better it
fits since I took it up.
The men are on the other side.
Hold it, hold it!
Get out!
Give me a gun! Somebody, give
me a gun. I don't have a gun.
Be quiet! Please, be quiet!
We're trying to get out.
It didn't happen, Daddy.
I know it.
Stop that!
I'd rather go to jail,
than go on like this.
He ain't got a chance.
Half his head's blown off.
Dear Lord, it's happened.
Please help us.
And Buck will never do anything
wrong again in his life.
My eyes.
I think I'm blind!
My eyes!
The light hurts so bad!
Tell Clyde to get us to a doctor.
Bonnie! We're dying!
Buck can't be moved now.
I believe I lost my shoes, Clyde.
I think the dog got them.
Surrender!
In the car! Come on!
Keep low!
Cross fire! Keep low!
Charlie, don't shoot!
The kids are in the cross fire!
I'll go get the car.
Hey, Buck, this way.
They're heading for the other car!
Shoot it! Knock the hell out of it!
Hold your fire!
Daddy, don't die!
Get away and leave him alone.
He's dying. Can't you see he's dying?
Let me go! Daddy!
You've killed him! He's dying!
God, can't you see him dying?
Maybe...
Can you all spare us
some drinking water?
Who are you, boy?
My name is Moss.
That's Clyde Barrow and Bonnie Parker.
What happened to them?
Are they fainting?
Is that really Bonnie Parker?
Daddy, daddy!
- Who's there?
- C.W.
Oh, it's good to see you, boy.
It's good to see you.
What's that on your chest, there?
Tattoo, daddy. Come on.
You've got to help them.
Help me get them in.
What happened to them?
Are you in trouble, son?
Help me get 'em in.
How come you marked yourself
all up with that tattoo?
What the hell made you do a
damn fool thing like that?
I came here to question Blanche Barrow.
So you're the Frank Hammer?
Hamer. I figure to have my picture
taken with those two...
...just one more time.
It says here: "Clyde fled
his dying brother."
Where? What do they mean "fled"?
How could I leave my brother to die, when
he was already dead when I left him?
Fled!
Newspapers!
While we're all lying
around here near dead,
...they had us holding up the
Grand Prairie National Bank.
Guess they hung that
one on us just for luck.
As soon as we get well, we're going to
hold up that bank. We're going to take it.
They don't know nothing, do they?
How come they always referring
to me, the newspapers as...
...unidentified suspect?
You just be glad that's all you are.
Long as they don't know your last name.
That's right, boy. Mr. Barrow's
looking out for your interests.
Hey, pa.
How's it feel to have a couple of
big deals stay in your house?
Ain't that something for me.
That's something for me?
You've been mighty nice to us.
I want you to let us pay you,
say, $40 for your hospitality.
I'm just happy to have
you folks here as company.
Anybody's a friend of
my boy, you know I...
Come on, let's go have some supper.
I'm starving. Come on.
You're all welcome here.
You know that.
And you just make yourself right at
home and stay as long as you want to.
You look like trash,
all marked up like that.
Cheap trash!
Bonnie says it looks good.
What does Bonnie know? She ain't
nothing but cheap trash herself.
Look what they do to you. You don't
ever get your name in the paper.
You just get them pictures printed
on your skin by Bonnie and Clyde.
They ain't nothing
but a couple of kids.
I'm so glad your ma ain't alive
to see this here thing...
...all jellied up like that!
I don't see what's so bad about it.
You wouldn't!
The word is out that Bonnie and
Clyde are holed up just out of town.
And they're fixing to bust in
here and take Blanche out.
All two of them?
Who is it?
I guess it's been kind of
rough on you.
Being the daughter of a
preacher, like you are.
I imagine old Buck wasn't
a bad sort, was he?
No, he wasn't.
I reckon...
...Clyde just sort of...
...led him astray, didn't he?
That's a shame, Blanche.
Yes, ma'am.
That's a shame.
That he led your Buck away.
Clyde, his own brother, Bonnie...
And that little feller.
The one that was with you when you
took that Texas Ranger in Missouri.
He was with you all along, wasn't he?
That's right.
I don't recollect his last name.
He was there that day we met them.
I didn't want to go. I didn't want to.
And Buck said we were just
going on a visit...
...so we wouldn't do no
stealing or robbing.
And we went up to Joplin,
and all of a sudden...
...all of a sudden, they
all just started shooting.
What're you writing?
I'm writing a poem about us.
Let me hear it.
Just let me finish this line.
It's called "The Story
of Bonnie and Clyde."
"You've heard the story of Jesse
James, of how he lived and died.
"If you're still in need
of something to read...
"...here's the story
of Bonnie and Clyde."
You think if I sent that into
the newspaper, they'd print it?
I'm going to do it.
"Now Bonnie and Clyde
are the Barrow Gang.
"I'm sure you all have read
how they rob and steal...
"...and those who squeal are
usually found dying or dead.
"They call them cold-hearted killers.
"They say they are heartless and mean.
"But I say this with pride,
that I once knew Clyde...
"...when he was honest
and upright and clean.
"But the laws fooled around,
kept taking him down...
"...and locking him up in a cell.
"Till he said to me, 'I'll never be free,
so I'll meet a few of them in hell.'
"If a policeman is killed in Dallas,
and they have no clue to guide.
"If they can't find a fiend,
they just wipe their slate clean...
"...and hang it on Bonnie and Clyde.
"If they try to act like citizens...
"...and rent them a nice little flat...
"...about the third night,
they're invited to fight...
"...by a sub-gun's rat-a-tat-tat.
"Someday they'll go down together.
"They'll bury them side by side.
"To few it will be grief...
"...to the law a relief...
"...but it's death
for Bonnie and Clyde."
You know what you've done there?
You told my story.
You told my whole story right there.
One time I told you I was gonna
make you somebody.
That's what you've done for me.
You made me somebody
they're going to remember.
Hey, Bonnie, how do you feel?
I mean, do you feel the way
you're supposed to feel...
...when you're, when you're,
after you're...
Yeah, just...
That's good, isn't it?
I figure that it's
a good idea to ask...
...because how else are
you going to know if it...
You did just perfect.
I did, didn't I?
I mean, I really did.
I never figured on that.
Clyde, why do you want to marry me?
To make an honest woman out of you.
What would you do...
...what would you do if
some miracle happened...
...and we could walk out of
here tomorrow morning...
...and start all over again. Clean.
With no record and nobody after us?
I guess I'd do it all different.
First off...
...I wouldn't live in the same
state where we pull our jobs.
We'd live in another state
and stay clean there.
Then when we wanted to take a
bank, we'd go into the other state.
Did they expect you to go
downtown with them tomorrow?
Who?
Bonnie and Clyde, that's who.
Sure. Always go with them.
You better go.
But when they go to get in their
car to come on home,
...don't you get back in there with them.
Why, daddy?
You listen to your pa for once,
can't you do that?
I'm your pa. I'm your kin.
Not that there Clyde Barrow.
What do you want me to tell them,
"I can't get back in the car with you?"
You tell them nothing.
I made a deal and got you
off with a couple of years.
You just be sure that you're
off the streets in that town...
...when they go to get in their car.
You think laws is going to
catch Bonnie and Clyde in town?
Clyde's got a sense.
Don't you know that, daddy?
Nobody catches Clyde. Never.
Never!
What happened to C.W.?
He's over there in the hardware store,
getting some light bulbs for his daddy.
You going to wear them like that?
Drive with one eye closed.
Want some ice cream?
Look here. Isn't that just the
prettiest thing you ever saw?
Look, you can see every fingernail
of her hand.
That's the prettiest thing.
Where is that boy?
Listen, I'll go get him.
Gladys Jean!
Time to go home now.
Get back there in about 20
minutes and we'll pick him up.
If that boy didn't have his head
strapped on him, he'd lose it.
Isn't that Malcolm there?
Got a flat tire. Ain't got no spare.
DVDRIP by Feedback Overflow.