BRIDGE OF SPIES
Translation. Review. Synchronization by Midofayed1.
www.doc-advice.com
1957 - COLD WAR
INSPIRED BY TRUE EVENTS
The next stop is Broad Street.
Broad Street will be next.
Upstairs. This way.
He did not come up this way.
Anything.
He is not up here.
Go back down.
Excuse me.
Go ahead and park
around the corner.
Visitors.
Do you mind if I
fetch my teeth?
Colonel, would you
turn around, please?
Sit down on the bed.
Let us go.
They are in the... The teeth
are in the on the sink.
Look at me. We are agents...
from the Federal Bureau
of Investigation.
Look at me!
I am talking to you.
We have received
information...
concerning your
involvement in espionage.
You can either cooperate
with us right now,
or, you will be under arrest.
Do you understand, Colonel?
No, not really.
Why do you keep
calling me "Colonel"?
You need to get dressed.
We have to search
your apartment.
Would you mind if I
cleaned my palette?
The paints, it will
be ruined otherwise.
It is just behind you there.
I have a cloth myself.
Thank you.
Start searching the place. Thank you.
All right! Search
the mattress,
the bed, the floorboards, his chair.
Would you put that in the ashtray?
On the window still there.
Take a good look at that desk.
Let us see the desk.
Would you not want
to get this ruined?
Do not you say "my guy."
He is not "my guy."
Yes, he is "your guy."
Who about are we talking?
We are talking about a person
whom did my client?
So, do not make him "my guy."
Okay, fine.
My point is, the person
insured by your client,
He does not deny that any
of these things happened.
"These... These things"?
Yes, these five things.
Wait, hold it, and hold
it, and hold it.
Not five things.
One thing.
Clearly, it is five things.
Well, I am sorry, It
is not clear to me.
Five things? Explain it to me.
It is self-evident.
Okay, and then tell
me what happened.
Tell me the story in a way that
makes sense for five things.
Fine, absolutely.
Your person is...
Not my person. Insured
by my client.
The person insured
by your client...
is driving down
State Highway 19.
When he loses control of his
car and hits my five guys.
The five people who hired me
to represent them.
Because you are not
honoring your claim.
You mean my client is not honoring
the claim, the insurance company?
Mr. Donovan, we are all
clear who is who, here?
Except my client
honors every claim.
They do, Mr. Bates.
Every single legitimate claim,
up to the limit of
their liability.
Which is $100,000
per accident?
In the case of
this man's policy.
And, this is one claim.
According to your description:
"He hit my five guys."
The person insured by my
client had one accident.
One, one, one.
Losing control of the car and
hitting five motorcyclists.
From their point of view,
five things happened.
Look, Bob. May I Bob?
"Jim."
If I go, bowling and I throw a
strike, one thing happened.
Ten things did not happen.
Jim, my people are
not bowling pins.
As much as your person may
have treated them as such.
If... Let me finish.
Let me finish.
If your house is
insured for $100,000.
And, a tornado
carries it away,
it carried away one house.
It did not pick up every
stick of furniture.
And, destroy it in a
separate incident.
If that is what,
you are saying,
Then, there is never any
limit to our liability.
That is the end of the
insurance business.
Then, Bob nobody is safe.
Waters, Cowan and Donovan.
How may I direct your call?
Good morning, Mr. Donovan!
Good morning, Alison!
I moved your 9:00 a.m.
with Prudential, Sir.
Why did you do that?
I asked to her do.
Is everything all right, Tom?
Why do not you leave your stuff
with Alison, and come on inside?
Something important
has come up.
Somebody is here to see us.
Natalie is getting
your coffee.
Nescafe, cream, two lumps.
Right?
That is right. Thanks.
- Lynn!
- Jim!
Nice to see you again.
How is the family?
Great, good. Thanks.
How is Annie?
Homicide. We had the
in-laws for the holiday.
If she acts on it, she will
have good representation.
Now, what is up?
Okay, here is the thing.
The Soviet spy who caught,
we want you to defend him.
Here is the indictment.
Wow!
I am not sure. I want
to pick that up.
The accused does not
know any lawyers.
The federal court
tossed it into our lap.
The Bar Committee took a vote.
You are the unanimous choice.
It is important to us.
It is important to
our country, Jim.
That this man is
getting a fair chance.
American justice
will be on trial.
Of course! When you
put it that way.
It is an honor asked.
But, Lynn, I am an
insurances lawyer.
I have not done
criminal work in years.
It is like riding a bike.
Is not it?
You distinguished
yourself at Nuremberg.
I was on the prosecution team.
Not the point.
You are no stranger
to criminal law.
Jim, look at the situation.
The man reviled publicly.
And, I will be, too.
Yes, in quarters that
is more ignorant.
That is exactly why
this has done,
and, capably done.
It cannot look like
our justice system,
tosses people on the ash heap.
Suppose I will do. As the
evidence, looks like.
Very overwhelming.
Great. Great.
Everyone will hate me but
at least I will lose.
What do you think, Tom?
The firm will suffer.
I have work here.
I think it is a
patriotic duty.
It is an important mission.
I told Lynn, the firm
could not say no.
You would have a tough
time saying no, too.
I think you have to defend
the son of a bitch.
You are doing it.
What are you doing?
Defending Abel,
the Soviet spy.
I may. I have to speak to...
Wait! How do you know? Did they
post it on the bulletin board?
No, I... I was talking
to Richard Earl.
Look, if I do this, I am
going to need your help.
Can you work tonight?
I have a dinner date, Sir.
It is Tuesday, right. Yeah, no,
I am free, completely free.
Thank you, Sir.
It is also an honor.
And, the Bar Association
asked me...
because they want to
show that even a spy,
gets a capable advocate.
Maybe it is the kind of
honor without we could do.
Honey, what are you
doing in home?
I have stood up.
That is despicable.
Who is this knot-head?
I would rather not to say.
Sit down. We just started.
People are scared.
They are building bomb shelters
to protect themselves.
- From people like this man.
- Ok.
I go to the store,
people are buying canned
food and Potassium tablets.
It is all about this man,
and what represents.
He is a threat to all of us.
A traitor.
- Who is a traitor?
- The Rosenberg was traitor.
Who were they?
They gave atomic secrets
to the Russians.
They were Americans.
They betrayed their country.
You cannot accuse Abel
of being a traitor.
He is not an American.
Listen to yourself.
You are defending him already.
You are rehearsing it on me.
You said you were just
thinking about taking it.
I am just thinking about
it, just very hard.
Everyone deserves a defense.
Every person matters.
Jim, what do we deserve?
Do you know how people
will look at us?
Family man is trying
to free a traitor.
He is not a traitor, Mary.
Yes, yes.
Roger, get that! He
is not a traitor.
Why do I have to
do all the work?
- You wait until us say grace.
- I am hungry!
He is about the most unpopular
man in this country.
You are trying to take
the second place!
Yeah, and I am third.
- Carol, you are dating wrong person.
- I want eat.
Mary, do not make
this argument.
When we are not
having an argument.
You are against him.
I am for him.
No. I am not for him. I am not
for the Russians spying on us.
I am for his right to have a
defense in a court of law.
This is why they call
it a court of law.
Sorry, Sir. I did not mean to
interrupt dinner.
A court of law... Hey, Doug.
No. Not at all. Hello, Doug.
Jim was just flailing.
I am not flailing. Go ahead, Doug.
You can join us for dinner.
We are having
meatloaf tonight.
You came over here to
help Jim think about...
Whether is he taking the case?
We are taking it! It is
exciting, is not it?
Lord, we thank thee
for blessings.
We are about to receive.
Thy bounty through
Christ, our Lord. Amen.
Good morning, Sir. My
name is Jim Donovan.
These are my credentials.
I am a partner in Waters,
Cowan and Donovan.
I had been admitted to the
New York Bar in 1941.
You had charged with 3
counts and 19 overt acts,
conspiracy to transmit
United States defense,
atomic secrets to
the Soviet Union.
Conspiracy to gather secrets.
And, failing to register
as a foreign agent.
Have many foreign
agents register?
If you do not mind
my asking, Sir.
Since your arrest.
Where have you been?
I could not say certainly.
You do not know.
They drove me to an airport.
And, put me on a plane,
took me off the plane.
Somewhere hot.
It is hot here.
Hotter, very humid.
They put me in a room.
You was beaten.
No.
I talked.
Offers was made.
What do you mean?
Offers of employment, to
work for your government.
Told if I cooperated,
no further charges would
be made against me.
They would give me money.
And, you declined?
As you see.
Of course! I cannot
endorse that.
I feel duty-bound to urge you,
to cooperate with the U.S.
government.
I said no.
Perhaps you could relay to your
friends at the CIA that I meant it.
No, no, no. I am not.
I do not work for the agency.
I do not work for
the government.
I am here to offer my services
as your legal counsel.
If you accept them as such,
I work for you.
If I accept you.
Are you good on what you do?
Yeah. Yeah, I am very good.
Have you represented
many accused spies?
No, not yet.
This will be the
first for both.
Yes.
All right!
"All right"? You accept.
Yes, all right!
Good, okay.
Let us start here.
If you are firm in
your resolve it,
not to cooperate with the U.S.
government...
I am.
Yeah.
Then do not talk to anybody
else about your case.
Inside of government
or outside.
Except to me, to the
extent that you trust me.
I have a mandate to serve you.
Nobody else does.
Frankly, everybody else
has an interest...
in sending you to
the electric chair.
All right!
You do not seem alarmed.
Would it help?
I would like
materials to draw.
That is not possible.
A pencil, a piece of paper.
Cigarettes.
Please?
Mr. Donovan, you
is a man like me,
doing the same for
your country.
If they were caught...
I am sure that you wish
them treated well.
What is your name?
Francis Gary Powers.
Rank, service?
First Lieutenant, United
States Air Force.
Do you have any association?
With the Soviet Union,
Lieutenant Powers.
Are you kidding?
Just answer the
questions, lieutenant.
Yes, no, or as
simply as you can.
Do you have any association
with the Soviet Union?
Hell, no.
Do you know why you are here?
Is that a no?
Yes. I mean...
No. It is just "no."
Yes. I have absolutely
no idea why I am here.
Eyes front, Lieutenant.
Yes, sir.
How would you do
in there, Gary?
Very good. I think. I
got my name right.
You probably outscored
Shin, then.
Who is winning?
That would be me.
Well, deal me in.
These are all mine, then.
I told you boys not
to play with him.
Okay, drivers.
Here is the deal.
You selected for a mission.
Which you are not to discuss.
With anyone outside
of this room.
No one.
I do not care who you trust.
Wife, mother, sweetheart.
The good Lord when
you pray at night.
You do not tell any
of them anything.
Of what I am about
to tell you.
Each of drivers has met
certain qualifications.
High-level security clearance.
Exceptional pilot ratings...
in excess of the required
hour's flight time...
in a single-seat aircraft.
We are engaged in a war.
A war does in this moment,
not involve men-at-arms.
It involves information.
You will be collecting
information.
You will be gathering
intelligence about the enemy.
The intelligence you gather
could give us the upper hand...
in a full thermonuclear
exchange with the Soviet Union.
Or it could prevent one.
For public purposes,
as far as your wife or mother.
Or, sweetheart, the good Lord,
your mission does not exist.
If it does not exist.
You do not exist.
You cannot be shot down.
You cannot be captured.
You work for the CIA now.
Jim, I heard your person is
speaking with a phony accent.
Does he keep this
up all the time?
Actually, I am sure that
is just the way he talks.
He has the Russian name.
However, a British passport.
I doubt that is genuine.
So, Jim, where are we?
I see here...
Yes. Judge, you see...
I just do not think that three
weeks are going to do it.
We got a massive amount
of evidence, as you know.
Do you want to postpone?
Six weeks.
I mean, there is just myself
and, my associate.
Jim, is this serious?
Sir?
Is this serious?
Yes. Yes, indeed it is.
You can see in the file.
Jim, this man is a Soviet spy.
- Allegedly.
- Come on! Counselor!
Your Honor.
Of course, I salute you.
We all salute you for
taking on a thankless task.
This man has due process.
Let us not kid each other.
He will receive a
capable defense.
And, God willing.
He will be convicted.
Come on! Counselor.
Let us not play
games with this.
Not in my courtroom.
We have a date.
And, we are going to trial.
Taxi!
I see your light on!
Son of a bitch!
You cannot wait to get
back to Manhattan.
His light was on, right?
Son of a bitch!
Against their
level of comfort.
The statute has not changed.
Excuse me, Sir.
Pardon me. Sorry.
Mr. Donovan?
What?
CIA.
Yeah.
I just wanted to chat.
How is the case going?
The case is going great,
could not be better.
Has your person talked?
Excuse me.
You met him. Has he talked?
Has he said anything yet?
We are not having
this conversation.
No. Of course not.
No. I mean. We really
are not having it.
You are asking me to violate
attorney-client privilege.
Come on! Counselor.
You know, I wish
people like you.
Would stop saying: "Come on!
Counselor."
I did not like it the first
time it happened today.
A judge said it to me twice.
And, more I hear it,
more I do not like it.
Ok. Listen. I understand
attorney-client privilege.
I understand all the
legal competitiveness.
I understand that is
how you make a living.
I am talking to you
about something else.
The security of your country.
And, I am sorry if the way
I put it offends you.
We need to know. What
is Abel telling to you?
Do you understand me, Donovan?
We need to know.
You do not go with
"Boy Scout" on me.
We do not have a
rulebook, here.
You are Agent Hoffman, yeah.
Yeah.
German extraction.
Yeah, so?
My name is Donovan. Irish.
Both sides, mother and father.
I am Irish. You are German.
What makes us both Americans?
Just one thing.
One, one, one.
The rulebook.
We call it the Constitution.
And, we agree to the rules.
That is what makes
us Americans.
It is all that makes
So, do not tell me
there is no rulebook.
And, do not nod at me like
that, you son of a bitch!
Do we need to worry
about you?
Not if I have been left
alone to do my job.
From this moment, forward.
You will not refer to the
U-2 as a spy plane.
Or, reconnaissance aircraft.
You will refer to it
as: "The Article."
The Article has an
80-foot wingspan.
A single Pratt powers and
Whitney J57 P-37 engine.
10,000 pounds of thrust.
A maximum speed of
430 miles an hour.
She may not be quick,
but at your cruising
altitude of 70,000 feet,
nothing will come
close to you.
70,000?
The idea is the enemy does
not even, know you are there.
It looks somewhat flimsy.
Every extra pound of weight
costs a foot in altitude.
We need to accommodate
the cameras.
That is a 4,500-millimeter
lens, times three.
A pin-sharp panoramic camera.
Four times as powerful as any aerial
reconnaissance cameras we have ever used.
You are going taking
pictures, many pictures.
At 70,000 feet. The
Article can photograph.
2,000 square miles of
territories in one pass.
Now, drivers,
give the Agent Sumner
your undivided attention.
The items you will need on
your mission is all over here.
B camera, revere 8
model 40 magazine,
Keystone Capri K-25, silver.
All how handle shaving brush.
Complete set of cipher tablets
on edible silver, foil.
Specialist photographic
equipment.
Yeah. We get the idea.
Thank you.
Excuse me. Agent Bosco.
"Blasco."
Sir.
There seems to be a
subsection to this list here.
Most of this stuff
came from his studio.
But, the rest is from the hotel
room he was holed up in.
Where we found him.
The hotel room you searched.
Yeah.
Can I see the warrant?
What?
Yeah, explain this to me.
There was a warrant.
A civil detention writ for
the arrest of an alien,
but, there was no
search warrant,
for suspicion of
criminal activity.
So, the search,
and the evidence.
That is the fruit
of that search,
That is all tainted, and
should not be admitted.
What protections he is due,
your honor. The man is not...
Who is the man? He is
Rudolf Ivanovich Abel.
He is a Soviet citizen.
He is not an American.
1886, Wick Wo vs. Hopkins.
The court held that even aliens,
in case Chinese immigrants,
could not be held to answer for a
crime without due process of law,
including any, alien that
entered the country illegally.
The Department of Justice...
has its first allegiance
to the United States.
I do not see how an alien,
if he is here illegally,
how he suffered
deprivation of rights.
Rights as what?
An American?
Rights as what, Counselor?
We are in a battle
for civilization.
This Russian spy came here
to threaten our way of life.
Now, I have a courtroom
of people waiting.
Get out there, sit
beside the Russian.
Let us get this over and done.
And, your motion is denied.
He should take some
insurance out on himself.
How did we do?
In there.
Not too good.
Apparently, you are not
an American citizen.
That is true.
And according to your boss.
You are not a Soviet
citizen either.
Well, the boss is
not always, right.
He is always the boss.
Do you never worry?
Would it help?
All rise!
"I pledge allegiance
to the Flag."
"Of the United
States of America."
"And to the Republic
for which it stands."
"One Nation under
God, indivisible."
"With liberty and
justice for all."
First, you have to
know what happens,
when an atomic bomb explodes.
There is a bright flash,
brighter than the sun.
It can smash buildings,
break windows all over town.
But if you are in shelter
and cover like Bert,
you will be much safer.
There are two kinds of attack,
with warning, without
any warning.
What is going on in here?
Okay, Dad.
This is very important.
When the war begins, the
first thing, they do...
Is cut off all the water,
and, all the electricity.
The first thing we should
do is keep filled,
use the shower in your room,
use the sink downstairs,
the garden hose outside.
Those are good ideas.
Roger, I do not see this.
As being something, you
have to worry.
Yeah, but when you
hear the sirens.
There may not be enough time
to fill the tub and the sinks.
Not will have any sirens.
What is this?
When the bomb comes,
the Reds will aim go for
the Empire State Building.
But, the bomb goes off
at 10,000 feet up.
In Life magazine, it
is called an air burst.
And, if the bomb
is 50 megatons.
The blast wave goes
out and out and out.
And, melts everything
from here to here.
Including where we live.
Yeah. Right there.
You know Roger,
no one is dropping
Atomic bombs on us.
The Russians want to.
You know that Russian
person, you are defending.
He is here to get
things ready.
For the people who
drop the bombs.
No. No, he is not...
Not is here for that.
He is not even Russian.
He was born, we think,
in Northern England.
Yeah. But, he is a
spy for Russia.
I do not even understand.
What are you doing?
You are not a Communist.
So, why are you defending one?
Well, because it is my job.
It never used to be.
In the case of the United
States of America,
versus Rudolf Abel.
As to the first count
in the indictment.
How do you find the defendant?
Guilty or not guilty?
Guilty.
As to the second count?
As to the third count?
Guilty.
Your honor. I make a motion to
set aside these guilty verdicts.
Against the weight
of evidence.
Denied.
The jury discharged.
Thank you.
I would like to add that,
if I were one of you.
I would have reached
the same verdict.
Sentencing will be.
November 15.
The death sentence is not
a foregone conclusion.
Do not worry.
I am not afraid to die,
Mr. Donovan.
Although.
It would not be
my first choice.
You left this behind.
Thank you.
Thank you very much!
You have never asked me,
if the charges were true.
If I am indeed a spy.
This is how we do it.
The case against you matters.
Making them prove it matters.
The fiction is...
Whether you did it or
not does not matter.
The state has to prove
it, that you are a spy.
You are not curious.
No, not really.
I always assumed you
were an artist.
My wife, she is the artist.
She is a musician.
In the Children's
Orchestra of Moscow.
What instrument?
The Harp.
Then, she is an Angel.
Standing there like that,
you remind me a man,.
Who used to come to our house.
When I was young.
My father used to say:
"Watch this man."
I did every time he came.
And, never once.
He did anything remarkable.
And, I remind you of him.
This one time, I was about
the age of your son.
Our house overrun by
partisan border guards.
Dozens of them.
My father was beaten and
my mother was beaten.
This man, my father's
friend, he was beaten.
I watched this man.
Every time they hit him.
He stood back up again.
They hit him harder.
Still, he gets back on his feet.
I think because of this,
they stopped beating him.
They let him alive.
I remember them saying it.
It means like:
"Standing man."
- Hello, Jim!
- Millie, you are a vision.
Mortie is busy getting ready.
Come on in.
- Scotch, Jim?
- Yes, please. Thank you.
Just a drop of water.
Your honor.
Hello, Jim! Just going out.
I got a few minutes though.
March of Dimes thing.
Millie is active.
Well, thank you for seeing me.
I just wanted to give you my
two cents on the sentencing.
And, I thought maybe, I
should pester you at home.
As not all of my points
are narrowly legal.
Yeah. It is that kind of case.
I hope I was not too
scratchy during the trial.
It is exactly what you say.
Nothing about this
is narrowly legal.
There are bigger issues.
Bigger issues!
Thank you, thank you.
Sir?
I think it could
be considered.
In the best interests
of the United States.
That Abel remains alive.
Why?
I am not saying, I
made up my mind.
But if he was going
to cooperate,
work with the government.
He would have done it already.
- True, but the issue here.
- You cannot.
Excuse me.
You cannot say it is in the best
interest of the United States.
That he spend the rest of
his days in a prison cell.
How is this national interest?
Not the incarceration
itself, Sir.
It is possible in
the near future.
An American of
equivalent rank.
Might be captured
by Soviet Russia.
We might want to have
someone to trade.
Wow!
That sounds like what-ifs.
You could do that until
the cows come home.
It is my business, what-ifs.
I am in insurance.
And, there is nothing
implausible about this one.
It is entirely really,
of what could happen.
It is the kind of probability
for people buys insurance.
If we send this person to his death.
We leave ourselves wide open.
No policy in our back pocket,
for the day the storm comes.
Nice speech.
Sir, there is also the
humanitarian an argument.
Should he die for doing the
job they sent him to do?
All right! Counselor.
I have to run.
Good see you, Jim.
I will walk you out.
All rise!
The United States
District Court.
For the Eastern District of
New York is now in session.
The honorable Mortimer
Byers presiding.
Be seated.
The defendant
will please rise.
In the measured
judgment of this court,
the following sentence,
based upon the jury's
verdict of guilty.
As to each count
of the indictment,
is believe to meet the
test, which has stated.
Pursuant to the verdict of
guilty as to all counts.
The defendant is committed
to the custody,
of the Attorney General
of the United States.
For imprisonment in a
federal institution,
to be selected by him for
a period of 30 years.
Marshals, you may take the
defendant into custody.
No... No electrocution?
No. No, no.
Why are not we hanging him?
In the name of God.
Sit down!
He is a spy! He is killing
us with his lies!
In the name of God.
Why are not we hanging him?
That is right!
He is a spy!
Mr. Donovan? Mr. Donovan?
- Just one question.
- Just one question, Sir.
My hat! My hat!
Nobody here has a comment.
Mr. and Mrs. Donovan
are not answering questions.
How do you feel now?
This national
nightmare is over.
Mr. Donovan, are you
happy with the verdict?
We are... We are firm
in case on appeal.
- Appeal?
- Appeal, yes.
Jim, you did a great job.
You fulfilled your
mandate and, then some.
The man is a spy.
The verdict is correct and there
is no reason to appeal it?
There is ample
procedural reason.
We know the search is tainted.
Fourth Amendment issues.
Will always weigh more heavily
in an appellate forum.
We have a good shot.
What about the goddamn
are you talking?
We were supposed to show he had a
capable defense, which we did.
Why are you citing the
goddamn constitution at me?
Tom, if you look
me in the eye.
And, tell me we do
not have grounds,
for an appeal, I will
drop it right now.
I am not saying that, you
know what I am saying.
Tom is saying there is
a cost to these things.
That is right.
A cost to both your
family and your firm.
I missed music.
They checked the radio to make sure
there was no transmitter in it.
I am sure they did.
That is a very great
artist, Shostakovitch.
I think.
Our strongest grounds
for reversal,
are constitutional.
Our best chance is if the Supreme
Court agrees to review your case.
Jim.
You should be careful.
Careful.
77 Sunset Strip.
Edward Byrnes.
And Richard Long.
Good morning, Suzanne.
Good morning, Dick.
There is a special delivery
letter here for you.
Her.
Mom!
What in the God's
name happened.
Honey, are you all right?
- Mom!
- Are you hurt?
I have her to upstairs!
- Are you all right?
- I sat with my back against the wall, Dad!
Are you okay?
Are you all right?
Dad, I sat with my
back against the wall!
- Good, good.
- Away from the windows!
Good, good, good.
Good boy, good boy, good boy.
It is okay. It is all right!
It is all right! They are
gone. They are gone.
They are cowards.
They are gone.
We have detectives
canvassing in the neighborhood.
Maybe we will find a
description of the car.
I do not think It
is very likely.
We are going to
need protection.
I have instructions to
leave two cars here.
It will be very obvious.
For how long.
I have to be in Washington
later on this week.
What are you doing?
What are you doing
to your family?
Pardon me, Officer.
You are still defending
this person.
Why are you fighting for him?
Okay. Knock that off, Officer.
I will knock off nothing.
I was in the third
wave at Omaha Beach.
I did my time in the service.
I was fighting these people.
Are you defending them?
Why do not you just do your
job as an officer of the law?
Okay, I am sorry. Let
us go outside. Come on!
What do you know?
Just forget him.
What am I not getting here?
Outside, Officer. I am sorry.
Defending a commie spy. Jesus!
Do you feel you
deserve this, Sir?
Should it become necessary?
To abandon the aircraft
over Soviet territory.
Then, there is a two and a
half-pound explosive charge,
contained within the fuselage.
First, you activate the circuits.
But to start the
70-second timer.
You need to flip the
switch marked: "Destruct."
It is imperative these
flights remain a secret.
And, this equipment does
not fall into enemy hands.
What about us?
I do not know if you are
kidding, Lieutenant Powers.
I am not.
What do you know
about the plane,
is as secret as
the plane itself.
If capture is a
foregone conclusion.
You go down with your plane.
Now, if you think, you
can ditch and get away.
If you are, close enough
to a border, fine.
You know the
ejection protocol.
But, if you ditch.
You bring the dollar with you.
There is a pin inside.
You scratch your skin anywhere,
it is instantaneous.
If you think, you
will be captured...
You use it.
Drivers do you understand me?
Spend the dollar.
Mr. Chief of Justice,
may it please the court?
The "Cold War" is not just
a phrase. Your Honor.
It is not just a
figure of speech.
Truly, a battle
is being fought,
between two competing
views of the world.
I contend that Rudolf
Ivanovich Abel.
"Colonel Abel,"
as he was called.
Even by the man
who arrested him.
Is our foe in that battle?
Auxiliary power.
Connected and on.
Oxygen seat pack supply.
Supply at 1,800.
Inverter?
On, light out.
He was treated as a
combatant in that war.
Until it no longer suited our
government to treat him.
Accordingly.
He not gave the protections.
We give our own citizens.
He subjected to
treatment that,
however appropriate for a
suspected enemy.
It was not appropriate
to a suspected criminal.
Fuel transfer?
Transfer switch off.
Destructor?
Destructor safety.
Climb data card.
Installed in aircraft.
I know this man.
If the charge is true, he serves a foreign
power but he serves it faithfully.
If he is a soldier in the opposing
army, he is a good soldier.
He has not fled the field
of battle to save himself.
He has refused to
serve his captor.
betray his cause.
He has refused to take
the cowards' way out.
The coward must
abandon his dignity.
Before he abandons
the field of battle.
That Rudolf Abel will never do.
Should not we?
By give him the full benefit.
Of the rights that define
our system of government.
Show this man who we are.
Who we are.
Is that the greatest weapon?
We have in this Cold War.
Will we stand by our
cause less resolutely?
Than he stands by his.
The President announced.
That a NASA weather plane disappeared
four days ago north of Turkey.
And, the Space
Administration fears.
That its pilot
died in the crash.
Radar showed the plane
wandering off course.
Deep into Soviet territory
before contact was lost,
complicated any
effort to recover it.
Or the remains of the pilot.
Now the news out
of Washington.
In a close vote today.
The Supreme Court
affirmed the conviction.
Of Russian spy Rudolf
Ivanovich Abel.
Five votes to four.
The case presented civil
liberties issues.
According to the Russian's
lawyer, James B. Donovan.
When asked how he felt
about today's loss,
Mr. Donovan simply
said: "Tired."
I will have more news for you
after this message.
Styling tricks.
It is over.
See the new, exciting
styling tricks.
You...
Marty?
I will be damned if I can find the
file on that Prudential case.
I... Mr. Waters had moved it
over to Jack Elwes's office.
Along with the first
draft of the appeal.
He did.
Yeah. He redrafted and filed that last
week while you were in Washington.
How long have we
been together?
You act as if I have
never closed a deal.
Set up a meeting
somewhere fancy.
I am betting Mr. Young would
like some of the finer things.
New York has to offer.
I want you to give
me the summary of...
Do you know anyone
from Leipzig?
"Leipzig." Am I getting
hate mail from Germany now?
From East Germany.
Is it your new one?
No.
No, no, no, no.
She pretends to be but it is
not even a good pretense.
"I am taking this liberty
to write to you."
"After having learned
from the newspapers."
"About your most
humane attitude."
"Towards my beloved
husband, Rudolf Abel."
Do I write back?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
What is the next move when you
do not know the game?
Francis Gary Powers.
"On the strength of Article
2 of the U.S.S.R. law."
"On criminal responsibility
for state crimes."
"To 10 years of confinement."
"The first three years
to be served in the prison."
"The term of the punishment,"
"including preliminary
detention."
"It shall be counted
from May 1,"
"nineteen hundred and sixty."
Mr. Donovan. Thank you
so much for coming.
It is a pleasure to
meet you, Mr. Dulles.
It is an honor, Sir.
Nescafe, cream, two lumps.
Thank you.
Okay, this letter
you received,
seems clear that the Soviets
are making an overture here.
They are doing it
through East Germany.
Because they still do not want to
acknowledge Abel as a Soviet citizen.
Much less a Soviet spy. So...
Lot of fiction is going on.
Yes, Sir, but you know end.
They got our person,
our spy pilot.
We have their person.
Prisoner exchange, I think
that is what they are after.
Which could hardly be a
surprise to you, Counselor?
It is an eventuality.
I think you foresaw.
Yes. I sure did, and I
am so rarely right.
Congratulations
Red-letter day.
Now, we have our man
over there. Powers.
Good man, but with a head full
of classified information.
Abel has a head full of
classified information, too.
He has not given us a lick.
Sir takes it from me.
He will not.
Yes, we know that, but
the Russians do not.
They want their man
back before he cracks.
We want Powers back
for the same reasons.
I think you are saying, Sir...
That might be a successful
conclusion for everyone.
Yes, if we indulge
their fiction.
We want you to
negotiate the swap.
Because you are a
private citizen.
It is not governments talking.
They do not acknowledge
Abel as a Soviet citizen.
We do not acknowledge East
Germany as a sovereign country.
We have not recognized
East Berlin.
Since it annexed by
the Soviets in 45.
I act as a negotiator,
representing...
You are not
representing anybody.
Not a government official.
You have no official standing.
So, some fiction on
our side as well.
Correct.
This means, of course, you cannot
rely on any acknowledgment.
Or, help if things go south.
CIA cannot be responsible.
We cannot be embarrassed.
Where do they want this
negotiation to take place?
There.
"There"?
East Berlin.
Well, is not East Berlin
getting rather...?
Yes, the place is
getting complicated.
Yeah, complicated.
The Soviet side has been setting up
checkpoints for the past few months.
To try to stop people hemorrhaging
to the Western sectors.
It has not worked.
We have intelligence
to suggest.
They may go one-step further.
And, well off the
entire Eastern sector.
Okay, that is it briefly.
The decision is
entirely yours.
You need time to kick around it.
No.
No. I do not.
Fine. Fine.
Best this all remains
confidential.
Let us not discuss any of this
with Mary or anyone else.
Share the correspondence
only with us.
Let us know what they
want to do and when.
I have no client, no
wife and no country.
Do not know what for I
am doing or when or who?
You are doing it
for your country.
But, your country does
not know that yet.
What about my client, the other
person in this equation? My person?
Your person? You
mean the Russian.
He is not your person
anymore, Counselor.
Your person is Francis
Gary Powers now.
What do I tell to Rudolf Abel?
Tell him not to drop dead.
Professor?
Papa went to university.
You should not be
here, Frederic.
They are having classes today.
He went to see where he goes.
What are you doing here?
I came to get you,
and your father.
You have to come with me. You
might not get out tomorrow.
Just... Just leave.
Yes. Yes, yes, yes, leave.
Right now.
Go back. Go back.
I will be okay. I am American.
Go back.
Go back to your father.
We will find another way. Go.
Hey.
Sir. Hi.
Papers, please.
The Student Frederic Pryor.
Yes, student.
What kind of photos?
My name is Frederic Pryor.
I am an economics student.
It is my dissertation.
My thesis.
You see. Look, look.
"The foreign trade system of the
European Communist nations."
It was a lot of work.
No. That is my only copy.
No!
Tell me something.
It came up at the last minute.
They have offices in London.
These clients. Not my idea.
Scotland, this
fishing expedition.
What kind of
fishing trip, Jim?
Salmon fishing.
Just tell me that you are
not going to be in any danger.
This is just a routine
business trip.
I will not worry.
I need my passport.
Just give me something
to hold on.
I do not even care
if it is the truth.
I am doing this for us.
Mr. Michener here is
your Berlin escort.
He is an attache with the U.S.
embassy.
It has gotten goddamn
complicated.
As you know, the last
letter from Mrs. Abel.
Whoever she is, talks about
a lawyer in East Berlin.
Mr. Vogel, whoever he is,
representing her interests, she says.
Yeah. Vogel says.
He has gone to the Russian
embassy in East Berlin.
They may be ready to
trade Abel for Powers.
No one knows who is who.
Essentially, they
are Russian, right.
Well! Soviet. We think so.
What do you mean? Could we
turn up the heat in here?
There is a wrinkle.
They might try to throw
you a curve ball.
Try to get you to accept another
prisoner other than Powers.
Another American?
The East German Stasis picked
up an American student.
Frederic Pryor.
The kid they found on the
wrong side of the Wall.
He is a graduate
student of Yale.
Came over here to
study economics.
They are making noises about
trying this kid for espionage.
Grave offense, capital crime.
Vogel got in touch with us,
said he represents Pryor.
Wait a minute! Vogel represents
Mrs. Abel and this kid?
Yeah, he is busy.
What is he?
Vogel is East German or Russian?
Try to figure it out
when you meet him.
At Russian embassy, East
Berlin, noon tomorrow.
Hoffman will show you
how to get there.
Wait! Show me how to get there.
I am going to have an escort.
Right?
That was the plan but as I
said, there is a wrinkle.
I will not be taking you.
Decision has made.
No U.S. government personnel are to
cross the border until further notice.
- Why?
- It is too dangerous.
The East Germans
grabbed this kid.
There is a degree of impunity.
We had not anticipated.
The point is the East German
agenda and the Russian agenda.
May not be the same thing.
Try to figure it out
and, act accordingly.
Try to make a deal.
Powers for Abel.
What about this
college kid, Pryor?
Do not you fall for that?
We can get him out
another time.
Powers is the whole ball game.
Where is your room?
I will be staying
at the Hilton.
It is not far.
This is a number
here in West Berlin.
Memorize it, and
give it back to me.
No, no. I... I mean, now.
The Soviets keep cutting
the international lines.
Local calls are okay.
Someone will pick
up day and night.
Now, this docket attached to your
passport will serve as your ticket.
Into and out of the
Eastern Soviet sector.
The meeting with Vogel is
set for noon tomorrow.
There are only a few
routes left to the East.
You take the S-Bah, the station.
We showed you on the way in.
You are going to get off at the
Friedrichstrasse station here.
Walk to the Soviet embassy
on Under den Linden here.
Look at the map now. You
should not take it with you.
You are looking at a map. You
are an American. You are a spy.
You could well detain.
Just avoid interacting
with people generally.
You do not... You do not
belong, so do not stick out.
Food is scarce over there and
things have started to fall apart.
There are gangs.
And, rule of law is less firm
established over there.
Definitely stay
away from the Wall.
On their side,
there is a line.
Cleared of buildings
along the Wall.
They call it the "Death Line."
Cross it and you will shot.
Where is there any outcome here?
I am not either detained or shot.
You do not worry too much,
about what Michener said.
No. I am worried about
what you are saying.
This kid, Pryor.
That the East Germans have.
How old is he?
Twenty-five. Why?
Same age as Dougie.
Who?
An associate of mine.
Frederic Pryor.
Okay, okay, okay.
We apologize if this offends.
Coat?
- Do you understand English?
- Yes, Sir.
I am James Donovan.
I am here to meet a Mr. Vogel.
Mr. Vogel. He does
not work here.
I am just supposed to meet
him. That is all I know.
Mr. Donovan!
We finally meet you.
I am Helen Abel.
- How is my husband?
- He is fine.
How is my Rudolf?
As good as, he can be expected.
We will get him back. Yes.
- This is our daughter.
- How do you do?
Lydia.
Are you Mr. Vogel?
No, no, no!
I am not Vogel.
I am Drew's cousin.
This is Rudolf's
beloved Drew's cousin.
- Yes. Drew's cousin.
- I am Drew's cousin.
Drew's cousin, yes.
I am Helen Abel.
When will you see him?
When will your government
releases him?
I am a little lost here.
I am supposed to meet
a Mr. Vogel.
Mr. Vogel is our lawyer.
We were supposed to
negotiate the exchange.
- Do you bring Rudolf here?
- Yes, yes, bring him here.
It does not happen unilaterally.
Do you understand?
It has to be an exchange.
Not here.
Mr. Donovan?
Mr. Vogel?
No, no, no. Goodness.
My name is Schischkin.
Ivan Schischkin.
I am the second secretary
of the Soviet embassy.
It would not be appropriate
for Mr. Vogel to join us.
He is a German national.
You are not here to...
To facilitate this meeting.
Perhaps Mrs. Abel,
would like to compose
her privately?
And let Mr. Donovan
and me to talk.
Thank you.
- So, I am confused.
- Yes.
I do not care
whom I talk to...
If it is about an
exchange of personnel.
Are you the person to talk?
Yes, yes, yes, of course!
We should talk.
Please, have a seat
Mr. Donovan.
How did you arrive to
the Eastern sector?
The train. The S-Bah.
You were alone.
Yeah.
You are credentialed.
Now, you must know
about me, Sir.
I am a private citizen.
I am a lawyer in Brooklyn
in the United States.
I have taken time out
of my busy schedule.
To help my client,
Rudolf Abel.
I authorized to arrange
an exchange of Abel.
For Francis Gary Powers.
This is a full pardon of Abel.
That will be signed when the
exchange actually takes place.
This is the only
reason I am here.
I hope and expect to make
this arrangement quickly.
Abel for Francis Gary Powers.
And, Frederic Pryor.
We do not have Pryor.
No? You do not!
I have heard of
Pryor, he has held,
by the German
Democratic Republic.
Not by the Union of Soviet
Socialist Republics.
I will tell you the
first problem.
The names of your
countries are too long.
Yes, yes.
If we release Powers.
It is only to promote
a good will...
Between our countries.
So, it cannot be an exchange.
Perhaps...
Perhaps you could
release Abel.
As a token of good will to
our friends in Germany.
Then, some months later.
We would release Powers.
- There is an idea.
- No. That Just will not work for us at all.
We need this to
be an exchange.
You can call it
what you want...
But an exchange it must be.
We can have Abel here
within 48 hours.
We need Powers at the same
time. We give you Abel.
This is...
Can we call this the
"impatient plan"?
You can call it
whatever you want.
I can relay your impatient
plan to Moscow.
See what they say...
They will wonder
why so impatient.
Because I have a cold.
I do not live in Berlin.
I want to go home.
They will think...
"Well, the Americans
must have gotten..."
"All the information
that Abel had to give."
"And now they are
impatient to trade him."
"Hoping to get in return
this man Powers."
"Perhaps, has not
yet given up..."
"All the information
that he has to give."
This is not an
equitable trade, Sir.
What you are saying is...
If Powers has given up
everything, he knows.
Then Moscow would trade?
Why would not they?
As for Abel, if he dies
in an American prison.
The next Russian
operative who is caught.
Might think twice about
keeping his mouth shut.
You never know. Abel might
want to see the sky again.
And, decide to trade Russian
secrets for small American favors.
How can we know this?
We are little man.
We just do our jobs.
Like Lieutenant Powers.
He is just a pilot.
He was making photographs
from 70,000 feet.
When he has shot from the sky.
People in my country
consider this...
An act of war.
We have to get off this
merry-go-round, Sir.
The next mistake our
countries make...
Could be the last one.
We need to have
the conversation.
Our governments cannot.
I will ask Moscow.
Who knows, what they will say.
There are many people,
Mr. Donovan.
Who does not want this
exchange ever takes place.
Can you come back tomorrow
to discuss their answer?
Powers for Abel.
And, Frederic Pryor.
As I said...
Pryor is in the hands
of the organs...
State Security of the
German Democratic Republic.
I am confident. You can
make arrangements.
I am merely a secretary.
In the embassy of
foreign Powers.
Okay.
You have to see Mr. Vogel.
I will give you his address.
There actually is a Mr. Vogel?
Why would you
imagine otherwise?
It is a short cab ride.
Please, Mr. Donovan...
Wear an overcoat
in this weather.
I had my stolen from me.
What do you expect?
It was from Saks Fifth Avenue.
Was not it?
Mr. Donovan.
Mr. Vogel.
- Please, come in.
- Ok.
Sorry about the embassy.
The Soviets decided
not to host me.
That is very irritating.
I am still trying to
grasp each party is...
Status?
Yes. And, interest
in the proceedings.
It is a new world.
All are very disorienting.
Is not it?
Let me tell you what
I have to offer.
I am a good friend...
- "Friend."
- No, he is older.
"Protege"?
Of the attorney general of the
German Democratic Republic.
Sit down, please.
This is unfortunate.
Frederic Pryor.
He was in the wrong place
at the wrong time.
But every accident,
properly viewed...
Is an opportunity?
Is not it, Mr. Donovan?
Your country refuses
to recognize.
The German
Democratic Republic.
They prefer to
make up stories.
That the G.D.R does not
exist, for instance.
Sorry.
As a means of forcing your
Government's recognition...
this real place. Sir.
In which you find yourself...
The G.D.R.
The attorney general is happy
to negotiate with you.
As a representative
of your government.
For Mr. Pryor return.
Mr. Vogel, I am not here.
As a representative
of my government.
All right!
I think that is childish,
Mr. Donovan.
I have no official status.
Fine.
You do not represent the USA.
I do not represent the G.D.R.
My client is Lydia
Abel, Rudolf's wife.
And, I have...
Lydia is the daughter.
Helen is the wife.
Well...
I am prepared to offer...
Frederic Pryor in exchange
for Rudolf Abel.
Then let us be clear.
We will produce Rudolf Abel.
You will produce, at the same
time, the student, Pryor.
At the same time?
Absolutely.
The exchange on offer is a
Russian at the end of his life.
For an American student
at the start of his.
Schischkin? He is not a
secretary of embassy.
Ivan Schischkin is the chief
of KGB in western Europe.
Whatever he is...
He is relaying our
proposal to Moscow.
And, they will decide.
Can I borrow your coat?
I lost mine.
How did you lose your coat?
You know, spy stuff.
- I will get you another coat.
- Good, because...
Who is...? Who is this Vogel?
He... We do not know.
He might be what
you said he is.
Friend of the
attorney general.
Just some person the G.D.R
tapped to handle this.
Sounds like the East Germans...
are fighting for a
place at our table.
The G.D.R gets Abel back
for the Russians...
winning their respect...
capturing the headlines
for their cause.
Which puts the East Germany
on the map.
We do not care
about their map.
Stick to the Russians.
It is Powers for Abel.
What does all mean?
This might actually happen.
Yeah. That is what you
seem to be telling me.
We will put Abel on a plane.
He will be here Friday.
So, if Schischkin gets the okay.
All that is the mechanics
of the trade.
How we swap our person
for their person.
Our "guys." Two people.
Powers and Pryor.
No. Now do not go
bleeding heart on me.
Powers is the whole ball game.
Forget this Ivy League boy.
Obviously it was a good idea.
To study Soviet
Economics in Berlin.
In the middle of the Cold War.
Powers is whom we need.
You do not even like Powers.
Everybody hates Powers.
He did not kill himself and he let
the commies parade on television.
He is the most hated
man in America.
After Rudolf Abel, maybe.
And me.
Now wake up! Come out.
I have to sleep.
I just have to sleep.
I told you could sleep.
Once we talk what
need to talk.
You must focus on me.
Your government does not care
about you. You know that.
Any of you.
You know that 12 U-2 pilots
incurred brain damage.
They are vegetables because of
altitude, insufficient oxygen.
They keep you flying, Gary.
You and your friends.
They gave you this,
a scratchier.
Potassium Cyanide.
Does that look like
they care about you?
What is the construction
of the destructor unit?
What means is this
unit working?
With what explosives
the unit charges.
What destruction
is it capable?
I do not know.
They never showed any of the
equipment to the pilots.
How far can the radar hide?
An area on map during flight.
I do not know! I do not know!
And you were making the
flight on April 9?
On the industrial area
and MIR bomber base.
At Baranovichi.
I was not.
This was my first flight.
I need to know about of
engine out glide to the ratio.
How the plane gets so high.
We know it reaches
altitude of 70,000 feet.
Gary, we know this.
I need to know where
the planes have flown.
Where they have flown, Gary.
We must have this talk now.
Now.
Then you can sleep a little.
Sir, wake up.
Wake up, Sir.
- Sir, can you come with me, please?
- Yeah.
- We have to move.
- Yeah, of course!
- Can you come with me, please?
- Yeah.
Okay.
Take your glasses.
- What time is it?
- It is late but, we need to talk.
We need that you get
in a plane, okay?
Yeah. Upsy-daisy!
- Upsy-daisy.
- That is right.
There we go. Keep moving.
Thank you.
Other way, other way.
There we go.
You say a plane.
This way, please. Keep moving.
So, I received a
favorable decision.
From Moscow on your proposal.
That we help our friends in the
German Democratic Republic.
By exchanging.
Mr. Powers for Mr. Abel.
That is well.
May I suggest the Glienicke
Bridge as a place of exchange?
Why not Checkpoint Charlie?
We are not looking
for publicity.
The Glienicke Bridge
is very quiet.
Especially early
in the morning.
Glienicke Bridge.
I will run to our side.
We can have Abel
here on Friday.
So, Saturday morning.
Always impatience, yeah.
I want to get home,
go into my bed.
So, Saturday morning.
5:30 p.m.
All right!
We have done here.
This is a number.
In case, anything
should come up.
All right!
Someone will answer
at any hour.
I do not expect to use it.
Shall we toast
the arrangement?
Why not?
Armenian Brandy.
- Good for your cold.
- Thank you.
Would you mind...?
This is not part
of our business.
I would like to ask you
a couple of questions.
You do not have to answer.
I have the answer what I know.
I like this person,
your person.
What happens to your person.
When he gets home.
We have to make a
determination.
Whether our person
is now your person.
Now, as I said to you before...
He has acted honorably.
He is still your person,
believe me.
Of course! You will
say if it were true.
If it were not true.
I guess it has come down.
Well, forgive me for pushing.
But is he in any danger?
If the determination is made.
Well, goodness.
As things are now,
everyone is in danger.
Cheers.
There will be no exchange
on Glienicke Bridge.
Excuse me, Sir.
There will be no exchange.
Not for Frederic Pryor.
Mr. Vogel, I thought
yesterday we have agreed.
We agreed on an exchange,
Abel for Pryor.
Now I learn, you are
a rug merchant.
Selling the same rug
to two customers.
- Abel for Pryor you sell to us.
- Yeah.
Abel for Powers you
sell to the Soviets.
I am not very sure,
the problem is...
If the arrangement satisfies
two parties, three, or four.
What difference does make?
The arrangement does
not satisfy this part.
Now, Mr. Vogel, please...
Obviously, you do not know
who with you are dealing.
The interest of the German
Democratic Republic.
To deal with...
Is it seems dealing with
another sovereign power?
The United States.
An equal power.
Instead, you treat
us as stooges.
For the Union of Soviet
Socialist Republics.
Can we just call them the
Russians? It will save time.
I have an appointment, Sir.
I think you are wasting time.
Now, tell me if I am
describing this wrong.
You have a kid, a
university student.
Someone knows he is not a spy.
Who have not threat to you?
In exchange for this person.
Who is worthless to you?
You play an equal
part in an exchange.
Between the Russians
and, the Americans.
And this is one transaction
between two of you and us.
We are not trying to do
two things here, Sir.
We are just doing one thing.
One, one, one.
It is hard for me to see, how the Republic
of East German Democrats has been slighted.
You agreed with the Soviets
without consulting me.
Is this a negotiation
or a conspiracy?
For it to be a conspiracy...
There would have to
be harm to you, Sir.
There are just benefits here.
We are of agreeing interests.
No. You decide they agree.
Where is your
appointment, sir?
In the West.
Good.
Look around you.
How does the Eastern sector
to compare the West?
Our Russian friends
have decided that...
We should not rebuild
our capital city.
We live in this ruin made
by our Russian friends.
Go ahead. Make your deal
with these Russians.
We will not be part of it.
There is no deal
without Pryor.
We are not leaving him here.
Is this your position
or of your government?
Sir, I am here.
I am talking to you.
You are not a representative
of your government.
They do not know who you are.
Neither do we.
You should be careful. This
is not Brooklyn, Mr. Donovan.
Look, Sir.
You must know every
respect that matters.
I represent my government.
You know who I am.
Do I know?
Do you have the proper papers?
Of course not. It
does not matter.
An American lawyer like you.
Can talk your way of anything?
Cannot you?
You go with him. Sir.
- Why?
- It is passport problem.
What... What is the problem?
What is the problem?
- You go with him.
- Sir. Come with us.
And, remember...
We control the fate
of Frederic Pryor.
My God!
Yeah. I will start with
some coffee, please.
Then I will have
the Hilton Combo.
The American breakfast.
And, coffee.
Both breakfasts?
Yeah, yeah.
One first or...
Both first, both.
When they are ready.
And, coffee.
You should not be here.
Well, sometimes in Germany.
You just want a big
American breakfast.
What happened?
Where were you last night?
Vogel arranged for me to
spend some time in the East.
Jesus!
Frankly, it is not
that much worse.
Than where you have
me here in the West.
The Russians are fine
with the exchange.
Now Vogel is saying that the
East Germans will not do it.
We are not going to get Pryor.
Great. Good.
So, the Soviets are set.
We get Powers.
Well done!
No. The East Germans
will not do it.
We will not get Pryor,
and that kid matters.
Every person matters.
Sure. That is why you tried.
That is why you tried.
Abel is on his way, so we are
all set for tomorrow morning.
- Wait a minute.
- Makes the things simple.
We are not getting the kid.
Yeah. I understand.
We are set.
We can ignore the message.
We got this morning.
What is message?
From the East Germans.
They called the number.
I gave you.
They said that wanted
to speak to you today.
- Vogel called.
- No.
An Officer of Harold Ott.
East German attorney general.
What does he want?
Well, to talk to you.
It is ok. I cannot ask
you to go back there.
Listen, you seem to be a persona
non grata to some elements.
We will not push our luck.
So, he wants to see me.
What time?
No. No. Now, listen. You... You...
You... You do not need to go.
In fact you should not go.
In fact, you cannot go.
We set with the Soviets.
We do not want to screw it up.
- I am not going to screw it up.
- You are not going!
Do not be a pain in the ass.
I ordered.
Enjoy your big
American breakfast.
I thought it should be negotiated.
At the highest level
as a courtesy to you.
Thank you, Sir.
I do not know how things
became so confused.
Well! I guess sometimes
they just became.
For sake of clarity.
I say, we are fully
prepared to exchange.
They called student
Pryor, for Rudolf Abel.
I understand Mr. Vogel that
Pryor is very important to you.
Yes, but...
We will do a memorandum
to that effect.
A memorandum.
Certainly, we commit a
bi-lateral exchange.
Yes, yes, sure. I am not sure.
What that means but...
My country also insists
on Francis Gary Powers.
No!
This is how things
became so confused.
Powers. What use is he, Sir?
You want him back for
punitive reasons.
What has done has done.
He has divulged. What
will he divulge?
As no doubt, Abel has also.
We are offering instead someone,
whom you insist is innocent.
And, this is right.
This is whom you
should retrieve.
The future.
Look to the future.
I am sorry. Could you
give me a moment, Sir?
I am very sorry, Sir.
The attorney general regrets.
That he had to leave
on urgent business.
- He left.
- Yes. Many apologies.
I have been waiting
for him over an hour.
Very sorry, Sir.
Young man?
Come here.
It is all right! Come here.
Take a seat.
Come on! Come on! Sit down.
Do you like your job here?
It is a very good job, Sir.
It must be...
It must be interesting.
Yes, Sir.
And, important too.
Your English is... Is good.
Yes. I hesitate to
say it is excellent.
It is excellent, Sir.
Good, good. Good.
I just lost my
negotiating partner.
And, I need somebody to talk.
You seem like a
reasonable young man.
Can I talk to you?
It is all right!
It is all right! I just...
I just need you to give
a message to your boss.
It has to be very,
very, very clear.
Do you understand?
Yes, Sir. But perhaps you
should wait until him.
No, no. The thing is. I have this
cold and I want to get home.
And, get in bed.
Can you give him the message?
Certainly.
This is the message.
There is no deal for Abel
unless we get Powers and Pryor.
- Do you understand?
- Yes, Sir.
It arranged for
tomorrow morning.
It will not happen,
unless we get two men.
Those two men.
- Two, two, two.
- Yes. Sir.
- Yes.
- If there is no deal.
Your boss must
tell the Soviets.
He has to tell the Soviets.
They are not getting
Rudolf Abel.
Yes, Sir.
And, tell him this.
That so far, Abel has
been a good soldier.
But he thinks is going home.
If we have to tell him it,
he is not going home.
That the Soviets
do not want him.
That he is never going home.
I imagine his behavior
might change.
And who will be held
responsible for that?
That is a long message.
Did you get it all?
- Yes, Sir. I got it.
- Good.
You are a good man.
Also, tell him...
There is no deal,
unless we hear...
before the end of
business today.
He has the number.
If the exchange is
not going to happen.
No reason for everybody
to get up in the morning.
No, Sir. That would
be pointless.
You are kidding me!
Not really.
I need some change.
This is exactly what you
were not supposed to do.
My instructions were to
feel out the situation.
Your instructions were to
get Powers, not Pryor.
That was not the original
deal. You fouled it up!
How do you know?
I feel very good about it.
You fouled it up!
Do not worry.
I think it is
going to be fine.
How do you know?
You do not know that.
United States. New
York, New York.
That whole thing...
Has me to feel out.
Would I swap one for one?
Which one?
I said: "No. Two for one."
They know where we stand.
Yeah, what if they think
about it and say...
Forget it! You keep our
person. We keep your people.
Well, then I have
fucked it all up.
Hey, honey! It is me.
Yeah. The fishing
has been great.
I am in London.
Just for one more meeting.
Then I am on my way home.
Yeah, yeah, I remember
that marmalade.
It is that shop right
by Regent's Park.
All right! I will
if I have the time.
Can I say hi to Roger?
Could I say hi to the girls?
Is anyone not busy?
Have they even noticed
I am not around?
We are on...
Two for one.
Hot dog!
Let us have a drink.
- One "wrinkle".
- What is that?
They will not release Pryor
with Powers not on the bridge.
They will release him
at the same time.
When the Russians give
us Powers on the bridge.
They will release Pryor
over Checkpoint Charlie.
What does that mean?
I think it means: We want
to have the last word.
They will do it.
You tell me.
You felt them out.
Where are they?
Where is our person?
They are late.
Nobody is late. We are early.
- May I?
- Yeah.
Hoffman?
Yeah?
I think they have...
What?
Snipers.
I am sure they have.
How are you sure they have?
Because we have snipers.
Step out, Sir.
Jim.
Dear Jim.
How are you?
Happy to see you.
Had you arranged
all this for me?
Let us see what that is before,
I take credit for it.
Any word about Pryor
from Checkpoint Charlie?
Nothing get yet.
Excuse me, Sir.
This is Lieutenant Joe Murphy,
the United States Air Force...
Here to identify Powers.
Lieutenant Murphy.
Sir.
There may be a slight glitch.
I was a young man when I left.
Whom will they find
to identify me?
I hope it is not your
East German family.
I doubt they could
identify each other.
Looks like our part.
Well, let us go.
You can stay here, Donovan.
Not likely.
Open the gate.
What do you think will
happen, when you get home?
I think...
I have vodka.
Yeah.
Rudolf, is there not
the possibility...?
That my people are
going to shoot me.
Yes.
- You are not worried.
- Would it help?
The answer to your
question, my friend.
I acted honorably.
I think they know that.
But sometimes
people think wrong.
People are people.
Let us see how they greet me.
What for can I look?
If I am embraced or just
shown the back seat.
Take off the hat.
Hey, Powers.
Hey, Murphy.
Yeah, that is Powers.
All right! Mr. Donovan.
We go now!
Hang on!
Believe me, I will tell you.
There is no one here.
They will release another man
at Checkpoint Charlie.
We are just confirming
that he is there.
Now!
As per plan if you, please.
Let us go.
Pryor will show up or,
he will not. Let us go.
They are waiting to see, If
we will do it without him.
We just have to stand here.
Show them we will not.
I do not give a shit
what they want.
We have our objective.
Go ahead, Abel.
Go ahead, Sir. You can go.
If it is not the plan,
we go home.
We exchange now,
or we go home!
- You are waiting for another man.
- Yes.
You want him, too.
I want him.
Does not matter
what he wants, Sir?
I am in charge, and
you are free to go.
Please go. Walk across.
I can wait.
It is something.
I am not sure yet.
Hang on!
Let us go.
We got him!
I...I am...
I sent you a gift, Jim.
It is a... It is a painting.
I hope it has some
meaning to you.
I am sorry. I did not
think to give you a gift.
This is your gift.
Are you okay?
Let us go, let us
go, and let us go!
Mr. Donovan?
Colonel Abel asked me
to give this to you.
Pardon me, Sir.
Were you in charge
of this thing, sir?
- Yeah.
- I have to thank you.
I have to thank somebody.
I gave them nothing.
It does not matter.
It does not matter
what people think.
You know what you did.
Welcome home!
What a trip!
Are you okay?
Yeah, I am fine.
- Did you get the marmalade?
- Yes, yes.
Yes. Yes.
I did.
As ordered.
Jim?
- This is from Arno's.
- So?
- On the corner!
- Well! Honey I was busy.
- Please. For God's sake.
- We were so busy.
- How is Roger? Is he home?
- He is home.
Carol is home, Peggy is home.
Everyone is home.
Mom? Come quick! Look!
- Mom comes here!
- Come see this! Look! Watch!
- Come on!
Francis Gary Powers.
Released from prison
in the Soviet Union.
He turned over to
American authorities.
Early this morning in Berlin.
The President commuted
the sentence of Rudolf Abel.
Mr. Abel has deported.
He has released in Berlin.
Efforts to obtain Mr.
Powers released.
Had underway for some time.
In recent efforts.
The United States
government has had...
The cooperation and assistance
of Mr. James B. Donovan.
A New York attorney.
Frederic L. Pryor,
an American student,
held by East German
authorities,
since August of 1961.
I thought Daddy was fishing.
Salmon.
Abel now disappeared
into the communist world.
Powers is answering
questions here.
And Donovan have gone back
to his practice law.
Now here is George Finnegan.
Speaking for the Douglas
Fir Plywood Association.
Following his return to Russia, Rudolf
Abel was reunited with his wife and daughter.
He was never publicly acknowledged
by the Soviet Union as a Spy.
Gary Powers died in a helicopter crash
in 1977, while working for KNBC news.
He was posthumously awarded
the CIA Director's Medal,
and the USAF POW Medal in 2000
and the Silver Star in 2012.
In 1962, Frederic L. Pryor received his
Ph.D. in Economics from Yale University.
He is currently Professor
Emeritus of Economics,
and Senior Research Scholar
at Swarthmore College.
Following the successful conclusion
of the Powers-Abel exchange.
James Donovan was asked by
President Kenned to undertake,
further negotiations on
behalf of the U.S.
In the summer of 1962, he was sent to
Cuba to discuss with Fidel Castro the terms,
of the release of 1,113 prisoners
held after the Bay of Pigs invasion.
When Donovan finished negotiations.
He had secured the release,
of 9,703 men, women
and children.
"EVERY HUMAN BEING IS IMPORTANT
LIKE FREEDOM"
BRIDGE OF SPIES
Translation. Review. Synchronization by Midofayed1.
www.doc-advice.com