I don't know a recent
Saturday I've sold more
Why so glum?
Were you bothering by
those waitresses making a fuss?
No.
But, honest. What are you supposed to say
when they keep talking about your looks?
I don't even know what they mean
"Beat them off with a stick. "
if that's your only problem
It's not
I got my report card
Three Cs, two Ds and an incomplete.
I see you studying so hard, Tom.
What do you think the problem is?
I'll just have to try harder.
I don't know.
I will. I will. I will.
I will...
Thanks, Dad, this talk helped.
Will you sign it, please?
Would it help if I got you a tutor?
That would be great
It better help
What can you do with yourself
if all you do is look good?
I'm frequently asked
what the special difficulties...
...are in being graduated from High School...
two months shy of my fifteenth birthday.
I sometimes think it was the difficulties
themselves which enabled me to do it.
If I'd been appreciated or even tolerated...
...I wouldn't have been in
such a hurry to graduate.
I hope the next student
who comes along and is able to excel...
...isn't made to feel so much an outcast.
But, I'm looking forward to college;
...and this is the happiest day
I've had in a long time.
So, I thank you and I forgive you.
Go ahead, Stephen. Take your last licks.
But this will heal
what I'm going to say to you
will scar you forever.
Ready? Here it is.
You'll never make more than
nineteen thousand dollars a year.
Okay, what about this:
You'll never leave South Boston
and I'm going to see the whole damn world.
You'll never know the pleasure
of writing a graceful sentence...
...or having an original thought.
Think about it.
Nineteen thousand dollars...
Not bad.
Dear Felatzia,
...it's truly amazing to me...
...that we live a world apart
and yet have the same favorite music.
I loved the picture you sent...
and have it up on my bulletin board.
You're growing...
Honey?
Oh God
Daddy. Don't ever do that to me.
Look, it's time for you to go to sleep.
I just have two more pen pals
and then I'm done.
Finish quickly. I don't want you
getting obsessive about these things.
Good night.
Dad, you want me to choose
my words so carefully...
...and then you just throw
a word like'obsessive' at me.
Now, unless I'm wrong
please correct me if I am,
...obsession is practically
a psychiatric term...
concerning people who don't have anything
else but the object of their obsession...
...who can't stop and do anything else.
Well, Here I am stopping to tell you this.
Okay?
So would you please try and
be a little more precise...
instead of calling a person
something like'obsessive'
Good night.
Hi. It's me.
It's thirty minutes
before you have to meet me in the lobby...
...nudge your mate.
I don't think it's time to eat...
...but there's a cafeteria
at the bus depot once we get down there.
I love working with you two.
It saves me a call.
Hi. Turn on your TV...
Arnold Schwarzenegger on the today's show
Good Morning America and the Morning News...
...and I think he's live on
at least two of them.
At 6 o'clock on the wake-up news
they used the wrong missile graphic.
And they call me this morning to say...
Now listen, Arnold just said that
he's been making three million a movie now.
But he's not ever gonna change.
He's still the same person when
he was making two million dollars a movie.
He feels no different.
He also bought a brand-new condo with Maria,
they gonna furnish tastefully.
A half hour in the lobby.
Okay, I'll see you in the lobbies.
There he is.
Hi.
I'd like to talk to you for a second.
Just a few questions?
No.
We came from Washington.
Move away from me.
Last week he was...
Ok No. Watch this.
I want you to watch this.
Fuck. Fuck. Fuck. Fuckes. Snot...
Fuckee.
You want to use that?
It depends on how big a news day it is.
Thanks.
I can't believe he said that.
Very proud of
He really...
You should work on your speech.
No.
It makes me nervous to think about it.
Let's do this.
We are being increasingly influenced
by the star system.
The network anchormen are so powerful
they compromise our last best hope.
Our profession is in danger.
The current group is clearly qualified,
...tied still to our best traditions, but...
...who follows these men?
Excuse me.
We are being pressured...
detect a loyalty...
Oh, I've known so many women like that.
They don't like their looks
so they're angry.
Excuse me.
Sure.
All of you know what I'm talking about.
We're all trying to act together
than we are.
But we care.
So, we're all secretly terrified,
aren't we?
I was going to talk about other trends
but...
...the magazine shows, news at profit,
...the historic influence of
Entertainment Tonight,
...the danger, the hope,
the dream, the question...
Oh,
I was going to show you a tape.
a story that was carried by
all networks on the same night
...the same night that not one...
network noted a major policy change in
Salt Two nuclear disarmament talks...
Here's what they ran instead...
Go ahead please.
Show the tape.
I know it's good film.
I know it's fun. I like fun.
It's just not news.
Well, you're lucky you love it.
you're going to get a lot more just like it.
Good.
Thank you
I dont think to be any q and a
Hi.
Hello.
I just wanted to tell you
how great you were.
My name's Tom Grunick.
Thank you
They hated me.
I don't hate them.
They say if you can reach even one person,
it means something...
And you did that.
Would you like to have dinner with me?
Sure
Another thing I can't stand
Is this dull?
no. No. No.
Another thing I can't stand is...
...when White House reporters bullshit
with each other after a briefing...
...and then one of them has a theory...
...and the other quotes it in his story as...
..."White House" sources say...
That actually goes on.
Yes.
I am not tired.
My room is down here.
Do you want to keep talking?
Yes, sure.
Come on.
Even I'm not that hard on myself.
No, really.
I got this job on a fluke...
...and wait till you hear where it ends up.
I was doing sports at the station.
The newspaper ran this untrue story
that I was leaving...
...and they got all these
tons of protest mail.
So.
So they made me anchor.
So great, right?
Except I'm no good at
what I'm being a success at.
How are you at back rubs?
It's sort of normal the way you feel.
In graduate school
everyone thought the only mistake...
...the admission committee made was
letting them in.
Listen to me.
You keep on thinking I'm somebody who...
...who lacks confidence.
That's not it.
I know I can talk well enough...
...and I'm not bad at
making contact with people,
...but I don't like the feeling that
I'm pretending to be a reporter.
And half the time I don't get the unders...
...the news I'm talking about.
It isn't that I'm down on myself.
Trust me,
I stink.
I trust you.
I didn't even have the chance
to get really good at sports.
I wasn't bad.
What about the obvious remedy?
Reversing things.
Maybe getting a job on a newspaper.
I don't write.
But that didn't stop me from
sending out audition tapes to the...
...bigger stations and the networks.
Well, come on.
it is your life.
Nobody is tying you to the fast track.
Did you go to college?
So, you're not well educated and
you have almost no experience...
and you can't write.
Yeah. And I'm...
And I'm making a fortune.
It's hard...
...for me to advise you...
...since you personify something
that I truly think is dangerous.
I agree with you. You're not qualified.
So get qualified.
You can insist on being better prepared.
You don't have to just leave it with...
'I don't write. I'm not schooled...
...I don't understand the news I'm reading...
...But at least I'm upset about it, folks. '
Whoa.
Just what do you want from me, anyway?
Permission to be a fake?
Stop whining...
...do something about it.
Well, you don't have to start right now.
I hated the way you talked to me just now...
...and it wasn't just because
you were right.
Oh God.
No.
It wasn't just the speech...
...the same thing happened with this guy.
I have passed some line some place.
I am beginning to repel people
I'm trying to seduce.
He must have been great-looking, right?
Why do you say that?
Because nobody invites a bad-looking idiot
to their bedroom.
Okay. Let's do me.
Sure.
I feel like I'm slipping...
...but do people who are actually
slipping feel that way...
...or is it always the really good people
who are moving up...
...who invariably think they're slipping
because their standards are so high?
This conversation is not worthy of you.
I'd give anything if that were true.
Good night.
Wouldn't this be a great world if insecurity
and desperation made us more attractive?
If needy were a turn-on?
Call if you get weird.
Take care.
I will.
I was just thinking it was the
shortest phone conversation we ever had.
I never told you the reason
I was telling you everything for.
Hey?
Those audition tapes I sent out...
I've been hired by your network
for the Washington bureau.
So I'll probably see you at work.
What?
Sorry.
They didn't hire Peter Stiller from
the Times and he had a great audition tape.
You want to start going over
who they could have gotten?
They can't take on people like this
for network news.
For God's sake. What's going on?
Okay, what about this?
Here's a tough ethical one.
Would you tell a source that you loved them
just to get some information?
Yes. Yes. Me too. Sure. You bet.
Jennifer didn't know
there was an alternative.
Here's a good one.
They allow us to have cameras
at an execution in Florida.
Do you broadcast tape of the guy
in the chair when they turn on the voltage?
Sure.
Why not?
Absolutely.
You bet.
Nothing like wrestling
with a moral dilemma is there?
yeah. Yeah.
Speak to you later.
Ok Bobby. Go back to 9-40, 5-40
We could...
Please, Bobbie, we're pushing.
They said I should observe the...
They said it would be okay if...
We're working here!
You can stand over in the uh, uh, uh...
Play back the last line...
Thanks.
Bobby?
He said something about...
Let me hear it!
Jane.
We'll need it in 14 minutes.
We're putting it directly into the...
Jane, Craig, just a second.
Let me hear it!
It's been a long time
since I've seen my folks and all but...
...I don't expect any big-deal homecoming.
Stop there.
I want to shoot the home-coming
from a book I have in the office.
You don't have time. Not a chance.
I'll be right down. It's right tight.
I've got to tell Ernie...
because there isn't enough time.
Yes, there is.
I don't think she's going to make it.
Okay, Bobbie,
just a two-second dissolve to the Rockwell.
Should I...
Just a two-second dissolve.
Oh, Jesus, we have three minutes...
Why do you do this to me.
Is it because I won an award?
Home coming...
Norman Rockwell's enduring portrait.
The return of a fighting man has always been
one of the more moving ceremonies of war...
We have a minute and a half.
It's my responsibility
to tell them we won't be ready.
Uh-uh. We're be ready.
In 84 seconds?
Oh, God.
You're saying'Oh, God...
They are going to go to up
and the screen will be black...
...they're going to go to black
because we're not there.
How about careers, huh?
We're not going to make it.
Whoops.
We got it.
No there she is.
Ok, stand by.
Home coming.
Norman Rockwell's enduring portrait
The return of a fighting man has always been
one of the more moving ceremonies of war...
Tearful women, proud men, excited children.
But J.D. Singer was right
his homecoming was no big deal.
Aaron Altman
An american comes home.
That's your news. I'm Bill Rorich.
Good evening.
Look at that smile.
That was good work.
Bill smiled. He liked it.
No, Bill loved it. That's a big smile.
I haven't seen Bill smile
like that in weeks.
Good piece.
Thanks Ernie.
I'm gonna see it again. Ernie?
He did smile.
Don't tell anyone I do this.
I'm sorry if I was in the way.
It was totally impressive. Great piece.
You weren't. Thanks.
How does it feel being here?
I can't believe I'm really here.
Do you know where Martin went?
I think he went downstairs. -Ok, thanks.
I can't believe I'm really here.
No I'm wrong.
He went to research.
I can't believe I'm really here.
No kidding.
If you're through work now...
No. Aaron and I go to Central America
on Wednesday so I'm cramming.
I thought you were incredible in there.
Everybody was.
I know how much I have to learn.
I'd really a lot appreciate it... if...
'Really a lot appreciate it... '
You make me nervous.
Anyway
if I can pick your brain...
I can't help you, sorry.
I'm not here to teach remedial reporting.
And it has nothing to do with the fact
I left your room instead of staying there?
Please.
You're gonna have to understand something.
This isn't personal.
Ok.
Good night.
Really? Well I'm sure you speak
English very well too. Thank you.
Ready for this?
He says they've been engaging
the Sandinistas pretty regularly...
...and he thinks there's gonna
be a shooting tonight.
Look at her.
If anything happens to me...
...you tell every woman I've ever dated
I was talking about them at the end.
That way they'll have to reevaluate me.
Put on the boot.
No. No. What the hell are... No.
Stop. Stop. Stop.
We are not here to stage the news.
Wait and see what he does.
Sir, you do whatever you want.
It's your choice.
Okay.
He just said he scared.
The first shots were fired
not ten seconds ago.
The Contras feel they must be outnumbered...
...this is so small a unit: that's a given.
Still they manage to hold their ground...
despite the fact that their
weapons have been acting up...
...by the misfiring or jamming.
No new shipment of arms
is expected until tomorrow...
...all they got today were the shoes.
Great line at the end.
Did you shoot their boots?
Yeah. Of course.
We can cut back at the end, right?
To the pan of the supplies boxes...
I can't believe I just risked my life for a
network that tests my face with focus groups
I don't feel good.
x
Hi.
How's it going?
...chosen by the military command.
A fire fight along the Nikaraguan border...
when we return.
First shots were fired not ten seconds ago...
Freeze.
Congratulations you two.
x
There's a guy downstairs
clerks brought in and vouches for.
He says he has something to say about
gays getting promotions at State...
Can I buy you dinner sometime soon?
I just got back.
I don't know which end is up.
Okay
Jane! Bill Rorish wants to speak
to you at the break, now.
I never heard of him handing over
compliments in the middle of the show.
Jane?
Yes?
Darling,
if it gets any better than that,
...I'm going to have to bring
you up here to New York.
Thanks.
I just wish you'd kept the first 20 seconds.
But thank you.
Well, the visual with the boots at the end
was just perfect.
God, he loved the boots.
Aaron should be hearing this
so I have an extra witness.
Well, you always want to give
the credit away, do you?
No, I don't. He happens to deserve
the credit. He's right here.
I'll speak to you soon.
He had to read over some new copy.
What?
Okay if I watch you tape
that interview downstairs?
Yes.
Thanks.
Laugh so they think I'm not dying
inside but have so much style...
...I just said something funny.
What did he say?
I'll never tell.
x
He's never gonna forget it.
This way.
Ok. I'm with...
Right.
Could you give me that adress
one more time. Alright.
Yeah.
It's good to finally beginning to work.
17204 color red or...
Yeah. 17204.
Got it. 17204
Yeah, right.
Jane! Got a story.
Hi, how are you?
Wait. I need you.
I got a story.
Some public official skipped a week
on his Christmas Club?
The House Armed Service Committee
has a secret report which says that...
the General Stillwell tank the Army
has dumped a fortune into plain won't work.
I got it cold, confirmed.
They have 5 million dollars
in this thing already. -Billion.
Right, billion... ok, of course.
They said I could have any producer I wanted
and I want you.
One source referred to it as a
5 billion dollar metal sculpture...
...too ugly to look at and too big to bury.
Did you write this?
I write for you sometimes.
Not because you have to.
General Elton McGuire is in
charge of the weapon system.
General, I don't want to bother
you anymore or your family.
But tomorrow there will be a
mob of me back here.
So, if you have anything to say,
why not say it now, sir, the way you want?
That's great. I think it's great you
left in what you said. Just great.
Yes, please let's never forget.
We're the real story. Not them.
Yeah, I know,
I went back and forth on it.
I liked it. He's not afraid of being human.
Tom Grunick, The Pentagon.
This if the Pentagon did
have enough problems...
Thanks Jenny.
Sure.
Tom, My youngest wanted to meet you.
This is Ellie.
Hi, Ellie.
Hi.
You should be honored
she never wanted to meet anyone here before.
But she said that she just
love you on television just now.
Hi, Ellie, remember me?
I'm not sure. I'm sorry.
I've been to your house.
And Aaron went on that 14 day
raft trip with us last year.
Oh yeah.
I had a big yellow raincoat on.
It was over my head.
Yeah.
The hair's different.
Yeah. Hi.
She knows me.
Hi, Dad... Did you see it?
I'll send you a tape...
I'm sorry I haven't called.
Things were a little bumpy for a while.
It's not important...
Hey, Dad.
I think I just may be able to do this job...
I'm glad you were sure.
Our host.
Come on in.
Sorry we're late. Jane's fault.
I don't know why we have
to feel defensive about it.
Newspapers are in business to make money.
Why not us?
I mean They criticize us for supposedly
pandering while they run WINGO Games.
Exactly right.
Excuse me. I'm paid to mix.
Goodbye, Paul.
Take care, Paul.
It takes a certain kind of...
...courage to talk like that in front
of the President of the News Division.
You think anyone who's proud of
the work we do is an ass kisser.
No.
I think anyone who puckers their lips and...
...presses it against his
boss' buttocks and then...
...smooches is an ass kisser.
My gosh,
and for a while there,
I was attracted to you.
Wait a minute
that changes everything.
x
Martin, would you excuse us for a minute.
No.
Come on.
You know I didn't mean to ask
This is very awkward.
I see Tom around you a lot...
...and this is such a small office
and I'd like to see him outside of work,
unless there's some reason for you to mind
in which case I just won't do anything.
Whew. Do I mind? Why do I mind? No.
Why?
I do mind.
I mean I think about him outside
works sometimes but...
...I know I don't respect him...
So what am I talking about...
What am I saying to you?
You're saying stay away from him.
I can't be.
We don't have to settle this
definitively right now.
Wait a minute!
Tell me one person who ever left
television news to work on a newspaper.
You're right.
Looks good.
See you.
Hi Tom.
Hi.
It's the firs time I've seen
you dressed like this.
You look so clean and pretty.
What do you mean clean?
At work there's always
this sort of film over you.
I've got to find someone.
It's important. Excuse me.
Jennifer. Hey, Jennifer.
Forget what I said you do
whatever you want to with him.
there's nothing I'm going
to do right this second.
Oh come on. It's your day off.
You're entitled.
You're leaving?
Okay. Right away.
Ernie.
Tom. Tom.
What is it?
A Libyan plane just shot up
one of our bases in Sicilia.
This might be at the time to tap that source
of us. He might have an angle or something.
Jennifer we need you.
Jane We want you to exec
produce a Special Report...
What?
A Libyan plane just shot up one of our
bases in Sicilia. It's all still happening.
Since Paul's here,
he's made out the assignments...
So Jennifer at the White House...
George at the Pentagon...
Martin at State...
...and we need an anchor
since Rorish is in his boat,
...so we're gonna do the whole report
this afternoon from here... with Tom.
What?
You're not gonna use him at all?
It's not my choice.
It's 1:35 and it is Tom.
You can reach me at the office.
Paul forgive me. I'm really sorry
interrupting you.
Paul. Yes, I need to talk to
you outside for just a minute.
Great.
Tom isn't ready for the job you're
about to hand him. Not near ready.
Not by the longest shot.
And Aaron's spent six weeks in Tripoli,
he's interviewed Gaddafi...
...he reported on the Eight-one story.
I think he's essential to do
the job we're capable of...
...and I think it's my
responsibility to tell you that.
Okay, that's your opinion.
I don't agree.
It's not opinion.
You're just absolutely right
and I'm absolutely wrong?
It must be nice to always
believe you know better.
To think you're always the
smartest person in the room.
No, it's awful.
You better get going.
Nervous?
Excited.
Tell George and Jennifer to
try and cover everything...
...without Tom having to
ask additional questions.
Ok Bobbie says...
Did you hear what I just said?
Do you have that? Take a breath.
And the most important thing...
...make sure his earpiece works,
...have back-ups ready.
That's never been more vital.
He must be able to hear me
at every second and clearly.
Tom.
We have twenty minutes.
Yeah ok.
You can wait in the studio.
Stand by
Good luck Jenny.
Ready.
Stand by please.
Thirty seconds to get ready
All the most checked in.
Everyone hears the program clearly?
Yes. Everything's good.
Executive producer. Wow.
Stand by bt5.
I'm gonna seconds there.
Thirty seconds. Alright.
Stand by camera one please...
Tom, can you hear me?
Tom? Tom?
Damn it... He can't hear me...
I told you if there was one thing...
I can hear you. I was just teasing.
Good afternoon.
A Libyan fighter plane attacked...
...a United States Military Installation
at Sicilia at 10.07am.
Libyan made 21 and it was itself
shot down by American F-14 Interceptors.
The Libyan missile destroyed an army
warehouse which, just 30 minutes earlier,
...had been crowded with servicemen.
When we take it back...
I can sing while I read...
I can singing and reading both.
The Libyan made 21...
on the U.S. air station at Sicilia.
The heat seeking missile virtually
disintegrated the plane on contact...
All remote stand by please.
George, you're ready?
Yeah
Should I cover everything or should
I save something for Tom to ask about?
Cover everything!
Ok, we're going to George.
Say'the Joint Chiefs are meeting
we have George Weln at the Pentagon'.
George Weln is at the Pentagon and reports...
...that the attack launched
by the lone Libyan pilot...
...has resulted in a massive
movement of US military might.
A lot of alliteration from anxious
anchors placed in powerful posts.
x
It's Aaron.
Yes?
Hi.
Listen. The pilot that shot down the
Libyan in 1981 is stationed right here.
Maybe you could get him.
Also Tom should say that F-14 is
one of the hardest planes to fly.
And They're nicknamed'Tomcats'.
Thanks.
The F-14 is one of the most
difficult planes to master.
They called'Tomcats'
George, isn't the F-14 Tomcat...
...one of the most difficult
machines for a pilot to master?
I think you're right.
and in the 70's the first crop
had a number of crashes.
There was trouble with them
in the early days back in the 70's.
Thank you George.
Jennifer Mack.
I say it here. It comes out there.
Hi.
Me again.
Listen Gaddafi doesn't foam
at the mouth or anything.
When you speak to him he's not at all nuts.
He seems like a leader very impressive,
self-control... that's what's so crazy.
Ok good. And we have the'81 pilot on
the way in Nobody else will have him.
You're welcome. So how does
it feel to be executive producer?
I gotta go.
Me too. Gotte go. We're very busy here.
It's the Gulf of Sidra.
The name of the US commander
is Nathan Benchley.
In the summer of 1981 two Libyan jets
suddenly attacked to American air...
The plan against Nathan
I don't really well...
...nations including the US...
...after a brief dogfight both Libyan jets
were down by the American fighters.
The name's Nathan Bencley.
... is at the Pentagon.
So, -that's great. That's great-
commander, it must have been a bit tougher...
...today, shooting down the Mig-21
The one you got was SU-22...
- What is it like... -
What is it like to be in a dog fight?
Ok, after this guy, we'll go for...
about ten seconds.
Ask him how does he know when he has a hit.
Dou you know you have a hit from one of
those screens inside your cockpit or...
That's good. That's good.
The equipment is very
sophisticated but the...
...whole pilot point of view you like to see
it to conform it. Thank you commander.
It's always been considered
an outlaw nation but strangely...
...some of those who have
interviewed Gaddafi find him,
...in a phrase we like
to use in this country,
very'presidential'.
Nice, Jane.
Just a minute.
Then we gotta get Martin Klein
To State for the message from Libya,
...then you'll have the carrier pilot
from the Sidra in time to...
What? No! You missed him!
We only have ten minutes left.
How can you talk to me
about parking problems?
No, not you'll try, you'll do it, do it or
I'll fry your fat ass, Estelle. Good-bye.
I had no idea she was this good.
Tom,
Fill for a second.
The latest message seems to
indicate that the Libyan pilot was...
...acting on his own without
authority from anyone else.
In other words, I think we're all okay.
Ok Tom.
The Libyan Government has disavowed
any prior knowledge of the attack.
I'm Tom Grunick, reporting from Washington.
Good afternoon.
Animation. Thanks everybody.
We are out.
You're great.
I've never been as proud
of one of my decisions.
Great work, Jane, really
You know? Really.
Well, there were no major gaffs anyway.
No major gaffs? You were brilliant.
Thank you Jane.
Thanks Ernie.
Sure.
This was important for Tom.
There's that bonding thing
that happens with the public...
...and an anchorman during a crisis.
It's not the conventions anymore;
it's this kind of moment.
Oh, hi.
Hi.
Great job.
You too.
Good work Tom.
Thanks.
What a baptismal. Congratulations.
Thanks. With all the help you get,
it's sure easier than local.
Where's Jane? Ã'm still juiced.
She's back there. Thanks.
Can I help you gentleman?
We're here to play the new news theme.
You're an amazing woman.
What a feeling having you inside my head.
Yeah. It was an unusual place to be.
It's like indescribable, you knew
just when to feed me the next line...
...second before I needed it.
There was a rhythm we got into,
It was like great sex.
You have to celebrate with me,
don't you?
Everybody's going to that
bar down the street,'Caps. '
I'm going over to Aaron's.
But maybe I'll hook up with all of you later
How long do you think you'll be there?
It starts off,
but it's very hi-tech syntho... like this.
Big finish.
I got chills.
Wasn't Tom great?
Well, it worked.
Really?
It was good.
Your calling in that information.
You are the classiest guy I know.
Here. Have a beer.
Celebrate.
God. It was so strange watching him.
What's the next step? Lip synching?
Okay.
You know I've been doing some of the
most important thinking of my life today.
I wonder if this is the right
time to tell you about it.
Whatever you think.
I figured out why it is I'm so hung up on
getting a chance at weekend anchor...
It's because if I do that well,
...then they'll pay me more,
...and my life will be great and
they'll treat me better. That's why.
Sounds like you may be on to something.
Which means I'm at their mercy...
...and who wants that?
No, I don't want to tell you
where this thought led me...
Why not?
In the middle of all of this...
I started to think about the one thing
that makes me feel really good...
...and makes immediate sense...
...and it's you.
I'm gonna stop right now.
Except I would give anything
if you were two people...
...so I could call up the one
who's my friend...
...and tell her about the one
that I like so much.
I'm not gonna say any more.
I merely do some about the pa...
Come on. I'll walk you to the corner.
You get some sleep.
Right now?
After I walking.
You were stunning today.
There, You have some place to go?
Yeah.
Good night.
Well, I felt something.
Hey. We're going to Caps Bar at
Seventeenth and Vermont;
Connecticut is clear on Sunday so...
...take that over to Fifteenth,
...and then straight down Vermont and we
should bypass Thomas circle that way.
If you don't go over forty we
should catch mostly green lights.
I didn't think you'd make it.
Well, I thought I'd check and see
if all of you were still here.
But you know I'll just go in and
join the gang and you two go on.
All the gangs have gone. We were
the last ones. There's no more gangs.
Well, I'll go in and have a burger.
Jennifer, you want to have another burger?
Hey, I know how to have a burger by myself.
I just feel like a little solitude.
I sure know that feeling.
Terrific work today.
Right back to you.
Thanks.
Good night.
I feel great.
Are you sure you...
What for?
We have the greatest car and the
greatest driver in all of Washington...
Give me some of that.
Where's the bathroom?
Through the closet.
I'm so tired of being
defensive about my closet.
But I always had problems
with space and it was...
...getting store I couldn't find anything
and you know how always buy new things.
So I converted a bedroom...
...and wait till you've been
doing this sixteen years.
I think it's a great solution.
Not only the storage but
you can see everything you have.
Do you do bunny rabbits?
Isn't this a great date?
Morning.
Good morning.
God help me.
Well, They've been looking at
just about everything.
Foren bureaus, domestic bureaus...
...and all kind of personal even equipment
Anyway, they seem to be very very serious...
...about making me cut...
24 million from the budget.
Now this is going to mean massive firings...
I'm doing whatever I can.
But I did want you to be aware...
...of this very serious situation.
Now, we're going to also be covering
the Alaskan serial killer trial...
on a continuing basis. I'd like it
to be assigned out of Washington...
which means we're going to have to
get someone on a plane to Anchorage.
We can't fool around anymore.
Jane.
Who do you think? George Weln or Jennifer?
Jennifer.
Night Emily.
Good night Jane.
Come on, I'll buy you a drink. There's a big
thing going on over at the Italian embassy.
I'm not sure I'd be good company tonight.
I'll be the judge of that.
I'll get my coat.
Two please.
Tom?
I'm alright.
Heavy hitters.
Yeah.
How you doing?
Good.
Network news. Washington.
I love it.
What do yo do when your real life
exceeds you dreams?
Keep it to yourself.
You know yesterday
I really wanted to know your...
...reaction to how we did
with the Libyan report.
I was going to ask but I think I'm...
...I'm a little intimidated with you.
Oh, stop it.
You can't talk about feeling intimidated
when you're on top of the world...
...It's unseemly.
I'm not buying into any of that.
I have a load to learn.
I'm not goingto act as if...
You have the job you have...
Shut up for a second.
Okay.
Pretty petty party, isn't it, pal?
I made one rule for myself
when this started...
...and I realized that I was going
to take a lot from you people...
because of being from sports...
And the rule was...
Never to pretend to know more than I did.
Can you name all the members of the Cabinet?
Okay, let's drop it.
What?
I mean I'm not gonna take a test for you...
I mean if that came up in conversation...
We're conversing. Oh no the names
of the Cabinet has slipped my mind.
Do you know them?
Ok, don't name them for me.
Just tell me if you know.
Yes, Aaron. I know the names of the Cabinet.
Okay.
All twelve?
Yes.
There is only ten.
You're feeling good, aren't you?
I'm starting to... Yeah.
We may do the capitols of the states next.
Fifty, right?
Hi. There you are.
x
Yes.
I'm so exhausted.
Punchy. Sick tired.
I can't think and I can't move.
I'm just a dead lump...
...of poured out flesh.
Would you like to come up?
Maybe we could just sit here.
Talk a little?
Okay.
I'm going to have to do a story
from beginning to end on my own.
Eventually.
I have an idea for something.
What?
If I tell you, can you manage
not to put it down or or...
...or tell me why it won't work or...
...is in bad journalistic taste
or anything like that?
Yes, Tom. I think I can manage.
Okay.
It's about women who are attacked
by someone they know on a date...
I'm sorry. I didn't mean it...
Keep it there.
Wait a minute...
I didn't say anything.
I'm innocent before...
Innocent?
You're guilty.
Door. Door.
Hello.
Jane. Yes.
Tom? Ãs that you?
Yes.
Hey you called me.
Is it your story?
No.
Are you going to the Correspondents' Dinner?
Why, you need me for the story?
No.
Were you going to go?
Maybe I'll get off work.
I'd like to go.
Good.
We can go together.
So.
So you like me, huh?
I like you as much as I can like
anyone who thinks I'm an asshole.
street cops say... that fits.
Is that last cut work for you, Bobbie?
Yeah.
Good.
Thank you for asking.
Thank you.
Acording to the FBI...
...there are more than
87000 rapes reported last year.
Most people think
if a rapist has a violent stranger...
...but today an attack
may be what's called'date rape'...
...being forced to have sexual intercourse
against your will with someone you know.
It's just you want to find a nice guy...
So anyways,
it was that you know
'give-him-a-chance' thing.
I was lonely.
So,
We went to a movie...
...and when he brought me home.
He said could he come up for one beer...
...and then he would go.
So how do you say'no', to that?
My cousin done it.
Really?
So first...
it was kind of a like wrestling match...
...which was awful enough because...
...it got very violent.
I'm a modest person...
...then he ripped my clothes off...
...and he forced me to...
...make love.
And the he stayed in my apartment...
...and he forced me more times.
I'm sorry.
I promised myself I wasn't gonna cry...
It's just...
...this whole thing has just messed me up.
Can I turn on the news for a second?
Alright, sex, tears, this must be the news.
I'm sorry. I'm in a pissy mood.
What's wrong with it?
Nothing.
I think you really blew the lid off nookie.
The victims often remain
too terrified to talk...
...the police powerless
to perform properly...
...and all the social welfare groups can
finally do is monitor this epidemic...
...of crime without punishment.
Tom Grunick, Annandale, Virginia.
Malcolm West on trial
for the murders of 15 men...
Nice work.
I've got to get a crew off the clock.
What did you think?
It moved me.
I did relate to it. I really did.
It was...
...unusual for you to cut to
yourself when you tear up...
...and that might not have been...
my choice.
...but it was real and it got me...
and...
I think a lot of the time I'm too
conservative about that kind of stuff.
Okay?
Okay.
Hey Tom. God it was really swell tonight.
Good.
Four more bodies now taken
from the frozen earth.
Jennifer Mack, Alaska.
How are you?
I was just writing you a note.
What do you say we take a walk?
Outside?
Yeah.
I'm no suggesting the worst will happen...
...it's just somebody with your brilliance...
...gets nibbles about
other jobs now and again...
...maybe down the road
you should look into it.
Ah, damn those fucking jerks.
They want to fire me.
All I know is that they've got to
fire a large number of people...
...and not even going by seniority.
There's a recklessness in the air. They...
Do one thing to me? What?
Get me one shot at
anchoring the Weekend News...
...they've never seen me do that.
It could turn it around for me.
I could do that this Saturday.
Everybody wants off for the
Correspondents' Dinner. -Do it then.
Please prepare carefully.
This couldn't happen at a better time.
Prepare what?
You have Saturday's news handy?
It's a long while since you read the news.
I'll have somebody work with you on it.
Just on superficial performance things.
Please.
Okay.
I think I'd better be alone for a while.
I understand. I'll go with you.
Thanks.
This is very uncomfortable for me...
...because well I don't mean This is a knock
but we approach this thing so differently.
We sure do.
and I don't mean it as a knock either.
Ok, go ahead.
I'll just tell what I think
and you can disregard it if you want.
Alright, I just don't know how
effective this is gonna be...
...because of our different approaches.
Ok.
Report tonight...
Wait.
What?
Your coat jacket is rising up in back.
Okay.
When you sit, sit on your jacket a little.
That'll give you a good line.
Report tonight...
Look at the monitor.
Ok.
Report tonight from far down on the Arabian
Peninsula indicate that heavy fight...
Your jacket Aaron.
For a second... What are you doing?
Don't touch me.
Sit on it.
No, but just dont handle me.
I'm sitting on it.
Now look.
Don't fit...
Fantastic tip.
That's great.
Continues for a second date between
government and rebel forces and...
No, no.
Don't let your eyes move from the beginning
of the sentence to the end like that.
You don't want to look shifty, do you?
No.
And the right side of your
face is the good one.
Go ahead.
They going to let me do the news like this?
Heavy fighting continues for a second day...
Try to punch one word or
phrase in every sentence.
One idea per story. Punch.
You were smokin' there toward the end.
The pointers were great.
I'll study the tape.
Go this way.
Just remember that you're not just
reading the news or narrating.
Everybody has to sell a little.
You're selling them this idea of you.
You know, you're sort
of saying is,'trust me.
I'm... credible.
So when you feel yourself just reading...
...stop and start selling a little.
So long.
You look like... this porcelain thing.
You look beautiful.
That's gorgeous.
What are you carrying?
A fistful of... and ten jacket.
Help me pick some, come on.
Ok.
I'm thinking the grey suit.
Tom... why don't I meet you there?
I've got some last minute stuff
I've got to take care of...
Hey, how did you resolve your dilemma
did you rent the tux or buy it...
I knew it. How much?
Okay. I see you there.
I didn't know you were going with him.
You are going to wear that shirt?
No, blue.
Let me look at the grey.
Look.
Not bad, right?
So how about a necktie.
Ok, you brought all of them.
How much was the tops?
Eleven hundered and fourty bucks.
No.
Yes
Try this one.
Okay.
Not bad.
I read about it in the magazine...
...that's how you can make sure
you don't put on too much perfume...
Could you at least pretend that this
is an awkward situation for you...
...me showing up while you're
getting ready for a date.
It's not a date.
It's co-workers going
to a professional conclave.
I hate missing it.
I wish I could be there.
Me too.
If it gets dull a little before
11:00, drop by the studio.
I'm not sure I'll be able to.
If... if not, I'll have the tape...
I'll wait for you at my house, ok?
Okay, great.
Good luck.
Thanks.
Have a good time tonight.
You too.
Come here.
What is it?
What's the matter?
What are you doing.
Oh no.
You are all wrinked and...
I've got shoulders.
Thanks.
Maybe I'll just stand here
and guard your corner.
I'll be here when you get back.
Thanks very much.
Don't take in and go nineteen to
Pennsylvania. Turn the underpath right...
Hey Nick...
Aaron.
Hey George.
What are you doing here?
Anchoring...
...anchoring the weekend news.
Way to go.
Thanks.
This is terrific Aaron.
It's a pleasure to read, really.
There's water on the set,
in case I get an attack of cotton mouth.
Yeah, sure. You'll be fine.
He was lecturing...
...finally I just said I'm sorry...
I refuse to look at it as a negative.
I'm young...
...and my news appeals to people my age.
And it's not like he just didn't hire a
twenty-six-year-old producer himself.
No kidding, twenty-six.
Well hello Tom.
He moves and smiles...
If he doesn't see me soon,
we're not supposed to be together.
It's for me?
Hi Jane.
Hey.
It's incredible who's here.
Who?
Me.
dress.
Thank you.
Ok 20 seconds there.
15 seconds.
10 seconds.
Graphic.
The weekend report with Aaron Altman.
Go...
Good Evening...
In mood and language better
suited to an espionage novel...
...than the delicate world
of the Western Alliance,
...the British Foreign Secretary
today pounced on what he termed,
...'The nest of professional spies
and amateur traitors...
...who were turning NATO
Headquarters into an instrument...
...whose only true function is folly. '
We begin our coverage
with Edward Towne in London.
Take it.
The British Foreign Secretary use the...
She's coming you now.
20 seconds.
Gee whiz.
I think I'm perspiring.
Don't worry.
Are you seen this?
5 seconds.
...the sub-bases referred to are
located in five countries...
Norway, Belgium, the Netherlands,
Spain as well as Great Britain...
This is more than Nixon ever sweated.
Our own State Department was rocked
not only by the revelation...
...but from the highly unusual
persistence of the State Press Corps.
Nice...
Martin Klein reports on
the ruckus at Foggy Bottom.
Just how noticeable is this, huh?
Do you have a big one?
Oh good Suzy, hurry.
5 seconds!
A bomb exploded on a railroad
bridge outside of the India...
...sending a passenger train...
120 people reported injured,
at least 22 people dead.
Commercial.
I wish I were one of them.
Remember Brinkley's great line
"It's as irrevocable as a haircut. "
I like that.
Can I have your autograph for my wife?
How you doing, Paul?
You're finally learning to be flexible.
Glad you changed your mind about Tom.
Ma'am can I check your purse?
I'd like to... contents by myself.
Excusae me sir.
May I see that briefcase?
I'd like to check the contents.
Can I see your purse please?
We gotta go.
Huh?
I'm sorry.
What?
You ok?
I'm so sorry I pulled you of the dinner...
These things can be a lot of fun,
everybody tries to me funny.
All of this is suddenly obvious.
People trying to make political careers
out of how many laugh together.
When you...
Why can't I let go of this woman?
At least kiss me when you do that.
You just can't stop editing me.
Huh?
This is hysterical.
I was half hoping I wouldn't
have a good time tonight.
You know why?
Because you're nuts.
Right, right.
Isn't she fun to tease?
What?
More and more lately...
...when I've watched you in action...
...seen all your energy.
I've been wondering...
...what it would be like
to be inside all that energy.
Me too.
I don't remember ever saying
anything like that exactly...
I don't know why I just did.
Oh let's see. Wait a minute,
Well, I can think of two reasons.
What?
Three... I just thought of a third...
If you talk about it,
you don't have to do it.
That's not it.
Good.
Another is you're trying to make it
all about sex and heat and nothing else.
or...
...it's that great feeling that you
don't want to hold anything back.
You know, intimacy.
Oh, shit. I'm a creep.
What?
I forgot all about Aaron. I promised
to stop by and see how he did.
I'd like to know. I'll go along.
No.
I'll be back at your place
as soon as I can.
Jane!
What happened?
Don't run off like everything's settled
the minute you make up your mind.
He might be weird,
He can talk more freely if I go alone,
why's that so hard to understand?
It's not that it's hard. It's just
that I like you to give me a minute...
...so I can catch up.
Okay.
Sorry.
Don't yell at me like that again,
you scared the life out of me.
It's open.
I was in the shower.
How'd it go?
You didn't see it or speak to anybody?
No.
Then it went very well.
Did it really go well?
Define your terms.
Do you feel good about it?
No.
Do others feel that you did well?
Then what was good about it?
I lost six pounds...
Aaron, will you tell me?
It was great...
There I was...
...writing my little first rate copy,
...sitting on my jacket,
punching my one thought.
Except I had this historic
attack of flop sweat...
They'll never let me anchor again, ever.
Oh, I lost one of your shoulder pads.
I think it drowned.
How was your evening anyway?
What do you mean, flop sweat?
You're making too much out of this.
I'll bet you were the only one aware of it.
People phoned in.
Stop kidding with me.
I want to know what happened.
I'm not kidding.
There were complaining phone calls
because you were sweating?
No, nice ones worried that
I was having a heart attack.
If all that happened,
how come you're so chipper?
I don't know.
At some point it was so off
the chart bad it got funny.
My central nervous system
was telling me something.
Jane, sweat running down my face,
makeup falling into my eyes...
...people turning this fusillade
of blow dryers on my head...
...all so I could read introductions to
other people who were covering stories...
...which is what I like to do anyway.
Yes.
And I'm chipper because
you finally showed up.
I'm gonna cook for us.
Tequila and eggs sound good?
I have to be someplace.
Now?
I told what's his name.
Tom, that I'd meet him.
Call him up.
It can wait, right?
I don't know.
I may be in love with him.
I knew it.
Get out of my house now.
I want you out of here.
I'm not kidding.
Get out of here.
You go to hell.
Come back here. Come on.
Don't go.
This is important to me.
I think it is important for you too.
Come on sit down.
Sit down.
What is this?
I'll take it.
What?
Give me one minute please.
This is tough.
Okay.
Let's take the part that
has nothing to do with me.
Let me just be your
most trusted friend now,
...the one that gets to say
all the awful stuff ok?
I guess.
Yes.
You can't end up with Tom...
...because it totally goes against
everything that you're about.
Yeah, being a basket case.
I know you care about him.
I've never seen you
like this with anybody, so...
...don't get me wrong
when I tell you that Tom,
very nice guy...
...is the Devil.
This isn't friendship.
You're crazy. You know that?
What do you think the job is
going to look like if he's around?
God.
Come on noone is going to be taken in
if he has a long, red, pointy tail.
Come on. What's it gonna sound like...
No.
I'm semi-serious here.
You're serious...
He will be attractive...
...he will be nice and helpful...
...he will get a job where he influences
a great God-fearing nation...
...he'll never do an evil thing...
he'll never deliberately hurt a living thing
...he'll just bit by little bit lower our
standards where they are important.
Just a tiny little bit.
Just coax along flash over substance...
And he'll talk about
all of us really being salesmen.
And he'll get all the great women.
Hey you.
I think you're the Devil.
You know I'm not. -How?
Because I think we have the kind of
friendship where if I were the Devil,
...you will be the only one I would tell.
Well you were quick enough to get
Tom's help when...
Yes.
I think if it's gone well for me tonight,
then I probably wouldn't say any of this.
I grant you everything...
...but give me this...
...he personifies everything that
you've been fighting against...
...And I'm in love with you.
How do you like that?
I buried the lead.
I've got to not say that aloud;
it takes too much out of me.
I've never fought for anyone before.
Does anybody win one of these things?
Hello.
Hi.
Where are you?
I can't get away just yet.
I'm at Aaron's.
Well, when?
I'm not sure. It seems like he
had sort of a mishap on the news.
I know. I taped it.
Well, it wasn't as bad as he think, was it?
It wasn't unprecedented or anything?
Not if you count'Singing in the Rain. '
Do him a favor and don't treat it like a
tragedy. You want me to talk to him?
He says you could hardly notice it.
I'll talk to him.
Don't say anything about anything.
Hi.
sorry I'm tying up Jane, I didn't realize
you two would be going this late. Sorry.
Don't worry about it.
I'll put her back on.
Hi again.
I'm sorry about this...
No.
Don't worry. That sounds more important.
Let's forget about tonight.
I don't know...
...if that's absolutely necessary.
I've my father coming
through tomorrow anyway.
I should get some sleep.
I'll see you at the office.
Good night.
Hello?
Yes.
Okay. Good night.
Good night?
Jane, I'm not some chore you have
to finish so you can stay on schedule.
Okay, great, Grunick. Easy shots now huh?
Good night.
He just cancelled.
He had a chance to think and he cancelled.
I can't breathe.
Damn it!
Oh what a guy.
Well, Jane, thanks for stopping by.
Good night.
I kept trying to call you,
you never called me.
Were you just diddling me? Ãs that it?
I'm great if I'm helping your career.
But when I'm a woman for a second,
I get immediately fucked around by you.
Jane, this is my Dad.
I'm very pleased to meet you sir.
Please forgive what I said.
I'm sorry.
You just light up a room and leave, huh?
You want my opinion?
The thing that's easy
to miss about Jane is...
You want my opinion?
And it's okay if you don't.
Yes, I would.
The way she just acted is not the
way an affectionate person acts.
Rorish.
Just when do you start, telling people?
Almost immediately.
I'd like to take everyone out after
the show. -Fantastic.
Hello Donny.
Bill, what a surprise.
Good to see you again.
Bill Rorich.
Bill, this is hard on all of us and...
...no time for compliments.
But I think it's extraordinary of
you to come down here for this.
Well If we're not here for each other during
the tough time we're not a news organization
Bill.
Welcome back to Washington. Bill.
Well, thank you.
I've forget is she on the list?
This is a brutal layoff...
And all because they couldn't
program Wednesday nights.
You can make it a little less brutal...
by knocking a million dollars
or so off your salary.
A bad joke. I'm sorry. Awful.
It's a miserable day...
...and that was just some kind of
sick-joke defense mechanism...
It just does not indicate
any of my feelings, not one...
...but just shows the kind of
stress this represents for all of us.
Bill.
Tom. It's about time.
It's good to see you.
Thank you.
I feel terrible about what happened.
What did he say?
He said...
...that he liked you...
...because you looked like
you had fire and honesty.
No.
Did he really?
Yes.
What?
Paul canned me.
Well, my brother will feel great,
now he's not the only screw-up.
Tom, Paul wants to see you.
Ernie. -What?
They're calling from work.
Tell them I'm on the way in.
It's Paul.
He'll just be in a minute.
I hate this so much.
You know I'm just old enough to be
flattered by the term,'early retirement. '
That's wonderful. What a lovely line.
Now if there's anything I can do for you.
Well I certainly hope you die soon.
Tom.
This is a severe cutback, Tom.
27 people in this bureau alone
including technical personnel...
...and we're going to
reorganize at the same time.
We're going to drop you out of
Washington and assign you to London.
He knew that we're gonna offer
me this before ever when in there.
I can't stand this.
This is not... -We careful each
other too much to be dishonest...
...so let me tell you the simple truth:
I'm leaving.
No matter who they replace me with here...
or they're gonna make me leave anywhere...
...the fact that each you take some...
...and I know you think
any better than I am.
Goddamn, no I'm not.
Oh my god. I'm gonna miss you.
Me too.
Have you guys seen Jane?
She's back there, getting my job.
The first woman bureau chief
we've ever had here.
What did they do with you?
They booted me out of Washington.
Impossible.
There's no system that
wouldn't value one of us.
Why? What did they do to you?
It's what he did.
I'm proud of him.
They told me they'd keep me...
...because they could plug me into
any story and my salary was in line.
The cost-efficient reporter.
So I quit.
Jane, I gotta tell you something.
Yeah?
Except for socially.
You're my role model.
You packing up tonight?
I'm sorry that they're sending you down
but I'm sure you'll make it back.
Where are they sending you anyway?
London.
London?
Yeah.
That's a promotion!
I don't think so.
Yes, that's where they had Rorish,
for God's sake, before they made him anchor.
I can't believe you.
They're grooming you for it
all and you don't even know it.
Hold it down, will you?
Can I ask you something?
You only had one camera crew
on that date rape piece, right?
Yeah.
You're not going to stick
around for the farewell party?
No. I don't know how much fun
it's gonna be when Martin Klein...
...and Ernie turn off their
credentials with the security guard.
Hi...
Can I speak to your wife?
No message at all,
I'I see you at home.
This is one story they are not gonna cover.
of course the network doesn't cover it
it must not be important so why worry.
I'm going to miss you.
You're a prick in a great way.
You know what I mean.
No, I liked the way it made me sound.
Okay. Be good. See you.
You figure out his hiring.
It's not... Donny.
Thank you, Jane.
Bye sweetie.
Good luck.
Oh sorry.
You know...
but I always wanted to tell you that...
...this is the third cutback...
These people...
This also awful.
It just hurts physically, doesn't it?
Like something's wrong with your bones,
...like your organs are
shifting inside your body.
Maybe I haven't been here long enough.
But, hey, congratulations on the promotion.
Congratulations? How can you say that to me?
I'm sorry I can't stand here
feeing bad because I don't feel worse.
This has happened
at every station I've ever been to.
Do they owe you any time off?
Fourteen weeks.
I think it's crazy for you to come in here
tomorrow morning and start a new job.
I have a week before after I get to my job.
Let's get the hell away
to some island fast and...
...and find out how we are
together away from this.
Well, I just think...
...that's an extraordinary proposal.
That's yes?
That's more than'yes'...
...that's'you bet. '
Hello.
Bastard, sneak, quitter.
Speaking.
I just found out. You didn't say
anything to me? You just resign?
Will you meet me now?
Oh, no, I can't. Maybe next week...
No, I'm going away tomorrow. Please.
Alright, I meet you the place in...
Ok, I'll meet you there.
Anyway my agent has a hot prospect
the number two station in Portland.
The general manager there says he wants
to be every bit as good as the networks.
Personally, I think he should aim higher.
Tell me the God's honest truth...
...are you leaving because of me?
Because if you are...
Ernie said you're lucky if you can
get out while you could still cry...
...which means I should have quit this place
three years ago.
You're just trying to say all great stuff so
I'll feel even worse that you're not around.
Let's go.
I just want to sit here.
I mean the feeling stay here...
...that's powerful.
Why is that?
Maybe the best part of your life is over and
you dont wanna get up and start the bad part
You are now required to sit here with me.
Come on.
...be smart for a second...
What do you...
...think will happen to us?
What will happen?
Okay, that's very easy.
Five, six years from now
I'll be in town to collect an award...
...representing the surge in
foreign coverage by local stations.
What will they call you at work?
The...
Yes.
anyway I'll be walking with my wife
and two lovely children...
...and we'll bump into you
...and my youngest son will say something...
...and I will tell him it's not nice
to make fun of single, fat ladies.
You won't be able to stay mad at me, right?
I hope so.
No. I'm not really mad.
I'll miss you, we'll talk,
we'll always be friends...
...we'll get hot for each other every few
years at dinner and never act on it, okay?
I gotta go.
Jane.
Do you know how Tom had tears in his eyes
in that interview we did with that girl?
Ask yourself how we were able to see that...
...when he only had one camera and that was
pointing at the girl during the interview.
I'm fairly sure I was right to tell you.
This whole thing just messed me up...
...maybe more than it should have...
I'm sorry.
Stand up.
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm sorry.
Don't be silly. What are you sorry about?
The way you were looking at me, I just went.
Point just...
I just need a minute more of your time,
so we can shoot from behind you towards me,
and, um...
...that way we have someplace to go when
we cut. And...
...I sit here, I nod my head, I look nerdy.
It kills me we didn't get you on camera.
It was so powerful seeing your reaction.
Really?
For a second there,
I thought you were gonna cry yourself.
That would have been something.
Give me a minute...
Fucking...
Oh, it's amazing.
Could you tell me where we can catch a bus
to Washington? Thank you very much.
Look who's the organized one.
I've got everything.
I'm not going.
Why?
I saw the taped outtakes of the interview
with the girl. I know you...
...acted your reaction after the interview.
It's verboten, huh?
I thought since
I almost did it the first time, but...
...I get you.
That's not the reason you're not coming?
Of course it's the reason.
It's terrible what you did.
We disagree on how God-awful it was.
Why don't you come with me and we can
disagree and get a tan at the same time?
Jesus, if you're gonna be glib about this
I'm gonna lose it.
Jane, keep it down.
Jane...
I was up all night and...
It made me ill.
That's better.
You could get fired for things like that.
I got promoted for things like that.
Working up tears for a new piece cutaway.
You totally crossed the line between...
It's hard not to cross it; they keep
moving the little sucker, don't they?
It just proves that the difference we...
This is a one-way argument. We've got 6 days
...if you go and we fight and
we hate it, we'll come home.
If you don't go? That's a much bigger deal.
I leave for London right after that.
So, it'd be very big deal if you stay...
The plane's boarding. You're
good at deadline. Here's your ticket.
It's amazing. You commit this incredible
breach of ethics and you act as if I'm nit...
I'm giving you a hard time about nothing
Try and get this. When you edited that...
I'm leaving now.
Gate 82.
Good morning.
Dupont Circle, please.
Don't take the beltway, because at this
time of day there's gonna be a...
...Go any way you want.
But New York Avenue's faster.
...when they told me
Bill had decided to retire...
...and offered me the Evening News,
...I thought it was the same kind of joke
we used to pull back at the station...
...turning off somebody's
prompter in the middle of a show.
But when they heard my reaction,
they thought I was kidding.
I told them I'd be their anchor but
I didn't want to be the Managing Editor...
...that there were people better qualified
than I to control the content...
...and if there weren't
we were all in trouble.
And now to something more important...
I'd like to introduce my fiancee.
Lila?
Aaron.
Congratulations.
Lila, this is Aaron Altman.
Oh yes.
Oh, this kid...
...couldn't possibly belong to anyone else.
What's your name?
Clifford.
Hey Cliff, do you know who this is?
The big joke?
I don't know.
Do you know? Jane's down here.
No.
I'll take Cliff over to see you.
Can I come along?
Yeah.
I'll meet you back at the place. Is that ok?
You'll be okay.
Come on, we'll see Jane now...
The speech was magnificent.
Oh my, I forgot to say something about
your speech.
I appreciate it.
Tom, we're proud of you.
Thanks.
Hey guys.
Come over here.
Hey, what is this?
My life's rushing in front of my eyes.
Clifford come out of here,
I wanna show you something.
Clifford...
Come on. I wanna show you something.
A picnic?
I thought for ol' Cliff here...
...but who know about this.
It would be great...
So...
Yeah,... culture shock.
You are more adorable than your pictures.
Look at you.
Look what I got for you Cliff.
That's terrific. Let me see it.
Come here.
Are you any closer to a decision?
I think so.
Aaron, they've been talking to me
about being a Managing Editor. -Really?
I'm gonna take it.
A great surprise.
I didn't think we had a chance.
They told me you wanted to stay
in Washington.
Well...
...there's a guy,
but he says he'll fly up a lot.
Well, we should talk. You have
time for dinner? Ã'd like you to meet Lila.
I'm sorry but I was looking forward to that,
I'm going back in a few hours.
It's so good to see you.
It's nice to see you.
Congratulations on history's longest
winning streak.
If you ever get restless in Portland,
let me know.
Why?
Okay.
Bye... boss.
Hey Cliff.
Cliff.
Come on.
So, who's the guy?
We met about three months ago.
He works at the surgeon general office.
He loves boating.
So, he's been getting me into water skiing.
I like it!
So, doll, what about you lately?
My wife got this new job...