It's the sense of touch.
What?
Any real city, you walk, you know?
You brush past people.
People bump into you.
In LA, nobody touches you.
We're always behind this metal and glass.
I think we miss that touch so much
that we crash into each other
just so we can feel something.
You guys okay?
I think he hit his head.
You don't think that's true?
Stay in your car.
Graham, I think we got rear-ended.
I think we spun around twice.
And somewhere in there,
one of us lost our frame of reference.
And I'm gonna go look for it.
- Calm down, ma'am.
- I am calm!
I need to see your registration
and insurance.
Why? it's not my fault! it's her fault!
- She do this!
- My fault?
Ma'am, you really need to wait
in your vehicle.
- My fault?
- Stop in middle of street!
Mexicans no know how to drive.
- She blake too fast.
- I "blake" too fast? I "blake" too fast.
- I'm sorry you no see my "blake" light.
- Ma'am.
See, I stop when I see a long line of cars
stopped in front of me.
Maybe you see over steering wheel,
you "blake" too!
- Ma'am!
- Crazy Mexican.
I call immigration on you.
Look what you do my car.
Officer, can you please write
in your report
how shocked I am to be hit
by an Asian driver.
- Ma'am!
- Ma'am, no. See, it's Detective...
All right. You've got to calm down.
- Hey, Detective. Nice entrance.
- Fuck you.
- Hey, you okay?
- I'm freezing.
Shit. I heard it might snow.
- Get out of here.
- That's what I heard.
- You got a smoke?
- No. I quit.
Yeah, me, too.
- What do you got?
- Dead kid.
Hey, Bob.
You get one free box of ammunition.
What kind do you want?
Yo, Osama!
Plan a jihad on your own time.
What do you want?
- Are you making insult at me?
- Am I making insult "at" you?
ls that the closest
you can come to English?
Yes, I speak English! I am American citizen.
- Oh, God, here we go.
- l have right like you.
- l have right to buy gun.
- Not in my store, you don't.
- Andy, get him out of here now!
- Dad, go wait in the car.
Now. Get out!
You're an ignorant man!
Oh, yeah, I'm ignorant?
You're liberating my country
and I'm flying 747s into your mud huts
and incinerating your friends?
- Get the fuck out of my store!
- No, you get the fuck!
- Now, come on.
- Get out!
No, don't touch me! He cheat me this man!
- Andy, now!
- Come on, let's go.
Okay.
You can give me the gun
or give me back the money.
And I am really hoping for the money.
- What kind of ammunition do you want?
- Whatever fits.
Oh, we got a lot of kinds.
We got long colts, short colts, ball heads,
flat nose, hollow points, wide cutters,
and a dozen more that'll fit any size hole.
Just depends upon
how much bang you can handle.
I'll take the ones in the red box.
- You know what those are?
- Can I have them?
Did you see any white people in there
waiting an hour and 32 minutes
for a plate of spaghetti, huh?
And how many cups of coffee did we get?
You don't drink coffee,
and I didn't want any.
Man, that woman in there
poured cup after cup
to every single white person around us,
but did she even ask you
if you wanted any?
We didn't get any coffee
that you didn't want and I didn't order,
and that's evidence
of racial discrimination?
Did you notice that our waitress was black?
And black women
don't think in stereotypes?
You tell me something, man.
When was the last time you met one
who didn't think she knew everything
about your little, lazy ass
before you even opened your mouth, huh?
That waitress sized us up in two seconds.
We're black, and black people don't tip.
So she wasn't gonna waste her time.
Now, somebody like that,
nothing you can do to change their mind.
Yeah, well, how much did you leave?
You expect me to pay
for that kind of service?
What?
What the fuck is you laughing at, man?
I'm seriously starting to think
that you're jealous of Karen.
Hardly. I'd just like to see you
get through a meal
without calling her
or anyone else for that matter.
Okay, look, no more phone calls tonight.
As a matter of fact,
here, you can hold the battery.
Okay?
$1 0 says she calls you in the car.
Wait, wait, wait.
You see what that woman just did?
- You see that?
- Why, she's cold.
She got colder
as soon as she saw us, dawg.
- Oh, man, come on, don't start.
- Man, look around you, man.
You couldn't find a whiter, safer
or better-lit part of this city right now.
But yet this white woman
sees two black guys
who look like UCLA students
strolling down the sidewalk,
and her reaction is blind fear?
I mean, look at us, dawg.
Are we dressed like gangbangers?
Huh? No. Do we look threatening? No.
Fact. If anybody
should be scared around here, it's us.
We're the only two black faces surrounded
by a sea of over-caffeinated white people
patrolled by the trigger-happy LAPD.
So you tell me. Why aren't we scared?
'Cause we got guns?
You could be right.
- Get the fuck out of the car!
- Give me the keys!
- Come on. Hurry up!
- Okay, okay, okay, okay.
Get down!
- No, no! Please!
- Don't look at me!
Motherfuck, I said don't look at me.
Turn around!
Move. Let's go, come on.
We're good. We're fine. Just keep moving.
No, no, no! Take that voodoo-ass thing
off of there right now.
I know you just didn't call
Saint Christopher voodoo.
Man's the patron saint of travelers, dawg.
You had a conversation with God, huh?
What did God say?
"Go forth, my son,
"and leave big slobbery suction rings
on every dashboard you find?"
Why the hell do you do that?
Look at the way your crazy ass drive,
then ask me again.
Chevy pickup and Mercedes
driving north on Balboa.
Pickup cuts in front. Driver of the Mercedes
gets pissed, pulls a gun.
Doesn't realize the guy in the pickup
is a cop coming off shift.
Wait a minute,
this Barry Gibb dude is a cop?
Yeah. Name's Conklin.
He's a narc out of Wilshire.
I got the Mercedes.
Mercedes takes a shot at him.
Detective Conklin returns fire. One shot.
Mercedes rolls to a stop.
Driver opens the door, falls out dead.
He looks very relaxed
for just having shot somebody.
He says he kept trying to drive away.
The Mercedes kept pulling up next to him,
screaming, waving a gun.
Shot back in self-defense.
- Anybody actually see who shot first?
- They just heard two bangs.
Find me a witness.
That is a nice gun.
Well, the car's registered
to a Cindy Bradley.
And that's not Cindy.
That is a William Lewis.
Found it under the front seat.
Hollywood Division.
Looks like Detective Conklin shot himself
the wrong nigger.
- How much longer are you gonna be?
- This is the last one.
Thank you.
You don't think reporters
listen to police calls?
I need to talk to you for a second.
You just give me a minute, all right?
- And find Flanagan, will you? Now.
- Yes, sir.
Yes, honey?
I want the locks changed again
in the morning.
You want...
Look, why don't you just go lie down, huh?
Have you checked on James?
Well, of course I've checked on James.
I've checked on him every five minutes
since we've been home.
- Do not patronize me.
- I'm...
I want the locks changed again
in the morning.
It's okay. Just go to bed.
You know what, didn't I just ask you
not to treat me like a child?
I'm sorry, Miss Jean.
ls okay I go home now?
It's fine.
Thank you very much for staying, Maria.
You're welcome. No problem.
- Good night, Miss Jean.
- Good night.
We'll see you tomorrow.
I would like the locks changed again
in the morning.
And you know what?
You might mention that we'd appreciate it
if next time
they didn't send a gang member.
- A gang member?
- Yes, yes.
- What, you mean that kid in there?
- Yes.
The guy in there with the shaved head,
the pants around his ass, the prison tattoo.
Those are not prison tattoos.
Oh, really?
And he's not gonna go sell our key
to one of his gangbanger friends
the moment he is out our door?
We've had a really tough night.
I think it'd be best
if you just went upstairs right now...
And, what? Wait for them to break in?
I just had a gun pointed in my face.
You lower your voice!
And it was my fault
because I knew it was gonna happen.
But if a white person
sees two black men walking towards her,
and she turns and walks
in the other direction, she's a racist, right?
Well, I got scared and I didn't say anything.
And ten seconds later
I had a gun in my face!
Now, I am telling you.
Your amigo in there is gonna sell our key
to one of his homies.
And this time it'd be really fucking great
if you acted like you actually gave a shit!
All right, what have we got?
Talk to me, Karen.
Flanagan doesn't think
anybody has the story yet.
I'm the goddamn District Attorney
of Los Angeles.
lf my car gets jacked,
it's gonna make news.
Fuck!
Why did these guys have to be black?
I mean, why?
No matter how we spin this thing,
I'm either gonna lose the black vote
or I'm gonna lose the law-and-order vote.
You know, I think you're worrying
too much.
You have a lot of support
in the black community.
All right. If we can't duck this thing,
we're gonna have to neutralize it.
What we need is a picture of me
pinning a medal on a black man.
Bruce?
The firefighter.
The one who saved the camp or something.
Northridge. What's his name?
He's Iraqi.
He's Iraqi?
Well, he looks black.
He's dark-skinned, sir, but he's Iraqi.
His name's Saddam Khahum.
Saddam? His name's Saddam?
Well, that's real good, Bruce.
Yeah, I'm gonna pin a medal
on an Iraqi named Saddam.
Give yourself a raise, will you?
It's been good doing business with you.
- How soon can I have them?
- I'm picking them up right now.
Look, you're not listening to me.
This is an emergency.
I keep telling you he's in pain.
He can't sleep.
Mr. Ryan, your father has been to the clinic
three times in the last month.
He is being treated
for a urinary tract infection.
That is by no means an emergency.
Now, if you have any more questions
about your HMO plan,
why don't you make an appointment
to come in between 1 0:00 and 4:00,
Monday through Friday?
What does my father do
about sleeping tonight?
I don't know. I'm not a doctor.
- l wanna talk to your supervisor.
- l am my supervisor.
- Yeah, what is your name?
- Shaniqua Johnson.
Shaniqua. Big fucking surprise that is.
Oh...
1 005 Bronson Avenue, Westwood.
Vehicle described as a black,
late-model Lincoln Navigator.
California plates, 4 Peter Charles Ida 31 5.
Suspects are two black males,
approximately 20 years of age.
That's not it.
That's not the vehicle, John.
The plates don't match.
The driver's gotta be 40, and nobody
jacks a car and takes it to Studio City.
They were doing something.
Enthusiastic.
Keep your hands
where I can see them, please.
I'm gonna need to see your driver's license
and registration.
No problem. I'm gonna have to
reach inside of the glove compartment
to get the registration.
- ls that okay?
- Nice and slow, please.
Okay.
How are you tonight, Officer?
Excellent.
Here you go.
Stay inside the vehicle, please.
Let's do it again right now.
Step out of the car, please, sir.
Wait, wait a minute, Officer.
I haven't been drinking or anything.
Then we shouldn't have a problem.
He doesn't drink.
He's a Buddhist, for Christ's sake.
No, it's okay.
It's fine.
Step onto the sidewalk, sir.
That's good. Right there.
Look at me.
I want you to stand on your right foot.
Touch your nose
with the index finger of your left hand.
I told you he doesn't drink.
Ma'am, I'm only gonna tell you one time
to stay in the vehicle.
- Ma'am?
- Honey, honey, I'm okay. I got this.
Don't you "ma'am" me.
Who the hell do you think
you're talking to?
Look, Officer,
my wife has had a couple of drinks...
All right, both of you turn around.
Put your hands on top of your head
and interlock your fingers.
No, wait. Wait a minute.
We're only a block away from our house.
Hands on your head. Interlock your fingers.
- That's not even necessary.
- Hands on your head.
Interlock your fingers.
Look, I'm a television director.
Me and my wife were just coming home
from an awards show.
Get your hands off him.
He has done nothing wrong.
Put your hands
on top of your head, ma'am.
- Will you just do what he says?
- Fuck you!
Put your hands
on top of your head, ma'am.
And you keep
your filthy fucking hands off me!
- You motherfucking pig!
- Christine, just stop talking.
That's quite a mouth you have.
Of course you know that.
Fuck you!
That's what this is all about, isn't it?
You thought you saw
a white woman blowing a black man,
and that just
drove your little cracker ass crazy.
Will you just shut your fucking mouth?
I'd listen to your husband, ma'am.
Put your legs open.
Now, do you have any guns or knives
or anything I might get stuck with?
I'm wearing a cocktail dress.
What do you think?
You'd be surprised some of the places
I've found weapons.
He's clean.
What do you think we should do about this,
Mr. Thayer?
My partner and I just witnessed your wife
performing fellatio on you
while you were operating a motor vehicle.
That's reckless endangerment,
which, incidentally, is a felony.
Now we can charge your wife here
with lewd conduct
and performing a sexual act in public.
Now you say you're a block from home.
Now, we could use our discretion
and let you go with a warning,
or we can cuff you
and put you in the back of the car.
What do you think we should do, sir?
Look, we're sorry,
and we would appreciate if you would
just let us go with a warning, please.
The man's apologizing, Tommy.
I think we can let him go. Don't you?
Yeah.
All right.
You can go.
You folks drive safe now, huh?
Let's go, Tommy.
lt won't close.
I can do that.
Dad, you couldn't even get it open.
Have respect for your father.
Give me the gun.
Here. Now you can shoot
anybody you want.
Dorri, that man could've killed your mother.
You think I should let crazy people
do what they want to us?
Farhad, it won't close.
Dorri, you should be at work.
Who are you calling?
I'm gonna report their asses.
Sons of bitches.
You actually believe they're gonna take
anything you have to say seriously?
Do you have any idea how that felt?
To have that pig's hands all over me?
And you just stood there.
And then you apologized to him?
I mean, what did you want me to do?
Get us both shot?
They were gonna shoot us
on Ventura Boulevard? Pathetic.
Yeah, well, maybe you would've
been satisfied with just being arrested.
Oh, I get it. Much better to let him
shove his hand up my crotch
than get your name in the paper.
You know, you finally got me figured out,
'cause see, that's exactly
what I was worried about, right there.
Oh, and it wasn't? You weren't afraid
that all your good friends at the studio
were gonna read about you in the morning
and realize that,
you know what, he's actually black?
You need to calm down right now.
No, what I need is a husband
who will not just stand there
while I am being molested!
I mean, they were cops, for God's sakes!
They had guns!
You know what?
Maybe I should've let them arrest your ass.
I mean, sooner or later you gotta find out
what it is really like to be black.
Fuck you, man. Like you know.
The closest you ever came to being black,
Cameron, was watching The Cosby Show.
Yeah, well, at least I wasn't watching it
with the rest of the equestrian team.
Yeah, you're right, Cameron.
I got a lot to learn 'cause I haven't
quite learned how to shuck and jive.
Let me hear it again.
"Thank you, Mr. Policeman.
"You sure is mighty kind
to us poor black folk.
"You be sure to let me know next time
you wanna finger-fuck my wife."
How the fuck do you say
something like that to me?
You know, fuck you!
That's good. A little anger.
It's a bit late, but it's nice to see!
- How's it going?
- Okay.
You didn't get scared or something,
did you?
There's no monsters in the closet, right?
'Cause I hate monsters.
- There's no such thing as monsters.
- Oh, that's a good thing.
I heard a bang.
Like a truck bang?
Like a gun.
That's funny, because we moved out
of that bad neighborhood.
And there's not too many guns
around here.
How far can bullets go?
They go pretty far.
But they usually get stuck in something
and stop.
What if they don't?
You thinking about that bullet
that came through your window?
Because we never did find it, did we?
I think it didn't see me
'cause I was under the covers.
And you think it was that same bullet
that you heard tonight?
- You think we should move again?
- l like it here.
Me, too. But if that bullet found out
where we lived...
Oh, hold on.
What?
So stupid! How can I forget?
No, forget it. You ain't gonna believe me.
Tell me.
Okay.
When I was five,
this fairy came into my room one night.
Right.
See, I told you
you weren't gonna believe me.
- Okay, go to sleep now, you little rat.
- No, tell me.
Okay.
So this fairy comes into my room
and I'm like, "Yeah, right, you're a fairy."
Anyway, we're talking, you know.
And she's flying all around the room,
knocking down all my posters and stuff.
She was flying?
Yeah, but she had these little stubby wings.
She could've glued them on, you know?
Like I'm gonna believe she's a fairy.
So she said, "I'll prove it."
So she reaches into her backpack,
and she pulls out this invisible cloak.
She ties it around my neck,
and she tells me that it's impenetrable.
You know what "impenetrable" means?
lt means that nothing can go through it.
No bullets. Nothing.
She told me that if I wore it,
nothing would hurt me.
So I did.
And my whole life,
I never got shot, stabbed. Nothing.
I mean, how weird is that?
Only she told me
that I was supposed to give it
to my daughter on her fifth birthday
and I forgot.
Can I touch it?
Sure, go ahead.
- l don't feel it.
- Yeah. it's pretty cool, huh?
lf you want I can take it off
and tie it around your shoulders.
She told me how to do it.
Unless you think it's stupid then...
- Don't you need it?
- No, not anymore.
So what do you think? You want it?
Okay, let's get out of here.
Okay.
Hold your chin up.
Okay. ls that too tight?
Do you feel anything at all?
Good. Then it's just right.
Do I take it off when I have a bath?
No, you leave it on all the time.
Until you have a daughter.
When she turns five, then you give it to her.
Okay?
Okay.
- Good night, sweetie.
- Good night.
No, no. You wanna listen to music
of the oppressor, you go right ahead, man.
How in the lunacy of your mind
is hip-hop music of the oppressor?
Listen to it, man. "Nigger this, nigger that."
You think white people go around
calling each other honkies all day, man?
Hey, honky, how's business?
Going great, cracker. We're diversifying.
How about this, huh? How about that?
Listen to that. You like that?
Man's singing about lynching niggers.
And you think there's a difference,
don't you? Huh?
Gonna buy me a rope
and lynch me a nigger
You got absolutely no idea
where hip-hop music comes from, do you?
I'd shoot them dead first
but I done broke my trigger
You see, back in the '60s
we had smart, articulate black men.
Gonna get out my sheet
Put my hood on my head
Like Huey Newton, Bobby Seale,
Eldridge Cleaver, Fred Hampton.
Gonna string them up good
These brothers were speaking out,
and people were listening!
Then they'll be dead
And then the FBI said,
"Oh, no, we can't have that."
In the home of the brave
and the land of the free
"I know, let's give the niggers this music
by a bunch of mumbling idiots
"and sooner or later, they'll all copy it,
"and nobody will be able to understand
a fucking word they say.
"End of problem."
What the fuck was that, dawg?
Holy shit!
- What?
- Man, we done ran over a Chinaman.
You're saying there's a Chinaman
under this truck?
What part don't you understand?
There's a Chinaman
stuck underneath the fucking truck.
Help me.
Oh, God.
What the hell did he do,
just leap out in front of the truck?
Man, this is so completely fucked up.
Oh, really? No shit!
Okay, hold up. Hold up, hold up, hold up.
- Get back in the truck.
- What?
- Yes, get back in the truck.
- You think we didn't drag him far enough?
No, no we gonna drive away.
And he gonna let go.
He's not gonna let go, Anthony.
You know why?
Because he's stuck underneath
the fucking truck!
Now, if he could've let go,
he probably would've considered
that option about a half a block back.
Now, what you and I gotta do,
just grab his arms
and pull him from underneath.
You grab his arm, it's gonna fall off.
Then you gonna be standing in the middle
of the street holding a Chinaman's arm.
Then what your ass gonna do, huh?
lf we leave this man here, he dies.
Then we're up for murder charges.
Now just grab his arm.
Why not just pull him out?
I don't wanna
cause any problems, Lieutenant.
I just want a new partner.
I understand. Your partner's a racist prick.
But you don't wanna stir up
any bad feelings with him.
Well, he's been on the force for a long time.
- Seventeen years.
- And I do have to work here, sir.
So you don't mind
that there's a racist prick on the force.
You just don't want him to ride in your car.
lf you need me to go on record
about this, sir, I will.
That'd be great. Write a full report.
Because I'm anxious to understand
how an obvious bigot
could've gone undetected
in this department for 1 7 years,
1 1 of which he was under
my personal supervision,
which doesn't speak very highly
of my managerial skills.
But that's not your concern.
I can't wait to read it.
What if I said I wanted a new partner
for personal reasons?
So now you're saying
he's not a racist prick,
you just don't like him.
- Yes, sir.
- That's not a good enough reason.
Well, then, I guess I should think
of a better one and get back to you.
So you think
I'm asking you to make one up.
No, sir. I just can't think of one right now.
You wanna know what I heard?
I heard it was a case
of uncontrollable flatulence.
- You want me to say he has flatulence?
- Not him. You.
You have uncontrollable flatulence.
You're too embarrassed
to ride with anybody else,
so you're requesting a one-man car.
I'm not... comfortable with that, Lieutenant.
I wouldn't be either.
Which is why I understand
your need for privacy.
Just like I'm sure you understand
how hard a black man has to work to get to,
say, where I am, in a racist fucking
organization like the LAPD
and how easily that can be taken away.
Now, that being said, it's your decision.
You can put your career and mine
on the line in pursuit of a just cause,
or you can admit to having
an embarrassing problem
of a personal nature.
Fuck.
Excuse me.
Excuse me. Sir?
- You finished?
- l replaced the lock.
But you got a real problem with that door.
- You fix the lock?
- No, I replaced the lock.
- But you gotta fix that door.
- Just fix the lock.
Sir, sir, sir. Listen to me.
What you need is a new door.
- l need new door?
- Yeah.
Okay. How much?
I don't...
Sir, you're gonna have to call somebody
that sells doors.
You try to cheat me, right, huh?
You have a friend that fix door?
No, I don't have a friend that fix doors, bro.
Then go and fix the fucking lock,
you cheater.
You... You know what?
Why don't you just pay for the lock,
and I won't charge you for the time.
You don't fix the lock! I pay?
What, you think I'm stupid?
You fix the fucking lock, you cheater!
Hey, I'd appreciate it
if you'd stop calling me names.
- Then fix the fucking lock!
- l replaced the lock!
- You gotta fix the fucking door!
- You cheat! You fucking cheater!
- Fine. Don't pay.
- What?
- Have a good night.
- What? No. Wait!
Wait! You come back here! You fix the lock!
Come here! You fix my lock!
Fix the fucking lock!
No, I understand.
You run over a Chinaman,
stuff him in the back,
then bring the truck here
so I can share in the experience.
Come on, man. it's a little bit of blood.
It'll wash right off.
Georgie, burn this thing.
Burn it? it's a brand-new Navigator.
All you need is a little piece of carpet.
You watch the Discovery Channel?
- Not a lot.
- They got some good shit on that channel.
Every night there is a show
with somebody shining a little blue light
and finding tiny specks of blood splattered
on carpets and walls and ceiling fans,
bathroom fixtures and special-edition
plastic Burger King tray cups.
Then the next thing they show
is some stupid redneck in handcuffs
who looks absolutely stunned
that this is happening to him.
Sometimes the redneck
is actually watching the Discovery Channel
when they break in to arrest him.
And he still can't figure out
how on earth they could've caught him!
Do I look like I wanna be
on the Discovery Channel?
- No.
- Then get the fuck out of my shop.
Oh, yeah, make sure you get that.
Without him, things could've gone
really fucking wrong tonight.
- Fuck! This could be a...
- Graham, don't! Don't! Don't you dare.
Don't.
Graham Waters.
No. No, he's not here, Mom.
- It's your mother?
- Yeah.
I'm not gonna go looking for him.
Look, he'll be home when he...
Just leave it alone, Mom.
Mom, I can't talk to you right now, okay?
I'm having sex with a white woman.
Okay, where were we?
I was white, and you were about
to jerk off in the shower.
Oh, shit.
Come on.
I would've said you were Mexican,
but I don't think
it would've pissed her off as much.
Why do you keep everybody
at a certain distance, huh?
What, you start to feel something
and panic?
Come on, Ria.
You're just pissed
'cause I answered the phone.
That's just where I begin to get pissed.
I mean, really, what kind of man
speaks to his mother that way, huh?
Oh, this is about my mother.
What do you know about my mother?
I know if I was your father,
I'd kick your fucking ass.
Okay. I was raised badly.
Why don't you take your clothes off,
get back in the bed and teach me a lesson?
You want a lesson? I'll give you a lesson.
How about a geography lesson?
My father's from Puerto Rico.
My mother's from El Salvador.
Neither one of those is Mexico.
Well, then I guess the big mystery is
who gathered all those
remarkably different cultures together
and taught them all
how to park their cars on their lawns?
Pop, you okay?
lf I could piss, I'd be okay.
I'm... Jesus.
I'm done now.
Give me a hand.
Wait a goddamn minute.
- Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- All right. Okay. Okay.
- Okay. There you go.
Wait, wait, wait. Stop, stop.
- l gotta go back.
- Okay.
What, are you gonna stand there
and stare at me?
So Conklin just shot him?
- They know each other?
- Sir.
- This a grudge thing?
- Not as far as we can tell.
You think this is racially motivated?
Well, a dozen people heard the shots.
Nobody saw anything.
- Who do we have on it?
- Graham Waters.
Waters. All right, well, tell him
that he speaks to no one but me.
Call a press conference for 4:00 ,
and I want Waters here at 3:30.
And would someone please find Flanagan?
- Oh, what up, Mo Phat?
- What's up?
Man robs purses from old ladies
and you all,
"Hey, how's it going, Mo Phat?"
That nigger will steal teeth
from a cripple, man.
You calling him a thief? And we do what?
The man steals from black people.
Only reason black people
steal from their own
is 'cause they terrified of white people.
Oh, man, please.
Think about it.
Sherman Oaks. Burbank. Santa Monica.
All scary-ass places
for a brother to find himself.
Now, drop Mo Phat off
at a Starbucks in Toluca Lake,
that nigger will run like a rabbit
soon as somebody say "decaf latte."
What the fuck did you do to my car?
Sorry I take your car, Miss Jean.
I turn key to my car, but nothing.
James wanted to take this to school,
but I don't want the kids to fight over it.
- Are these clean or dirty?
- All clean, senora.
You know, Maria,
just once I would like to wake up
and find these dishes in the cabinet.
- Okay?
- Si, senora. No problem.
I'm starting to understand now.
By your work, you're setting an example
for our neighborhood.
Sort of like a big brother
kind of thing, right?
Well, yeah, you laugh, man.
But you have never seen me steal
from a black person ever in your life.
What the hell do you think
you doing right now, man?
Waving down the bus.
Man, put your hand down, dawg!
Are you out of your mind?
You actually expect me to get on a bus?
No. I was hoping we could push your car
across town.
You know why? 'Cause we just
don't do stuff like that no more.
You have no idea, do you?
You have no idea
why they put them great big windows
on the sides of buses, do you?
- Why?
- One reason only.
To humiliate the people of color
who are reduced to riding on them.
How do you know that?
You know, you could fill the Staples Center
with what you don't know.
Oh, you know,
the Kings are playing tonight.
You don't like hockey! The only reason
you say you do is to piss me off!
I love hockey.
Cut! Print. Moving on.
Okay, that takes us into scene 1 2,
and we are in the bathroom.
Jamal, that's what I'm talking about.
Right on.
- Cam, Cam, you got a second?
- Yeah, Fred. I just wanna grab some coffee.
Yeah, listen,
I think we needed another take, buddy.
That looked pretty terrific, man.
This is gonna sound strange, but is Jamal
seeing a speech coach or something?
What do you mean?
Have you noticed...
I mean, this is weird for a white guy to say,
but have you noticed
he's talking a lot less black lately?
- No, I haven't noticed that.
- Really?
Like in this scene, he was supposed to say,
"Don't be talkin' 'bout that."
And he changed it to,
"Don't talk to me about that."
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
You think because of that,
the audience won't recognize him
as being a black man?
- Come on.
- ls there a problem, Cam?
- Excuse me?
No, we don't have a problem.
I mean, 'cause all I'm saying is,
it's not his character.
Eddie's supposed to be the smart one,
not Jamal, right?
I mean, you're the expert here,
but to me, it rings false.
- We're gonna do it one more time.
- Thanks, buddy.
Everybody back to one, please.
Let's do it one more time.
Jamal...
- Morning, Carol. Who do I have?
- Hold for a minute, please.
Mr. Trujillo called and canceled,
but you have a walk-in, Mr. Ryan.
Send him in.
- Mr. Ryan.
- Yeah.
My name is Shaniqua Johnson.
I believe we spoke last night.
Oh, yeah. I wanted to apologize about that.
I haven't been getting too much sleep.
My father's in a lot of pain.
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
This doctor he's been seeing
says he's got a urinary tract infection.
But he's been taking this medicine
for a month now,
and he just keeps getting worse.
- And he's been back to see Dr. Robertson?
- Yeah.
- Between you and me, the man's an idiot.
- Really?
Well, no offense,
but the guy sees 1 00 patients an hour.
I think his nurses
are doing most of the work.
lf you're unhappy, your father's welcome
to see a doctor outside the network.
And if this new doctor
says it's not an infection,
says it's his prostate and it needs to be
operated on, is that gonna be covered?
- Not unless Dr. Robertson authorizes...
- Then what good is that gonna do?
I'm sorry. There's nothing else I can do.
All right. Well, you know what I can't do?
I can't look at you
without thinking about the five or six
more-qualified white men
who didn't get your job.
It's time for you to go.
Now, I'm saying this 'cause
I'm really hoping that I'm wrong about you.
I'm hoping that someone like yourself,
someone who may have been given
a helping hand,
might have a little compassion
for someone in a similar situation.
Carol, I need security in my office.
You know, you don't like me, that's fine.
I'm a prick.
But my father doesn't deserve
to suffer like this.
He was a janitor.
He struggled his whole life.
Saved enough to start his own company.
Twenty-three employees, all of them black.
Paid them equal wages
when no one else was doing that.
For 30 years
he worked side by side with those men,
sweeping and carrying garbage.
And then the city council decides
to give minority-owned companies
preference in city contracts.
And overnight, my father loses everything.
His business, his home, his wife.
Everything.
Not once does he blame your people.
I'm not asking you to help me.
I'm asking that you do this small thing
for a man who lost everything
so people like yourself
could reap the benefits.
And do you know
what it's gonna cost you? Nothing.
Just a flick of your pen.
Your father sounds like a good man.
And if he'd come in here today,
I probably would've approved this request.
But he didn't come in. You did.
And for his sake, it's a real shame.
- Get him the hell out of my office.
- Prick.
Yeah, sir, I spoke to our employee,
and he told you you needed to replace
or repair the door.
He say he fix the lock.
- You come here, see how fixed it is!
- You're yelling again.
I am not yelling! I'm upset!
- Yes, I am.
- Mom, are you all right?
Stop washing. Insurance must take picture.
Okay?
- Yes.
- Look what they wrote.
- They think we're Arab.
- Please, you come see my store.
When did Persian become Arab?
I want... I want his name. Yes.
Oh, my God.
- l want his name!
- Dad.
- Give me his name!
I'm not giving you his name, sir.
Dad, did they take the gun?
- Not fix my lock! I want his name!
- Baba.
- I'm gonna hang up now, sir.
- Don't hang up!
Don't hang up! Shit!
Oh, thank God.
Mom?
Mom, it's cold. Come on.
Did you find your brother?
No, Mom.
I was doing good.
I was... I was doing real good.
- l know, Mom.
- l was doing good.
It's okay.
Did you find your brother?
No, Mom.
Tell him to come home.
Tell him I'm not mad, okay?
Okay, baby?
- Okay, Mom.
- Okay, baby.
Okay.
- Did you apologize to your mother?
- She wasn't there.
Internal Affairs called.
Found something in the Mercedes.
That's lunch. One hour.
I tried to call.
Sounded like you were having
a bad day, huh?
Yeah.
What?
I got scared, Cam.
You know, it's not like I haven't been
pulled over before, you know?
But nothing like that.
And, yes, I was a little drunk
and I was mouthing off.
I'm sorry.
But when that man
was putting his hands on me...
I don't wanna talk about it.
I couldn't believe
you'd let him do that, baby.
Look, I know what you did
was the right thing. Okay?
But I was humiliated.
For you.
I just couldn't stand to see that man
take away your dignity.
Yeah. That's what happened.
Oh, baby, don't do this.
- No. No, you're right.
- Come on.
I ain't doing it.
You gonna walk away from me?
- Cameron!
- Just go home.
I understand.
Thanks.
- Has your father read his policy?
- He doesn't read English.
Mr. Golzari,
you said that you called the locksmith?
Yes. I tell him, fix it.
They said that their man told you
to fix the door, and you didn't do so.
Are you saying it's his fault?
Insurance company is calling it negligence.
They're not covering any of this.
No.
This store is all we have.
I really am sorry.
What time you must go to work?
Not until tonight.
Go home and sleep.
It's okay. It's okay. Go home and sleep.
Hey.
Maybe they didn't tell you,
but I've been reassigned.
Yeah, they told me.
I just wanted to say good luck
and it was good riding with you.
You, too.
Wait till you've been on the job
a few more years.
- Yeah.
- Look at me, look at me.
Wait till you've been doing it a little longer.
You think you know who you are?
You have no idea.
Yo, Gomez, you ready to roll, homie?
Ready , amigo.
Radio check, 2-1 -L-2-3.
21 -L-23, picking up strange noises
from your car.
Likewise, 21 -L.
Is your mike open by any chance?
Call it in.
Ma'am? Can you hear me?
Paramedics are rolling.
They'll be here in two minutes.
All right. Get an extinguisher,
and get that fire out.
Jesus.
Ma'am, are you hurt?
- Can you move?
- l can't breathe.
Okay. Okay, I'm gonna get you out.
It's okay.
Okay. Okay.
Okay, I'm gonna get you out.
- No.
- It's okay.
- Get away from me.
Get away from me. Stay away from me.
- Not you!
- Fuck it.
- It's okay.
Don't touch me! Don't touch me!
Keep away from me!
Lady, I'm trying... I'm trying to help you.
Fuck you! Not you!
Somebody! Anybody else!
- Please, somebody!
- Stop moving!
Not you!
No! Get your filthy fucking hands off me!
- Stop moving.
- No!
Lady, I'm not gonna fucking hurt you!
Okay. Okay.
Please don't touch me. Don't, don't.
I'm not gonna touch you.
But there's nobody else here yet,
and that's gasoline there.
We need to get you out of here
right away. Okay?
- Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
- Okay.
I need to reach across your lap.
Can I do that, please?
Yeah. Yeah.
Thanks.
ls anything broken?
I don't think so.
Okay. I think that's good.
- Are you gonna get me out?
- Yeah.
I'm gonna get you out. Okay?
Look at me. Look at me.
I'm gonna get you out.
Oh, fuck!
- I'm sorry.
- That's okay.
I'm gonna have to cut your belt, okay?
I'm gonna have to cut the belt.
It's okay, it's okay.
It's okay. it's okay.
Okay, we're gonna get you out.
Everything's gonna be fine. Look at me.
Everything's gonna be fine.
We're gonna get you out of here.
Ryan!
Pull!
It's okay.
It's okay. You're gonna be okay.
All right. Here we go. it's okay, it's okay.
It's all right. I got it now. I got it.
Ma'am? Ma'am, can you walk with me?
It's cool, it's cool. it's okay.
Here we go. All right, you're doing great.
You're doing great.
The DA wanted me to apologize.
He really wanted to be here himself.
No, he didn't.
lf he did his own dirty work,
none of us would have jobs.
- Jake Flanagan. I work with Rick.
- Graham Waters.
- Thanks for coming in, Detective.
- He just pulled into the garage.
Great, great. Press conference
is in 1 0 minutes, so we'll make this short.
Internal Affairs says this Conklin has
two suspicious shootings on his record.
Both black men.
Both times he was cleared, but only just.
Detective Lewis
makes black man number three.
You know any reason
why we shouldn't hang Conklin for this?
Well, it's... it's more complicated
than we originally thought.
We found $300 ,000 in the trunk of the car
that Detective Lewis was driving.
Shit!
Go down to the garage.
Tell him to stay in the car
until he hears from me.
You found the money in the Mercedes.
I thought that wasn't his car.
Well, the car's actually registered
to a Cindy Bradley.
We haven't been able
to get in touch with her, yet.
Apparently, she left town this morning.
So it wasn't Lewis' car.
He may not have even known
the money was in it.
Do you really think you're gonna be able
to make that fly?
Latasha Harlins, Rodney King.
- These names ring a bell, Detective?
- Yeah, vaguely.
We have attorneys
for this slain police officer
camping in our offices.
We have his mother
and a half a dozen men of the cloth
who swear that Lewis
was one of the twelve apostles of Christ.
We have two black city councilmen
and a congresswoman
who call on the hour, every hour,
demanding to know
what the District Attorney
intends to do about this.
And you want him
to walk into that press room
and tell them all
that the situation is complicated?
Give us a minute.
No problem.
Who knows about the money?
You gotta be kidding me.
There are only two people in this room.
Myself, my partner, Ferguson
and Internal Affairs.
- Jim Ferguson?
- Yeah.
Okay. Okay, I guess I don't see a problem.
As it wasn't Lewis' car, the money
isn't clear evidence of any wrongdoing.
And even if it was,
we aren't going to prosecute a dead man.
Which means
the money Internal Affairs is holding
can't even be considered evidence.
What? You know, you can
do this whole dance if you want to,
but I'm willing to bet
when the coroner's report
comes back tomorrow
it's going to say that Detective Lewis
was coked out of his head.
Fucking black people, huh?
- What did you just say?
- l mean...
You know, I know
all the sociological reasons
why per capita eight times more black men
are incarcerated than white men.
Schools are a disgrace.
Lack of opportunity.
Bias in the judicial system.
All that stuff. All that stuff!
But still, it's gotta get to you,
on a gut level as a black man.
They just can't keep their hands
out of the cookie jar.
Of course, you and I know
that's not the truth,
but that's the way it always plays,
doesn't it?
And assholes like Lewis just keep
feeding the flames. it's gotta get to you.
What did you say you did for the DA again?
You coach ball down in Compton.
Am I right?
Oh, please, don't do that.
Don't act like you know
something about me, okay?
What do you think those kids need?
To make them believe, to give them hope?
You think they need another
drug-dealing cop
or do you think they need
a fallen black hero?
Why don't you cut through
the bullshit, Flanagan,
and just tell me what it is you want?
The DA's squad loses
its lead investigator next month.
Rick is quite adamant
that his replacement be a person of color.
It's a high-profile position, and he wants to
send the right message to the community.
And the right message is,
"Look at this black boy I just bought?"
Well, fuck you very much,
but thanks for thinking of me.
Actually, we were thinking of you.
Until we saw that.
It's your brother's file.
Twenty something years old
and already three felonies.
Three-strikes law.
Kid's going away for life for stealing a car.
Christ, that's a shitty law.
There's a warrant in there.
But still, hey,
he had every opportunity you had.
Fucking black people, huh?
So all...
All I need to do to make this disappear
is to frame a potentially innocent man?
What are you?
The fucking defender of all things white?
We're talking about a white man
who shot three black men.
And you're arguing with me
that maybe we're not being fair to him?
You know what? Maybe you're right.
Maybe you're right.
Maybe Lewis did provoke this
and maybe he got exactly
what was coming to him.
Or maybe, stoned or not,
just being a black man in the Valley
was enough to get him killed.
There was no one there to see
who shot first, so there is no way to know.
Which means we could get this wrong.
Maybe that's what happened
with your brother. Maybe we got it wrong.
Maybe Lewis isn't the only one
who deserves the benefit of the doubt.
You're the one closest to all this.
You need to tell us.
What does your gut tell you?
So, Graham.
What do I tell them?
You tell me, and I'll tell them.
Well, I think given
Detective Conklin's history,
it's pretty clear what happened last night.
Okay.
Before I get to why we're here,
I know that many of you have heard
that we had our car stolen last night.
And as you could imagine,
my wife and I are both pretty shaken up.
But we're okay.
And Jean and I truly appreciate
all your calls and your concern.
Thank you.
Now, just affer 9:00 p.m. last night,
Detective William Lewis,
an eight-year veteran of the force
and an active member
of the black community,
was gunned down by a fellow officer.
Hi, sweetie.
Bye, Lara.
Get out of the car!
Give me the keys! Get out the...
What the fuck?
Whoa! What the fuck are you doing, man?
Shit!
- You wanna get killed, nigger?
- Say that again!
What the fuck?
- Say that again, bitch!
- You stupid motherfucker!
- Say it again, huh! Call me a nigger again!
- Christ!
- Yo, man, what the fuck? Get off of him.
- Fuck you!
- Shoot him!
- Fucking blow your head off!
Shoot this motherfucker, man!
Look, man, I swear to God,
I'm gonna blow your head off!
Stop talking and shoot!
Come on, stop! Let's go!
- Shit, here comes the po-po.
- Shit.
- Get off of me.
- Fuck off.
- Jesus.
- Hey, hey. Where you going, man?
Hell, no!
- Oh, shit.
- Anthony! Anthony!
Get the fuck out of my car!
Shit! Damn!
What are you doing, man?
Get out of the car!
Fuck you!
- Get the fuck out of my car!
- You get the fuck out of the car!
Unit 25 in pursuit of a black Navigator.
Westbound on...
I will blow you away. Get the fuck out!
2-2 Ida Tom Adam 3...
Oh, Christ!
- Get the fuck out of the car!
- You get the fuck out of the car!
- Get out of the fucking car!
- It's my fucking car!
- It's my fucking gun!
- Fuck, it's my gun now!
You just give me my fucking gun!
Fuck!
Hands in plain sight!
Step out of the vehicle!
Slowly step out of the vehicle.
Get out of my car.
Oh, you so brave, you get out the car, man.
Turn off the engine.
Throw the keys out the window.
You fucking want me?
Here I am, you pig fuck!
Lie face down on the ground.
Spread your arms and legs.
No, you lie face down on the ground
and spread your arms and legs.
Don't come any closer!
Down on your knees!
Fuck you, man! What are you gonna do?
- Pull the fucking trigger, then!
- On your knees now!
You get on your knees
and suck my motherfucking dick
while you down there.
Do I look like I'm fucking joking with you?
Yeah, that's what you look like,
a fucking joke to me.
- This man is making threatening gestures.
- Threatening gestures?
You wanna see a threatening gesture?
I got a threatening gesture for you.
- l know this man! I know this man!
- Get back.
Fuck off. Give me some space.
I know this guy.
- Get out of the way.
- You don't fucking know me.
Step away.
Give me some goddamn room.
I know this guy.
- Man, don't walk up on me!
- See what's happening here?
Do you wanna die here, huh?
ls that what you want?
'Cause these guys really wanna shoot you.
And the way you're acting,
they'll be completely fucking justified.
- Fuck you!
- Fuck me? Fuck me?
I'm not the one who's fucked here.
You're the one who's fucked here.
'Cause you're the one whose head's
gonna be blown off
and onto that man's patio.
- Officer Hanson, step away.
- He's a friend of mine, okay?
He's a fucking friend of mine!
This man is not armed!
He's not gonna shoot you, or me,
or anybody else, all right?
So give me two goddamn seconds.
Can you do that?
Lower your firearm! Lower your firearm!
Are you starting
to understand the situation?
What do you want from me?
Unless you think your wife
is gonna be better off with a husband
who has a bloody stump for a head,
I want you to sit down on that curb,
put your hands on your head,
and do nothing
until I speak with these officers.
I'm not sitting on no curb. I'm not putting
my hands on my head for nobody.
Then stand right where you are
and keep your hands in plain sight.
Can you do that, huh?
Yeah, I can do that.
Good.
I told this man to stay where he is
and keep his hands in plain sight.
This man better be related to you by blood
because this is fucking nuts.
I need this favor.
You can check the guy's name, his license.
He's got no priors, no warrants.
I need to let him go with a warning.
- What kind of fucking warning?
- A harsh warning.
Thank you.
You've been warned.
Do you understand me?
You want something from me?
'Cause I'm right here.
- Look, I'm trying to help you.
- l didn't ask for your help, did l?
Go home.
Yeah, that I can do.
Look at me.
You embarrass me.
You embarrass yourself.
Daddy's home!
- What's up?
- Give me my money!
- What? What money?
- Daddy!
- To pay for my store. Give me my money!
- Honey, stay inside. Elizabeth!
- You give me my money.
- Daddy.
I want my fucking money!
Give me that truck.
That's not my truck, bro.
- Daddy?
- Elizabeth!
Hey, hey, hey. You okay?
You know what? Hey, I got $50 . Here, here.
$50? You took everything!
Mommy?
I'm coming, I'm coming.
- He doesn't have it.
- Hasn't got what?
I have it. He doesn't have
the impenetrable cloak.
Lara, stay out of the street!
It's okay, Daddy.
- What? What?
- I'll protect you.
It's okay. Daddy's okay.
- It's a really good cloak.
- Good.
How's it going?
I sent her out for groceries,
and that was two hours ago, Carol.
Well, you know what? You are one to talk.
You go through, like,
six housekeepers a year.
I'm not snapping at you. I am angry.
Yes. At them! Yes!
At them, the police, at Rick, at Maria,
at the dry cleaners
who destroyed another blouse today,
at the gardener
who keeps over-watering the lawn.
l...
I just thought that...
Carol, I just thought that
I would wake up today
and I would feel better, you know?
But I was still mad. And I realized...
I realized that it had nothing to do
with my car being stolen.
I wake up like this every morning.
I am angry all the time,
and I don't know why.
Carol, I don't know why. And l...
Yeah, yeah, call me back.
Bye.
I really appreciate this.
No problem.
So how long you been out there tonight?
It's cold.
Hour, maybe.
Big surprise, huh?
Yeah, this ain't exactly
pick-up-a-brother territory.
True.
- So where you headed?
- Anywhere the other side of the hill.
I'm going to El Segundo.
El Segundo's cool.
- You've been there?
- Fuck, no.
That's some good music.
No, really. I'm starting to understand it.
Wrote me a country song myself
just yesterday.
I'll bet you did.
Whatever.
So what was going on
in the Valley tonight?
Iceskating.
Love the iceskating, man.
You know, when I was a kid,
I always wanted to be a goalie.
Come on.
What, you think that's funny or something?
I think you're having fun.
Yeah. Whatever.
- Something else funny?
- Oh, yeah.
Yeah? What's that?
People, man. People.
People like me.
No, no, no. I'm not laughing at you, man.
Yeah, I can see that.
Why don't you laugh outside?
Dawg, why are you getting
all bent out of shape?
I'm not getting bent, man.
I'm just pulling over.
Come on, man, keep driving.
I said I'm not laughing at you.
And I'm not telling you
to get the fuck out of my car.
Why you being a fucking jerk, man?
Just drive the car.
I've got a better idea. Get out now.
Fine. You want me to show you?
I'll show you.
Get your hands out of your pocket.
Put your hands where I can see them.
Who the fuck you think you're talking to?
You wanna see what's in my hands?
I'll show you what's in my fucking hands.
Oh, God.
Thank you, brother Merle, for that.
That was Merle Haggard here on KYHA,
the scene of country music here in LA.
It's a cold night, and it's getting colder.
And we're giving out tickets to the rodeo
coming to the Fairplex in Pomona,
so give us a call...
- Hey, you okay?
- I'm freezing.
Shit. I heard it might snow.
- Get out of here.
- That's what I heard.
- You got a smoke?
- No. I quit.
Yeah, me, too.
- What do you got?
- Dead kid.
Hey, Bob.
Choi Jin Gui! Choi Jin Gui!
- Choi Jin Gui! Choi Jin Gui!
- Do you speak English?
I am speaking English, you stupid cow!
My husband name Choi Jin Gui!
- Jin Gui!
- Ma'am!
Kim Lee.
I thought you were dead.
I called every hospital.
It's okay. I'm okay.
I went crazy speeding. I drove into a car.
Oh, my God. Are you okay?
Got into big fight with poor woman.
I called her names.
Oh, fine. I die from worry and you laugh.
Thank you for finding me.
- Will you do something for me?
- Anything.
Go to the locker.
No, next one.
ln my wallet there's a check.
Bring it here.
Oh, I get it. When I said
get me a black Lincoln Navigator,
you thought I said
get me a white piece-of-shit panel van.
Fine, it's fine.
Just give me whatever for it, man.
You should see this.
I'll take the van.
They're chained to the van.
So I'll take them, too.
You wanna buy these Chinamen?
Don't be ignorant.
They're Thai or Cambodian.
Entirely different kind of chinks.
- What the hell are you gonna do with them?
- Sell them. What the hell do you think?
I'll give you $500 apiece,
and you can keep the van.
Oh, no!
No! No!
This is Dorri.
My baby. My poor baby.
Mom.
I promise you. I promise
I'm gonna find out who did this, Mom.
Oh, I already know.
You did.
I asked you to find your brother,
but you were busy.
We weren't much good to you anymore,
were we?
You got things to do.
You go ahead. I'll sign the papers.
Mom, I wanna stay with...
I just wanna wait with my baby.
He came home. Did you know that?
My little boy.
When I was sleeping,
he brought me groceries.
It's the last thing he did.
Baba.
What happened?
What did you do?
Baba, what did you do?
I shoot a little girl.
What?
No, she's okay. She's...
She's... Here.
The gun shoot her,
but she's okay, Dorri. Nothing happened.
She's my farishte.
- What are you talking about, Daddy?
- My farishte, Dorri.
My angel.
She came to protect me.
To protect us.
You understand?
Take this. Please.
Take it.
Hey, hey.
Everything is okay, Dorri.
It's okay.
- Okay, Daddy.
- Okay.
Jean?
- Rick?
- Yeah. What's wrong?
I fell down the stairs.
- Are you all right?
- I tried calling you.
I couldn't get through to anyone. Not...
Not Kath, not Marge, not Julie, not...
I'm getting in the elevator. I'll be in my car.
I'll be home in 20 minutes.
It's okay. Maria drove me to emergency.
It's just a bad sprain.
Carol was the only one that was home
and she said she couldn't come get me
because she was getting a massage.
Well, that's because she's a bitch.
She's been my friend for 1 0 years.
All right, honey. Feel better.
I'll be there soon.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Miss Jean.
Would you like to sit up?
Here.
Good.
- Do you want to hear something funny?
- What, Mrs. Jean?
You're the best friend I've got.
Hi.
I love you.
All right.
Everybody out, man. You're free to go.
All right, come on.
Come on, now. This is America.
Time is money. Chop, chop.
Come on, y'all.
Come on.
That's $40 .
Buy everybody chop suey.
You understand?
Dopey fucking Chinaman.
Oh, my God!
What the hell is wrong with you people?
Don't talk to me,
unless you speak American!