♪ Come on, now, get down ♪
♪ 1989 ♪
♪ The number, another summer ♪
♪ Get down ♪
♪ Sound of the funky drummer ♪
♪ Music hittin' your heart ♪
♪ 'Cause I know you got soul ♪
♪ Brothers and sisters ♪
♪ Listen if you're missin', y'all ♪
♪ Swingin' while I'm singin' ♪
♪ Givin' what you're gettin' ♪
♪ Knowin' what I'm knowin' ♪
♪ While the black band's sweatin' ♪
♪ In the rhythm rhymes rollin' ♪
- ♪ Got to give us what we want ♪
- ♪ Ugh ♪
- ♪ Got to give us what we need ♪
- ♪ Hey ♪
♪ Our freedom of speech
Is freedom or death ♪
♪ We got to fight the powers that be ♪
♪ Fight the power ♪
♪ As the rhythm's designed
To bounce what counts ♪
♪ Is that the rhyme's
Designed to fill your mind ♪
♪ Now that you've realized
The pride's arrived ♪
♪ We've got to pump the stuff
That make you tough ♪
♪ From the heart it's a start ♪
♪ A work of art to revolutionize ♪
♪ Make a change, nothin's strange ♪
♪ People, people we are the same ♪
♪ No, we're not the same ♪
♪ 'Cause we don't know the game ♪
♪ What we need is awareness ♪
♪ We can't get careless ♪
♪ You say what is this? ♪
♪ My beloved, let's get down to business ♪
♪ Mental self-defense of fitness ♪
♪ Bum rush the show ♪
♪ You got to go for what you know ♪
♪ To make everybody see ♪
♪ In order to fight the powers that be ♪
♪ Fight the power ♪
♪ We got to fight the powers that be ♪
- ♪ Get down ♪
- ♪ Come on, get down ♪
- ♪ Come on, come on, come on ♪
- ♪ Get down ♪
- ♪ Come on, get down ♪
- ♪ Come on, come on, come on ♪
♪ Fight the power ♪
♪ We got to fight the powers that be ♪
♪ Elvis was a hero to most ♪
♪ But he never meant shit to me ♪
♪ Ya see, straight out racist ♪
♪ The sucker was simple and plain ♪
♪ Motherfuck him and John Wayne ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm black and I'm proud
I'm ready ♪
♪ I'm hyped, plus I'm amped ♪
♪ Most of my heroes
Don't appear on no stamp ♪
♪ Sample a look back you look ♪
♪ And find nothin' but rednecks ♪
♪ For 400 years if you check ♪
♪ Don't worry, be happy ♪
♪ Was a number one jam ♪
♪ Damn if I say it
You can slap me right here ♪
♪ Get it ♪
♪ Let's get this party started right ♪
- ♪ Right on ♪
- ♪ Come on ♪
♪ What we got to say ♪
♪ Power to the people, no delay ♪
♪ Make everybody see ♪
♪ In order to fight the powers that be ♪
♪ Fight the power ♪
♪ We got to fight the powers that be ♪
Wake up.
Wake up, wake up, wake up.
Up ya wake, up ya wake,
up ya wake, up ya wake.
This is Mister Señor Love Daddy.
Your voice of choice.
The world's only 12-hour
strong man on the air.
Here on WE-LOVE radio, 108 FM.
The last on your dial,
but first in your hearts,
and that's the truth, Ruth.
Here I am. Am I here?
Ya know it. It ya know.
This is Mister Señor Love Daddy
doing the nasty to ya ears,
ya ears to the nasty.
I's only play da platters dat matter
the matters dey platter,
and that's the truth, Ruth.
From the heart of Bed-Stuy,
you're listening to WE-LOVE radio.
Doing the ying and the yang,
the hip and the hop,
the stupid fresh thing,
the flippity-flop.
I have today's forecast for you.
Hot! Sss!
The color for today is black.
That's right, black.
So you can absorb some of these rays
and save that heat for winter.
So you wanna get on out there,
wear that black and be involved.
Also today's temperature's
gonna rise up over 100 degrees.
So that's a Jheri-curl alert.
That's right, Jheri-curl alert.
If you have a Jheri-curl,
stay in the house
or you'll end up with a permanent plastic
helmet on your head forever.
All right, we're going to
say hello to Mister and Missus,
that's Mister and Missus.
And happy birthday to Big Red,
Little Red
and Miss Annie Mae,
who's 100 today.
If you're careful
and stay out of this heat,
you might live to be that old yourself.
There's also a water shortage,
so keep those showers down to one minute.
Two minutes
if you're showering with a friend.
- You better get on out there.
- Oh, damn!
It is hot!
You'll get that pink slip.
So get up, get up, get up
and get on out there!
That's what I'm talking about.
We don't want to see
anybody losing their jobs
'cause ain't nobody
got no money as it is.
All right.
Now we're going to talk about it.
The streets are coming alive.
We're going to rock 'n' roll...
Good m-m-morning.
M-M-My name is Smiley.
This is M-M-M-M-Malcolm... X.
And this is M-M-M-M-Martin K-K-King.
Now, th-they are d-d-dead.
But w-we still h-h-have to f-f-f-fight
a-against ap-apartheid.
10, 15, 20, 30, 40, 50, 60, 70, 80, 100.
20, 40, 60, shit!
80... 300.
20, 40, 60, 80... Wait, that's 300.
300, 350, 450... cash dollar bills.
Mookie. Why are you always
bothering me when I'm sleeping...
Wake up, wake up.
Stop breathing down my neck!
Why should I wake up, Mookie?
It's gonna be hot today, Jade.
Saturday's the only day
I get to sleep late.
Damn.
Stop, Mookie. That's not funny.
Why don't you leave me alone
when I'm sleeping?
What's the matter? You don't love
your brother Mookie anymore?
I loves you, Jade.
I'll get a lock
and keep your ass out of here, Mookie.
Why don't you go to work, man,
and leave me alone for once?
Later. Got to get paid.
Yeah, brush your teeth.
I brushed my teeth.
Your breath stinks.
It's your upper lip.
What's up, there, Sal?
How you doin' there, boy?
Man, I got to get me
a Cadillac like that.
I'm gonna get me a car just like that.
Big old Cadillac.
Oh, it's hot.
Sonny, how's the vegetables, huh?
Good morning, Sal, Pino, Vito.
Pop, you talk to that air-condition guy?
I been calling him all week.
He won't come around
unless he has a police escort.
Pino, get a broom and sweep up front.
Vito, get a broom and sweep out front.
- Huh?
- Get a broom and sweep out front.
What?
Get a broom and sweep out front!
See, Pop?
It's just what I was telling you.
Every time you tell Pino what to do,
he tells me to do
what you told him what to do.
He's brain-dead, Pop, for years.
- Both of you, shut up.
- Tell Pino!
What, am I talking to myself, here?
Is that what I'm doing?
I didn't want to come to work anyway.
I hate this friggin' place.
I detest it like a sickness.
You-You detest this place
like a sickness?
That's, like, really hate, you know?
That's hate.
- I didn't say that.
- Oh, you didn't say that?
What, I just heard it.
Am I going crazy?
Did I just hear that, Vito?
I mean, do you think you can do better?
No, I didn't think so.
You see, Pino,
this is a respectable business,
and there's nothing wrong with that.
If there's something wrong with that,
I want you to tell me.
You... No, you can tell me right now.
- Is there something wrong with that?
- No.
All right. There's nothing wrong.
All right? Okay?
Look, do me a favor.
- Get a broom and sweep up.
- Tell Vito.
What are you, deaf or what?
Pop asked you.
I'm going to kill somebody today.
- I can't believe it, you know?
- What?
That you like her.
- I don't like her.
- Yeah?
Yeah, I don't like her.
Hell no.
- Hey.
- Hi, Mookie.
Mookie.
Hey, Mook.
Mornin', Mookie.
Morning, Miss Mother Sister.
Now Mookie, don't work too hard today.
The man says it's going to be hot
as the devil.
I don't want you falling out
from the heat, you hear me, son?
- I hear you, Mother Sister. I hear you.
- Good.
- All right.
- I'll be watching you, son.
Mother Sister always watches.
Mookie...
You're late again.
You live up the block, what?
Your Cadillac broke?
Hello, Sal, Vito.
Yo, Mook. What up?
Just coolin'.
You're still late.
Why don't you Relax, Pino?
Take it easy. You'll live longer.
Here, take the broom.
The front needs sweeping.
Wait a minute. I just got here.
You sweep.
I bet you Sal asked you first anyway.
That's right.
Vito, stop that.
You know, just fuck that shit.
I deliver pizzas.
- That's what I get paid for.
- You get paid to do what we say.
What we say? Did you hear Sal?
I didn't hear Sal say nothing.
- Who's working for who, huh?
- Shh.
Come on in, Mayor.
Morning, gentlemen.
Pino, Mookie, Vito, Sal.
- How are you?
- Ooh-whee.
It's gonna be a scorcher today.
That's for sure.
Need any work done 'round here?
Daddy...
Why don't you leave him alone?
Huh?
He's a good man.
Leave him alone.
Choose your weapon, Mayor.
You dropped something, Mayor.
You are going to have
the cleanest sidewalk in Brooklyn.
Clean as the Board of Health.
Ha!
All right, Mayor.
Pop, I don't believe this shit.
You running welfare or something?
Every day you give this azupep
a dollar.
- What's azupep? What's this azupep shit?
- Are you Italian? Do you know azupep?
The Mayor ain't no azupep.
Every day you give this azupep a dollar
for sweeping our sidewalk.
What do we pay Mookie for, huh?
He don't even work.
I work harder than him,
and I'm your own son.
Pino, let's see you carry
six large pies up six flights of stairs,
no elevator either and shit.
- Why don't you both shut up?
- Yeah, tell 'em, Pop.
And why don't you shut up,
too, Vito?
- Me and you are gonna have a talk.
- Aw, says who?
- Says who?
- Says me.
- Who are you?
Hey, hey!
Now what did I just say?
Don't start that
"Mookie don't work" shit, all right?
- Yo, Ahmad!
- I coulda done that.
Man, shut up. Yo, Ahmad!
Shit. Look, stop.
Look, Punchy, you want to do
any more screaming, be my guest.
'Cause I'm too through.
Yo, who's out here yelling my name?
- Well, Punchy told me to.
- Punchy told me to.
Don't listen to this knothead.
It'll get you in trouble, girl.
Heard that, Punchy.
- Yo, Ella? Ella?
- What?
You got a brain, right?
Use it.
Peace, y'all.
- Peace, Radio Raheem.
- Peace, man.
You the man.
I'm just visiting.
- It's your world, G.
- For real, in a big motherfuckin' way.
Yo, that boy's livin' very large.
Even walks in stereo.
Yo, P.E.'s in full effect, boy!
Radio Raheem like a motherfucker.
Radio Raheem.
Blastin' that big box.
Cold rockin' the scene.
Where's the Miller High Life?
Where is the Miller High Life?
No more High Life.
You look what we have and buy.
No more High Life?
What kind of a joint is this?
How come no more High Life?
Look, doctor, this ain't Korea or China
or wherever you come from.
You get some Miller High Life
in this fuckin' joint.
You buy another beer.
Da Mayor...
don't drink this Lite shit.
Tastes like cold pot liquor.
All right, all right.
But you're askin' a lot
to make a man change his beer.
You askin' lot, doctor.
Hey! You old drunk!
What did I tell you about drinkin'
in front of my stoop?
Move on.
You're blockin' my view.
You are ugly enough.
Don't stare at me.
The evil eye doesn't work on me.
Mother Sister,
you been talkin' about me for 18 years.
- What I ever done to you?
- You a drunk fool.
Besides that?
The Mayor don't bother nobody,
And nobody don't bother the Mayor
but you.
The Mayor just tend to his own business.
I love everybody.
- I even love you.
- Hold your tongue!
You don't have that much love.
One day, you gonna be nice to me.
We may both be dead and buried,
but you gonna be nice.
At least civil.
I told you.
I'm not going to babysit for you,
and that's it!
What are you talking about?
Yesterday you said
you were gonna do it.
Now today you're changing your mind?
No, I'm not changing...
Get off of me, Mami, please!
It's, like, I do everything for you,
but you can't do shit for me!
Yeah, right.
Right, Mami.
No, it's not like that, Mami.
Uh-huh. I can do everything for you, Mami,
but you won't do shit for me, right?
Stop it!
That lady makes me sick!
Your father makes me sick, too.
Everybody makes me sick.
Shit.
Your father ain't no real father.
He's a bum.
Chump change, to-the-curb,
pulling no major pub, bum!
Mike.
Fuck Mike Tyson!
Mike Tyson ain't shit.
I remember when he mugged that woman
right there on Lexington.
- I remember that shit.
- And you're going to tell him that?
I'll tell him that. I ain't...
Fuck Mike Tyson!
- To his face?
- You goddamn right!
Mike Tyson will knock
your goddamn eye out.
- I ain't scared of Mike Tyson.
- You talk shit now.
- I'll drop him like a bad habit.
- ML, you hear that?
- Yeah, sure. Go ahead.
- Yeah, boy.
If Tyson dream about whippin' my ass,
he better wake up and apologize.
Well, gentlemen,
the way I see it...
if this hot weather continues,
it's going to melt the polar caps
and the whole wide world.
And all those parts
that ain't water already
will surely be flooded.
You dumb ass, simple motherfucker!
Now, where you read that shit, eh?
The polar caps.
- Oh.
- Don't worry about it.
And when it happens,
and I'm in my boat,
and you black asses are drowning,
don't call for me
to throw you no rope,
- no lifesaver, or no nothing.
- No nothing.
You fool,
you 30 cent away from a quarter.
How the fuck you gonna get a boat?
Hey, yeah, boy.
Don't worry about it.
Goddamn right,
don't worry about it.
Look at you.
You're raggedy as a roach,
eat the holes out of doughnuts.
Raggedy motherfucker!
- Shit, don't worry about it.
- I'm in good shape, eh?
I'm in good shape.
I'll be back on my feet soon enough.
Not in them raggedy-ass shoes!
Look at you.
Shoes so run over,
he gotta lay down to put 'em on.
- So, ML, ML, ML, tell me.
- Mm-hmm.
So when is all this goddamn ice
supposed to melt?
Hello. Sal's Pizza.
Yep.
Meatball hero, eggplant Parmesan.
You got it.
Yeah, we deliver.
Of course, we deliver.
All right. Where is that?
You gonna pay now
or you gonna pay on layaway?
How much?
You been coming here at least
three times a day.
What are you, a retard?
It's $1.50.
Yo Sal, put some cheese
on that motherfucker, man.
Extra cheese is $2.00.
- $2.00?
- Yeah, $2.00.
Hey, you can forget that shit.
Yeah.
What...
Damn, Sal, you're cheap, man.
...right, and he called him a bum.
- A bum?
- I don't think he was a bum.
He just wasn't right,
and he wasn't compassionate.
- As Sal would say...
- I need passion in my life.
As Sal would say,
he's a mamaluke.
He's a mamaluke!
Yeah, right.
Yo, Mook!
- Mookie!
- What?
How come you got
no brothers up on the wall?
Man, ask Sal, all right?
Hey, Sal, how come you got
no brothers up on the wall here?
You want brothers on the wall?
Get your own place.
You can do what you wanna do.
You can put your brothers and uncles,
nieces and nephews,
your stepfather, stepmother,
whoever you want, you see?
But this is my pizzeria.
American-Italians on the wall only.
- Take it easy, Pop.
- And you...
Hey, don't start with me today.
What?
Yeah, that might be fine, Sal,
but you own this.
Rarely do I see
any American-Italians eating in here.
All I see is black folks.
So since we spend much money here,
we do have some say.
Boop.
You lookin' for trouble?
Are you a troublemaker?
Is that what you are?
- You making trouble?
- Yeah, I'm a troublemaker.
I'm making trouble.
You're a real ball-breaker.
Relax. You're always coming in here
looking for trouble, aren't you?
Suppose I busted your head.
How would you...
Oh, Mookie, you want to get
your friend out of here?
What, you gonna kick me out now?
You gonna kick me out?
No, I'm not kicking you out.
You're kicking yourself out.
What? Look, we want some brothers
up on the wall...
You know, Malcolm X, Nelson Mandela,
you know, Michael Jordan!
Tomorrow!
Come on, Mookie.
Get him out. All right?
- I'm trying to get him out!
- Yo, I paid for this.
Take your slice.
I know you paid for it. Let's go.
Yeah, all right, you're kicking me out.
Gonna beat me in the head.
- Gonna kick me out.
- Come on. Let's go.
Yeah, okay. Yeah, all right.
Look, I paid for my...
- Look, boycott Sal's! Boycott Sal's.
- Go!
I got your boycott swinging.
Boycott Sal's.
Yo, I paid...
What you laughin' at?
Mookie, I paid for my slice, man.
Yo, man, come on.
I spend much money in there!
- What are you trying to do?
- What am I trying to do?
- I want brothers up on the wall.
I gotta work here, man.
You're fucking my shit up, man.
And this is between me and Sal, man.
- You're fucking me up.
- I ain't trying to fuck you up, Mook.
You know, I ain't trying to fuck you.
I'm sorry.
You're sorry?
Look, come back in a week,
it'll be squashed, all right?
- A week?
- A week.
- Yeah. Yeah.
- All right?
- Bet. Bet.
- Bet.
Pizza.
Mook...
Stay black!
I mean, this guy's your friend,
right?
If I'm wrong, tell me I'm wrong.
Is he your friend?
- He's my friend.
- Okay, if he don't behave,
I don't want him in here anymore.
He's out.
I can't do nothing with him, Sal.
- You talk some brother talk to him.
- Brother talk?
Look, people are free to do
the hell whatever they want to do.
What free?
What the hell are you talking about? Free?
Free? There's no free here.
I'm the boss.
No freedom. I'm the boss.
You want freedom?
There, that's free.
You take an order, and you take it out.
He's got an order there for you.
Come on, let's go, move.
Come on! Let's go to work here!
- What are you laughing at?
- You're standing here doing nothing.
Him...
You're afraid of the goddamn oven.
- Hit the oven!
- Is this the address?
That's the address.
"Is that the address?"
Is that what he just asked me?
Is that the address?
Mookie.
Come here, doctor.
- Mayor, I got to go. I'm working.
- Come here, doctor.
This is the Mayor talking.
All right. All right.
- Doctor?
- Come on, what? What?
Always do the right thing.
- That's it?
- That's it.
I got it. I'm gone.
M-M-Mookie...
How you doin', Smiley?
P-P-Pay...
- t-two d-d-dollars.
- The other one, the other one.
- T-Two d-d-dollars.
- The other one, Smiley.
One-One d-dollar.
That one.
Tonight, when I get paid.
When... When you get p-p...
- Bye, M-Mookie.
- Bye, Smiley!
M-M-M-M-Malcolm.
M-M-M-M-Martin.
Shit.
Seen your brother this morning.
Yeah, on his way to work, I hope.
This might take a little bit of time,
Mother Sister.
I got nowhere to go.
We haven't had a good sit-down
for a long while.
Mm.
Tender-headed runs in my family.
Are you tender-headed?
Yeah. Me, too.
I don't fool with it.
That's why only you can touch it.
Ouch!
I'm sorry, Mother Sister.
The comb got caught.
Be gentle, child.
Mother Sister's an old woman.
Yes, Mother Sister.
Ooh-whee!
I didn't know
you had such beautiful hair.
Fool, there's a lot in this world
you don't know.
I'm not stopping.
I'm on my way.
Mother Sister,
why are you so cruel to Da Mayor?
It isn't right.
I ain't studying no Mayor.
He reminds me
of my least favorite peoples,
my tenant and my ex-husband.
Goddamn! Bless his soul.
Whew!
♪ Ooh yeah ♪
♪ All right ♪
♪ You can't stand it ♪
♪ I know you can't stand it ♪
♪ You can't stand the heat ♪
♪ Is the weather ♪
♪ I know the times
Is just screwin' up your mind ♪
♪ But we must stick together ♪
What's up, fellas?
♪ No work for you for miles around ♪
♪ The family's on the verge
Of breakin' down ♪
♪ The rent is due ♪
♪ The landlord makin' threats ♪
♪ The pressure's buildin' up ♪
♪ The more you sweat ♪
♪ I know you can't stand it ♪
♪ You can't stand it ♪
♪ You can't stand the heat ♪
Get your ass wet!
Get your ass wet.
♪ You can't stand the heat ♪
♪ You're burning ♪
♪ I know it's hot
There's no need to blow your top ♪
What are you doing?
Ahmad, put me down, man!
Oh, my God!
Did you see that, man?
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
It's Radio. Radio, man.
Hey, what's up, Radio?
What's up Radio?
Don't! Stop! Stop!
Yo! Don't be fucking
with the water now.
Oh, man, go ahead, man.
Go ahead, you got it!
There's going to be
a lot of fucking trouble
if you get this car wet.
Ain't nobody fucking around, man.
Why don't you just go ahead?
This is an antique there, hotshot.
Man, go ahead!
It's a what?
Hey, man, I'm...
I'm serious, man!
All right.
Okay, you won't get wet, man.
Yeah, well, make sure I don't.
- Go ahead!
- You're not gonna...
- Just hurry up, man. Damn.
- Drive the car!
All right, I'm driving it.
You ain't got no business
in this neighborhood, anyway!
- Get out! Get out, motherfucker!
- Come on, let's go!
- Hey, fuck you back!
- Turn the fucking water. Turn the water!
Go!
Those son of a bitches!
They got me fucking soaked!
Officer! Officer, wait a minute.
Hold it!
I want an arrest made right now!
- Right now!
- What's the matter?
- I'm fuckin' soaked!
- Calm down.
Would you please calm down, sir?
Tell us what happened.
Two black kids,
they soaked me with the fire hydrant.
They ruined my car! Look!
This is an antique!
- They got me fuckin' soaked!
- So where are they?
Where are they?
Brilliant fucking question!
- Where are they?
- They ran away!
Where do you think they are?
- Do you wish to file a complaint, sir?
- Yeah, I want to file a complaint.
I want 'em locked under the fucking jail.
Hey, Marco,
I'm gonna turn off the water, okay?
- Yeah.
- Where you going? Where's he going?
Did you happen to catch the name
of the suspect, sir?
Officer,
what the fuck are you doing?
- Fuck that hydrant.
- Just calm down.
- Calm down, my ass!
- Did you happen to catch the name?
Fuck you, their names!
Moe and Joe!
What do I know their names?
Moe and Joe what, sir?
Moe and Joe what?
Moe and Joe Black.
How's that?
They're brothers, sir?
Yeah, they're brothers.
Yeah, they're fucking brothers.
This hydrant
better not come back on again,
or there's going to be hell to pay!
Come answer to me, goddamn it!
Ask him. He knows.
He's a witness.
He saw the whole fucking thing!
Go on, man.
Tell him what happened.
Would you let us do
the questioning, sir?
Fucking bullshit.
- You know anything about this?
- Who were the punks?
Doctors, those that'll tell don't know,
and those that know won't tell.
- What the fuck is that? Voodoo shit?
- Wise guy.
Hey, Mayor don't know nothin',
all right?
Hey! He's leaving?
Keep this hydrant off.
Huh?
You wanna swim?
Go to Coney Island.
Ho, I'm talking to you!
He's leaving? What about me?
- What about you?
- I suggest you get to your car quick,
before these people start
to strip it clean.
Have a nice day, sir.
He left there about a half hour ago?
No, no problem. Thank you.
Yeah, half hour, right.
Mookie left...
Where the hell you been, Mookie?
I got a business to run, okay?
Run it then, all right?
- Take that to the radio station.
- To Love Daddy?
Yeah, Love Daddy.
Hey, Pop, I'm going
to go with Mookie, okay?
Yeah. You make sure
Mookie don't jerk around.
- Wait up, Mook!
- Oh, where you going?
You ain't going anywhere.
- Where the hell you going?
- How you doing?
Vito, I know Pino's your brother and shit,
but you should kick his ass.
The next time he touches you,
you should kick his ass.
- Whoa, whoa!
- The next time he hits you, fuck him up!
Whoa! Whoa!
Hey, yo, Mook.
I mean, I appreciate this concern,
and all,
but I don't think
it's any of your business, really.
I know it's none of my business,
but you need to kick his ass.
Smiley, not now.
If I had a brother like him,
we'd be fighting all the time.
- Look, first of all...
- Smiley!
First of all, Mook,
you don't got a brother like him.
Smiley, get out of here!
First of all,
you don't got a brother like him.
If you did, you wouldn't know
what to do with him
because you never had
a brother like him.
He's my brother.
I'm not going to hit him.
- I got a sister.
- You never clocked your sister.
- But I got a sister.
- Does she bug you like Pino bugs me?
Yeah, but you're not supposed to hit
a girl like you hit a guy.
- All right.
- Just fuck your brother up one time.
It'll be over with, we'll be out of
this fucking conversation, all right?
You think it might do some good?
Yes, all right?
A lot of good.
Let's give...
Love Daddy!
Peoples, my stomach's been grumbling,
but help has arrived.
My main man Mookie has saved the day!
Straight from Sal's Famous Pizzeria
up the block.
Step up to the mike, Mookie.
Come on. Come on!
Don't be shy.
Mmm, this smells good.
Go ahead.
This is your Love Daddy talking,
Starvin' like Marvin.
Say something to the people.
All right, Love Daddy.
I'd like to dedicate this record
with all my heart and soul...
to Tina.
All right!
Let me put this song on
while I go to work
on this chicken parmigiana hero
with extra cheese
and extra s-sauce.
Yo, Stevie, man.
Chill, man.
- Shut up, man. I'm trying to read.
- Have some fucking respect, huh?
- It's just a bad dream, man.
- What'd you hit me in the neck for?
It's just a bad dream, man.
Yo, man, lower that, man!
- I want to listen to my salsa music!
- Chill! Chill! Chill!
You think you got it like that, bro?
¿Chocolate?
Let's go, motherfucker!
Turn it up, Stevie, baby!
- Blow it, man, blow it!
- Yeah, blow it away!
Turn it up, Stevie!
- Yeah, Yeah!
- Turn up the bongos!
Oh, yeah!
Salsa!
- Yo, Steve! Put it up louder, Steve.
- Yeah, man!
Pendejo!
Yeah, what's up?
You got it, bro.
Hey, pendejo!
Come on, Steve, man.
You're dead, choco-man.
He's a punk anyway, man.
Yo, pendejo!
What's up?
He's a sucker, man. He's a punk.
He's a sucker, man.
- See that game last night?
- Uh-huh. I saw it.
Best pitcher in the game...
Dwight Gooden.
- I knew you were gonna bring that up.
- Who's better?
You know Roger Clemens is better.
Clemens sucks, man.
He can't carry Dwight's jock.
- Oh, man. How can you say...
- Dwight's best in the game.
- Who won consecutive Cy Young Awards?
- What's up, Buggin' Out?
- Got you.
- What's happening?
- You the man.
- No, you the man.
No, you the man.
- No, I'm a struggling black man
trying to keep my dick hard
in a cruel and harsh world.
Yo, hey, what's up
with the white boy?
Buggin' Out, don't start no shit,
all right?
Vito's down.
Vito's down, all right?
- All right?
- Yeah, right.
- Vito's down.
- Yeah.
Phew.
Yo!
Damn.
Yeah?
You almost knocked me down.
Man, the word is, "Excuse me."
- Oh, excuse me. I'm sorry.
- Not onlyjust knocked me down,
you stepped on my brand-new
white Air Jordans I just bought.
And that's all you can say is,
"Excuse me?"
- What, you're serious?
- Yeah, I'm serious.
- I'll fuck you up quick two times!
- Two times!
Who told you to step
on my sneakers?
Who told you
to walk on my side of the block?
- Who told you to be in my neighborhood?
- I own this brownstone.
Who told you to buy a brownstone
on my block, in my neighborhood
on my side of the street?
What do you want to live
in a black neighborhood for, anyway, man?
- Motherfuck gentrification.
- Well?
As I understand it,
this is a free country.
- A man can live wherever he wants.
- Free country.
Free country?
Man, I should fuck you up for saying
that stupid shit alone!
Yo, man,
your Jordans are fucked up!
Damn, man. You might
as well throw them shits out.
Them shits is broke!
They looked good before
he messed them up.
He did this shit on purpose, man.
He was even talking about your mama.
I heard that shit, too.
Man, they used to be so fine!
- Yo, man, how much you pay for 'em?
- A hundred bucks!
- American dollars.
- $108 with tax.
- I'd give him 100 headaches.
- Look, you're lucky
the black man has a loving heart.
Next time you see me coming,
you cross the street.
- I'm out of here.
- Yo, man, break his feet!
- Damn, my brand-new Jordans!
- Take his bike!
I should make you
buy me another pair!
- Black Panther, whip his ass!
- Take his bike!
- Man, kick his ass!
- You're lucky I'm a righteous black man!
Otherwise, you'd be
in serious trouble, man! Serious!
- Fuck him up!
- Man, let's fuck him up.
Man, why don't you
move back to Massachusetts?
I was born in Brooklyn.
Get outta here!
I should send Vito
with you all the time.
Yeah. No more 90-minute deliveries
around the corner.
Pino, I work hard like
everybody else in here, all right?
You know that's true, Pino.
Vito, come here.
Come here.
What's going on between you two?
You guys boyfriend and girlfriend
or something? Something I don't know?
- What'd we just talk about?
- What?
- What did we just talk about?
- What are you talking about?
- Smack him.
- Hey! Hey!
Any smacking around here
is gonna be done by me.
You gonna listen to this shagamay,
listen to him tell you to smack me,
your older brother?
Just remember who you are,
all right?
Your name is Vito Frangione,
not Vito Muhammad.
Huh?
I would love for you
to stay out of my business.
Stop putting these thoughts
into my brother's head, okay?
Look, I don't play
that Muhammad shit, all right?
What Muhammad shit?
Look...
Don't fuck me, all right?
Oh, man.
Fuck, man.
I hate this place.
What a waste.
As I was saying before we were
so rudely interrupted
- by New York City's finest...
- What was you saying?
The motherfucker wasn't saying shit.
Yeah. Look at that.
Look at what?
It's a goddamn shame.
What's a goddamn shame?
- Sweet Dick Willie.
- That's my name.
Goddamn, man,
do I have to spell it out?
Come on, man,
make it plain.
Okay, but listen up.
I'm going to break it down.
Let it be broke, motherfucker.
- Can you dig it?
- It's dug.
Look at those Korean motherfuckers
across the street.
I bet you they haven't been
off the boat a year
before they opened up
their own place.
That's right, man.
It's been about a year.
A motherfuckin' year
off the motherfuckin' boat,
and they already got a business
in our neighborhood.
A good business...
occupying a building
that had been boarded up
for longer than I care to remember,
and I've been here a long time.
- Yeah, he been here a long time.
- Hey, boy.
And now, for the life of me...
You know,
I can't figure this out.
Either them Korean motherfuckers
are geniuses...
or you black asses are
just plain dumb.
Fuck you.
It's got to be because we're black.
Ain't no other explanation.
No, no, I know, man.
You know it's true.
Ain't they always trying
to keep the black man
to be about shit!
Oh, oh!
You motherfuckers hold that shit down.
I'm tired of that old excuse.
I'm tired of hearing that shit.
- Shit.
- You know, I tell you. I swear, man,
I will be one happy fool
when we open our own business
right here in our neighborhood.
I swear to God.
I will be first in line to spend
- what little money I got.
- I'll be right there with you, man.
You motherfuckers are always talking
that old Keith Sweat shit...
"I'm gonna do this,
I'm gonna do that."
You ain't gonna do a goddamn thing
but sit your monkey ass on this corner.
Hey, ML,
when you gonna get your business?
Huh?
Yeah, just like I thought.
You ain't going to do
a goddamn thing.
But I'll tell you what I'm gonna do.
Hear me?
I'm gonna go there and give them
Koreans more of my money.
Fuck outta my way, goddamn.
It's Miller time, motherfuckers.
Old moose head fuckers
telling me what to do.
And Coconut,
you got a lot of damn nerve.
You got off the boat, too.
Hell, leave me alone. Shoot.
Hey, Kung Fu! Come on.
Give me one of them damn beers, damn it.
- What? No more free beer.
- Get your ass in there and serve me some.
- No more free beer.
- Don't be pushing on me, baby.
- Hey, man, no more free beer.
- I'll drop you.
- Don't start no shit with me.
- Mr. Sweet Dick.
That's right.
Sweet Dick Willie is my name.
That's my name.
It's a motherfuckin' shame.
Man, ain't that a bitch?
- Hey, doctor. What's your name?
- Eddie.
- How old are you?
- Ten.
Question: What makes Sammy run?
- I said my name is Eddie.
- What makes Sammy run?
- My name is Eddie Lovell.
- Relax.
Eddie,
I want you to go to the store for me.
Question: How much is it gonna cost?
How am I supposed to know
how much it's gonna cost
if I don't even know
what I'm buying?
Eddie, you're too smart
for your own britches.
Now listen to me. How much do you want
to go to the corner store for Da Mayor?
- Fifty cents.
- You got a deal. Here.
I want you to get me a quart of beer.
Miller High Life.
Anybody bother you, say it's
for your bedridden, old granddaddy.
Now, go on. Go!
What is wrong with him, man?
He ain't be giving nobody no money.
- Leave the man alone.
- Look at this here, man.
- This is nice, man.
- You need to cut this shit out.
Man, who told you
you were the mayor of this block?
Shit, he's self-appointed.
- Man, leave the man alone. Damn.
- Shut up!
- Yeah, yeah, look, look, look.
- Damn.
- Y'all leave me the hell alone.
- Ah, man.
I ain't going out like that, man.
You walk up and down this block
like you own it.
For real, His Honor.
You're so old,
you're like a fossil.
Yo, man, you're a bum, man.
You're an old drunk zero, man.
Now what do you got to say
for yourself?
What you know about me?
Can't even pee straight,
nary a one of you.
What you know about anything?
Unless you...
Unless you done stood
in the door...
and listened to your five hungry children
crying for bread.
And you can't do
a damn thing about it.
Your woman standing there...
You can't even look her in the eye.
Unless you done that, you don't know me,
my pain, my hurt, my feelings.
- You don't know shit!
- Oh, man!
- Let the old man finish.
- Don't call me bum.
Don't call me a drunk.
Y'all ain't got the sense
that God give a billy goat!
Don't call me nothing!
It's disrespectful.
I know your mamas and your papas
raised you better.
Yo, man, I hope you finished
your little soliloquy, man,
'cause first of all,
I been peeing straight for years.
You understand what I'm saying?
And you're right.
I wouldn't stand in the doorway
listening to my five children go hungry.
I'd be out getting a job,
doing something, anything,
to put food in their mouths.
And you're right.
I don't wanna know your pain.
I don't care to know your pain.
You're the one that put yourself
in this situation, man.
Every day... Every day, I see you walk up
and down this block, inebriated.
- Chill, man.
- Never sober!
- He's an old man.
- But that's what D-A stands for.
"Da" Mayor... drunk ass.
Man, come on!
- Fuck that! This man's getting me mad!
- Ahmad, Ahmad!
He don't get no respect! He ain't never
gonna get respect here, boy!
How you gonna tell me
how my parents raised me?
- I respect those who respect themselves!
- Ahmad! Come on, man!
He's not gonna respect himself as someone
who drinks like a fuckin' fool!
Tina, I know
I haven't seen you in four days.
- I'm a working man.
- Uh, that's really nice,
but you know, I work, too,
and I seem to make time.
What do you want me to do, huh?
I want you to spend some time
with me and Hector!
I want you to try
and make this relationship work.
If not, I'd rather not be bothered
with your ass.
- Mookie, you are too, too tired.
- All right, all right. Damn.
I'll be over sometime today.
You always say later!
Later, say, if I get off work.
Bring some ice cream.
I'm burning up.
Mookie, do you love me?
- Do I love you?
- Mookie, get off the phone!
Be off in a second, all right, Sal?
Do I love you?
I dedicated a record
on Love Daddy's show to you.
So what?
How's anybody going to call in,
Mookie?
- All right!
- My God, you probably wasted...
You know, if that ain't love,
you're crazy.
Are you deaf or what?
Pino, I'm talking on the phone.
I can see that.
Tina, I gotta go.
Yeah, Pino's an asshole.
I'll see you later today.
Later!
Everybody happy?
Sal's Famous.
- Yeah, delivery.
- Yeah. Yeah, okay.
- You got two large anchovy and pepperoni.
- Hurry up.
Okay. Just hold on one second.
See, Daddy?
Mookie's fucking talking on the phone,
people are trying to call in orders.
He's making us lose business.
Mookie!
Twenty minutes.
How come niggers are so stupid?
If you see a nigger,
kick his ass.
Fuck you,
and stay off the phone.
Hey, Mookie.
Forget about it.
Can I talk to you for a second?
What?
Pino, who's your
favorite basketball player?
Magic Johnson.
- Who's your favorite movie star?
- Eddie Murphy.
Who's your favorite rock star?
Prince. You're a Prince freak.
- Boss. Bruce.
- Prince.
Bruce.
Pino, all you talk about is
nigger this and nigger that.
And all your favorite people
are so-called niggers.
It's different.
Magic, Eddie, Prince...
are not niggers.
I mean, they're not black.
I mean...
Let me explain myself.
They're...
They're not really black.
I mean, they're black,
but they're not really black.
They're more than black.
It's different.
- It's different?
- Yeah. To me, it's different.
Pino, deep down inside,
I think you wish you were black.
Get the fuck out of here.
Laugh if you want to. You know,
your hair is kinkier than mine.
What does that mean?
And you know what they say
about dark Italians.
You know,
I been listening and reading...
- You been reading now?
- I read.
I've been reading about your leaders.
Reverend Al "Mister 'Do" Sharpton.
Jesse. "Keep hope alive."
- That's fucked up.
- "Keep hope alive."
Hey, that's fucked.
Don't talk about Jesse.
And even the other guy,
what's his name?
Faraman, Fairakan...
Minister Farrakhan.
Right. Sorry.
Anyway, Minister Farrakhan
always talks about the so-called day
when the black man will rise.
"We will one day..."
What does he say?
"We will one day rule the Earth
as we did in our glorious past."
- Yeah, that's right.
- What past you talkin' about?
I mean, what did I miss?
We started civilization.
Man, keep dreaming, man.
Then you woke up!
Pino, fuck you. Fuck your fucking pizza,
and fuck Frank Sinatra.
Yeah? Well, fuck you, too,
and fuck Michael Jackson.
You dago, wop, guinea,
garlic-breath, pizza-slinging,
spaghetti-bending, Vic Damone,
Perry Como,
Luciano Pavarotti, solo mio,
non-singing motherfucker.
You gold-teeth, gold-chain-wearing,
fried-chicken
and biscuit-eating monkey,
ape, baboon, big thigh,
fast-running,
high-jumping, spear-chucking,
360-degree basketball-dunking,
titsoon, spade, mulignan.
Take your fucking piece of pizza
and go the fuck back to Africa.
You little slanty-eyed,
me-no-speaky-American,
own every fruit and vegetable stand
in New York,
bullshit Reverend Sun Myung Moon,
Summer Olympic '88,
Korean kick-boxing, son-of-a-bitch.
You Goya bean-eating, 15-in-a-car,
30-in-an-apartment,
pointy shoes, red-wearing,
menudo, mira mira,
Puerto Rican cocksucker.
Yeah, you!
It's cheap.
I got good price for you,
Mayor Koch, "How I'm doing?"
Chocolate-egg-cream drinking,
bagel-and-lox, B'nai B'rith,
Jew asshole.
Yo! Hold up! Time out!
Time out!
Y'all, take a chill!
Ya need to cool that shit out!
And that's the double truth, Ruth!
Sal, can you do me a favor?
That depends, Mookie.
Can you pay me now?
I can't do that.
Sal, just this once.
Can't you do me a solid, man?
No. Tonight when we close.
Sal, I want to get paid now.
Look, you know you get paid tonight
when we close.
All right? We're still open.
All right, if I pay you now,
I won't see you tonight.
That's a bet.
Yeah, that's a bet, huh.
I'm going to remember that, Sal.
You got to do what you got to do,
you know?
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- I'm gonna remember that.
- I want you to remember that.
Please do me a favor, huh, Mook?
Remember that.
Come on, Sal.
I can't.
Radio Raheem!
Mook.
What's happening?
- It's your world.
- Where you headed to?
I'm going to get a slice.
- You going down to Sal's?
- Word.
I gotta make a few deliveries,
and I'll check you back there.
- On the rebound.
- Bet. All right.
Oh, shit! Let me check it out.
- That's the hype!
- Newest latest.
Let me tell you the story
of right hand/left hand.
It's a tale of good and evil.
Hate.
It was with this hand
that Cain iced his brother.
Love.
These five fingers,
they go straight to the soul of man.
The right hand... the hand of love.
The story of life is this.
Static.
One hand is always
fighting the other hand,
and the left hand is kicking much ass.
I mean, it looks like the right hand,
love, is finished.
But hold on.
Stop the presses.
The right hand's coming back.
Yeah, he got the left hand
on the ropes now.
That's right. Yeah. Ooh!
It's a devastating right,
and hate is hurt and down!
Ooh! Ooh! Left hand, hate,
K.O.'d by love.
If I love you, I love you.
But if I hate you...
There it is, love and hate.
- I love you, brother.
- Bet.
Radio Raheem,
check you later. Peace.
♪ Fight the power ♪
♪ We've got to fight the powers that be ♪
Two slices.
No service
till you turn that shit off!
Two slices.
Turn it off!
Mr. Radio Raheem,
I can't even hear myself think!
You are disturbing me!
You are disturbing my customers!
♪ Fight the power ♪
Two slices.
You come into Sal's...
there's no music.
No rap, no music,
no music, no music.
Capisci?
Understand?
Yo, put some extra mozzarella
on that motherfucker and shit.
Extra cheese is $2.00.
Pizza delivery!
All right. Later.
Mousie, what's up?
Watch out. Move!
Nigga wearin' the same shit!
What's up, buddy?
How you livin', man?
Oh, here come Mookie, man.
Check it out. Mookie!
- What's up, man?
- Give me some of that!
- Get a job.
- We don't need no job, man.
- Get a job, man.
- Oh, man, shut up, man.
Buggin'.
Where the females?
You don't do nothin'
with them anyway.
- Hey, I've got it like that.
- Mookie.
M-M-M-Mookie.
All right. Here you go.
Stop bothering me.
Th-Th-Thank you, b-b-b-black man.
All right.
Leave me alone.
- Jade!
- What?
Mookie,
how come you're not at Sal's?
I'm working.
What's this, Mookie? Another one
of your patented two-hour lunch breaks?
I wanted to come home
and take a quick shower.
- Hey, Sal's gonna get mad.
- You know, later for Sal.
Sometimes I think you're more concerned
about him than me,
- and I'm your brother.
- Yeah.
Yeah, Mookie, that's real smart.
You know, Sal pays you, Mookie.
That's why you should work.
You ever think about that?
Yeah, I work.
Slavery days are over.
My name ain't Kunta Kinte.
Yeah, Mookie. I just
don't want you to lose the one job
you've been able to keep
for more than a month.
That's all, okay?
I'm carrying you as it is.
Don't worry about me.
I'll always get paid.
Yeah. You always get paid.
What about your responsibilities, huh?
Why don't you take better care of those?
- What responsibilities?
What are you, deaf, Mookie?
You know damn well
what I'm talking about.
Take care of your responsibilities,
all right?
Who you yelling at, anyway?
- Who you yelling at?
- I'm yelling at you!
- I'm going to take care of this shower.
- Yeah, take a shower.
I'm your big brother.
Don't be yelling at me, now.
- Get out of here. You're a bum.
- Cut that shit out.
Don't call me no bum.
Whoo!
Hey, Jade, if I want to shower
in the middle of the day, it's all right.
Fuck Sal.
WE-LOVE roll call, y'all.
Boogie Down Productions,
Rob Base, Dana Dane...
Marley Marl, Olatunji,
Chuck D, Ray Charles,
EPMD, EU, Alberta Hunter,
Run-DMC, Stetsasonic,
Sugar Bear, John Coltrane,
Big Daddy Kane,
Salt-N-Pepa, Luther Vandross,
McCoy Tyner, Biz Markie,
New Edition, Otis Redding, Anita Baker,
Thelonious Monk, Marcus Miller,
Branford Marsalis,
James Brown, Wayne Shorter,
Tracy Chapman, Miles Davis,
Force MDs, Oliver Nelson,
Fred Wesley, Maceo,
Janet Jackson, Louis Armstrong,
Duke Ellington, Jimmy Jam,
Terry Lewis, George Clinton,
Count Basie, Mtume,
Stevie Wonder, Bobby McFerrin,
Dexter Gordon, Sam Cooke,
Parliament-Funkadelic,
Al Jarreau, Teddy Pendergrass,
Joe Williams, Wynton Marsalis,
Phyllis Hyman, Sade,
Sarah Vaughn, Roland Kirk,
Keith Sweat, Kool Moe Dee,
Prince, Ella Fitzgerald,
Diana Reeves,
Aretha Franklin,
Bob Marley, Bessie Smith,
Whitney Houston, Dionne Warwick,
Steel Pulse, Little Richard,
Mahalia Jackson, Jackie Wilson,
Cannonball and Nat Adderley,
Quincy Jones,
Marvin Gaye, Charles Mingus,
and Mary Lou Williams.
We want to thank you all
for making our lives
just a little brighter
here on WE-LOVE Radio.
Yo, man,
it's hot as a motherfucker.
- Why don't you fan me with your ears?
- Stop playin'!
Leave it alone.
- Why y'all think everything is a joke?
- Man, shut up.
Chill, man.
It's too hot for that.
That's why I asked you
what you want to do.
We don't have money
to do anything.
I'm beat.
Daddy, you know,
I've been thinking.
Maybe we should sell this place.
Get out while we're still ahead...
and alive.
You really think you know
what's best for us, Pino?
Maybe we could...
Couldn't we sell this
and open up a new one
in our own neighborhood?
There's too many pizzerias
already there.
Then maybe we could try
something different.
What am I gonna do?
That's all I know.
What am I doing?
I been here 25 years.
Where am I going?
I'm sick of niggers.
It's like I come to work,
it's Planet of the Apes.
I don't like being around them.
They're animals.
Why you got so much anger in you?
Why? I'll tell you why.
My friends, they laugh at me.
They laugh right in my face.
They tell me, "Go. Go to Bed-Stuy.
Go, go feed the moulies."
Do your friends put money
in your pocket, Pino?
Food on your table?
They pay your rent,
a roof over your head? Huh?
They're not your friends.
If they were your friends,
they wouldn't laugh at you.
Pop, what can I say?
I don't want to be here.
They don't want us here.
We should stay
in our own neighborhood,
in Bensonhurst,
and niggers should stay in theirs.
I never had no trouble
with these people.
I sat in this window, I...
I watch these little kids get old.
And I seen the old people get older.
Yeah, sure, some of them don't like us,
but most of them do.
I mean, for Christ sake, Pino,
they grew up on my food.
On my food.
Now, I'm very proud of that.
You may think it's funny,
but I'm very proud of that.
Look, what I'm trying
to say, son, is, uh...
Sal's Famous Pizzeria
is here to stay.
I'm sorry.
I'm your father,
and I love you.
I'm sorry, but...
but that's the way it is.
Hey, S-Sal.
- Hey, S-Sal.
- How you doing?
These are $2.00.
Get out.
Get the fuck out of here, man!
Get the fuck out of here!
Two dollars.
Sal.
Come on. Get out of here.
Get the fuck out of here, man!
- Hey! Hey! Hey!
- Every day it's the same shit.
- Hey, hey!
- Hey, what?
Oh, yeah?
Get a fucking job, man!
Why don't you get a fucking job,
man?
Go to fucking work!
- Fuck you, man.
- S-S-Sal.
Get out, man. Get out!
See what I'm saying?
Leave that boy alone, man.
You know he ain't right!
- Goddamn!
- Get a fucking job, man!
- I'm sick of this shit.
- You get a job!
Huh? What? I got a job.
I got a job, man.
- Bring your ass over here, punk!
- No, I ain't going over there.
I got no reason to go over there.
- F-F-F-Fuck...
- I got no reason to go over there.
- What are you gonna do, fuckin' jump me?
- F-F-Fuck you!
Fuck you, man!
Get the fuck out of here!
F-F-F-Fuck you!
Go inside. Go inside.
Smiley, here, here, here.
Smiley, here.
- Here's a couple of dollars.
- F-Fuck!
- Come on. Come on. Here.
- Fuck you!
- Fuckin' asshole!
Hey, Willie, take it easy.
He didn't mean nothin'.
- Okay?
- Fuck!
- Fuck you!
- This is what I'm talking about.
Whoo!
Let's go, Jade!
Da Mayor, we need your leadership.
- Doctor, what are you talking about?
- I'm organizing a boycott of Sal's Famous.
Shit.
Keep walking, doctor.
I don't want to hear none
of your damn black foolishness.
Damn. No juice.
No, man, no.
No!
Hell, no, goddamn it.
Sal ain't never done nothin' to you
before, man, and me neither.
Hear me? What you ought to do
is boycott that goddamn barber
that fucked up your head.
Shit.
Come around here,
fuckin' with Sweet Dick Willie.
- Go on, man. Get out.
- Get the fuck away.
Go on, beat it.
Would you sign a petition
to boycott Sal's Famous Pizzeria?
- What?
Man, I ain't boycottin' jack,
you string-cheese head motherfucker.
I'm about to go get a slice right now.
Shit, I was born and raised
on Sal's pizza.
- What the fuck you talkin' about?
- Shit.
You crazy, man?
As good as them motherfuckin' pizzas is?
Black Panther eat pizza,
we eat pizza.
- Boy!
- Yo, I heard you.
I'll do it without your help.
That's 75 cents.
- Thanks.
- Thanks, hon.
Sal! We're going to boycott
your fat pasta ass.
You're gonna boy...
You're going to boycott me?
You haven't got the balls
to boycott me.
He's going to boycott me.
Are you kidding?
Get... Here's your...
Here! Here's your boycott.
Up your ass.
You're going to boycott.
Here... Where you going?
Oh! Where you going?
- I'm talking to you, Pino!
- I'm right here.
All right, go inside.
I can take care of myself, all right?
- Take it easy, all right?
- No, I want you to go inside.
Here's your boycott! Up here!
Son of a bitch.
Messed up my Jordans with muck.
Damn!
Get this thing straightened out, man.
White boy, black man.
I can't believe this crap.
- Ah, your Jordans are dogged!
- Oh, man! You, too?
- Well, stop.
- Yeah, me, too.
Oh, you hangin' out with baby sis.
Look, Buggin' Out,
we're not hangin' out.
- She's escortin' me back to Sal's.
- Stop lying. That's not even true.
- I'm just goin' to get a slice.
- A slice?
Yo, yo, Jade, you can't do that.
Not today.
You don't know this, but I'm organizing
a boycott of Sal's Famous.
Why? What'd he do?
You know them pictures
he got on the wall of fame?
- So?
- So? Wake up.
- Don't you notice somethin' about them?
- No, Buggin' Out, I haven't.
You know, you're wasting my time.
Just leave that shit alone.
- You should. You really should.
- Hey, yo, Mook!
- I'm gone.
- I'll see you there.
Stay black, Mook.
- So, Buggin' Out, how you been?
- How I been?
Every single one of them pictures
is somebody Italian.
- And?
- And we want some black people up.
- So did you ask Sal?
- Yeah, I asked him.
We don't want nobody in there,
nobody spending good money in Sal's,
until we get black motherfucking pictures
on that wall.
Buggin' Out,
what good is that gonna do, huh?
You know, if you really tried hard,
Buggin' Out,
you could direct your energies
in a more useful way, you know?
Jade, you got to be down.
What, you ain't down?
Yeah, Buggin' Out, I'm down, but I'm down
for something positive in the community.
Are you down for that?
Jade.
Jade, I still love you anyway.
Yeah, I still love you, too,
Buggin' Out.
I'll see you later, man.
Later. Damn.
Man.
You're pushing it, Mookie.
You're really pushing it.
I don't pay you good money
to have you jerk me around.
Now, you keep it up,
you're gonna end up in the street
with the rest of your homeboys.
About time, Pop.
Jade.
- How you doin', Jade?
- Great.
- Where you been?
- Just working hard. Keeping busy.
- How's business going?
- Business is great.
We were wondering when you
were gonna stop by and pay us a visit.
- How's my brother doing?
- Well, he's, uh... Mookie is...
He's great.
You know, he's a good kid.
- Hey, Pop. Stop lying.
- Thanks.
- He's only kidding, Jade.
- I know.
- What can I fix you?
- Regular slice.
No, no, I'm going to make you
something special,
something very special,
if you don't mind.
Yeah, no, that'd be great.
That'd be great.
- Okay, what do you want to drink?
- Cream soda.
Changed,
it used to be root beer.
If I'm wrong, tell me if I'm wrong.
I know.
I want a change of pace, you know.
Hey, Vito, clean off the table
for Jade, okay?
All right, Pop.
Come here, Jade. Sit here.
This is the best booth.
♪ Fight the power ♪
♪ Fight the pow... ♪
Twenty D Energizers.
Twenty C Energizers?
D. Not C. D.
C Energizers?
D, motherfucker. D!
Learn to speak English first,
all right? D.
- How many you say?
- Twenty, motherfucker. Twenty.
Motherfuck you!
Motherfuck...
Motherfucker, you...
You all right, man. You all right.
Just give me
the motherfuckin' batteries, all right?
Twenty D fuckin' batteries.
Hey, wait.
Yo, wait, wait, wait.
- What's the date on them, man?
- Motherfuck...
What's the date on them?
- The date! The fuckin' date!
- What?
Can you fuckin' speak English?
The date!
- Date?
- Date. Date.
- They're Marcha!
- Marcha?
- Motherfuck...
- What you talkin' about, Marcha?
1991.
Oh, March.
That's March, motherfucker, March.
Yo, man, you sure that's 20?
- Twenty.
- No, man. No, no, no. Take 'em out, man.
Count 'em again.
Count the shits again, man.
Motherfucker.
May I help you?
I want some flowers.
- The whole thing?
- The whole thing.
- It's very expensive.
- I know. I'll pay.
I thought you might like these.
I guess not.
There is nothing like
the smell of fresh flowers.
Don't you agree, Mother Sister?
Summertime...
All you can smell is the garbage.
Smell overpowers everything,
especially the soft,
sweet smell of flowers.
You don't mind,
I'm gonna sit right here,
catch myself a breeze or two,
and then I'll be on my way.
Thank the Lord,
the sun is going down.
It is hot as blazes.
Yes, Jesus.
Well, guess I'll be on my way.
- Oh.
- Oh, goddamn, man!
Cut that shit down!
You should play some Bobby "Blue" Bland
or something, you fucker.
- What to say?
- Come on!
- Man, I don't know how he does it.
- Oh, man! Goddamn!
Loud-ass shit. Fuck.
- ML?
- What?
- Come here.
Come hold this for me, baby.
- Yo...
- Hold what, sucker?
- You know what I'm talkin' about.
- That's okay.
At least my moms didn't name me
Sweet Dick Willie.
- Uh-huh, uh-huh.
- I told you about that "mama" shit.
Hey, nobody talkin' about your moms.
I ain't say nobody, motherfucker.
I said you!
- Hey, hey.
- Come on, man, squash all that.
- Just squash that shit.
- No, Dick, listen.
- You know I didn't mean it like that.
- You did, too!
- Shit.
- I just wanted to know
who named you Sweet Dick Willie.
Man, it's just a name.
Goddamn. Shit.
- How you get the name ML?
- Yeah! Uh-huh.
ML stands for ML.
Now that's some stupid shit,
right there.
You hear me?
That's some stupid shit.
'Cause everybody know
why they call me Sweet Dick Willie.
- Everybody.
- Boy, I swear, you Negroes kill me.
- Shit.
- Always holding onto,
always talking about your dicks.
See, I don't know about you,
but it's too hot to fuck.
Man, you out your fuckin' mind?
It ain't never too hot
or never too cold for fuckin'.
Hear me? I had my best
piece of woman on a humid day.
- Shit.
- Ain't that something.
Over in the projects.
Close to your woman.
Hey, boy, get out of here, man!
Shit.
- Oh, Lord, have mercy.
- Oh, boy. Hey, boy.
Goddamn. I better
not see her naked on payday.
Piraguero!
Everybody out!
The Icee, Icee Man is here.
Hey, hey!
Looking good, looking good.
Here we are.
Look at these beautiful people, huh.
The Icee man is here.
Ah, ah.
- I want coconut.
- Give me lemon.
Tell me what you need. Aha!
There you go, my love.
There you go.
Aha, that's your color.
- That's your flavor.
- Thank you.
I want more syrup on mine.
He's always drinking beer.
Hey, hey, now!
Hey, where's everybody going?
Ice cream!
- Ice cream!
- Doctor!
Doctor, don't you know no better
than to run out in that street
in front of a car?
What you trying to do,
kill yourself?
- Come on. Let's get up. Come on.
- Ah.
You gonna be all right.
You gonna be all right, my boy.
Eddie, you gonna be just fine.
Eddie, what's wrong?
Mayor knocked me down.
You ought to be ashamed of yourself.
Miss, that boy's
just scared to death.
What happened...
I was walking along the street,
minding my own business.
I looked out and I seen your son
about to get hit by the car,
so I dashed out to save him,
and I had to knock him down
to keep us both from getting hit.
Matter of fact, I saved two lives today...
his and mine.
Eddie, is that the truth?
Eddie, you hear me talking to you.
Come on.
I'm talking to you, boy.
He gonna be fine, miss.
Just fine.
What'd I tell you about lying?
What'd I tell you?
- Mommy, Mommy! I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
- Ease up!
Get upstairs, now!
And when your father come home,
he gonna wear your little behind out, too!
Miss, you didn't have
to hit your boy like that.
He's already scared to death.
I appreciate you helping my Eddie,
I truly do.
But I'll have nobody question
how I raise him.
- Not even his daddy.
- You're right, miss.
You're right.
Excuse me.
I don't want to sound like a jerk.
- But can I say something here, Jade?
- Yeah, Sal.
You got the biggest eyes
I've ever seen in my life.
They, like, jump right out of your head.
You know that?
I feel embarrassed even saying that.
I feel like a jerk.
- Thanks, Sal. Thanks a lot.
- All right, don't even mention it.
It was delicious.
Thanks a lot.
- I gotta talk to you.
- Mookie.
I got to talk to you.
Come on, come on.
- All right, Mookie.
- Come on. Let's go.
Hey, Jade, don't forget
to come back soon, okay?
Hey, Mookie, take it easy.
What are you grabbing her arm?
You're going to bust her arm.
Vito...
Jade, I do not want you
in Sal's no more, all right?
- Mookie, what? Stop tripping.
- No, you're trippin'.
Read my lips.
Don't come in Sal's no more.
What are you so worked up about?
The way Sal looks at you.
About the way he talks at you.
- He's just being nice.
- Nice?
- He's completely innocent.
- Innocent?
I didn't stutter.
You heard me.
Look, all Sal wants
to do is hide the salami.
You're really crude, Mookie.
You know that?
I admit it. I'm crude.
Do not come in Sal's anymore.
- You are not welcome.
- You got a lot of nerve, you know that?
I'm gonna tell you something
for the last time, Mookie.
Stop trying to play
big brother to me, okay?
I'm a grown woman!
You can hardly pay rent,
and you're gonna tell me what to do?
- Come off it!
- That makes no sense at all.
- Oh, it doesn't, huh?
- No.
You got your little $250 a week,
plus tips.
- I'm getting paid.
- Peanuts.
You know, in a while,
I'll be making a move, all right?
- Yeah, when?
- Don't worry about it.
- When, Mookie? That's what I wanna...
- When?
- Don't worry about it.
- Jade, don't come here no more.
- Look, it's got nothing...
We're not talking about that.
Take your skinny butt
around the corner and go home.
I'm tired of supporting
a grown woman, okay?
Take your butt around the corner.
I'm tired of supporting
a grown man. Okay?
I wanna know when you're gonna
pack your bags and go, okay, Mookie?
Hey, just don't come in Sal's no more,
all right?
- I'll be back.
- And no more pizza, either.
I don't care if you fire me
this exact fucking moment.
If you're saying
what I'm thinking you're saying,
you better not say it
because I don't wanna hear.
Yeah, hear this. Do me a favor.
Leave Jade alone.
You know, Mookie, not for nothin',
but if you were just
a little bit taller,
I'd kick you right in the ass
for what you're thinking.
As a matter of fact, I should
kick your ass on principle alone.
Here. You got a delivery.
This the right address?
Yeah, what is this with the...
Yeah, it's the right address, Mook.
That's the right address.
Yeah, I wrote it myself. Why?
I'm checking.
Sometimes you make a mistake
and I deliver fucking pizzas
to the wrong fucking address.
I don't make mistakes.
I don't make...
- You don't make mistakes?
- No.
Hey, hurry back, okay?
Don't get lost. We're still open.
Do me a favor.
Make the pizza, huh?
Mr. Mayor.
I saw what you did.
That was a foolish act.
But it was brave.
- That child owes you his life.
- I wasn't trying to be a hero.
I just seen what was happening,
and I reacted.
Didn't even think.
Probably wouldn't have done it
on second thought, if I had thought.
Yeah, Da Mayor's getting to be
an old man, now.
I ain't run like that in years.
I went from first to home
on a bunt single.
Scored the winning run. It was two out
in the bottom of the ninth.
It was August 1, 1939.
Snow Hill, Alabama.
Ol' Mud Cat Bunch-of-Bones
was the pitcher.
Now, he hated my guts.
He ran back, come down off that mound,
and I took off
like white lightning
up a black snake's ass, I...
Maybe I, uh...
Maybe I ought to be
a hero more often, huh?
Maybe you shouldn't.
Don't get happy.
This changes nothing between you
and me.
You did a good thing, and Mother Sister
just wanted to thank you for it.
I want to thank you.
You're welcome.
Delivery from Sal's Famous Pizzeria.
What the hell took you so long?
Is it hot?
Lady, I've never delivered
a cold pizza in my life.
Come here.
You know,
you think you're slick, Tina.
I know. How else
was I gonna get you up here?
I haven't seen you for a week.
I'm working, you know.
Making money, getting paid.
I see you forgot
the ice cream again.
Ah, shit, I forgot.
Yeah, you know, your memory's
getting really ridiculous.
- It's disgusting.
- I forgot. I got things on my mind.
Yeah, and I really wanted
some ice cream, too.
It'll make you any happier,
I'll run out and get some.
No, no, no. That's out.
You won't come back, either.
- You know, I can't be staying long anyhow.
- How long?
- Long enough to do the nasty.
- Ahh!
No, come on, Mookie! That's out.
Hold up. Wait a minute.
First of all, it is too hot,
all right?
And if you think I'm gonna
let you get some,
put your clothes on
and leave here
and not see your black ass
for another week,
- you must be bugging.
- I'll see you tomorrow.
Yeah, right.
And my name is Boo Boo the Fool.
So no nasty, huh?
- No.
- Tina, let's do something else, then.
- What?
- Trust me.
Trust you? Uh, Mookie,
the last time I trusted you,
we ended up with a son.
- Remember your son?
- I do remember my son. His name's Hector.
What are you trying to say?
I'm a bad father?
On the strength.
- Let me talk to you for a second.
- What? What?
Over here.
Tina... take your clothes off.
Mookie, I already told you
it's too fuckin' hot to make love.
- It's too fuckin' hot.
- Yeah.
- Why are you always cursing?
- I don't fuckin' curse that much.
"I don't fuckin' curse that much."
What the hell are you talking about,
Mookie?
- All you do is curse.
- I do not!
Anyway, no rawness
is jumping off tonight, all right?
And that's it.
- No rawness?
- No. No rawness.
Why it's always gotta be like that
when you come over here and shit?
- It's not always like that.
- It always has to be fuckin' like that...
Mookie, what are you doing?
What are you doing?
I'm not cursing.
Mookie. Come on!
I mean it.
I'm not playing.
"I'm not playing."
Damn, don't be so anxious.
That's right. Take it off.
- You're sweating.
- Of course I'm sweating, you moron.
It's only 100 degrees in here
and shit.
Look, freeze. Don't move.
I'll be right back, okay?
- What do you mean you'll be right back?
- Just stay there.
Where you going?
I'll be right back.
What the hell you got me
standing on the bed for?
Where the hell you going?
How's my son, Hector?
Honey, do you hear that?
He wants to know how you are doing.
And he has the straight face
of asking about it.
Good for nothing.
English! English!
I want my son to speak English,
all right?
- Why don't you just get out of my kitchen?
- It's bad enough his name is Hector.
Get out of my kitchen.
I don't want to hear anything.
Get out. Out, I said.
Yes, children.
This is the cool-out corner.
We're slowing it down
for all the lovers in the house.
I'll be giving you
all the help you need.
Musically, that is.
This shit is cold.
Supposed to be cold.
It's an ice cube.
Later for your shit.
Mira.
- Mira.
- What?
Tina, you don't got a forehead.
You got a eight-head.
Mookie,
you're corny as shit.
You got one of them Sade foreheads.
Fuck you.
Goddamn,
that's a big-ass forehead.
I need an iceberg...
It'd be better than this ice cube.
Thank God for the lips.
Thank God for the neck.
Thank God for kneecaps.
Thank God for elbows.
Thank God for thighs.
Thank God for the right nipple.
Thank God for the left nipple.
Feels good.
Ah. You likes,
you likes, you likes.
Anyway.
I got to be going.
You better come back.
I'll be back tonight.
You better come back,
or else I'm gonna kick your ass.
- Oops.
- What?
Guess I got to be back then.
All right.
- Get out of here.
- I gotta go.
- Bye.
- I'm not leaving yet.
- Get out of here.
- All right. Later.
- Later.
So just out of curiosity,
how long you gonna stick around here?
You mean tonight?
I mean the neighborhood,
you know.
Well, I figure about 50 years.
Yeah, because I'm going into
the real estate business, you know.
I figured I'd put up a big high-rise
in the neighborhood.
- Yeah. Lot of people want to move here.
- Why not?
You want a condominium?
Put a couple of straws in there,
Mr. Trump.
- But of course.
- Mr. Trump's.
- Trump's Pizza.
- I heard of that place, man.
- No, it's Trump's Plaza.
- Oh.
- Do me a favor. Get out of here.
- See you, Sal.
Take care, Salvatore.
Pino, take the soft drinks
out of the back and load up here, okay?
Okay, Pop.
Sal, if you want me
to deliver faster,
you gotta give me
a jet rocket or something.
'Cause I can't be running with pizzas.
The cheese ends up on one side.
Mookie, I didn't say nothing.
You must have a guilty conscience.
You got a guilty conscience?
Sal, I'm not guilty of anything.
You gotta be guilty of something.
Otherwise you wouldn't come in here
saying the things you said.
Come on, Sal.
Where we going?
Oh, shit.
- You're corny.
- Vito, give me a hand. Come on.
Corny as shit.
- Come on, Vito.
- What?
What the fuck's the matter?
Vito, I want you to listen to me.
I'm your brother.
I may smack you around
every once in a while,
but I'm still your... your brother.
So what, Pino?
So fucking what?
I love you, man.
I'm listening, I'm listening.
Good, 'cause I want you to listen.
Jesus Christ, Pino.
I said I'm fuckin' listening.
Good. Vito, black, white.
No.
- No, no, no.
- No?
- What the hell you talking about?
- Are you listening to me?
Stop busting my balls, Pino.
I said I'm fuckin' listening
ten fuckin' times already.
Mookie is not to be trusted.
- I trust him, Pino. I fuckin' trust him.
- No, no.
No mulignan can be trusted.
The first time you turn your back,
boom.
The spear, right here, man,
in the back.
Yeah?
How do you know this?
- I know.
- How do you know, man?
- I know. I read.
- Give me a break, Pino.
I never seen you read nothing
in your fuckin' life.
Read your history.
It's historical.
He, them,
they're not to be trusted.
- What do you want me to do about it?
- I want you to be on fucking guard, man.
Fuckin' hit me?
You be on guard,
'cause Mookie has Pop conned,
so we got to look out for him.
You don't know what the fuck
you're talking about.
That's exactly
what I'm talking about.
- Yeah?
- Vito! Pino! Let's go!
We'll be right there, Pop.
One minute.
You better listen to what I say
or I'll rip you...
I'll fuck you up.
You know I'll fuck you up.
- You know something, Pino?
- What?
You don't know everything
you think you know, man.
You think you know it,
but you don't know it.
Mookie, he listens to me.
You don't, man.
He does, man.
You fuckin' don't.
You're fuckin' stabbing me
in the back, man.
Radio!
Buggin', what's up?
How you been, man?
Living large, bro.
Yo, that the only tape you gots?
You don't like Public Enemy, man?
The shit's dope.
No, I'm down, but you don't
be playing nothing else.
I don't like nothing else.
Yo, check this, man.
You know Sal?
Yeah, I know that motherfucker.
I've been trying to organize a boycott of
Sal's Famous, you know what I'm sayin'?
I almost had to bust him
in the head today, man.
Gonna tell me... Tell me, Radio Raheem,
to turn down my box and shit, man,
and didn't even say "please."
Who the fuck he think he is,
Don Corleone and shit?
He makes much money off
us black people,
and all he got up in there
on the wall is Italians.
You know, Sylvester Stallone,
okeydoke-lookin' motherfuckers.
- You see what I'm saying, homeboy?
- On the strength.
Yeah, well we shouldn't buy one slice,
spend one red penny up in there
till he put folks of color
up on that wall.
That's what I'm talking about, man!
- Yo, you got my back?
- Your back is got.
- My brother.
Yo, Smiley.
Come here, man.
What you listening to?
M-M-M-Malcolm.
M-M-M-Malcolm, huh?
Cut off that rap music!
I'm in here trying to get me
some motherfuckin' goddamn sleep.
- Yo, I'll fuck you up quick!
- Two times!
Th-Th-Th-three t-times!
Sal, start counting my money tonight
'cause I gots to get paid.
Come on, Vito.
Come on.
This is terrific.
I mean we had a great,
great day.
You know something?
There's nothing like a family
in business working together.
I'm gonna rename the place.
I'm going to call it Sal
and Sons' Famous Pizzeria.
Why not? You guys are gonna
take it over someday, anyway, right?
And, Mookie...
Mookie, I want to tell you that there's
always gonna be a place for you here,
right here at Sal's,
Sal's Famous Pizzeria.
Because you've always
been like a son to me.
Yo, Sal! Can we get some pizza, man?
We're closed, man! We're closed.
- You shut up!
- Shut the fuck up, man!
All right, let them in.
Let them in.
They love my pizza.
Four slices,
and I'm out of here.
Sal, we're trying to go home!
- Open the door, Mookie!
- Shut up!
You ain't nothing
but a delivery boy, bitch!
- Simple ass!
- Stupid!
Man,
shut the fuck up!
- Sit your black ass down!
- Shut up, man! Fuck you!
Yo, Sal, Sal,
four slices, man, regular.
- To go, all right?
- Hey, why you gotta curse?
Looking good.
- Looking real good, man.
- Fuck it, man. Come on. I'm hungry, man.
♪ Fight the power ♪
♪ We got to fight the powers that be ♪
♪ Elvis was a hero to most ♪
♪ But he never meant shit to me ♪
♪ Ya see straight out racist
The sucka ♪
What'd I tell you you
about that noise?
- What about them pictures?
- What the fuck? Are you deaf?
No! Are you?
Fuck you!
We want some black people
on that motherfucking wall of fame now!
We're trying to go fucking home!
We've been here all fuckin' day,
Buggin' Out.
Turn that jungle music off!
We ain't in Africa!
Why it got to be
about jungle music?
Why it got to be about Africa?
It's about them fucking pictures!
It's about turning that shit off
and getting the fuck out of my place!
Radio Raheem!
- Fuck you!
- And fuck you, too!
- Kick some ass, Sal!
- Get in there, Pino!
This is music!
My music!
Fuck your music!
Well, turn it off, then!
Hey, man, get the fuck out of here!
We're fuckin' closed!
Fuck you!
We're closing you
guinea bastards for good!
For good, motherfucker!
Until you get some black people
on that motherfucking wall of fame!
- You're gonna fucking close me?
- You goddamn right!
You black cocksucker!
I'll fuckin' tear
your fuckin' nigger ass!
- Niggers?
- Oh, we're niggers now?
- We niggers now.
- I will fuck you up!
You fucking white trash!
Come here.
I'll fuck you up!
Sal, put the fucking bat down!
- Come on, Ahmad!
- That's right, you fucking guinea!
Open the motherfucking counter!
You black cocksucker!
You nigger motherfucker!
I just killed your fucking radio.
My music! You motherfucking...
Lay off, you motherfuck!
Get off him!
Get the fuck off him!
Get off him! Get him!
- Motherfucker!
- Get him!
He fucked up my eye!
Ahmad, no!
Please, stop it!
- Yo, yo, yo, stop!
- Please, stop it!
You don't fuck with my box, man!
Look at that.
Punch him in the grill right now!
- You don't fuck up my box!
- No, get off me!
Stop it!
Get the fuck up!
Come on. I'm gonna
kick your ass some more!
- Come on!
- Get the fuck out! Get the fuck out!
- We gotta get to Sal's, brother!
- Fight!
Mookie!
Hey! Break it up!
Hey! Hey!
Break it up!
- He's gonna kill him.
- Break it up!
What are you doing?
You're gonna kill him!
- Stop! Stop!
- Break it up!
Stop!
- Stop! Break it up!
- You're gonna kill him!
Let me at 'em.
Let me at 'em, man!
- Get... Get out of the way!
- Get the fuck out of the way, man!
Break it up,
right now!
- Get off! Get off him, get off me!
- Let me through! Let me through!
Gary, get the big guy!
- Let me through!
- Gary!
Get off me!
I'll kill you,
you motherfucker!
Just take him off me!
Get over here.
What are you doing? Sal!
Get the fuck off me, man!
Get off of me!
Get off me!
Goddamn it!
You're taking me down, huh?
You ain't taking Vito
or Pino or Sal, huh?
Get the fuck off me!
Get his other arm!
Take him down!
Just take him down!
Just take him down, man!
Let him go, goddamn it!
You're killing him!
Give it up, asshole!
Give it up!
- Just take him down!
- Come on!
Give it up!
- Let him go! Let him go!
- Stop it, goddamn it!
Stop it!
- Aah!
- Get his arm! Get his arm!
- Gary, that's enough!
- Shut up.
Gary, that's enough, man!
- Gary, that's enough!
- Shut the fuck up!
Radio Raheem!
No!
Radio!
- Radio Raheem! Radio Raheem!
- Get up.
- Get the fuck up! You ain't dead!
- Get up, asshole!
- They killed him!
- Quit faking it!
- Get up, asshole!
- Get up!
Get the fuck up!
Let's get him out of here.
I'm a black man, goddamn it!
I'm a black man!
You can't kill us all!
You can't fucking kill us all,
goddamn it!
It's all right, brother!
It's all right. They done fucked up.
Let's get him out of here!
- Come on!
- Radio!
Get him to the car.
Get him to the car. Let's go.
Get out of the way, now!
Back off, assholes!
You fucking pig-fucking murderers!
You can't kill us all, man!
You can't fucking kill us all!
Back off, back off!
Everybody, back off!
Get back!
Fuck you, man!
Get off me!
- Get the fuck off me!
- Shut up, nigger!
- I'm gonna fuck you up! Damn it!
- Shut up!
I told you to shut up!
- Back off!
- Radio, Radio, can you hear me, man?
- Radio!
- Back off!
This ain't even right, man.
Yo, what happened to rights?
I'm gonna get your back, man.
Yo, get him out!
- Fuck that, man!
- Bitch!
Radio!
No!
Mookie, they killed him.
They killed Radio Raheem!
It's murder.
They did it again,
just like Michael Stewart.
Murder! Eleanor Bumpers!
Murder!
Damn, man! It ain't safe
in our own fucking neighborhood!
Never was.
Never will be.
We ain't gonna stand for this shit
no more, Sal. You hear me?
Ain't gonna stand
for them fuckin' police. Punk!
It's as plain as day.
They didn't have to kill the boy.
They killed him.
You ain't shit, Sal.
Shit, man.
You do what you gotta do.
Aw, fuck that, Sal!
Listen, listen, listen.
Good people, please.
Let's all go home.
Somebody's gonna get hurt.
Yeah. You, boy!
If we don't stop this
and stop it now,
we gonna do something we're gonna regret
for the rest of our lives.
Sal and his boys had nothing
to do with what the cops did.
One of the police was black!
- Leave him alone.
- I'm gonna get you
and them three stooges,
Sal, you hear me?
Go on, Mr. Sal.
- How'd you do it, man?
- Go on.
You see how they had him
in a choke hold, man?
I knew that choke hold
was killing people, man!
- This ain't no kid, man.
- He had a radio.
- You can't save him.
- He had a radio, a fucking radio!
He died because he had a radio!
All he wanted pictures on the wall,
and he died!
Sal, what you got to say, Sal?
...called the cops!
Vito called the cops!
Your son called the cops, boy!
Man, get the fuck out of here, man!
Somebody's gotta pay.
Fuck that, man!
Aw, shit.
Hate!
No!
Let him go! Let him go!
Sal, this is Da Mayor.
- What are they doing?
- Come on, Sal.
- Sal, Sal, Sal.
- Sal, come on. Come on, quick.
- What the fuck are they doing?
Get them out of there!
Get...
That's my place!
- That's my fucking place!
- Sal!
Fucking niggers.
Radio!
Radio! Radio!
Burn it down!
Radio!
Radio! Radio!
Burn it down!
Come on, let's clean house.
Shit. Come on.
I no white.
I no white!
It's your turn, sucker!
- I no white! I no white!
- No white!
- I no white! I'm black!
- What? Black?
- Yeah, I black!
- Me black! Me black!
- Where you black at?
- Me black!
- I black!
- Me!
You, me, same!
We same.
Same?
Me black!
- Open your eyes, motherfucker!
- ML, leave the Korean alone, man.
He's all right.
Yeah, leave him alone, man.
Yeah? He's all right.
- He's black. Ain't that a bitch?
- Shit.
Oh, fuck you, now!
Howard Beach! Howard Beach!
- Let's go! Let's go!
- Howard Beach! Howard Beach!
Full pressure!
I want full pressure. Let's go!
Howard Beach! Howard Beach!
Spread out.
Spread it out.
Watch Howard Beach!
Howard Beach!
- Howard Beach!
- Go! Go! Good, good, good!
Howard Beach!
Good people, please disperse!
Please disperse!
Howard Beach! Howard Beach!
Good people, we're giving you
one more warning to please go home!
This is our home!
Okay, you've had your warning!
Hose the black fuckers down!
Get off of me! Get the fuck off me!
Back up, man.
Back up!
Yo! Yo! Yo!
Well, come on!
Come on!
Get your fuckin' black hands off me!
- Come on, asshole. Come on!
- Hold still, goddamn it!
Come on. Move it.
Motherfucker, come on!
- I'll break your arm.
- Is this Birmingham?
Fucking Alabama.
Yo, where's Bull Connor?
Son of a bitch!
Oh, no! No!
No!
Oh, no!
No! No!
No!
♪ Fight the power ♪
- ♪ Fight the power ♪
♪ We got to fight the powers that be ♪
♪ Fight the power ♪
- ♪ Fight the power ♪
♪ We got to fight the powers that be ♪
My people, my people...
What can I say?
Say what I can.
I saw it,
but I didn't believe it.
I didn't believe it,
what I saw.
Are we gonna live together?
Together, are we gonna live?
This is your Mister Señor Love Daddy
talking to you from WE-LOVE Radio,
108 FM on your dial,
and that's the triple truth, Ruth.
Today's weather?
Hot!
Wake up!
Fuck!
My money. Shit!
Where are you going?
To get my money.
Ah, don't try that shit,
okay?
You know,
you're gonna run out of here
and I ain't gonna see your black ass
for another fuckin' week.
- Tina, it's not even like that.
- It is like that.
You don't give
a fuckin' shit about me,
and you definitely don't give
a shit about your son.
Look, I care about you.
I care about my son.
- I'll be right back.
- Oh, my God.
- Why don't you be a man?
- I am a man, all right?
Then act like a man.
Why don't you be a fucking man, Mookie?
Shit.
I'm so tired of your shit.
Why do we have to go over this
shit again and again and again?
Because you don't fuckin' listen,
Mookie!
If you listen to me,
I wouldn't have to repeat myself
like a fucking radio,
all right?
Look what kind of mother you are,
using fuckin' language like that.
- What kind of mother am I?
- Why don't...
You need to... Your ass isn't even here!
So don't be telling me
- what kind of mother I am.
- Get another vocabulary, all right?
- Why don't you get a fucking life?
- Yeah.
- Look...
- Look what?
- I'll be back.
- What... Don't leave, Mookie.
- Don't leave.
'Cause I'm tired of this shit,
all right?
You walk out that door, that's it.
All right?
I have to get my money from Sal.
I'll be back, all right?
Your shit is to the curb, Mookie,
all right?
And I'm tired of it, all right?
'Cause you need to step off
with your stupid-ass self, okay?
And you need to get a fucking life,
Mookie, all right,
because the one you got, baby,
is not working, okay?
And I ain't going to deal
with this shit no more!
Fuckin' ass, stupid ass,
fuckin' pendejo.
Shit.
I'm tired of this fucking shit.
Good morning.
Is it a good morning?
Yes, indeed.
You almost got yourself killed
last night.
I've done that before.
Where did you sleep?
I didn't.
I hope the block is still standing.
We're still standing.
What do you want?
I want my money.
I want to get paid.
You don't work here no more.
Sal, I want my money.
Your money couldn't begin to pay
for the window you broke.
Motherfuck a window.
Radio Raheem is dead.
I know he's dead.
I was here. You remember?
He's dead because of his buddy.
That cocksucker started all this shit.
He's responsible for that kid's death.
And he wanted to close me,
and you stood there like a fuck
and you watched 'em burn me down!
I watched it. I also watched the cops
murder Radio Raheem.
You're gonna get over
from the fuckin' insurance anyway, Sal.
- You know the deal.
- What the fuck is wrong with you?
This ain't about money.
I could give a fuck about money.
You see this fuckin' place?
I built this fuckin' place!
With my bare fuckin' hands!
Every light socket,
every piece of tile.
Me! With these fuckin' hands!
You know what the fuck that means?
Yeah, it means pay me
my motherfucking money.
- That's what it means, Sal.
- Okay, Mookie.
How much do I owe you?
My salary is 250.
250 a week.
One...
that's two...
that's three...
that's four...
and that's five.
You got $500.
You're a rich fucking man.
Are you happy? You happy?
He's got 500 fuckin' dollars!
He's a big man!
He's a rich fucking man!
He's never gonna have
any more trouble!
Not Mookie!
He's fuckin' rich!
Who the fuck you yelling at?
You're wealthy, Mookie.
You're a real fuckin' Rockefeller.
You got your fuckin' pay.
Now leave me alone, huh?
Sal, my salary's 250 a week,
all right?
I owe you 50 bucks.
- Keep it.
- You keep it.
- No, you keep it.
I don't believe this shit.
Believe it.
Are you sick?
I'm hot as a motherfucker.
I'm all right, though.
Well, they say it's even gonna
get hotter today.
What are you gonna do
with yourself?
Make that money.
Get paid.
Sal, I got to go see my son,
if it's all right with you.
Hey, Mook. It's the Mook man.
I see you walking down the block.
Go on home to your kid.
Now the news and weather.
Our mayor has commissioned
a blue-ribbon panel, and I quote,
"To get to the bottom
of last night's disturbance.
The City of New York will not let property
be destroyed by anyone."
His Honor plans to visit our block today.
Maybe he should hook up
with our own Da Mayor, buy him a beer.
Your Love Daddy says register to vote.
The election is coming up.
There's no end in sight
from this heat wave,
so today,
the cash money word is chill.
That's right. C-H-I-L-L.
When you hear "chill,"
call in at 555-LOVE,
and you'll win cash money, honey.
This is Mister Señor Love Daddy
coming at you from
what's last on your dial
but first in your hearts,
and that's the quintessential truth,
Ruth.
The next record goes out
to Radio Raheem.
We love you, brother.
♪ From the heart of Bed-Stuy ♪
♪ W-E-L-O-V-E ♪
♪ I was looking through
A window at my life today ♪
♪ And for the first time ♪
♪ I saw things in a different way ♪
♪ In the middle of my mind ♪
♪ It was there all the time ♪
♪ Never explain love ♪
♪ It's not like anything
You've ever done ♪
♪ If it is there, it's yours to keep ♪
♪ And the boundaries, they grow deep ♪
♪ Never explain love ♪
♪ Let the experience take over you ♪
♪ And when you do ♪
♪ Never explain love ♪
♪ I was looking for a reason ♪
♪ I was searching for a sign ♪
♪ To try and understand
This relationship of mine ♪
♪ But I didn 't need to go far ♪
♪ I was reading it all wrong ♪
♪ Never explain love ♪
♪ It's not like anything
You've ever done ♪
♪ If it is there, it's yours to keep ♪
♪ And the boundaries, they grow deep ♪
♪ Never explain love ♪
♪ Let the experience take over you ♪
♪ And when you do ♪
♪ Never explain love ♪
♪ Before I knew ♪
♪ I almost knew it all ♪
♪ Who needs to be rational ♪
♪ When love isn't practical ♪
♪ Oh, I knew this was inside ♪
♪ And it's so wrong ♪
♪ It's so right ♪
♪ Whoa-oh-oh, ahh ♪
♪ Never explain love ♪
♪ It's not like anything
You've ever done ♪
♪ If it is there, it's yours to keep ♪
♪ And the boundaries, they grow deep ♪
♪ Never explain love ♪
♪ Let the experience take over you ♪
♪ And when you do ♪
♪ Never explain love ♪
♪ It's not like anything
You've ever done ♪
♪ If it is there, it's yours to keep ♪
♪ And the boundaries, they grow deep ♪
♪ Never explain love ♪
♪ Let the experience take over you ♪
♪ For when you do ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Never explain love ♪