[Engine Whirring]
[No Audible Dialogue]
♪♪ [Country Intro]
[Tammy Wynette]
♪ Sometimes it's hard ♪
♪ To be a woman ♪
♪ Givin' all
your love ♪
♪ To just one man ♪
♪ You'll have
bad times ♪
♪ And he'll have
good times ♪
♪ Doing things
that you don't understand ♪
♪ But if you love him ♪
♪ You'll forgive him ♪
♪ Even though he's hard ♪
♪ To understand ♪
♪ And if you love him ♪
♪ Oh, be proud of him ♪
♪ 'Cause after all ♪
♪ He's just a man ♪
♪ Stand by your man ♪
♪ And show the world you love him ♪
♪ Keep giving all the love you can ♪
♪ Stand by your man ♪
♪ And show the world
you love him ♪
♪ Keep giving all the love you can ♪
♪ Stand by ♪
♪ Your man ♪♪
[Kisses]
I'm gonna play it again.
You play that thing one more time,
and I'm gonna melt it down into hair spray.
- Well, let me play the other side then.
- No, Rayette. It's not a question of sides.
It's a question of musical integrity.
Well, then let me sing one for ya.
♪ When there's a - ♪
Hold it. Hold it.
- Oh-ho, Bobby!
- What? What?
- You quit that now.
- You said you're gonna help me pick a song.
- I did?
I'm gonna cut off
your damn water, Bobby, I swear.
Selfish.
You can play on the piano,
and your whole damn family...
can play on some type of musical instrument.
And all I'm askin' is for you
to help me improve my musical talent.
And you'd think you would.
Dipesto, why don't you
take that sign off your tit...
and why don't you and me go out
and have us a real good time?
Where are we goin'?
I don't know.
But I'll holler up to Elton and Stoney.
Bobby, now, listen a minute.
You know, I'll go out with you...
or... I'll stay in with you...
or I'll do anything
that you like for me to do...
if you will tell me that you love me.
You can sing the song.
You are never satisfied.
That's right.
Oh, honey, I'm sorry.
[Laughing]
[Cheering, Chattering]
All right. Here it is.
[Cheering]
They were all set up right for ya.
Get right in there, Dipesto.
- That's all you gotta do. Just relax, honey.
- [Woman] Come on, Rayette!
- Keep that left foot - The right - left foot forward.
- Bear down. Bear down.
Not too much of a match, is it, Elton?
You better leap out
with your right foot.
- In the gutter. Isn't that wonderful?
- The ball's too heavy for me, honey.
The pins, you know. I can't see them.
I can't make 'em out.
Just squint. I squint.
Well, there they are right down there.
They're at the end of all these little boards.
You notice 'em leadin' down.
Just spot and follow through.
- But there are so many of 'em.
- What's that for?
- That's for luck.
- Oh, you're crazy.
- Go on out there and show Ray how to do it.
- You slobbered on me.
[Chuckles]
It ain't the first time.
Watch this.
There she is. She's doing
a little variation on the Apache shift.
- I taught her that.
- [Shouting]
- Are you mad at me?
- No, I'm not mad at you, honey. It'll be all right.
- We're not excited.
- Look at me and tell me you're not mad at me.
I'm not mad at you.
[Chuckles]
- [Woman Shrieks]
- Whoo!
- Listen. I'm gonna show you how it gets done.
- Go on. Beat it.
- Don't talk about it - do it.
- Isn’t he pretty?
[Shrieking]
Good one!
Very good.
- [Groans]
- [Chuckles]
[Laughing]
Show me a little somethin' now.
Give me spirit. Give me something.
That stupid thing just goes
all cocky-wobbly, honey.
- If you'd just do what the hell I tell ya.
- I did! Didn't I, El?
You got another ball coming.
[Groans, Mutters]
- Come on, Rayette.
- Just relax, Ray. That's all.
- Attaboy, Ray!
- [Laughing]
That was real good, wasn't it?
I finally did it.
Great. You throw the big Z's for 19 frames...
and then you throw a strike
on the last ball of a losin' game.
Wonderful. Just wonderful.
Wasn't that wonderful, ladies?
- Are you talking to us?
- Wonderful.
I guess I'll go wait in the car.
Why don't you go wait in the car, Rayette?
I will. I'll wait there right now.
One minute, honey, and I'll go with ya.
Me and Stoney got to get on home,
relieve the sitter.
Why don't you and Ray
just come on by the place?
All right. Uh, why don't you go on?
Here. I'll, uh - I'll take care of the beers.
- And would you walk Rayette along with ya?
- Sure.
- Thanks, El.
- [Squeaks]
- Oh. Uh, what do we owe you?
- Four dollars, sir.
Okay.
- [Coins Clatter]
- Excuse me.
- Here's a five. Thanks very much.
- Thank you.
[Muttering]
We've been wanting to ask you.
You're on the TV, aren't ya?
[Chuckles]
Am I? On the TV?
She says you're the guy that sells
all the cars on... TV.
Well, I might have sold a few cars.
I told ya!
My name's Shirley, but they call me Betty.
And her name's Twinky.
- [Chuckling] Twinky?
- Yeah, 'cause she's so twinky!
[Laughing]
Boy, oh, boy.
Well, Betty and Twinky,
it, uh, sure is nice talking to you girls.
I wish that I had some more time.
- That's a wig you wear, isn't it?
- Me?
Yeah. I told her it was you,
but that you're wearing a wig...
'cause on TV you're mostly all, uh,
bald up there.
Yeah, your little friend's real - real sharp.
Well, I don't, uh -
I don't wear the wig on TV...
because if you're gonna be out there
in front of two and a half million people...
you've got to be sincere.
I mean, I like to wear it when
I'm in bowling alleys and slipping around.
Stuff like that. I think it gives me a little class.
What do you think?
- Oh, definitely.
- Yeah, but I can see a little bitty of the net up there.
That's what give it away.
A little net.
Yeah, well, I - I wish I had
more time to talk to you girls...
but, uh, I have to -
I'll, uh -
Come on, Ray.
We're gonna go over to Elton's.
I'm not.
You're just gonna sit here?
Yes.
Okay. I hope no one hits on you.
I hope they do.
Okay. See you later.
No one would want to hit on you.
You look too pathetic.
Come on, Dipesto.
We can still have a good time.
You're the pathetic one, not me.
I'm goin' over to Elton's.
I am not a piece of crap.
[Clicks Teeth]
I'm sorry.
You treat me like I was.
Go slip around...
right before my face.
And in front of Elton and Stoney that way.
What do you imagine they think of somebody
you treat like that?
[Clicks Teeth]
Now, now, Ray.
Now, sweetheart, Elton and Stoney
know that I love ya.
They're just gonna think
that I'm not too nice a guy, which I'm not...
and that you're a real hell of a good person
for puttin' up with me, that's all.
[Crying]
You'll just find me dead one time.
Just kill me.
Shh.
Come on, be a good girl.
You ever really get up and leave me...
you'll read about it in the newsprint.
I'm not gonna get up and leave you.
Now, come on.
Let's go over to Elton's and have a good time.
You love me, Bobby?
What do you think?
[Machinery Whirring]
[Man Speaking, Indistinct]
[Man, Indistinct]
Fuck.
You got banana on your face.
I do?
I still ain't figured out
how you got me workin' back out here.
I got you to come and work out here?
I ain't figured out how you let me get you
to come out here and work on these rigs.
I've never worked on these damn things before.
You've worked on 'em before.
I can't figure out
how you let me get us out here.
Somebody had to look out for you.
[Laughing]
You're a mess.
[Scoffs, Laughs]
You're crazy.
[Laughing]
[Steam Whistling]
- All right. I'm gonna bet two dollars right off.
- [Man] I'm in.
- I think you're bullshittin' me now.
- Well, I have to see it.
- What you got, Bill?
- A pair of nines.
- Can you beat two pair?
- There's three aces right there, natural -
- Oh, you pull me.
- I pull - I got me a hand!
I think it's time for me to go home.
See you in the mornin', boys.
- See you in the morning, Glenn.
- I don't know if I'm goin' out there
tomorrow at all, man.
I've - I got a - I got a lot of money
tied up in everything I got.
- [Mumbling, Blows Raspberry]
- [Laughing]
I don't want no chains going around
and all this.
It's all right, but I prefer card playing.
Where is it?
What the hell is goin' on
in the middle of this game?
People talkin' and all this.
We got money here or what?
[Together]
♪ Ride a cockhorse to Banbury Cross ♪
- ♪ To Banbury Cross we go ♪
- ♪ Tra-la ♪
Okay. When I was four, just four years old...
I went to my mother and I said,
"What's this hole in my chin?"
I saw this dimple in my chin in the mirror
and didn't know what it was.
And my mother said -
Guess what my mother says.
She says, "When you're born,
you go on an assembly line past God.
"And if he likes you, he says, 'You cute little thing,'
and you get dimples there.
And if he doesn't like you,
he goes, 'Go away."'
So, about six months later,
my mother found me saying my prayers...
and I was going,
"Now I lay me down to sleep."
My mother says,
"What are you covering up your chin for?"
And I said, "Because if I cover up the hole,
maybe he'll listen to me."
[Elton Grunts, Laughs]
♪ Ride a cockhorse to Banbury Cross ♪
- ♪ To Banbury Cross we go ♪
- ♪ Tra-la ♪♪
♪♪ [Ukulele Intro]
[Elton] ♪ Do you wanna buy a ticket
to the raffle of a dog ♪
♪ That comes a-runnin', lickin' ♪
♪ When you whistle
holler Claude ♪
♪ A big brown dog
just as sound as a ring ♪
♪ He'll be eight years old
if he lives to the spring ♪
"Unfit." I look unfit to you, Elton?
I'm fit! I'm fit.
♪ If you haven't got your ticket yet
well, you'd better order it ♪
♪ He'll wet your carpet
and he'll fertilize your grass ♪
♪ He's got three white feet
and a hole in his ass ♪♪
♪♪ [Ends]
Don't you know no songs
about women or nothin'?
[Chuckles]
Yeah, but I'm just too loaded to think of 'em now.
- Hey, watch out for all this traffic.
- Oh, God!
[Elton]
I ain't in no hurry.
Believe starting off your day like this,
goin' to work?
Unbelievable. Let me have a drink, will ya?
Thanks, Elton.
Ooh, boy, that's tough in the morning.
What the hell are these people doing here?
Isn’t this some goddamn thing, Elton?
Jesus Christ!
- [Horn Honking]
- [Mutters]
What does he want?
Boy, I can't stand this goddamn freeway.
[Honking Continues]
Oh, yeah, I heard ya!
Why don't you flash your lights so's
we can see what else you got for Christmas?
- [Honking Continues]
- Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Where you goin'?
- [Tires Screech]
- [Dog Barking]
Ants! Why don't we all line up
like a goddamn bunch of ants...
- in the most beautiful part
of the day and gas ourselves!
- [Barking]
[Barking, Snarling]
[Horn Honking]
Hey, get off my car.
[Horns Honking]
Hey, Bobby!
[Honking Continues]
♪♪ [Classical]
Oh, shit! What's he doing?
[Honking Continues]
♪♪ [Continues]
♪♪ [Ηumming]
Play it!
[Laughing]
You better quit foolin' around! Come on!
- [Tires Screech]
- Bobby, he's turning!
Will you hold your horses?
- ♪♪ [Continues]
- [Honking Continues]
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Child Crying]
I was with Elton last night, Rayette.
It's the truth.
Rayette.
You son of a bitch!
[Crying]
[Rayette] Now reach for it.
Come on, reach for it.
Come on.
It's good for you.
Come on. Let's go see Bob.
[Stoney]
I can't see!
[Crying]
- Isn’t he sweet?
- I can't see the set.
- You take him for a while. Go ahead now.
- How you doin'?
You oughta get yourself
one of them little things, Bobby.
[Crying]
Ah! That's it.
Just crush that one too,
then I won't get any.
[Man On TV]
Bless my soul. It's a new harmonica.
- [Woman On TV] That's for your birthday.
- [Man] My birthday?
How do you know when my birthday is?
I don't even know myself.
Bye, Stoney.
The kitchen's on fire, Stoney.
Your mother just died, Stoney.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye.
- See you, Elton.
- All right, Bob.
See you later. Thanks a lot.
[Man On TV]
Incidentally, what's his name?
[Rayette]
You just love that little baby, don't you?
Well, what if she was, Bob?
I can't see nothing so bad in that.
Well, what if I were to let you in
on a little secret that she is?
That's right. She told me.
She's all torn up about it too,
which I hate to see.
Oh, hell.
Isn’t it something you just have to face up to?
I'll tell ya, somewhere along the line
you even get to likin' the whole idea.
When Stoney first give me the news, I could've shit.
[Laughs]
Well, isn't that nice?
It's ridiculous! I'm sitting here
listening to some cracker asshole...
lives in a trailer park
compare his life to mine.
Keep on telling me about the good life, Elton,
because it makes me puke.
Well, if you're sayin' you think
you're something better than what I am...
now, that's somethin' else.
But I can't say much of someone
who could run off...
and leave a woman in a situation like this
and feel easy about it.
And that's all I have to say.
Well, I'm glad that's all you got to say, Elton...
because I'm about
as goddamned tired of your mouth...
as I am working on this goddamned job!
[Elton]
Shit-ass!
Hey, Longcipher!
Longcipher, I'm quittin'.
Do you hear me, Longcipher?
I said I'm quittin'.
I don't give a damn what you do.
I'm glad to get rid of both you dumb guys.
Hey! What's goin' on?
Hey!
Hey, what's goin' on?
[Grunting]
Don't do that, Bob.
It don't make sense!
They've got the right, Bob!
It's the law.
The law.
[Groans]
[Grunts]
[Grunting]
[Groans]
Hey, don't you think
you could just leave him?
I mean, sure as hell, If he'd have known
who you were, he wouldn't have done that.
- Would you, Bob?
- What the hell's goin' on, Elton?
All right. Let him go.
[Coughing]
What's goin' on, Elton?
I got accused of robbing a filling station
down in the Indian nation. Didn't I tell ya?
I just got wild and jumped my bail.
They come runnin' at me a whole year later.
Isn’t that somethin'?
Hey, tell Stoney for me, hear?
[Horn Honking]
♪♪ [Piano, Classical]
Hi. Miss Dupea?
Upstairs. Up those stairs.
♪♪ [Continues]
♪♪ [Woman Humming]
- ♪♪ [Piano, Classical]
- ♪♪ [Humming]
♪♪ [Humming Continues]
There she goes again.
My one-year-old can carry a tune
better than that.
Miss Dupea?
Miss Dupea.
- Yes?
- I'd like to remind you again...
that this is not an opera
or a musical comedy.
Oh.
I'm sorry. Was I singing again?
If you wanna call it that.
Well, you have simply to tell me.
That's all.
[Clears Throat]
That's exactly what I am doing again.
Must you let me get two-thirds
of the way through the movement?
This is tiring me.
I have another suggestion.
Why don't we take a break, Miss Dupea?
For pity sake.
- Is she gonna cry again?
- I don't want to take a break.
Some coffee. Uh, what would you like
in your coffee, Miss Dupea?
- Tea.
- One tea.
- Tell her Bobby's here.
- Bobby's here.
Oh, my goodness!
Robert Eroica.
[Crying]
I can't look at you.
Well, don't then.
You always do this to me.
Well, I don't mean to.
Here's your tea, Tita.
Thank you.
Don't put it there.
Why? What's wrong?
This is a very special CB 275.
No kidding.
It has absolutely
no objectionable idiosyncrasies.
♪♪ [Piano: The Spinning Song]
Robert, I have to talk seriously to you.
- Everybody still living up on the island?
- Well -
At the moment, there's really just...
Daddy, Carl and myself... and Van Oost.
- Who's Van Oost?
- Catherine.
She's a pianist. She's working with Carl.
Carl's a fiddler.
What's he doing coaching piano?
Well, 11 months ago...
he was on his bicycle on his way
to the post office in the village...
and he ran straight into a jeep
and sprained his neck.
[Scoffs]
Strained his neck?
That's not funny.
He permanently sprained his neck.
And since then, it's been extremely
painful for him to tuck the violin.
[Laughs]
Crashes into a jeep and totals his neck.
Robert.
I have - I have to tell you.
Daddy's very ill.
Oh?
- What?
- He's had two strokes.
He's not -
- They feel he - maybe he might not recover.
- Don't tell me about this.
But don't you think it's right...
that you should see him at least once?
- [Engineer] Miss Dupea.
- Just a minute, please.
Robert, don't you think it's right
you should see him?
Yeah. I guess so.
I'm going back up tonight.
Will you come with me?
No.
I-I'd rather drive up.
Maybe I'll go into Canada after.
I'm not gonna stay long, Tita.
You know, one week at the most.
I know.
♪♪ [Piano On Tape Playing Backwards]
Well.
Come on. I'll walk you out.
I'll be back in two minutes.
[Engineer]
We've had our break, Miss Dupea.
- They hate me, I feel.
- Maybe you'd better stay.
I want to talk to you about so many things.
I'll be seeing you in a couple of days.
I'm so glad.
Me too.
Bye.
[Betty Gasping, Moaning]
[Sighs]
[Heavy Breathing]
♪♪ [Record: Country]
[Tammy Wynette]
♪ Our little boy is four years old ♪
- Hello?
- ♪ And quite a little man ♪
♪ So we spell out the words we don't ♪
- You got the day off?
- ♪ Want him to understand ♪
♪ Like T-O-Y or maybe ♪
♪ S-U-R-P-R-I-S-E ♪
- Are you sick?
- ♪ But the words we're hiding from him now ♪
♪ Tear the heart right out of me ♪
- Guess you heard about Elton.
- ♪ Our D-I-V-O-R-C-E ♪
Okay, I got your point. I hope you didn't strain
yourself getting in here before I hit the back door.
♪ Me and little J-O-E ♪
♪ Will be goin' away♪
I have to go home.
My father's sick.
♪ And this will be pure
H-E-double-L for me ♪
- ♪ Oh, I wish ♪
- I'll be gone for two or three weeks.
- ♪ That we could stop this ♪
- You'll be gone, period.
♪ D-I-V-O-R-C-E ♪
♪ Watch him smile ♪
♪ He thinks it's Christmas ♪
♪ Or his fifth birthday ♪
- ♪ And he thinks C-U-S-T-O-D-Y ♪
- I'll try and call you from up there.
♪ Spells fun or play ♪
- [Crying]
- ♪ I spell out all the hurtin' words ♪
- ♪ And turn my head when I speak ♪
- Come on, Dipesto.
I never told you it'd work out to anything.
Did I?
I'll send you some money.
That's all I can do.
I'll try and call you from up there.
♪ Me and little J-O-E ♪
- Bye, Ray.
- ♪ Will be goin' away♪
♪ I love you both and this will be pure ♪
♪ H-E-double-L for me ♪
♪ Oh, I wish that we could -♪♪
[Shouting, Swearing]
♪♪ [Continues, Stops]
You wanna go with me?
♪♪ [Country Intro]
[Tammy Wynette]
♪ When there's a fire in your heart ♪
♪ Break the glass, sound the alarm
Follow me ♪
♪ I'll be there ♪
♪ Instant service, speedy fast
I was your first, I'll be your last ♪
♪ No matter who you have in between ♪
♪ When there's a fire in your heart
break the glass, sound the alarm ♪
♪ When she's not all she seems ♪
♪ Instant service, speedy fast
I was your first, I'll be your last ♪
♪ No matter who you have in between ♪♪
♪ There's been hot spells and cold spells
ever since we met ♪
♪ I've seen your big fires, your small fires
but I won't give up yet ♪
♪ Oh, someday you'll yearn
'cause your heart's gonna burn ♪
♪ For that old familiar glow ♪
- ♪ You'll be first - ♪
- [Chuckles]
- Like it?
- I love it.
♪ You'll be burned out
or smoked out ♪
♪ And come back to me ♪
♪ I know ♪♪
- What the hell are they doing?
- Is that - Is that an accident?
- Who was - Who was driving?
- "Who was driving?" You were driving.
Hey, what the hell's going on?
Rotate, mack!
Look at my car. Look at my car.
I just bought it brand-new from a used car lot,
and the steering goes to pot on me.
- You're lucky nobody was hurt.
- Can you give us a lift?
Come on, Terry. We got a ride.
You're gonna give those people a lift?
- Well, I can't just leave 'em here.
- I'd like to go back...
and punch the son of a bitch
in the used car lot out.
Jesus! What a rude person.
- What's your name?
- Palm Apodaca.
- Terry Grouse.
What?
How far are you going to?
Washington.
We'll get off in Washington.
We'll hook a ride.
Where are you going?
Alaska.
Alaska? What, are you on vacation?
She wants to live there because it's cleaner.
Cleaner? Cleaner than what?
You don't have to tell everybody about it.
Pretty soon they'll all go, and it won't be so clean.
What makes you think it's cleaner?
I saw a picture of it. Alaska's very clean.
It appeared to look very white to me.
Don't you think?
Yep. But that was before the big thaw.
Before the what?
I had to leave this place
because I got depressed seeing all the crap.
And the thing is,
they're making more crap, you know.
They got so many stores and stuff
and junk full of crap.
- I can't believe it.
- Who?
Who? Man, that's who.
Pretty soon there won't be any room for man.
They're selling more crap
that people go and buy than you can imagine.
[Scoffs]
Crap.
I believe everybody should have a big hole
where they throw the stuff in and burn it.
They'd never find a hole big enough. Never.
Now, take me now. Look at me.
When I was just one person -
before I was with Bobby -
I was collecting onto me
more garbage every day...
till I was getting to thinkin'
that I should get a disposal.
Disposal?
What's that but more crap?
I've never seen such crap.
- Mass production is what does it.
- What do you mean, mass?
I have to come out and tell you the truth.
You're not that clean either.
Wait a minute.
I'm not that neat maybe, but I am clean.
Well, you're not that bad.
But some people.
[Scoffs]
People's homes - just filth.
I've been in people's homes -
In my personal observation,
I think that more people are neat than are clean.
My personal thing, I don't see that.
I'm seeing more filth. A lot of filth.
What they need to do every day -
No, once in a while -
is do a cockroach thing,
you know, where they spray the homes.
Can you imagine if their doors were painted
a pretty color, and they had a pot outside?
- Yeah, could be adorable.
- And they picked up.
Then it wouldn't be filthy
with Coke bottles and whiskey and, uh -
Those signs everywhere -
they should be erased!
All those signs selling you crap
and more crap and more crap.
I - I don't know. I don't know.
I don't even want to talk about it.
- Well -
- It's just filthy! People are filthy.
I think that's the biggest thing
that's wrong with people.
I think they wouldn't be as violent
if they were clean...
because then they wouldn't
have anybody to pick on.
[Scoffs]
Dirt.
Not dirt. See, dirt isn't bad.
It's filth. Filth is bad.
That's what starts maggots and riots.
Hey, follow that truck.
They know the best places to stop.
That's an old maid's tale.
Bullshit!
Truck drivers are the only ones
that know the best places to stop on the road.
Salesmen and cops are the ones.
If you'd ever waitressed, honey, you'd know that.
- Don't call me honey, mack.
- Don't call me mack, honey.
I wouldn't be a waitress.
They're nasty and full of crap.
You just hold on to your tongue!
Hold on to this.
- [Laughing]
- If you think that you can talk to me like that -
Shut up! All of ya.
[Horn Honking]
I'd like a, uh, plain omelet,
no potatoes, tomatoes instead...
a cup of coffee and wheat toast.
No substitutions.
What do you mean?
You don't have any tomatoes?
Only what's on the menu.
You can have a number two, a plain omelet.
It comes with cottage fries and rolls.
I know what it comes with,
but it's not what I want.
- Well, I'll come back when you make up your mind.
- Wait a minute.
I have made up my mind.
I'd like a plain omelet.
No potatoes on the plate.
A cup of coffee and a side order of wheat toast.
I'm sorry, we don't have
any side orders of toast.
I'll give you an English muffin
or a coffee roll.
What do you mean you don't
make side orders of toast?
You make sandwiches, don't you?
- Would you like to talk to the manager?
- Hey, mack!
Shut up.
You've got bread and a toaster of some kind?
I don't make the rules.
Okay, I'll make it as easy for you as I can.
I'd like an omelet, plain...
and a chicken salad sandwich on wheat toast.
No mayonnaise, no butter, no lettuce,
and a cup of coffee.
A number two - chicken sal san...
hold the butter, the lettuce
and the mayonnaise.
And a cup of coffee. Anything else?
Yeah. Now all you have to do
is hold the chicken, bring me the toast...
give me a check for the chicken salad sandwich,
and you haven't broken any rules.
You want me to hold the chicken, huh?
I want you to hold it between your knees.
[Snickering]
You see that sign, sir?
Yes, you all have to leave. I'm not taking
any more of your smartness and sarcasm!
- You see this sign?
- [Gasps]
Fantastic that you could figure that all out
and lie that down on her...
so you could come up with
a way to get your toast.
- Fantastic!
- Yeah? Well, I didn't get it, did I?
No. But it was very clever.
I would have just punched her out.
People.
[Scoffs]
Animals are not like that. Mm-mmm.
They're always cleaning themselves.
Did you ever see, um...
pigeons?
Well, he's always picking
on himself and his friends.
They're always picking bugs
out of their hair all the time.
Monkeys too.
Except they do something
out in the open that I don't go for.
You know, I read where they
invented this car that runs on, um -
that runs on, um -
When you boil water?
- Steam.
- Right, steam.
A car that you could ride around in
and not cause a stink.
But do you know
they will not even let us have it?
Can you believe it?
Why? Man!
He likes to create a stink.
I mean, I've seen filth
that you wouldn't believe.
[Scoffs]
What a stink.
I don't even want to talk about it.
♪♪ [Country Intro]
♪ When there's a fire in your heart
break the glass, sound the alarm ♪
♪ When she's not all she seems ♪
♪ Instant service, speedy fast
I was your first, I'll be your last ♪
♪ No matter who you have in between ♪
♪ When there's a fire in your heart
break the glass, sound the alarm ♪
♪ Follow me ♪
♪ I'll be there ♪♪
You depressed about your daddy, hon?
No.
I imagine it's me then, isn't it?
Is what you?
Are you depressed I come along?
Who says I'm depressed?
Is that a happy face I see?
'Cause if it is,
I'll just catch a Greyhound back.
Oh, you're not gonna kill yourself this time.
I wish I'd known.
[Switch Clicks]
[Sighs]
Well...
I don't know if I'm gonna be able
to get to sleep.
Hint, hint.
[Exhales, Sighs]
Guess I'll have to count the sheep.
One, two...
three, four...
five, six...
seven -
Look at this ol' cold shoulder.
What am I going to do about it?
You know, if you wouldn't open your mouth,
everything would be just fine.
- Tick-a-lock!
- [Chuckles]
Why can't I come out with you
to your family's house?
Now you give me one good reason.
I have to see what's going on first.
My father's sick. You understand?
They wouldn't be prepared
for my bringing anyone.
So how long do I have to sit
and twiddle my thumbs in that place?
Look, Ray, if you can't do
what I'm asking you...
why don't you just take the money
and go on back south with it?
Oh, now, hon, don't talk like that.
Look, will you try and understand?
This is not something that I want to do.
Jesus Christ! You ought to know me
well enough for that.
All right, hon.
It'll be all right.
I mean, there's stuff for me to do.
They got magazines in there
and TV, right?
Yeah. I'll try and call you
in a couple of days.
All right.
Bye.
[Clattering]
- [Ship Horn Blows]
- [Seagulls Squawking]
[Bell Clanging]
[Ship Horn Blows]
♪♪ [Piano, Faint]
♪♪ [Piano Continues: Classical]
♪♪ [Piano Continues]
[Scissors Snipping]
He doesn't even know
who the hell I am.
[Silverware Clattering]
- How long has it been since -
- Remember Mother used to say, "Bobby" -
- Excuse me.
- Go ahead.
I was just going to ask Robert how long
it had been since he's been away from here.
Three years.
No, no, no. It's more
like two years, isn't it? Hmm?
Oh, it's been more than that, Carl.
Tita, you have no sense of timing
away from the piano, dear.
I don't think that's true.
It's true.
What have you been doing since then?
Odd jobs of work here and there.
Nothing too interesting.
You no longer play at all?
[Carl] You know, Robert,
before my misfortune -
I'm not sure you're aware of my accident,
Robert. Mm-hmm?
Yeah. Tita was telling me about it.
Well, you know, it's very difficult for me
to turn my neck.
This way especially. If I -
For instance, if I want to look at Catherine...
I have to shift the whole base
of my body around this way.
- Hmm?
- I was real sorry to hear about it, Carl.
- I said I was real sorry to hear about it.
Anyway, as I was saying -
Catherine, what was I saying?
Hmm?
You were saying something...
about something that happened
around the time of the accident.
Oh! Yes. Just before the accident...
just after I'd come off tour
with the Betanthaller Quartet...
Father and Herbert and I had a summit
conference concerning you, mm-hmm.
Oh, my. A summit conference.
Where was I, I wonder?
Polishing silver behind the coal bin?
Well, I don't know where you were, penis envy.
[Laughs]
I hope I didn't hear that.
[Laughing] Nevertheless, they wanted
to hire a detective to ferret you out...
and I talked them out of it, because I felt
that whatever you were doing...
you had a perfect right to do, no matter
how nonsensical your adventures might be.
- It was as simple as that, Robert.
- Well, I really appreciate it, Carl.
I don't think you ought to imply
that Daddy was wrong in front of Daddy.
Don't force him that way, Spicer.
[Clears Throat]
How long have you been here?
Um, only two months.
Well, satiety is my father and mother. Hmm?
[Laughs]
- Carl?
- Mmm?
If you're finished,
I think I'd like to go do some work.
Oh, certainly, dear.
Excuse me. See you later.
I hope you feel right at home, Robert.
I feel fine.
♪♪ [Piano, Classical]
♪♪ [Piano Continues]
He has ways of communicating, Robert.
I can tell when he's expressing
approval or disapproval...
just from his eyes.
Yeah. Some range.
I can't take much more
of seeing him sitting there like a stone.
- It's not that bad.
- Yes, it is.
Will you stay a while?
I don't know.
[Dog Barking In Distance]
♪♪ [Piano, Classical]
[Chattering]
Mmm.
- ♪♪ [Piano]
- ♪♪ [Catherine Vocalizing In Tune]
♪♪ [Carl Vocalizing]
Now, breathe!
- ♪♪ [Catherine Continues Vocalizing]
- All right! ♪♪ [Vocalizing]
♪♪ [Both Hit High Note]
[Carl]
Now, once more. Once more.
[Parking Brake Sets]
- Hello.
- Hi.
Been lookin' all over for you.
You have? I went riding.
- Riding?
- Mm-hmm.
That's dangerous, you know.
- Riding?
- Mm-hmm.
You play the piano all day and then
jump on a horse, you could get cramps.
[Chuckling]
Well, I like to ride.
Rain or shine,
I do it any chance I can get.
- It's very invigorating.
- Is it?
Yes.
Well, I don't like to get
too invigorated myself.
- You don't?
- Mm-mmm.
What else do you do?
Well, there's fishing, boating.
There's concerts on the mainland.
[Sighs] I feel silly telling you this.
This is really your home.
You probably know better than I
what there is to do.
Nothing.
- ♪♪ [Piano]
- Nothing?
Nothing.
Well, it must be very boring for you here.
That's right.
I find that hard to comprehend.
I don't think I've ever been bored.
Excuse me.
♪♪ [Piano Continues]
What are you doing right now?
Right now I plan to take a hot tub
and soak myself.
And then after that?
After that, mmm, I plan to read some music
and rest for a while.
Tomorrow then?
Tomorrow?
Tomorrow's a full practice day.
But the day after tomorrow
I will be free.
Carl has hydrotherapy on Tuesdays.
- The day after tomorrow?
- Will you be free?
Yeah, I'll probably be free.
♪♪ [Piano Continues]
[Father Belches]
[Mouths Words]
One thing
I find very difficult to imagine...
is how one could have this
incredible background in music...
and then just walk away from it
without giving it a second thought at all.
I gave it a second thought.
I mean, how could you no longer play at all?
I think that's very strange.
I've played a little bit here and there.
As a matter of fact,
once I was a... rehearsal pianist.
For a ballet? An opera?
Las Vegas musical revue.
- [Laughing] You don't call that music.
- Oh, yes, I do.
It's music, you know?
♪♪ [Imitates Fanfare]
♪♪ [Continues Vocalizing]
♪ Bring on the girls
are singing you a song ♪
♪ And off with the
Hey, I'm gonna show ♪
[Rapid Chattering, Indistinct]
♪ Lepers and clowns ♪
♪ I'm a Las Vegas belly dancer with a ♪
[Rapid Chattering, Indistinct]
♪♪ [Singing, Indistinct]
♪ Girls, girls ♪
- If you're not feeling good-
- [Carl Chattering]
[Chuckles]
More gingerbread?
[Clears Throat]
No, thank you.
♪♪ [Piano, Classical]
Applesauce?
♪♪ [Piano Continues]
[Rain Falling]
[Loud Thud]
[Exhales]
- ♪♪ [Violin]
- [Mutters]
You know what I suggest, Ray.
Yeah. Well, that's-that's what I suggest...
because I don't know
how long it's gonna be.
♪♪ [Ends]
I have to go now.
I have to get off now, Ray.
[Sighs]
Yeah. Well -
Uh, I'll try and call you
in a couple of days.
If you're gone, you're gone.
Bye.
[Handset Rests In Cradle]
Robert, shh!
My playing put Father to sleep.
Would you help me with this, please?
That's it. Ooh!
- You sure you should be playing, Carl?
- [Groans]
What do you mean? I'm in superb shape -
except for my neck. Hmm?
Well, there's something funny
about the way you move.
I'm not aware of - What do you mean?
2-18.
I'd hate to see you walk across
a concert stage like that.
- Oh! [Chuckles]
- 2-19.
I'd get somebody to coach you
on how to walk if I was you, Carl.
I think it's a substantial problem.
[Chuckles Softly]
Damn it.
Look at that.
[Chuckles]
- Why are you being so mean?
- Mean? I'm not being mean.
He does walk funny.
Don't you see that?
- He's walking around -
- [Laughing]
I don't think I'd notice.
I'm so used to Carl.
Yeah, well -
[Laughs]
Bobby, do you think Spicer
is attractive?
I think he's got a terrific personality.
[Tita]
Spicer was formerly a sailor.
Look. [Chuckles]
Don't you see that? Look at that.
The guy's -
[Chuckling]
Sailors are sadistic, I feel.
You see? There's nothing particularly
wrong with my walk, hmm?
- Now, where were we?
- At game, Carl.
[Chuckles]
[Tita Laughs]
Well, that's three games to "Z," Carl.
Well, what do you say
about a rematch, Robert? Hmm?
I thought you were going to the mainland today.
You'll miss the ferry.
Just when I was hitting my stride.
Say good-bye to Catherine
for me, will you?
Can I play now?
Tell her I'll be back sometime
tomorrow probably, will you?
- [Car Door Opens]
- Where is she, anyway?
- [Car Door Closes]
- Who? Oh.
- [Engine Starts]
- Shopping in the village.
My turn.
Yeah, why don't you and Spicer play.
[Car Departing]
Spicer.
Hi.
Hello.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
Robert?
Would you do something for me?
Would you play for me?
- [Door Opens]
- [Tita] Catherine, your game!
[Tita]
Catherine?
Will you?
♪♪ [Piano: Chopin's Prelude in E Minor,
Opus 28, No. 4]
♪♪ [Piano Continues]
That was beautiful, Robert.
I'm surprised.
Thank you.
I was really very moved by -
[Laughs]
What's wrong?
Nothing. It's just, um -
I picked the easiest piece
that I could think of...
and I first played it when I was eight years old,
and I played it better then. [Chuckles]
Can't you understand it was
the feeling I was affected by?
I didn't have any.
- You had no inner feeling?
- None.
Well, then, I must have been supplying it.
Maybe if you'd supply a little more,
it might rub off on me. Who knows?
I doubt it.
Oh, I could get interested.
Well, I couldn't.
- [Door Slams]
- [Footfalls Retreating]
♪♪ [Single Note]
What does it have to be with you?
Grim and serious?
Look, you played...
I honestly responded...
and you made me feel embarrassed
for having responded to you.
- It wasn't necessary.
- Yeah, it was.
I faked a little Chopin,
you faked a big response.
[Chuckling]
I don't think that's accurate.
Up till now, all I've been getting from you
is meaningful looks at the dinner table...
and a lot of vague suggestions
about the day after tomorrow.
I am not conscious of having given you
any particular looks.
And as for the day after tomorrow,
this is the day after tomorrow.
And I am, unfortunately, seeing you.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I'd like to take a bath.
- What the hell do you want anyway?
- I'm getting some bath oil.
- Some bath oil?
- Mm-hmm.
How about some avocado or some of this?
Or some of this jasmine? How about this?
- How about any -
- [Shouts] What are you doing?
What are you doing screwing around
with all this crap?
I do not find your language
very charming.
It isn't. It's direct.
I'd like you to leave
so that I can take a bath.
Is that direct?
[Bottle Rolls On Floor]
Serious?
Is that what's important to you?
Yes, that's what's important to me.
- Okay, let's be serious. Sit down.
- No, don't do that.
Shut up!
No inner feeling.
I told him the truth finally.
He was my husband,
and I loved him very much.
But my God.
[Laughs]
It wasn't working any better
the second time than it did the first.
He was a cellist.
And there was I...
no longer 17, looking up at him.
And I said to him...
"Joseph, you're full of beans,"
and I left him.
[Laughs]
Is that what you said to him?
Something like that.
As a matter of fact, Joseph introduced me
to Carl right around then.
How are you?
I'm incredible.
Carl restored me. He really did.
He's much more substantial
than you give him credit for being.
Do you think you could discreetly
move across the hall now?
Yes, I think I could discreetly move
across the hall now.
- [Door Opens]
- Robert?
I have free time tomorrow morning
before Carl gets back - if you'd like.
Of course I'd like it.
- ♪♪ [Piano, Classical]
- [Catherine Shouts, Indistinct]
- [Growls]
- [Laughing] Bananas, bananas!
[Parking Brake Sets]
You certainly do have a beautiful
piece of real estate out here, Mr. Dupea.
Can he hear me?
He's not hard of hearing.
Oh. Well, that's a blessing at least.
This certainly is an improvement
on the motel and the coffee shop.
How could you ever have left
such a beautiful place, Bobby?
I don't know.
You mean you've been staying
in a motel all this time?
For two whole weeks, and there wasn't
hardly nobody there to talk to but me.
But I don't understand.
Why did you stay at the motel?
- There's plenty of room here.
- Well, I was goin' to...
but Bobby had to kinda come up here,
he said, and feel it up here first.
But then it took so long,
I run flat out of money.
You know, you didn't leave me
any number or anything, honey.
And I had to, you know,
get in a taxi and come on out here...
in the hopes that I would not be
intrudin' myself.
Oh, no, not at all, dear.
You're perfectly welcome to stay here.
Well, thank you.
That's a very nice thing for you to say.
[Chuckles]
Not at all.
You certainly do have
a beautiful head of hair.
Thank you.
- Is it natural?
- [Bobby] Rayette.
What?
Just finish eating.
Oh, am I holdin' up dessert?
No, no, not at all.
Take all the time you want.
I do eat slow as a bird.
Whereas Bobby can pack it away
like a speed swing.
- Is there any ketchup around?
- Oh, for God's sake!
Robert, please, let's not be rude, hmm?
It's okay.
He didn't mean anything by that.
I don't, huh?
[Door Slams Shut]
Bobby's just about the moodiest man
I've ever been with.
[Car Engine Starts, Departs]
[Tammy Wynette On Jukebox]
♪ That you might ♪
♪ Take away ♪
- ♪ To have you ♪
- [Man] Oh, yeah.
♪ Then lose you ♪
♪ Oh, wouldn't be smart ♪
♪ On my part ♪
♪ Don't open the door♪
♪ To heaven ♪
♪ If I can't come in ♪
♪ Oh, don't touch me ♪
♪ If you don't love me ♪
♪ Sweetheart ♪♪
[Boat Motor Idling]
[Seagulls Squawking]
[Coughing]
[Ship Horn Blowing]
- Are you all right?
- Where are you going?
I'm going to pick up some friends
of Carl's and mine.
- I want to talk to you.
- I'll be back later.
No, I want to talk to you right now.
I want to explain -
- No, it isn't necessary.
- [Horns Honking]
- Yes, it is. Yes, it is.
- You don't have to do that.
Come on, get moving!
- Will you shut up?
- Come on!
[Catherine]
Robert, I have to go.
Catherine, will you just
wait one minute?
- [Horns Honking]
- [People Shouting]
I haven't been being fair to Carl.
I have to tell you that.
- [Horns Honking Loudly]
- [Mutters] Why do you have to tell me that?
What? I can't hear you.
- [Ship Horn Blowing]
- [Horns Honking]
I'm sorry everything's been so confusing.
I'll see you later this evening.
- [Ship Horn Continues Blowing]
- [Thunderclap]
But, you see, man is born into the world
with his existent adversary from the first.
It is his historic, mythic inheritance.
So, is this startling?
Aggression is prehistoric.
An organism behaves according to its nature.
And its nature derives from
the circumstances of its inheritance.
The fact remains that primitive man
took absolute delight...
in tearing his adversary apart.
And there is where I think
the core of the problem resides.
Doesn't that seem
unnecessarily apocalyptic?
I do not make poetry.
Is there a TV in the house?
[Thunderclap]
I remarked to John that rationality
is not a device to alter facts.
But moreover, I think of it
as an extraneous tool, a gadget.
Somewhat like, uh, the television.
To look at it any other way
is ridiculous.
There's some good things on it though.
- I beg your pardon?
- The TV.
There's some good things on it sometimes.
I have strong doubts.
Nevertheless, I am not discussing media.
- Oh, but there is always hope for the few.
- What about love?
What about it?
Wouldn't you say that more ill...
has been done in the name of love
than in the name of abomination?
No. No, I wouldn't.
Well, you are a romantic, Catherine.
And once more
about to be married.
So you can be excused
from objective discussions. But ask Carl.
Ask him if even the institution of marriage
is completely free from it.
Ask him.
I think these cold, objective
discussions are aggressive.
- Excuse me.
- That's reactive.
- [Thunderclap]
- But if I may say...
without dampening
the spirit of your adventure -
You haven't dampened my spirit, Samia.
- Excuse me.
- Well, I should hope not.
But I want to say, though,
it's still open to some discussion -
- I'm sorry. [Speaking French]
- that there seems to be less aggression...
- or violence, if you like -
- I'm sorry. I don't speak French.
- the higher classes and loftier natures -
- [Dog Barks]
What kind of doggy is this?
- [Carl] This is a, uh, border collie.
- [Continues, Indistinct]
- I had a baby kitty-cat once.
- [Samia Continues]
It was a little fluffy thing.
Bobby gave it to me.
- Remember, Bobby?
- [Indistinct, Stops]
Little pussycat you gave me?
Yeah.
It had two little white front paws.
And, oh, I was crazy after her.
We left her at some friends' house...
and she got squashed flatter than
a tortilla right outside their mobile home.
There. Do you see what I mean?
The choice of words juxtaposed
with the image of a fluffy kitten.
The enchantment of words -
"squashed," "flat," etcetera, etcetera.
Well, she was.
Well, perhaps, but it was
just what I was trying to point out.
Don't sit there pointing at her.
I beg your pardon?
- I said, don't point at her, you creep.
- But I was just telling about -
Where the hell do you get the ass
to tell anybody anything about class...
or who the hell's got it
or what she typifies?
You shouldn't even be in the same room
with her, you pompous celibate.
- Carl, this is really too much.
- Just calm down -
You're totally full of shit!
You're all full of shit!
- [Thunderclap]
- [Rain Falling]
Catherine!
Catherine.
- Bobby -
- I can't talk to you. Leave me alone.
Catherine?
[Tita Chattering]
- What the hell is goin' on in here?
- What are you doing?
[Spicer Muttering]
- Hey, where is Catherine?
- Hey, get out of - This is my room.
- I don't know where Catherine is.
- [Arguing, Indistinct]
I'm talking to you -
I'm talking to you, Tita!
- Be polite, will you?
- I told you to take your hands off my sister, nurse!
- Move out!
- Stop it!
[Tita]
Stop it! Stop it!
- Whoa. Will you - Hold it!
- [Tita Screams]
Take it easy. Take -
Take it easy, will you?
[Tita Screaming, Indistinct]
- You stop it!
- Will you give up?
- [Glass Shatters]
- Stop!
- Will you give up, please? Give up, will you?
- Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
- Give up!
- [Tita] No!
Give up! Give up! Give up!
[Tita]
Bobby!
[Panting]
I just wanted to talk to you.
It's useless.
Look, give me a chance.
I'm trying to be delicate with you...
but you just won't understand.
I couldn't go with you -
not just because of Carl and my music,
but because of you.
You're a strange person, Robert.
I mean, what will you come to?
If a person has no love for himself,
no respect for himself...
no love of his friends,
family, work, something...
how can he ask for love in return?
I mean, why should he ask for it?
Living here in this rest home, asylum -
that's what you want?
Yes.
That will make you happy?
I hope it will. Yes.
I'm sorry.
[Bird Squawking]
Okay.
[Dog Barking In Distance]
Are you cold?
[Sighs]
I don't know if you'd be...
particularly interested
in hearing anything about me.
My life - I mean...
most of it doesn't add up
to much that I could relay it...
as a way of life
that you'd approve of.
I move around a lot.
Not because I'm looking
for anything really, but -
'Cause I'm getting away
from things that get bad...
if I stay.
Auspicious beginnings -
you know what I mean?
[Sighs]
I'm trying to imagine your -
your half of this conversation.
[Clears Throat]
My feeling is - I don't know -
that, uh, if you could talk,
we wouldn't be talking.
That's pretty much the way
that it got to be before I left.
Are you all right?
I don't know what to say.
[Gasping]
Tita suggested that we try to -
I don't know.
I think that she feels -
I think that she feels that we've got
some understanding to reach.
She totally denies the fact
that we were never that comfortable...
with one another to begin with.
The best that I can do is apologize, and -
We both know that I was never
really that good at it anyway.
I'm sorry it didn't work out.
- Bobby!
- [Rain Falling]
- You're leaving.
- Yeah.
I said a week.
I think I overstayed myself.
You were going
without saying good-bye to me.
[Sighs] I didn't want
to say good-bye to anyone.
What about me?
I'll say good-bye to you, Tita.
Oh, Robert.
[Rain Stops]
- [Rayette] Watch the birdie.
- [Shutter Clicks]
- Bye.
- Come on.
- Wait a sec.
- I want to go.
- I want Tita to take a picture...
- of you and me in front of the place.
- [Bobby Mutters]
Listen, I never got to thank y'all
for your hospitality.
You tell Carl for me if any of you want
to come down to our place anytime...
you'd be more than welcome.
Bye now.
[Rayette]
♪ Your kiss is like ♪
♪ A drink ♪
♪ When I am thirsty ♪
♪ Oh, and I'm thirsty ♪
♪ For you ♪
♪ With all my heart ♪
♪ But don't love me then pretend ♪
♪ As though we've never kissed ♪
♪ Don't touch me ♪
♪ Don't touch - ♪♪
Cut it out!
Son of a bitch, Bobby!
You quit pushing me away like that!
I've had enough of that
to last me an entire lifetime.
Why don't you just be good to me
for a change?
There isn't anybody gonna look after you
and love you as good as I do.
Did you hear me?
Baby?
[Lever Clicks]
[Gas Pump Bell Dings]
I'm-I'm goin' in that café
for some coffee.
You want anything?
No.
You got any change?
You don't have any change?
[Shouting]
Sure you don't want anything?
Fill it up, will you?
[Gas Pump Bell Dings]
[Air Brakes Hiss]
[Coughing]
Hey, wait a minute.
[No Audible Dialogue]
Haven't you got a jacket
or anything with you?
Oh, no. Uh -
Jesus. Uh - It got burned up.
Everything in the car
got the shit burned out of it.
Uh, everything.
All I've got is what I've got on.
I got one behind the seat.
If you want it, put it on.
No, it's okay.
Suit yourself.
I'll tell you one thing.
Where we're goin',
it's gonna get colder than hell.
- No, that's okay.
- [Knobs Clicking]
I'm fine.
[Gas Pump
Bell Dings]