I'm inviting you for breakfast.
I can't. I have to go to church.
Well, after church, then.
Come on,
we haven't seen you for so long.
Why don't you put this on, please, I...
I don't want your
little baby to get sick.
It's so cold out.
- Come on.
- OK.
OK?
Hmm?
You'll come?
Oh, yeah.
Great.
- Could you put the whole thing on?
- Oh, yeah.
See you.
- You owe me five dollars.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Well, not till he's
sitting at the table,
I don't owe you anything, there, baby.
Something's going on with him.
I'm worried.
Well, you keep saying that.
I think your...
I think your maternal instincts
might be kicking in.
In all the world,
there are books and books
and books of laws.
But in all this world,
there really is only one law.
We need never ask,
"Lord, what should I do?"
Because the Lord has told us what to do.
Love one another.
That, my friends, is the one true law.
Love is God in action.
The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ,
the love of God,
the fellowship of the Holy Spirit
be with you all now and forever more.
- Amen.
- That was a nice service, dear.
- That was nice, yes.
Hi, Mrs. Gruner.
Do you want some help?
Oh, thank you, dear.
It's my turn
to drop them off at the hospital.
Yeah.
You know,
you're a good-looking fellow, Lars.
- Where's your girlfriend?
- I don't have one.
- Are you gay?
- No.
My grandson's gay.
I know all about the gays.
Yeah, I know, but I'm not gay, so...
Well, don't leave it too long.
It's not good for you.
OK.
Here.
Give this to somebody nice. For a start.
Hello, Lars.
I guess...
I'll see you at work tomorrow.
Yeah, OK, bye.
Karin, my brother is 27 years old.
Maybe he wants to be left alone.
- That's not what he wants.
- Oh, really? Hey. Go.
- How do you know that, exactly?
- Because that's not how people are.
Oh, there he goes.
Lars! Come on, you promised!
- Is that normal?
- Five dollars.
- Morning.
- Good morning, Cindy.
Did you have a nice weekend?
That new girl's kind of cute, huh?
You and Margo, what do you think?
Lars, Lars, you gotta see this.
I'm not really in the mood
for porn this morning.
It's not porn.
OK, it is, but check it out, all right?
Huh? You like?
Man, they're solid.
Like, if she'd weigh 125 pounds,
then she weighs 125 pounds.
- Is that right?
- You can customize everything.
They got all these different heads
and parts.
You can design your own woman.
- And, Lars?
- Uh-huh.
- Lars.
- Yeah.
They're anatomically correct.
- You're not going to buy one, are you?
- I wish.
Look how much they cost.
I'm wiped out from the new Xbox.
Morning.
- Morning.
- Oh, hey! Yeah. Morning.
Margo's here, everybody. Hurray.
Could you put the headset on?
Hey, I was thinking,
we're the only ones from the lake.
We could carpool.
- Lars, it's your day for coffee, buddy.
- Oh, yeah.
You know what your problem is, Margo?
You're just too aggressive.
Just chillax, you know.
Shut up.
Wait! Stop! Stop!
Karin!
What? What?
We want you to come for dinner.
Will you come?
- You scared me.
- Sorry.
- Oh, sweetheart, sorry.
Wait.
- It's OK. I can't. I can't.
- Wait, why not? No!
Why not? Come on, Lars, we miss you.
Yeah.
I brought my work home so I have to...
I'll get in trouble.
No, you didn't.
Yeah. Did you hear that?
That's my phone I think.
No. Come on! Wait! Wait!
Lars, stop! Stop!
- Come on, please?
- I have other plans.
- No.
- And I can't.
Lars, there's salmon
and cherry pie in there.
- Could you please let me go?
- No.
OK.
- Is that all you can eat?
- Yeah, that was delicious. Thank you.
- No, no, you stay there.
- No, I can take...
No, it's my turn.
You boys talk.
OK, Karin's been worried about you.
She thinks you've got a problem because
you spend so much time by yourself.
- I'm fine.
- That's what I told her.
- Exactly what I said.
- OK.
Dad was kind of like that, too, so...
Yeah, but he didn't really want
anyone around, so that's the difference.
That's not true.
OK, you know, yeah, sure,
maybe after Mom died.
But, you know,
you didn't know him before that.
I mean, not that you could have,
but, I'm just saying.
Karin and I would really like it
if you moved in.
Oh, that's... No, that's OK. Thank you.
- The house is half yours.
- Yeah, I know that. I'm fine. Thanks.
Just putting it out there.
- Well, good night. Sleep tight.
- Good night.
Oh, wait.
Here are some leftovers for you.
- Do you have my blanket?
- Oh, yeah.
- I'll get it. I'll get it.
- It's on the...
- Grab these.
- Thanks.
I'll be right back.
It's a beautiful blanket.
- Gus says your mother made it for you.
- Yeah.
When she was pregnant.
Well, she must have loved you very much.
Like we do.
- Are you mad at me?
- Is he coming?
- Here we go. Good night.
- Thanks, good night.
What? We talked. He's fine.
- Hello?
- Hey, Lars. It's Karin.
They just delivered a huge box for you.
It's in the garage.
- Oh, OK. Thanks.
- OK, bye.
Thanks.
That's a nice sweater.
Hey. Come on in.
That's OK.
Is Karin gonna come to the door?
- Karin.
- Yeah?
Honey, come here. It's Lars.
- Really?
- Yeah.
She's just doing some kind of a...
It's pregnant women's yoga.
So...
No, it's good. It's good, good stuff.
- Hey.
- Hi.
What's up?
I have a visitor.
- You have a...
- In the garage?
- Now?
- Yeah.
A visitor?
That's great.
Yeah.
- And she's not from here.
- She?
Yeah.
Wow. What do you... What do you...
What do you know? Where...
- Where did you meet this person?
- On the Internet.
Yeah, well, everybody's doing that now.
That's great!
She doesn't speak much English, though.
It's OK.
It's really the same
with the guys at work, it's...
- It's not that big a deal.
- OK.
Well, yeah.
Well, you know, she's in a wheelchair.
So I just don't want her
to feel weird about it.
- Oh, no. No.
- So what? We don't care.
OK.
And I have to ask you a really...
I know that it's a really big favor.
Yeah.
Well, she's just really religious
and because we're both young and single,
it just doesn't feel right for us to
stay in the garage alone together.
Oh, no. We'll put her
in the pink room.
No. She can sleep here.
- In the pink room?
- Yeah.
- OK.
- Sure. And there are new towels.
Just give us half an hour to, you know,
pick up and get something in the oven.
- Okey-dokey.
- Get the place ready.
- OK. Let's get started.
- All right.
Man, that is...
You quiet ones are...
You know what they say about the...
It's great. It's great.
See you in a little bit.
- OK.
You know, Bianca's a missionary.
Well, was a missionary. Right. Sorry.
Because she was raised by nuns.
But now she's on a sabbatical
so she can experience the world.
Isn't that neat?
She's shy.
Well, you are.
Everything's so new for her. Right?
- Are you hungry?
- We're starving.
Gus, will you give me a hand
in the kitchen?
How was that?
I know.
Oh, my God!
I mean, so, he's crazy, right?
I mean, he's crazy.
- Shh.
- Karin...
- What are we gonna do?
- I don't know.
Huh? What are we gonna do?
Oh, my God! He's... Karin!
We're gonna have to
put him in a hospital, I think.
We're gonna have to put him in a
hospital. I can't afford that.
Karin, I can't believe this.
My little brother
is totally, totally insane!
- Pull yourself together.
- How am I...
Gus! Calm down!
How are we gonna
pull ourselves together?
- Calm down, OK? Now!
- He's talking to a doll, baby.
We're just gonna get
through this somehow, OK?
I just don't know how
we're gonna do it.
I don't, either. But you gotta be calm.
- OK?
- OK.
- I'm sorry.
- It's OK.
Karin. Karin! She's not gonna eat!
So, you're never gonna believe this.
It makes me mad,
but Bianca's from the tropics.
She... Well, she's Brazilian.
Well, half Brazilian,
half Danish, that's right.
And somebody stole her luggage.
- Oh?
- Yeah, and they stole her wheelchair.
That's terrible.
Yeah. Can you believe that, Gus?
- Yeah, I can't believe it.
- Right.
Well, it makes me angry.
Anyway...
I wanted to ask you a favor.
She doesn't mind. I promise.
Karin, you don't mind
lending Bianca some clothes, do you?
She doesn't have any.
Do you?
I'm not sure we're the same type, Lars.
Well, that's OK, Karin,
because Bianca doesn't really care
about superficial things like that,
so it's OK.
- Sure.
- Yeah, that's...
See, I told you.
Thanks.
Well, this used to be my mom's room.
So, if you need anything,
Gus and Karin are right across the hall.
I'm in the garage.
You know that. So, what else?
Your towels are brand new,
thanks to Karin.
Lars, I think we should go to bed,
you know?
OK.
Just, you know, one second.
I just wanted to say
that I'm so glad you're finally here.
Lars, I think right now would...
Yeah. OK, good night.
Wait. Gus had a good idea.
He's... He's concerned
about Bianca's health.
You know, just with the traveling
and the change of climate
and everything.
Well, it's stress, you know.
I'll make an appointment
with Dr. Berman for tomorrow.
- For early tomorrow.
- We'll all go.
Yeah. You remember Dagmar.
OK.
- You think that's a good idea?
- I do. I think we should do it.
Yeah. That's a good idea
because I was gonna go
- shopping for wheelchairs anyway.
- Let's just go to bed.
- So, good night.
- Night.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Oh, my God!
Natasha escaped from Moscow
where she was forced
to strip for the Russian mob.
Now all she wants
is an all-American male to love.
Midori left a high-paying job in Tokyo
because she was unsatisfied as a woman.
Tammy dropped out of high school
to join the rodeo.
Are you the right cowboy
to tame this wild filly?
The doctor will tell us what to do.
But she's family practice.
We're gonna need a shrink.
No, she is, she's a psychologist, too.
Oh.
She says you have to be, this far north.
What'll people think?
We can't worry about that.
Right.
Right there is where
my dad used to work.
Our dad.
That's the library.
I have a card
and you can borrow it if you want to.
Well, actually, I'll have to take them
out for you, but you just tell me...
Oh, I don't know.
I don't know, actually.
Gus, what was it that Dad did?
Water and power.
My job's at the school department.
I miss everybody,
but there's so much to do in the house.
I'll go back just as soon
as the baby's old enough and you're...
Yeah, sure.
Readers Digest
Midwest Living or Country Home?
That's what I would say.
Well, her blood pressure's low.
- Is that serious?
- Could be. We'll have to wait and see.
It's fine.
Mine's probably low, too.
I want you to bring her in every week
for special treatment.
Can you do that?
Yeah. Are you sure
that that's necessary?
Yes.
OK. OK.
What do you think?
Well, if that's what she says,
then we should.
OK.
You can set that up with Joanne
at the desk.
I look forward
to getting to know you, Bianca.
Karin, I'm telling you,
he belongs in a hospital.
No! My Uncle Garth
went to one of those places
and he never came back.
Yeah, but he needs more help
than you and I are able to give him.
I told you something was wrong
and you wouldn't listen!
If I may...
Has Lars been functional?
Does he go to work, wash, dress himself?
So far.
Has he had any violent episodes?
Oh, no. No, never. He's a sweetheart.
He never even raises his voice.
OK. We gotta fix him. Can you fix him?
I don't know, Gus.
I don't believe
he's psychotic or schizophrenic.
I don't think this is caused by genes
or faulty wiring in the brain.
So then what the hell
is going on, then?
- He appears to have a delusion.
- A delusion?
What the hell is he doing
with a delusion, for Christ's sake?
That's what we have to find out.
Chances are he's been
decompensating for some time.
Guess we didn't realize.
Have there been any changes
in the family in the last year or so?
No, everything is pretty much
exactly the same
except that Karin is pregnant
and Lars is nuts.
You know,
this isn't necessarily a bad thing.
What we call mental illness
isn't always just an illness.
It can be a communication,
it can be a way to work something out.
- Fantastic. When will it be over?
- When he doesn't need it anymore.
How can we help?
- Go along with it.
- Oh, no. No, that's... No.
Oh, my. No, no, no. No.
No, I mean, pretend that she's real?
I'm not gonna do that. I mean, I can't.
- I'm just not gonna do it.
- She is real.
- Well...
- I mean, she's right out there.
Right, right. I get that.
But I'm just not gonna...
You know, I'm just not gonna...
I'm not gonna do it, so...
You won't be able
to change his mind, anyway.
Bianca's in town for a reason.
- Right, but, but...
- It's not really a choice.
OK. OK. All right, then, we'll do it.
Whatever it takes.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
And everyone's gonna laugh at him.
And you.
She loves kids.
Yeah.
- More coffee, Lars?
- Yes, please.
You want to see a funny face?
Does Bianca want some?
Yeah.
- There we go.
- Thank you, Karin.
Gus? No. OK.
Yeah, sure.
You're not gonna go to work today, Gus?
- I don't feel good.
- Oh, no.
Well, Bianca could help you, you know.
She has nurse's training.
No, she doesn't.
She doesn't have nurse's training, Lars,
because she's not a person.
She's a big plastic thing.
That's amazing.
Did you hear that?
Bianca just said that
that's why God made her, to help people.
Are you gonna be late?
For work?
I am gonna be late.
Oh, no, I have to go. OK.
- Bye-bye. I'm going to check in.
- Okey-doke.
And you have my number at work,
right, Karin?
Yep.
I wanted to tell you
that you look really pretty today.
I hope that you feel better, Gus.
Me, too.
- And thanks so much for breakfast.
- No.
- OK, gotta go. Bye!
- See you.
Well, I had to try, you know?
What? What? What?
It's just...
I don't know.
It's true. We've been all wrapped up
in ourselves. We have, Gus.
This is not my fault, though.
It's not my fault.
Come on, Bianca,
let's make a couple of calls.
Good morning, Cindy.
You look really pretty today.
Thank you. Oh, Mr. Sunshine.
It's way in advance, but you know
how excited I get about these things.
All right, where are they?
I know you took them.
- Did not.
- You did, too. As revenge.
- For what?
- For the fake rat I put in your drawer.
Oh, that.
Lars, I'm missing
three of my action figures.
It's your turn to get coffee.
OK, listen up, Margo.
Those action figures
are extremely important to me.
All right? They're worth a lot of money.
If I don't see every damn one
back on my desk pretty soon,
then you can tell your teddy bear
to watch his back.
I'll return them. One at a time.
- You going to Cindy's party?
- Oh, no.
I was hoping you would.
I really wish you would.
Well, maybe.
That'd be great.
Do you think
I could bring my girlfriend?
Oh... Yeah, yeah, I mean,
I'm totally bringing somebody.
- Wow!
- I didn't know there were sex dolls.
Love dolls. That's what they call them.
I saw a special on cable.
So are you serious?
Bianca really has a...
So she's really just
one of the girls, then.
I'm sorry.
No way!
Does she have a sister?
Wish I had a woman that couldn't talk.
It's not that funny.
We don't want anything to do with her.
She's a golden calf.
And we all know what happened with that.
He's not worshipping her,
they're just dating.
These young people have no willpower.
He's sick, all right? He's sick.
I guess, we were just hoping,
if we came to you,
you could help, you know,
just pave the way a little.
If you could just
try to understand, it's...
- He is a nice man.
- We can try.
I don't even know why we're here.
This is absurd.
Oh, for heaven's sake,
what's the big deal?
Sally, your cousin
puts dresses on his cats.
Hazel, your nephew
gave all his money to a UFO club.
And, Arnie, everybody knows
your first wife was a klepto.
She wasn't.
Then why is she buried
in a pair of my earrings?
- Now, that's enough.
- These things happen.
Lars is a good boy.
You can depend on me.
Thanks, Mrs. Gruner.
Well, he's not bringing her to church,
now, is he, Reverend Bock?
Well...
...the question is, as always...
What would Jesus do?
Holy, Holy, Holy
Merciful and mighty!
God in three persons
Blessed Trinity!
I would like to take the opportunity
to welcome all of our new visitors
to our church today.
Bianca, it's good to see you.
Lars, God bless.
God bless. God bless.
- Thank you so much.
- You're welcome, my dear.
Getting close.
- Well...
- Be careful. Watch yourself.
These are for you, Bianca.
Thank you.
Bianca, this is my friend, Mrs. Gruner.
She has a darling figure.
Those are nice, huh?
They're not real, so they last forever.
Isn't that neat?
Hello.
Get back here!
There we go.
OK, watch your head on the way in.
Watch, watch, watch, watch, watch.
There we go.
Are you comfortable? Yeah?
I'll get the chair.
Oh, can you put her seatbelt on?
Bianca, Gus is gonna
put on your seatbelt, OK?
Oh, can you put that on her legs,
'cause she gets cold.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
Thanks, Gus.
Yeah, where are you guys...
Where are you going?
Just one second.
She doesn't know, it's a secret.
But I can tell you.
It's just that she's asking me
all these questions all the time
and she wants to know
everything about me,
so I thought that I would take her
to the lake where we used to play.
Yeah.
- Do you remember that?
- Yeah.
It sounds... Yeah, that sounds nice.
Yeah. Gotta go.
I'm coming. Why are you yelling?
Gus and his friends used to
come up here all the time.
In the summer, they'd go fishing.
In the winter, they'd play hockey.
They'd build all kinds of cool forts,
and, like, they'd build snow forts...
Watch your head.
Here we go. There.
Is this OK? You OK? OK?
OK, this is the tree house,
and we have a rope swing and a ladder.
You should watch me chop wood, too.
I'm really good at it.
I'm sorry.
I couldn't wait any longer.
I wanted to see how she was doing.
Well, after the treatment,
she has to rest.
It doesn't work
without the resting.
Keep me company.
Lars, keep me company.
Do you know how many sessions
she's gonna have to have?
No, I don't.
It's a tricky illness, Lars.
But, you know, what I could use
is a more complete history on her,
- like, parents...
- Oh, they died when she was a baby.
Well, that's not fair.
Yeah, but she doesn't feel
sorry for herself or anything.
She just wants to be normal,
have everyone treat her normal.
That's nice.
- I admire that.
- Yeah, me, too.
- Is that your husband?
- Yes. He died.
Oh, no.
I'm sorry.
- Do you have kids?
- No.
You must get really lonely.
Sometimes I get so lonely I forget
what day it is and how to spell my name.
How about you?
You're funny.
So what's the difference between
a delusion and a hallucination?
It's false perception
versus false belief.
OK, so when Moose thinks
the FBI's after him...
- The EEA.
- INS.
IRS, ATF, AAA.
- Right, that would be a delusion.
- No, dude, they are after us.
What are we doing?
Why are we doing this for him?
Oh, come on.
It's funny.
Is it?
I don't know.
I don't know, maybe not.
So tell me about Karin.
I don't know her very well.
Oh, she's wonderful.
Gus and I are both very lucky
with women. She's wonderful.
But she...
We don't have to talk.
Let's find you something to read.
No, it's just...
- Between us.
- Of course.
I'm worried about her.
- I think she has a little problem.
- Oh, maybe you shouldn't tell me.
No, it's OK. It's just...
And I think it's 'cause she's insecure,
but she's just always trying
to hug everybody.
You know, some people don't like that.
Some people don't like to be hugged.
But she doesn't realize that,
she takes it personally and thinks...
You know, it hurts her feelings.
I don't know what to do about that.
Do you?
But it's such a comfort sometimes
just to have somebody's arms around you.
Don't you think?
No.
Come on, it feels good.
It does not feel good, it hurts.
Oh.
Like a cut or a bruise or...
Like a burn. Like when you
go outside and your feet freeze
and then you come back in
and they thaw out? It's like that.
It's almost exactly like that.
Same with everybody?
Well, not really with Bianca.
But everyone else.
So you don't let people touch you?
Lars, isn't that hard to get away with?
No, not really, here,
'cause I have all these layers.
And that helps.
Look, we can't change Karin.
But I can help you.
That's fine.
- Pain?
- Yeah, but I can take it.
You OK?
Uh-huh.
- Well, that's enough for today.
- Yeah. Thanks.
What?
Yeah, I'm OK.
Well, it's scientifically proven
that everyone's favorite word
is their own name,
so if you just say their names a lot...
You OK?
You can see
that it's gonna make them happy.
Yeah.
Mr. Sunshine!
And this must be Bianca.
Well, welcome.
Welcome, come on in.
I have my boots on
but I brought my shoes.
Don't worry about it.
Baxter? Baxter, baby.
Lars, this is my husband.
Hi, Lars.
Bianca.
How are you?
Is that for me, Bianca?
Thank you.
Can Baxter get you two
something to drink from the kitchen?
Lars?
I'll have a beer.
And for Bianca?
She doesn't drink.
She doesn't like it when I drink,
either, but I'm just gonna have one.
I can help you with your coats.
This is Margo, and this is Bianca.
Hi. Hi, Bianca.
I'm glad you sent around that memo.
I would have freaked.
It's so bizarre.
- It's a disorder.
- What a weirdo.
Lars?
Look at him.
He's in love
with that slutty hunk of silicone.
Her name's Bianca.
- Does he have sex with her?
- Babe, that's what she's for, yeah.
So, I hear you guys are getting married.
- Yes.
- No.
Tickle fight!
I would kill to have hair like hers.
Oh, I'd cut it, like, to here.
Long in front, short in back.
Lars would never let her cut it.
Guys and long hair.
I don't care.
However she likes it,
that's how I like it.
That's my kind of guy.
I need wine.
I'll get it.
Anyone else?
- Oh, no. No, thanks.
- No.
Hey, chief.
Oh, hey, Lars. Bianca? Total babe.
Thanks.
Best thing is, man,
she doesn't even know how hot she is.
That's what you want in a woman.
They stay with you 'cause they don't
know they could get somebody better.
Know what I'm saying?
Hey, is she... flexible?
Yes.
Did you have fun?
Yeah.
I'm just happy, that's all.
"And so he solaced himself with
pacing up and down the little meadow,
and writing and carving
on the bark of the trees
and on the fine sand
a multitude of verses,
all in harmony with his sadness,
and some in praise of Dulcinea.
But what distressed him greatly
was not having another hermit there
to confess him."
Pain?
It's OK.
That's OK, I can take that.
You must be excited
about a baby on the way.
Uh-huh.
Don't you want to be an uncle?
- Do you ever want to be a mom?
- I don't know.
Yes.
But I'm not able
to have children of my own.
That's too bad.
Bianca's like that, actually.
Yeah, she can't have babies, either.
That's a shame.
When she was a baby, her mom
died in the middle of things, so...
When she was being born.
Like yours.
You have a lot in common.
Lars, you know
we've learned a lot since then.
Things are better.
Yeah, but it could still happen, right?
It's highly unlikely. It's...
It's... rare.
Yeah, but it still could.
Lars, just take a breath.
It's OK.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, it's just so dangerous.
It's so dangerous.
I don't like to think about it.
Lars, sit down.
Put your head between your knees.
Sit down.
Just put your head between your knees.
Bend over. Bend over.
OK. OK.
OK.
- I'm sorry.
- It's OK.
Take a breath.
Look, they have cell phones.
We should get cell phones. Huh?
Then we can call each other
whenever we want.
When you're doing all your things
and I'm working.
How about afternoons,
Monday and Wednesdays,
and then maybe all day Saturday?
Yeah? Yeah? You sure? OK!
Bianca, is that OK with you?
Bianca wants to volunteer at the
hospital on Thursday afternoons.
You do?
What about your blood pressure?
Just think of all the bald children.
Wouldn't they just love her?
That's true.
Just a little bit of layering here
and some texture, kind of right there.
And I don't know
what you guys think but...
- Bangs?
- I like that.
- That looks great.
- Oh, that's pretty. Real pretty.
Are you sure?
'Cause it's not growing back, right?
What's that Sound? By Veronika Charles.
I hear the telephone.
Ring, ring!
- Hey.
He's not gonna get any better, is he?
No. Probably not.
He's gonna love that thing...
...his whole life and it's all my fault.
No, it's not. It's...
Yeah, I don't know.
I mean, I left home as fast as I could.
You know?
I never thought about him.
And then the two of us
move back here all fat and happy,
and he moves into the goddamn garage
like the family dog.
You know?
And I let him.
No wonder he goes
and orders a fiancée in a box.
Come here.
Hello.
Bianca!
We're upstairs.
What's going on?
It's the hospital volunteer banquet
at the VFW.
- Doesn't she look beautiful?
- Oh, she does. She looks beautiful.
That's... 'cause...
We were supposed to play Scrabble.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
Her schedule's on the refrigerator.
Did you check?
No, I didn't. I guess I forgot.
Could I have a moment
alone with her, please?
Thank you.
They never fight.
I don't like his tone.
Now you listen to me.
Bianca has a life of her own.
No self-respecting woman's
gonna be at your beck and call, mister,
and the sooner you learn that,
the better.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
You're away at your job all day.
What's she supposed to do?
Wait for you? Would you do that for her?
Would she even ask you to?
She's out in the community,
doing things for others less fortunate.
You should be proud of her.
And what about me?
Big baby. He's just like my husband.
She'll be home at 11:00.
She's my girlfriend
and I shouldn't have to check
a schedule to see her!
Are you OK?
How would she feel if I just left her?
If I just abandoned her like that.
Whoa, wait, she didn't abandon you,
she'll be back.
How do I know that, huh?
People do whatever they want.
- They don't care.
- No, we all care.
Lars, we do care.
No, you don't.
That is...
That is just not true!
God!
Every person in this town
bends over backwards
to make Bianca feel at home.
Why do you think
she has so many places to go
and so much to do, huh?
- Huh?
- I don't know.
Because of you!
Because all these people love you!
We push her wheelchair.
We drive her to work.
We drive her home.
We wash her. We dress her.
We get her up, we put her to bed.
We carry her.
And she is not petite, Lars.
Bianca is a big, big girl.
None of this is easy for any of us,
but we do it.
We do it for you!
So don't you dare tell me
how we don't care.
I think it's the person's job
who's upset to say that they're upset
because we can't, you know...
- Hey.
- Oh, hey.
- How was the game?
No, the cheese inspectors
beat the crap out of us.
Is everything all right?
I mean, I usually put Bianca to bed.
Yeah, I know.
OK, I'm telling him.
Well, we wanted
to talk to you about that.
You don't have to do that anymore.
I'm gonna do that.
You sure? Because I don't mind.
And I thought that you...
I'm so sorry.
It's just been one of those days.
It's fine, yeah, I mean,
it's up to you and...
Good. I'll leave you guys.
Hey, Gus?
- What's that?
- Thank you, though.
- I didn't do anything.
- Yeah, you did.
I'm tired.
- Did I miss something?
- Shh! We had a big fight.
- Really?
- Yes.
I think it's kind of cold out.
Lars, have you met Erik?
Not officially.
You're pretty famous around here.
I know.
Hell of a grip, too, pal.
Yeah.
Yes?
My office.
(whispering0 I think I'm gonna stay.
She's feeling pretty lousy today.
We'll both stay.
I asked her to marry me last week.
Congratulations.
When's the happy day?
- She said no.
- Oh.
Oh, no.
Yeah, I know, I couldn't believe it.
Stop it! You have no right
to talk to me like that.
No, you don't. No, you don't.
I don't talk to you like that.
Could you stop yelling?
I was talking to Bianca,
and she was saying that in her culture,
they have these rites of passages
and rituals and ceremonies.
Just all kinds of things, you know,
that when you do them,
at least when you're done,
if you live through them,
that you know that you're an adult.
Doesn't that sound great?
It does.
How did you know?
- How did I know what?
- That you were a man.
No, I couldn't tell you.
Was it...
OK. Was it sex?
Yeah, you know, yeah.
I mean, it's... Yeah, it's kind of...
No. Well, it's kind of sex but it's
not... It's not, you know...
I don't know. I don't know.
It's a good question.
Yeah, but I have to know.
Hold that thought.
You know, you should ask Dagmar.
I did ask Dagmar
and she said that I should ask you.
OK, you know,
I can only give you my opinion.
That's all I want.
Well, it's not like you're all
one thing or the other, OK?
There's still a kid inside, but you grow
up when you decide to do right, OK?
And not what's right for you,
what's right for everybody,
even when it hurts.
OK. Like what?
Like...
You know, like,
you don't jerk people around, you know.
And you don't cheat on your woman.
And you take care of your family,
you know.
You admit when you're wrong,
or you try to, anyways.
That's all I can think of, you know?
It sounds like it's easy
and for some reason it's not.
I know, because nothing's easy.
It's like the old man.
He didn't have to take care
of two kids alone.
He could have given us
to an orphanage or something.
You know, people do that.
But he loved us and he tried to do right
even though he didn't know how,
and even though he had a broken heart.
I shouldn't have left you alone
with him. He was too sad.
It scared me and I just...
I just ran.
And that was selfish.
And I'm sorry.
That's OK.
OK.
You've crossed the line.
Well, you kept
swiping my action figures.
- I hide them. I don't hang them.
- Well, whatever, Margo.
You're too old
for that thing anyway, OK?
- Take off the noose.
- No.
Take it off.
Face it, Margo, the bear is dead. OK?
Burn on you.
I warned her.
It's not just the bear.
I broke up with Erik.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Yeah, you know,
I didn't even have a good reason.
He just wasn't very interesting.
Then why was he your boyfriend?
I get lonely.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Thank you.
Sure.
Hey, what are you doing on Friday night?
I have this school board meeting.
Bianca got elected so...
- That's great.
- Yeah.
Yeah.
OK.
Why?
I was just thinking that maybe
we could all go out sometime.
Never mind.
After I drop off Bianca, I'm free.
But, you know, just me so...
That would be great, Lars.
Thank you.
OK.
Nice shot.
You're putting too much
spin on the ball.
I know.
Yeah, still.
Sorry, we're full up. Next week
is the ladies' league tournament.
- Nada?
- Dude!
Tell them lady go.
No way, Nelson. They'll shred me.
Hey, is that Lars?
Hey, buddy.
- We're full.
- No problema.
Yes!
- Margo, I kicked your butt!
- No, Nelson, I'll kick your butt.
- Congratulations.
- Thanks.
Margo!
Oh.
- Oh!
- Yeah!
Baby, where you been all my life?
This is exactly what I needed.
Things look so much better.
Anyway, thanks for going bowling
with me, Lars.
I don't...
I don't wanna give you
the wrong idea about this.
I just...
I'm never gonna cheat on Bianca, ever.
Oh. No.
Oh, my God, I hope you didn't think
that. Lars, I would never do that.
I would never do that.
OK, good. Yeah, yeah, I...
It's just 'cause a man
doesn't cheat on his woman, that's that.
Absolutely. And vice versa.
Besides, I don't need
to steal anybody's boyfriend.
One day I'll find a man of my own and...
...we'll be happy, too.
Yeah, that's the way it works, I guess.
Snow.
I was hoping that winter was over.
No, it's just a thaw.
Winter isn't over till Easter.
Thanks again.
Hey.
Good night, Lars.
I'm not sure how well
these treatments are working.
No?
What do you think?
I don't know.
I'm sorry.
I don't know. It's hard.
It's hard because...
I know that she loves me,
but I ask her to marry me
and she says no.
Or she says, "I don't know."
Or she doesn't say anything.
Nothing?
"When I was a child, I spake as a child,
I understood as a child."
Hey.
Doesn't it feel good?
Wake up! Wake up!
She won't wake up.
Bianca! I think she's unconscious. Hey.
- Are you sure?
- Look at me. Bianca.
Hey. Hey, hey, hey, hey. Hey!
- Bianca's unconscious.
- Can you hear me?
Bianca.
Come on, wake up.
Hey, hey, hey, she looks all
right. She looks all right.
She looks all right. Hey, hey, hey, hey!
- Call 911!
- OK. OK.
All right.
911.
Well, I don't know. Why do you always
expect me to know what to do?
They're here. Call Dr. Berman.
I'm sorry, you'll have to wait out here.
Don't worry about it. It's all right.
- I just wanna see...
- It's OK. Doctor's on the way.
OK. Hello? Hello?
- Lars. Lars.
- Yeah.
What?
Bianca's very sick.
No, she's not. She's not.
Come on, she's not sick.
She's not, Lars.
She's dying.
- But...
- God.
We're gonna keep her here
till she's stable,
but she wants
to go home with Lars tonight.
- Can I see her?
- Sure.
What?
I'm sorry but I just don't get it.
I don't.
I mean, what's this gonna do to him?
How could you let this happen?
I'm not letting it happen, it's Lars.
It's always been Lars.
He's making the decisions.
He's the one who found her unconscious.
He's the one who said she's dying.
You OK back there?
They gave her something so she's asleep.
Anything you want, Lars?
We wanna stay together
in the pink room tonight.
Come down to the family room, Lars.
Let Bianca rest.
We sent Gus and Karin to the movies.
They didn't want to leave you two.
No, I'm glad that they...
I'm glad they left.
I feel terrible that all this is
happening so close with the baby coming.
That's how life is, Lars.
Everything at once.
We brought casseroles.
Thank you.
Is there something
that I should be doing right now?
No, dear. You eat.
We came over to sit.
That's what people do
when tragedy strikes.
They come over and sit.
OK.
Don't you feel a little better?
I got spring fever.
We're going to the lake.
You wanna come?
Hey, Lars, why don't you come with us?
It would do everybody good.
Bianca?
Don't you wanna see this beautiful day?
- Is there a storm coming?
- The weather said no.
It looks like a storm to me.
Well, I need to stretch my legs.
Let's take a chance.
Lars?
I think we're gonna watch the water.
Well, we won't be far.
- Holler if you need us.
- OK.
All right. So you think
it's not the right color?
Well, I don't know.
Does it match the curtains?
What? I think so.
Here, hey, just be careful.
OK.
Gus.
No, no, don't run.
Lars!
Lars asked us not to wear black today.
He did so to remind us
that this is no ordinary funeral.
We are here to celebrate
Bianca's extraordinary life.
From her wheelchair,
Bianca reached out and touched us all
in ways we could have never imagined.
She was a teacher.
She was a lesson in courage.
And Bianca loved us all...
...especially Lars.
Especially him.
Hi.
- You OK?
- Yeah, I'm sorry, I just...
Yeah, I don't know. It's just funerals,
and Mom and Dad, and, you know...
- He's unbelievable, huh?
- Yes.
I wanted to thank you for...
Gus?
- So, shall we see you at the house?
- Of course.
- OK.
- Sure.
She asked me not to be sad,
but I can't help it.
Yeah, me, neither.
But it will get better with time.
That's what everyone keeps saying, so...
It's true, I think, in a way.
But there'll never be anybody like her.
Well, I suppose we should...
...catch up with everyone.
Do you wanna take a walk?
Yes.