NARRATOR: In The New York
Herald, November 26, year 1911
there is an account of
the hanging of three men.
They died for the murder of
Sir Edmund William Godfrey
husband, father, pharmacist,
and all-around gentleman resident
of Greenberry Hill, London.
He was murdered by three vagrants
whose motive was simple robbery.
They were identified as Joseph Green
Stanley Berry,
and Daniel Hill.
Green, Berry, Hill.
And I would like to think this
was only a matter of chance.
As reported in the Reno
Gazette, June of 1983
there is the story of a fire
the water that it
took to contain the fire,
and a scuba diver named Delmer Darion.
Employee of the Nugget Hotel
and Casino, Reno, Nevada
engaged as a blackjack dealer,
well-liked and well-regarded
as a physical, recreational,
and sporting sort
Delmer's true passion was for the lake.
As reported by the coroner,
Delmer died of a heart attack
somewhere between the lake and the tree,
but most curious side note is the
suicide the next day of Craig Hansen
volunteer firefighter,
estranged father of four,
and a poor tendency to drink.
Mr. Hansen was the pilot of the plane
that quite accidentally lifted
Delmer Darion out of the water.
Added to this, Mr. Hansen's tortured life
met before with Delmer
Darion just two nights previous.
All I need is a two.
All you need is a deuce. All right.
That is an eight.
DELMER: Glad you like my
work. All right. Moment of truth...
NARRATOR: The weight of the guilt
and the measure of coincidence so large
Craig Hansen took his life.
[GUNSHOT]
And I am trying to think this
was all only a matter of chance.
The tale told at a 1961 awards dinner,
for the American Association
of Forensic Science
by Dr. John Harper,
president of the association
began with a simple suicide attempt.
JOHN: ...curiosity.
NARRATOR: Seventeen-year-old
Sydney Barringer
in the city of Los Angeles
on March 23rd, 1958.
The coroner ruled that
the unsuccessful suicide
had suddenly become
a successful homicide.
To explain, the suicide
was confirmed by a note
in the right hip pocket
of Sydney Barringer.
At the same time young Sydney stood on
the ledge of this nine-story building
an argument swelled three stories below.
[MAN AND WOMAN SHOUTING]
The neighbors heard, as they
usually did, the arguing of the tenants,
and it was not uncommon for them
to threaten each other with a shotgun,
or one of the many handguns in the house.
FAYE: I'm gonna put you down!
NARRATOR: And when the
shotgun accidentally went off...
You asshole!
NARRATOR: Sydney just happened to pass.
What?
Shut the fuck up!
NARRATOR: Added to this,
the two tenants turned out to be
Faye and Arthur Barringer
Sydney's mother and Sydney's father.
When confronted with the charge
which took some figuring out for
the officers on the scene of the crime
Faye Barringer swore she
did not know the gun was loaded.
I didn't know.
She always threatens me with
the gun, but I don't keep it loaded.
DETECTIVE: And you didn't load the gun?
Why would I load the gun?
NARRATOR: A boy who lived in the building
sometimes a visitor and
friend to Sydney Barringer
said that he had seen, six days
prior, the loading of the shotgun.
Ricky, come here a minute.
NARRATOR: It seems that
all the arguing and fighting,
and all of the violence was far
too much for Sydney Barringer,
and knowing his mother
and father's tendency to fight
he decided to do something.
[GUN CLICKS]
He said that he wanted
them to kill each other,
and that's all that they
wanted to do, kill each other,
and that he would help them
do that if that's what they wanted.
NARRATOR: Sydney Barringer
jumps from the ninth-floor rooftop.
His parents argue three stories below.
Her accidental shotgun blast
hits Sydney in the stomach
as he passes the
arguing sixth-floor window.
He is killed instantly,
but continues to fall
only to find, five stories below, a
safety net installed three days prior,
for window washers that
would've broken his fall,
and saved his life if not
for the hole in his stomach.
So Faye Barringer was charged
with the murder of her son,
and Sydney Barringer noted
as an accomplice in his own death.
[FAYE GRUNTING]
And it is in the humble
opinion of this narrator
that this is not just
something that happened.
This cannot be one of those things.
This, please, cannot be that.
And for what I would
like to say, I can't.
This was not just a
matter of chance. Ha, ha.
[FAYE SHOUTING]
These strange things happen all the time.
In this big game that we play,
life, it's not what you hope for.
It's not what you
deserve. It's what you take.
I'm Frank T.J. Mackey,
a master of the muffin,
and author of Seduce and Destroy
now available to you on
audio and video cassette.
Seduce and Destroy will
teach you the techniques
to have any hard-body blonde
just dripping to wet your dock.
Bottom line? Language:
the magical key to unlocking
the female analytical mindset.
Tap directly into her hopes, her wants
her fears, her desires,
and her sweet little panties.
Learn how to make that lady
"friend" your sex-starved servant.
Seduce and Destroy produces an
instant, money-back guaranteed
trance-like state that will get you...
Hey.
FRANK [ON TV]: ... naughty
sauce you want fast.
Hey, how many more times [SNIFFING]
do you need to hear
the all-too-famous line...
So?
[WOMAN GASPING]
FRANK: ... "I just don't
feel that way about you"?
DICK [ON TV]: For over 30
years, America has hung out,
and answered questions with Jimmy Gator.
An American legend
and a true television icon
Jimmy celebrates his 12,
000th hour of broadcast this week.
Have I been around that long?
DICK [ON TV]: He's a family man
who's been married for over 40 years
with two children and one
bouncing baby grandchild on the way.
We've tuned in each day to
see the human interaction
between Jimmy and some very special kids,
and we hope there's 30 more
years of watching that happen.
I'm Jimmy Gator.
STANLEY [ON TV]: Donald W. Winnicott.
1911. North America. South America.
The answer is four. The
answer is 22. Gravity.
The answer is The Life of Samuel Johnson.
[DOG BARKING]
FRANK [ON TV]: I don't care
what your last bank statement is.
Let's go. You should have
done that 10 minutes ago.
-STANLEY: We need more dog food.
-RICK: Talk in the car.
-Look, I got a serious audition today.
-FRANK: Are you lonely?
-RICK: That one too?
-I need this one.
FRANK: Well, let me tell you.
RICK: I don't understand why you
need four bags of books to go to school.
There's no reason for
this many backpacks.
-Be ready at 2:00.
-It should be 1:30.
RICK: I told you I got an
audition. I won't be here till 2:00.
Get your stuff. Come
on. Gotta go. Love you.
-STANLEY: Love you too.
-Okay.
Donnie, do you have an answer?
I do, Jimmy. Prometheus.
JIMMY: It is!
[CROWD ON TV APPLAUDING]
Donnie, how does it feel?
[CROWD ON TV LAUGHING]
It's pretty exciting. Bet you don't get
many people my age getting braces.
NURSE: You were so
cute on that game show.
Bet you can't answer any
questions now, though, huh? Ha, ha!
-So we're all set to go, Donnie.
-DONNIE: Good.
-I'll see you tomorrow morning.
-Okay.
-RECEPTIONIST: Bye.
-You're running around like crazy.
I'm gonna be late for work.
[GABRIELLE'S "DREAMS"
PLAYING ON CAR STEREO]
[WOMAN SHRIEKS THEN CROWD SHOUTS]
MAN: Hey.
It's the Quiz Kid, Donnie Smith.
PHIL: Hello, hello.
[DOGS BARKING]
-How's today, then?
-Fucking bullshit is what this is.
EARL [WHISPERING]: Fucking regrets.
And we do these things,
move through this life.
I'm gonna need your help, Phil. You
got to help me on something today.
I'll take care. Anything, Earl.
Well, you're his doctor, and that's why.
Tell me something. Tell me something.
He needs more pills.
He needs more... Fuck it.
He needs more pills, and
I need some answers,
so I'm coming to see you.
[DOOR SLAMS]
Morning, Linda.
I love you, my darling.
I'll be back in a while, Phil.
I have to do some things,
and I have to see
something, and I'll be back.
Fuck.
Fuck, fuck, fuck.
WOMAN [ON RECORDING]: Press one to hear
this person's personal
description of themselves,
and two to leave a
personal message of your own.
[PHONE BEEPS]
JIM [ON RECORDING]: Well, hello.
This is Jim. I work in law enforcement.
I'm an officer for the LAPD,
and work out of the
North Hollywood district.
I love my job, and I
love to go to the movies.
I try to stay physically
fit. My job demands it.
I'm getting up there, though.
"I'm 32 years old, and I'm 6'2"
tall, and I weigh about 180
if that's important to you.
I'm really interested in meeting
someone special who likes quiet things.
My life is very stressful, and I hope to
have a relationship that is very calm,
and undemanding and loving,
so if you are this person, please
leave me a message at box number 82.
Thank you.
OFFICER: So much violence,
but that's the way of the
world. Good luck, as always.
Serve and protect and all that other
blah, blah, blah on the side of the car.
JIM: Let me tell you something.
This is not an easy job.
I get a call on the radio from Dispatch.
It's bad news.
And it stinks.
But this is my job, and I love it
because I wanna do well.
In this life and in this
world, I wanna do well,
and I wanna help people.
And I might get 20 bad calls a day,
but one time I can help
someone, I make a save
I correct a wrong or right a situation
then I'm a happy cop.
And we move through this
life, we should try and do good.
Do good.
And if we can do that,
and not hurt anyone else
well, then...
[BANGING ON DOOR]
-JIM: Hello?
-MARCIE: I turn around, there's something.
-Whoa! Slow down.
-You can't just come in here.
-The door was open.
-You not allowed to come in.
-Calm down.
-I am calm!
I got a call to this apartment,
report of a disturbance.
There's no disturbance.
I got a call of a disturbance.
I wanna see what's going on.
-Yeah, but there's no disturbance.
-Then you got nothing to worry about.
You don't tell me. I know my rights.
Just come right in. You can't just...
All right, ma'am, you wanna test me?
All right? You wanna tell me
about the law book, we can do that.
You push me far enough,
I will take you to jail.
-Okay? Now calm yourself down.
-I am calm!
No. You are not calm.
You're screaming at me.
Do you understand?
I got a call of a disturbance,
and I'm going to check it out.
That is what I'm going to do.
-Are you alone in here?
-I ain't got to answer your questions.
No, you don't, but I'm
gonna ask you one more time.
-Are you alone in here?
-What does it look like?
-There's no one else in here?
-You in here.
Okay. That's true, but
is there anyone else
besides me and besides you in this house?
-No. I said that already.
-Mm-hm.
-Are you lying to me?
-I live by myself.
That might be true, but the
question I'm asking you, ma'am
is there anyone else
in this house right now?
-No.
-Okay.
-What is your name?
-Marcie.
Okay. Marcie, I'm gonna
need you to take a seat here.
-I prefer to stand up.
-Okay. I'm not asking.
-I didn't even do nothing.
-Move, ma'am.
[MARCIE SIGHS]
Okay. So, like I was saying, I'm
here to check on a disturbance.
Now, some of your neighbors
heard screaming and a loud crash.
-I don't even know no loud crash.
-Okay, what...?
[METAL CLANKS]
-What was that?
-Nothing.
-Sit back down on the couch.
-I ain't gotta do a goddamn thing.
-What's this bullshit?
-Do not do this.
-Do not do this. Do not slap me, ma'am.
-This is bullshit. This is bullshit.
This is bullshit. For what? For what?
For what? Huh? Tell me for what.
No, tell me for what.
-JIM: I asked you to sit on the couch.
-MARCIE: This is bullshit.
[MARCIE GRUNTS]
This is bullshit. This
is fucking bullshit.
15-L-27, I'm gonna need backup.
What the fuck is this?
It's bullshit, motherfucker!
-I want you to stay right there.
-Fucking bullshit, and you know it!
-JIM: Stay right there, Marcie.
-Don't you go in my bedroom!
This is bullshit, motherfucker!
Don't go down the hallway!
Don't go down my motherfucking hallway!
JIM: This is the LAPD!
Don't go in my goddamn bedroom!
JIM: Come out now with your hands up!
MARCIE: What did I tell
you? Ain't nobody in there!
Where the fuck you going, motherfucker?
Don't go in my goddamn bedroom!
Stay out of my motherfucking
closet! What did I tell you?
-Don't go down my hallway!
-This is the police!
If there is anyone in
this closet, come out,
and show yourself to
me now, with your hands up.
Marcie, do not drag
that couch any further!
Don't do this, ma'am!
There's nobody in my
motherfucking closet!
If I have to open this
closet, you will get shot!
MARCIE: Come back here!
Come back here, motherfucker!
What can't you goddamn
fucking talk to me?
-There's nobody in there! I told you!
-JIM: Marcie, quiet down!
MARCIE: This don't make no fucking
sense! This don't make no goddamn sense!
This is bullshit, motherfucker!
Why can't you talk to me?
Whoa! Whoa-ho!
What the hell is this, Marcie?
That ain't mine.
LINDA: He's dying. He's
fucking dying as we're sitting here.
There's not a fucking...
Jesus, how can you tell me to calm down?
I can help you through this,
but there's certain things
you're gonna have to take
care of, and we can go over them,
but I need to know that
you're listening to me, okay?
I'm... I'm in a fucking state.
It's like he's going, and I don't...
Just tell me practical things, like
what the fuck do I do with his body?
What do I do when he dies? What
next? What happens then? What next?
That's what Hospice can take care of.
They'll send over a nurse, somebody who...
No. Phil. He has Phil now.
Phil is one of the
nurses from the service?
Yeah.
If you're happy with Phil taking care
of him and helping you, that's fine,
but contact Hospice
to arrange for the body.
You don't understand. It's...
There's more pain than before, and the
fucking morphine pills aren't working,
and it's like... The past two
days, he can't really swallow,
and I, um... I don't know
if the pills are going down.
I can't see inside his mouth anymore,
and I'm up all night staring at him,
and I don't know if the pills are
going down. He moans and he hurts.
We can fix that, because I can give you...
Are you listening?
-Yeah. I'm listening. I'm getting better.
-Do you wanna sit down?
I need to sit down.
Okay, Linda, Earl's not gonna make it.
He's dying. He is. He's
dying very, very rapidly.
The thing here is to make this experience
as painless and easy for him as possible.
You understand?
Now, Hospice will take care
of all the technical things.
They will help you. They
will take care of the body.
They are who you call when he dies.
There's the number of Hospice.
Okay. Now, as far as
the morphine pills go
there's something else to consider.
There's a very strong, very
potent solution of liquid morphine,
and it's a little bottle.
It has an eyedropper.
It's easy to get into his
mouth and drop on his tongue,
and it will certainly
diminish the pain that he's in.
But you need to realize that,
uh, once you give it to him
there really is no going back.
It will certainly cure his pain, but he
will drift in and out of consciousness
even worse than he
is now, Linda. I mean...
All sign of the recognizable
Earl will pretty much go away.
I... What the fuck can I say to...?
I don't know what to say to that.
I don't want to do this.
Sit here.
I can see the things, you know.
It's getting there,
that's the cocksucker.
I see that pen.
I see it. I know it's there.
I reach for it.
No.
No. No goddamn use.
[SIGHS]
I have a son, you know.
-You do?
-Yeah.
-Where is he?
-I don't know.
I mean
he's around, but...
He's here in town, but I don't know.
You know... he's a tough one.
Very...
-Got a girlfriend, Phil?
-No.
-Get a girlfriend.
-I'm trying.
Do good things with
her. Share the things.
-All that bullshit is true, you know.
-Yeah.
Find a good one, hold on, and all that.
Where's Linda?
She went out. She, uh, said
she went out to run some errands.
-She'll be back.
-Oh.
-She's a good girl.
-Yeah.
She's a little nuts. Heh. But
she's a good girl, I think. Yeah.
-She's a little daffy. Yeah.
-Yeah.
She loves you.
Well, maybe.
-Yeah.
She is a good one.
When's the last time
you talked to your son?
I don't know.
Ten.
Maybe ten... Five...
Fuck.
[SOBS]
That's another thing that goes.
-Your memory?
-Time lines, you know?
I can remember things,
but not right there.
-You know?
-Yeah.
"Yeah"? What the fuck do you know?
-I've seen it before.
-Oh, other fucking assholes like me?
-Ah, there's no asshole like you.
-Cocksucker.
[PHIL CHUCKLES]
How come every word you use is
either cocksucker, shit balls, or fuck?
-Do me a personal favor.
-Go fuck myself.
-You got it.
-Ha, ha.
[EARL COUGHING]
[EARL GROANS]
I can't...
I can't hold on to this any longer.
I'll get another pill.
Another morphine pill.
No. Give me the fucking phone.
-Who you gonna call?
-I wanna see this. I, uh...
-Where is he? Do you know?
-Who?
-Jack.
-Is Jack your son?
Do you want to call him
on the phone? I can call him.
I can dial the number if you
can remember the number.
It's not him. He's a fucking asshole.
Oh, Phil, come here. This is so boring.
So goddamn... Goddamn...
You know, that dying wish,
and all that old man on a bed...
-Wants one thing.
-It's okay.
Find him on a...
Frank.
His name is Frank Mackey.
-Frank Mackey?
-Yeah.
That's your son?
Not my name.
[EARL SIGHS]
Go find...
Find Lily.
Give me that. Give me.
Give me... If you give me that
over there on, uh...
Oh. Fuck. I can't hold on to this.
I got it. I got it.
EARL: Yeah.
Ah.
[AUDIENCE CHEERING AND APPLAUDING]
[STRAUSS' "ALSO SPRACH
ZARATHUSTRA" PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
[AUDIENCE CHEERING AND APPLAUDING]
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
[AUDIENCE WHISTLING AND CHEERING]
Respect the cock.
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
And tame the cunt.
[ALL CHEERING]
Tame it.
Take it on headfirst with the
skills that I will teach you at work,
-and say, "No."
-AUDIENCE: No!
-You will not control me. No!
-You will not take my soul. No!
-AUDIENCE: No!
You will not win this game.
Because it is a game, guys.
You wanna think it's not, huh?
You go back to the schoolyard,
and you have that crush
on big-titted Mary Jane.
[AUDIENCE CHEERING AND APPLAUDING]
Respect the cock.
[AUDIENCE CHEERS AND APPLAUDS]
You are embedding this thought:
-I am the one who's in charge.
-MAN: Yeah.
-I am the one who says, "Yes."
-AUDIENCE: Yes!
-"No."
-AUDIENCE: No!
-"Now."
-AUDIENCE: Now!
"Here."
[AUDIENCE CHEERING AND APPLAUDING]
Because it's universal, man.
It is evolutional. It is anthropological.
-It is biological.
-MAN: Yeah.
It is animal.
We [FRANK GRUNTING]
are...
[AUDIENCE CHEERING AND APPLAUDING]
...men.
[AUDIENCE CHEERING NEARBY]
DOC: You need to ask
yourself what you can do...
-You Gwenovier?
-Yeah.
I'm Captain Muffy, Frank's assistant.
-This is Doc. We can go in right here.
-Sorry I'm late.
He started about 35 minutes ago,
but he's probably getting
all pumped up right now.
FRANK: Look down at the top of the page.
At the top of the page, what does it say?
AUDIENCE: "Get a calendar."
FRANK: Right. I
cannot stress this enough.
It's a simple item. It's 99
cents at the corner store.
But if you look into your packs,
reach deep into your packs
you will see that I have been
nice enough to include one. See?
Yeah, yeah. That's just
the kind of prick I am.
You're gonna need this
calendar. It doesn't seem like much.
It's a simple item. It is a small item,
but it is going to make all
the difference in your world.
You meet a girl, work
an A-3 interruption.
Let's say an eight-day waiting
period before next contact.
How are you gonna know
when those eight days are up?
AUDIENCE: Mark the calendar.
That's right. Mark the calendar.
You're gonna mark that calendar.
You're going to stick
with me and this calendar.
You're gonna set goals.
If you really, really wanna
make that friend something else
you're gonna have
to be tough on yourself.
You're gonna have to set goals.
Uh, you, sir, in the, uh,
brown short-sleeve shirt.
I can't read your name tag.
What's your name, please?
[PHONE KEYPAD BEEPING]
[PHIL SIGHS]
[LINE RINGING]
-WOMAN [OVER PHONE]: Hello.
-Hi, uh, is Frank there?
-No, you have the wrong number.
-Um...
I'm sorry. I'm looking
for a Frank Mackey.
Yeah, no, there's no Frank here.
Is this, um, 818-775-3993?
Yeah. No, you have the wrong number.
Do you know a Jack, by any chance?
[LINE HANGS UP]
Just a regular deal.
Loosers and tighters.
-We're all set upstairs.
-GEOFF: And then she called me up,
and she asked me for advice about a guy.
-Got everything you need?
-All set, thanks.
FRANK: Does she know how you feel
about her? Have you discussed that?
GEOFF: Yes. Absolutely.
FRANK: And what does she say?
She says she doesn't
feel that way about me.
[AUDIENCE MURMURING]
I don't think there's anyone in this
room that doesn't understand that pain,
and I wanna thank you
for sharing that with us.
Let me tell you what we're gonna
teach Denise when we set goals, all right?
What I say is, "Denise.
Denise the Piece."
I mark it down. Oh, I write it up.
And you have been warned
because I have my lasers
I have my Tasers, I have my ICBMs
I have my bazookas, I have
my jets pointed right at you.
Because me and my
brothers, we like to celebrate,
and on the first of
May, we celebrate V-Day.
[AUDIENCE APPLAUDS]
And come June, oh, baby,
it is the lick of my spoon.
[AUDIENCE CHEERS]
Come August, we like to celebrate
Saint Suck My Big Fat Fucking Sausage.
[AUDIENCE CHEERS AND APPLAUDS]
I set goals for myself,
and when I say I do not
wanna take it anymore
I will not take it anymore.
You think she's your friend,
Geoff? You think she's your friend?
They're not your friends.
Do you really think she's gonna
be there when things go bad?
Huh, guys? When things go wrong, do
you think they're gonna be there for us?
Ho-ho, you think again.
Oh, fucking Denise, Denise the Piece
you are gonna give me that
cherry pie, sweet mama baby.
[AUDIENCE CHEERS AND APPLAUDS]
Oh, yeah, but listen
up. That is not to say
that we don't all need
females as friends.
We're gonna learn later that having a
couple of chick friends lying around
comes in real handy in setting
jealousy traps. We'll get to that later.
Right now, what I want you guys to do
is pull out your blue booklets, page 18.
We're going quickly. We're
gonna workshop it later.
Eighteen, blue booklet.
"Form A Tragedy."
This is simple and clean,
and if done correctly
can be very, very
effective in getting some bush.
Here we go. You call up your
so-called friend and set a date.
Let's say make it around
7:30. You call her on the phone.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Hello?
Hi. Uh, is Claudia here?
She's sleeping.
Are you...? Are you her boyfriend?
You're Jimmy Gator, right?
That's right. What's your name?
I'm Ray.
-So are you her boyfriend?
-No, I'm just a friend.
I see.
-Ha, ha, what are you doing here? I mean...
-I'm her father.
Mind if I come in?
-Yeah, sure.
-Thanks.
-CLAUDIA: What the fuck is this?
-JIMMY: It's me, Claudia. It's me.
What do you want? Why are you here?
I'd like to talk to you. Uh,
your boyfriend let me in. I just...
That's not my boyfriend.
-Wanna call me a slut now or something?
-No, I don't.
What the fuck do you want?
-I wanna sit. I wanna talk to you.
-Don't sit down.
I want to, uh... God, I
want so many things.
-Maybe we could talk...
-I don't wanna talk to you.
There's things I have
to talk to you about.
I don't want to talk to you.
That's all right. It
doesn't have to be now.
We can make a date
to set some other time.
I didn't mean to walk
in on you like this.
Why are you here? Why are
you doing this? Coming in here?
-You wanna call me a whore?
-No, I... Claudia...
I don't want you to
think I'm that way to you.
I'm not gonna call
you a slut or something.
Yeah, ha, ha. Yeah, right.
What are you doing here?
What the fuck are you doing in my house?
Please don't yell, honey.
Just don't go crazy.
I'm not crazy! Don't
you tell me that I'm crazy!
Claudia, I'm sick. I'm sick, Claudia.
-Fuck you.
-No, no, please, listen to me.
-Fuck you!
-Listen to me right now, Claudia.
I am dying.
I got sick, and then I fell down...
Fuck you! Get the fuck out of my house.
I'm dying. I have cancer, Claudia.
I have cancer.
-And I'm dying very soon.
-Fuck you.
-It's metastasized in my bones.
-Fuck you!
Claudia, it's... I'm not lying
to you. This is the truth.
I'm telling you, Claudia,
I'm going to lose.
Get out.
Get out! Get the fuck out of here!
-Get out! Go!
-Your mother would like to hear from you.
Fuck you. Get out!
Get the fuck out of my house now!
Get out!
[AD JINGLE PLAYING ON TV]
WOMAN 1 [ON TV]: Keep
your body running good.
MAN 1: Prevention is everything.
MAN 2: If you don't
maintain it, I'll be fixing it.
WOMAN 1: Keep fit. Stay healthy.
MAN 3: if your car is running
good, take it to Jiffy Lube...
...and they offer Pennzoil.
MAN 4: Prevention.
WOMAN 2: It's worth it.
MAN 2: Hey, you don't wanna see me.
AVI: Don.
Hey, Avi.
Just one sec.
MAN [ON TV]: Say goodbye to the
plastered-down look of heavy hairspray,
and hello to the natural-looking...
-Please.
-SOLOMON: Don't, Donnie. Don't do this.
This is so fucked,
Solomon! I don't deserve this!
Don't get strong, Donnie.
This is making sense.
This is making a lot of sense.
You are not doing the
job. The job I ask you to do.
A job I give you.
Over and over and over.
I'm sorry, but I'm not gonna
say "I'm sorry" much more.
I don't have any money,
Solomon. If you fire me...
SOLOMON: I pay you.
I give you a paycheck.
Your sales suck, Don.
I give. I give.
When I find you, when I meet you, what?
I put your name up
on a fucking billboard.
I put you in my store. My salesman.
My fucking representation of
Solomon Solomon Electronic.
The Quiz Kid, Donnie
Smith, from the game show.
I lent you my celebrity,
my name. Exactly.
Oh, fuck you. Fuck you.
I paid you! I paid you!
I gave you a fucking chance, and a chance,
over and over, and you let me down!
I trust you with so much!
Keys to my store. The codes to my
locks. The life and blood of my business.
In return, you smash in 7-Eleven!
And late! Always late! Loans!
The loans for your
kitchen that you never did.
I paid you back!
SOLOMON: Two years! Two
years later, and from your paycheck!
I never charged interest.
Solomon, please. Please.
I am so fucked here if you do this.
This is the worst timing. The
worst timing I could ever imagine.
I need to keep working.
I have so many debts, so many things.
I have... I have... I
have... I have my surgery.
-My oral surgery coming.
-What surgery?
Oral surgery. Corrective teeth surgery.
-SOLOMON: What is that?
-Braces.
-SOLOMON: You don't need braces.
-Yes, I do.
-AVI: Your teeth are straight.
-I need surgery!
I need corrective oral surgery.
Donnie, you got struck by
lightning that time in Tahoe.
I don't think braces is a good idea.
Solomon, just let me
ask you once, please.
Please don't do this.
-AVI: How are you paying for the braces?
-I don't know.
SOLOMON: Well, that's just incredible.
How much are braces, anyway?
It's, uh... It doesn't matter.
AVI: It's, like, $5000.
I've seen it. I know.
-Now you're pissing me off.
This is incredible.
This is fucking stupid.
You're paying $5000 for
braces you don't need?
-I've been a good worker.
-Don't.
-No need for braces.
-Where are you gonna get the money?
-I don't know.
-You were going to ask me.
-I have been a good worker.
-No need for braces, Donnie.
That is none of your business!
I've been a good and loyal worker
for you, you fucking assholes!
-Hey, fuck you. Watch it, now.
-Give me your keys.
-No, don't...
-Give me your fucking keys!
OFFICER 1: identified
as Porter Parker, age 59...
...better known as the
dead guy in the closet.
Says the building guy,
this is her husband.
DETECTIVE 1: He comes
around, raises some shit
screaming and yelling something.
There's a son and a kid.
-Her son?
-Her son. That's right. And the kid.
They were here, and from late last night,
and through the morning,
screaming and yelling.
-Where are they?
-DETECTIVE 1: They are not to be found.
She's got $600 and a large
box of condoms next to the bed.
-She was real belligerent...
-OFFICER 2: Three wedding rings.
CORONER: Guys coming in and out
all day. This is the building guy talking.
OFFICER 1: Building guy says the son
and the closet guy are always going at it.
-DETECTIVE 2: And what is she saying?
-OFFICER 1: Not a goddamn thing.
Thanks, Randy. Whoa!
How much you pay me for my help?
It's more complicated
than that, little man.
Put me on the payroll and
find out. Find out what's up.
Okay, you don't just sign
up to be a police officer.
-It's about three years of training, okay?
-I'm trained. I'm ready to go.
-You wanna buy some candy to help...?
-No. No, sorry, little man.
You wanna take my
statement? I'll perform for you.
-Gotta get paid, though. Gotta get paid.
-Mm-hm.
Why aren't you in school today?
No school today. My teacher got sick.
Oh, you don't have substitute
teachers where you go to school?
No. So, what did they find out in there?
JIM: That is confidential
information, little man.
DIXON: Tell me what you
know. I'll tell you what I know.
JIM: No can do.
DIXON: Leave this one to the
detectives, they ain't gonna solve shit.
I can help you. Make
you the man with the plan.
Give you the gift
that I flow. Think fast.
-You wanna know who killed that guy?
-Okay. You come here.
-DIXON: No.
-Come here.
You wanna disrespect
an officer of the law?
I can help you solve the
case. I can tell you who did it.
Oh, you're a joker,
huh? Telling me jokes?
-I'm a rapper.
-Oh, you're a rapper. Oh, okay.
-You got a record contract?
-Not yet.
Give you a clue for the bust
if you show me some trust.
You ever been to juvenile hall?
I ain't fucking with you!
Hey, watch the mouth. Watch it.
Come on, man, just watch me.
Watch and listen.
[SIGHS]
Okay.
[RAPPING] Presence With the
double-ass-meaning gifts I bestow
With my riff and my flow
But you don't hear me, though
Think fast, catch me, yo
'Cause I throw what I
know With a resonance
For your trouble-ass
fiend In weaning yourself
Off of the back of the shelf
Jackass crackers, body-stackers
Dick-tooting niggers
Masturbating your triggers
Hold it, homeboy. I don't
need to hear that word.
Living to get older With
a chip on your shoulder
Except you think you got a
grip 'Cause your hip got a holster
Ain't no confessor, so, buster,
you better just shut the fuck up
Try to listen and learn
Whoa, cut it, Coolio. I've had
enough of the mouth and the language.
I'm almost done.
Finish it up without the lip.
Check that ego Come
of fit, I'm the prophet
The professor I'm gonna
teach you about the Worm
Who eventually turned to catch wreck
With the neck of a long-time oppressor
And he's running from the devil
But the debt is always gaining
And if he's worth being hurt
He's worth bringing pain in
When the sunshine don't work
The good Lord bring the rain in
Now, that shit will
help you solve the case.
Okay. Whatever that meant.
I'm sure it's real helpful, Ice-T.
DIXON: Did you listen to me?
I was listening to you.
I told you who did it, and
you're not even listening to me.
I'm through playing games.
Be cool. Stay in school, okay?
Get out of the street now.
[ENGINE STARTS]
Move it.
-RICK: Come on, let's go.
-You're late, not me.
-RICK: You could have been in front.
-I didn't see you from the window.
Well, you... Why didn't
you just, uh...? I don't know.
You could have come in the
front. I don't know. Hurry up.
-All right, you ready to keep winning?
-Sure.
[ENGINE STARTS]
RICK: You okay?
Busted my ankle there.
You gotta have that
makeup lady fix your hair.
-STANLEY: Okay.
-Okay? It's really wet.
-There you are. There you are.
-I'm sorry we're late, Cynthia.
-Oh, that's all right.
-RICK: We got caught in traffic.
-Your book is okay. How you doing?
-I'm fine.
Yeah? Yeah, you ready to go, go, go?
Know anybody involved
in that Alan Thicke thing?
The Corey Haim thing?
Terrorist in the high school?
-Uh, no.
-Where's Richard and Julia?
Oh, good. Um, they're here. They're fine.
They're in the dressing
room, so we're all set.
-Okay. See you later.
-You go to it, handsome.
-See you.
-Okay, buddy, love you.
[SIGHS]
-Good luck, Rick.
-Hey, Peter.
Dick, Dick. I'm sorry. Dick.
Fuck. Can't get that fucking name.
[GRUNTS]
-Who's ready to beat the record?
-JULIA'S DAD: That was close.
RICK: It's cats and
fucking dogs out there.
-Cats and dogs indeed.
RICK: I've never seen it
rain this bad since last year
because of La Nia or
El Nio or whatever the shit.
[RICK MUTTERS IN SPANISH]
RICK: Sorry I'm late.
-What was your name again?
-Amy, Mr. Jennings.
DICK: Call me D.J. You
said Amy, right? Listen.
Trust me, you know. But stay focused.
Where's the news department?
-CYNTHIA: It's upstairs.
-Have you ever been there?
Oh, sure. Why?
I was wondering about
the weather department.
Uh-huh.
I was wonder whether the weather people
have outside meteorological services,
or if they have in-house instruments.
Um, I can check on that,
and later we can take a tour.
-Oh, okay.
-Sounds good?
-You asking because it's raining outside?
-I guess.
Uh-huh. What do you do?
Whatever's happening, you look into?
[ELEVATOR DINGS]
-Something like that?
-I don't know.
Ha, ha, you don't know, huh?
Well, it's not a bad way to be.
Interested in everything
that's going around.
Wet... Wet is wet. Just that simple.
-STANLEY: Hi, Mary.
-Hi, hon, Stanley.
[PHONE RINGS]
Production.
MARY: Rose is on the phone.
Here are the cards for today.
-Fifteen minutes to go over those cards.
-Sorry.
-Find Paula for me.
-You want her right now?
-Yes, now.
-We're on the air in 20 minutes.
Fucking hell, Mary. Yeah, hi.
-Hi, how you doing?
-JIMMY: I'm drinking.
-Slowly or quickly?
-As fast as I can.
You come home soon after the show.
I went to see her.
Some fucking asshole answers
the door in his underwear.
He's 50 years old.
There's coke and shit
laid out on the table.
Did she talk to you?
She went crazy. She
went fucking crazy, Rose.
-Did you tell her?
-Oh, I don't know.
I gotta go. I don't have time.
I got a lot more drinking
to do before I go on.
-I love you.
-Love you too.
Shit.
[SOBS]
[SIGHS]
[SNIFFING]
[AIMEE MAN'S "MOMENTUM"
PLAYING LOUDLY ON STEREO]
[MUSIC PLAYING LOUDLY INSIDE]
-Hello?
-JIM: Police! Open the door!
Who is it?
JIM: It's the LAPD! Open the door!
CLAUDIA: I'm coming!
I have to get dressed!
You're not coming fast
enough! Open the door!
Didn't you hear me? I said I'm
coming, and that means I'm coming!
I just have to get dressed, all right?
I really... I have to get dressed!
I hate coming here and
not being able to talk.
It's fine. I understand.
I wish the circumstance was better.
I don't know what's gonna
happen. It's so fucked.
-I feel so over the top with everything.
-Running out of your medication at all
let alone at a time
like this, could be drastic.
Thank you, Dr. Diane.
MAN 1 [ON TV]: ... even your
pocket. And the pocket fisherman's...
MAN 2: ... 7:30 this Saturday night.
RON: ... dollars and 99 cents.
MAN 3: Hold it, on.
It's only four easy...
NASDAQ trading at [MOANING]
DICK: Stanley Spector and his
brilliant friends, Richard and Julia
can defeat today's adult
challengers, Mim, Luis, and Todd.
They're moving towards a
half-a-million-dollar team total,
and a What Do Kids Know? record.
WOMAN [ON PHONE]: Pink Dot.
-Hi. I'd like to get
an order for delivery.
-Phone number?
-818-725-4424.
-Partridge?
-Yeah.
What would you like?
I'd like to get an order
of, um, peanut butter...
-Mm-hm.
-...uh, cigarettes, Camel Lights.
-Uh, water...
-Bottled water?
-Um, no. You know what, forget the water.
Just give me a loaf
of bread. White bread.
Okay.
-And, um, do you have Playboy magazine?
-Yeah.
Okay. One of those. And,
uh, Penthouse, the magazine?
-Yeah.
-You have that? Okay. Uh, one of those.
-And, um, Hustler?
-Yeah.
-Do you have that?
-Yeah, I said.
-That it?
-Yeah, that's it.
You still want the peanut
butter, bread, and cigarettes?
Yeah. What?
The total is 31.90.
Thirty minutes or less.
Okay. Thank you.
-Is that cash or credit card?
-Cash.
-Thanks.
-Thank you.
-Bye.
[MUTTERING]
ALL: Respect the cock and tame the cunt!
FRANK: Have a great lunch!
[ALL CHEERING]
This is Gwenovier from Profiles.
She's here for the interview.
-Nice to meet you.
-I admire your work.
-Thank you. I have us set up in a suite...
-It's not very safe for you here.
I finish one of these
seminars, Gwenovier...
I swear to fucking God.
I mean, I am Batman.
I'm Superman. I'm like a... A fucking...
[EXHALES]
I'm like a fucking
action hero after that.
I could walk out if this room right now.
I could go down the hall,
walk down the street,
and pick up any little honey I
meet that has even one second to stop.
-GWENOVIER: All it takes is one second?
-Just one second, girl.
One glance, one hesitation
one subtle look my way for me to know,
and then it is:
Bing, bang, boom.
Oh, my God. Oh!
I'm away on a tangent.
[ALL LAUGHING]
-I tell you...
-GWENOVIER: Don't hurt yourself, okay?
I tell you, I do.
I get so fucking jazzed at these seminars
see, because I am what I believe.
I do as I say.
I live by these rules
as religiously as I preach them.
That's why I am getting the nasty
left, right, center, up, down, sideways.
The Battle of the Bush is being
fought and won by Team Mackey.
-We're gonna start rolling now.
-What? I thought we were rolling.
Come on, go, go, go, Gwenovier.
I am firing pearls at you here.
I want you to know that I'm
not succeeding in the bush
because I'm Frank T.J.
Mackey. Ah, you think about this.
I mean, there are women
who, uh, wanna destroy me.
No. I find that hard to believe.
[LAUGHS]
It makes it very difficult,
twice as hard for me.
There's some hottie I'm moving in on
knows me, knows my, you know, my,
uh, plans and my schemes, you know?
She's gonna wanna fuck with me.
She's gonna go back, you know
tell her friends: Yada, yada, yada...
"You know, Frank T.J. Mackey,
he ain't all that." You know.
"He ain't all that. Didn't get me."
So, me, I am...
You know, I'm just on full afterburners
-full-throttle through hottie heaven.
-Okay.
[FRANK PANTING]
-Just dodging left. Dodging right.
-Yes, I understand.
Dodging these bullets
from these terrorists.
I should've known this was gonna happen.
Calm down, take it
easy, and be a good boy
okay, Mr. Mackey?
Thank you. Now, you sit back there
put your microphone on for me, please...
-Yes, ma'am.
-So we can do this thing, all right?
Okay, um...
-Okay. Let me start by asking you...
-Just a second. One second.
You missed a button.
FRANK: Thank you.
What do you wanna know?
[GABRIELLE'S "DREAMS" PLAYING ON STEREO]
Make it happen.
This is you, Donnie. Go, go, go.
[SUPERTRAMP'S "GOODBYE
STRANGER" PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
[PATRONS CHATTERING]
[PATRONS LAUGHING]
[PATRONS CHATTERING AND LAUGHING]
Hello. You're back again, huh?
Yeah. Yes. Hi.
-What can I get you?
-Uh, Diet Coke.
[BOTH SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
MAN: You look tired.
You want one of these?
Better pour you one of these, huh?
WAITRESS: Can you ring me up?
-THURSTON: Brad, good to see you.
-BRAD: It's good to see you.
THURSTON: You make that
down payment on the Harley yet?
BRAD: Not yet. Not
yet. I'll make it next week.
[BOTH SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
BRAD: Six days. You'll be the first.
Ha, ha, I would love that.
-Want another one?
-Yes.
Uh, I'd like a tequila.
-WAITRESS: What kind?
-It doesn't matter.
[AIMEE MANN'S "MOMENTUM"
PLAYING LOUDLY ON STEREO]
JIM: Open up the door now!
CLAUDIA: Yes, hi! Hello!
Yeah.
I'm sorry. I had to get dressed.
-You the resident here?
-Yes.
-You alone in there?
No one else in there with you?
No. What's wrong?
First of all, you're
gonna have to turn down
the music so we can have a conversation.
[MUSIC STOPS]
[TV PLAYING INDISTINCTLY]
You mind if I come in?
No. Go ahead.
You got your neighbors
real worried for you.
I'm sorry.
-You live alone?
-Yes.
-What's your name?
-Claudia.
-Claudia what?
-Wilson.
Okay, Claudia Wilson
-are you trying to go deaf?
-What? Ha, ha.
-Did you hear what I just said?
-Yes, but I don't know what...
Okay. You're listening
to your music so loud
-you're gonna damage your ears.
-Okay.
If you continue to listen
to your music at that level
you're gonna damage not only your
ears, but your neighbors' ears as well.
-I didn't realize it was that loud.
-Yeah.
Well, that right there is the
first sign of hearing loss, okay?
Okay.
I see you got your TV on there too.
You usually keep that
on at the same time?
I don't know. I mean, um... What is this?
-You been doing some drugs today, Claudia?
-No.
-Have you been doing some drinking?
-No, ha, ha.
Okay.
I got a call of a disturbance here.
Some loud music, A, and
some screaming and yelling.
Has there been some
screaming and yelling here?
Yes.
I had someone come to my door.
Someone that I didn't want here.
And I told them to
leave, so it's no big deal.
They left. I'm sorry.
-Was that your boyfriend?
-No.
-You don't have a boyfriend?
Well, who was it?
I was... He's gone.
I mean, it's not... It's over, you know?
You mind if I have a look
around for your safety?
-It's fine.
-Okay.
Uh, what...? What are you looking for?
Claudia, why don't you let
me handle the questions,
-and you handle the answers, okay?
-Okay.
-I'm here to help you.
-So do you still have to do homework?
-Not as much as I used to.
Since we started, I haven't
gone to school much.
-I've had so many auditions.
-I don't have regular classes anymore.
-What do you do?
-They let me have my own study time.
-My own reading time in the library.
-That's pretty cool.
-Do you have an agent, Stanley?
-STANLEY: No.
You should get one. I'm serious.
You could get a lot of stuff out of this.
-Like what?
-What do you mean? Endorsements and shit!
-Richard.
-Bite it, Cynthia.
You get stuff from people that
want you to endorse their product.
Commercials, a sitcom,
an MOW or something.
-What's MOW?
-Hello. Movie of the week.
I went for one this morning
with Alan Thicke and Corey Haim.
RICHARD: Was it a callback?
JULIA: No, but I'll
probably get a callback.
RICHARD: If we beat the
record, you might get a callback.
JULIA: I'll get it because
I'm a good actress, Richard.
-RICHARD: Saucy, saucy.
-CYNTHIA: Come on, guys. Settle down.
-Cynthia?
-What do you want?
-STANLEY: I gotta go to the bathroom.
-CYNTHIA: Can you hold it?
[ALL CHEERING]
Yessiree! Whoa!
That was absolutely fantastic,
and I thank you very much.
As a matter of fact, we may even
take you folks on the road with us.
LUIS: That's my thing. Come
on. I'm serious. Come on.
Milk and sports, man. You never
heard...? Milk and sports, okay?
Anything baseball. Um,
anything dealing with numbers
when it comes to those, you
know, or who broke whatever record.
Any kind of dairy product,
any kind... Dairy recipe
um, like goat milk, goat
cheese, goat... All that stuff.
Wow, check this out over here.
So, um, look guys, just work
with me on that. Work with me.
Excuse me, can you bring
me low-fat milk, please?
A couple of ice cubes.
Ah, they don't look so tough.
-STANLEY: Do they look smart?
-No.
-RICHARD: What are they gonna do, beat us?
-STANLEY: Maybe.
We're not going out two
days before we set the record.
It's not gonna happen.
RICHARD: Yeah. When they want us done
they'll call in the Harvard
SWAT team or some shit.
Ready to run.
-BURT: You smell like trouble.
-I'm fucking hammered.
-You okay?
-You know.
Good. You have a
chance to look those over?
Oh, come on. It's the same
fucking shit for 30 years, Burt.
You look like you have
money in your pocket.
[THURSTON CHUCKLES]
Maybe I'm just happy to
see my friend Brad there.
[DONNIE CHUCKLES]
DONNIE: Just throw some money around.
-Money, money, money.
-It's Brad.
Ooh. This sounds threatening.
Do you have love in your heart?
I have love all over.
I even have love for you, friend.
-Is it real love?
-Well...
The kind of love that makes
you feel that intangible joy
in the pit of your stomach
like a bucket of acid and
nerves running around,
and making you hurt
and happy and all over...?
You're head over heels?
You lost me with the last couple
of cocktail words spoken, my boy,
but I believe it's that sort of love.
Sounds nice to me.
I have love.
Hmm, a very chatty kind.
Indeed you do, it seems.
No, I mean, I'm telling you.
I'm telling you, I have love.
Yes, and I'm listening avidly, fellow.
My name is Donnie Smith,
and I have lots of love to give.
-Hello.
-Hi.
Wow.
Lot of stuff here, huh?
[BOTH SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
It's 30 seconds.
[BELL RINGS]
...Eye on you. I'll be back.
-Hi, Cynthia.
-Jakety, Jakety.
RICHARD: The fuck is going on over there?
-I gotta go to the bathroom.
-Jesus Christ, Stanley.
No, no, no. You cannot do that. Let
me explain something to you people.
You have to tone it. Don't
be real aggressive like that.
Be subtly abusive so they
don't know what's happening.
You say, "You're not gonna go
outside and play with your friends
until that entire room is
cleaned floor to ceiling."
Oh, Julia's room's the same way.
JULIA'S DAD: Like a pigsty.
But it's the outfits we're into now.
Oh, you should have seen what
she had on walking out the door.
I said, "No. We're going to
school, not a fashion show."
RICHARD'S MOM: It's not
a fashion show. It's school.
JULIA'S MOM: Absolutely.
It's not a fashion show.
Shh.
Let's make some fucking
money here, people.
You with me, Jimmy?
JIMMY: The book says, "We
may be through with the past,
but the past ain't through with us."
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
We met upon the level, and
we're parting on the square.
In my fucking sleep, Burt.
And five, four, three, two...
Live from Burbank, California,
it's What Do Kids Know?
Going into our 33rd year on the air, it's
America's longest-running quiz show,
and the place where three
kids get to challenge three adults,
and in the end, we'll see who's the boss.
Moving towards their eighth
consecutive week as champions
we have the kids:
Richard, Julia, and Stanley.
And our new adult challengers
today are Mim, Luis, and Todd.
And me, I'm Dick Jennings,
and now say hello to your
favorite host and my boss
Jimmy Gator.
[ALL CHEERING]
Back again, again, again. I'm
Jimmy Gator, and believe it or not
we are at the end of Week
7, heading towards Week 8
with these three incredible
kids, who... Hello, hello.
...Are just two days and two games away
from the What Do Kids Know? record...
...for the longest-running
quiz show in television history.
Now, we are, as you know,
endorsed by the PTA,
and the North American
Teachers' Foundation.
We keep our standards high, and that's why
we are the longest-running quiz show
in television history. I wanna
say something about these kids now.
These kids right here, I think
they're gonna be here a while.
But today is a dangerous day
because I have just met with
the adult challengers backstage,
and let me tell you, they are
a terrific challenge for our kids.
So let's get this show
up and away, shall we?
[AUDIENCE APPLAUDS]
DETECTIVE: We wanna
know where your son is.
"Jerome Samuel Hall." Did he
fight your husband? Is this the Worm?
-DETECTIVE: They had a fight. An accident.
-OFFICER: They call him Worm?
DETECTIVE: We wanna
know where your son is.
-Help us, Marcie.
-Do they call him Worm?
-Help us help your son, Marcie.
-OFFICER: Do they call him Worm?
DETECTIVE: Help us help your son, Marcie.
OFFICER: Your son and your
grandson. Help us help them.
Is this the Worm?
[DOOR OPENS]
JIMMY [ON TV]: Let's jump right in.
A quick recap for those who don't know.
Round One. Three
categories. Steals are okay.
Point scale escalating from 25 to 250,
one of which is a conversation bonus.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
[DOGS BARKING]
-Hi.
-That'll be 31.90.
The categories are "authors, chaos
versus superstring, and rub-a-dub."
[DOGS BARKING]
-Max. Thanks.
-Bye.
Adults won a coin toss
backstage, so they get to pick first.
Team captain: Mim.
[DOGS BARKING]
First question, for 25.
This female author's most
famous work: O Pioneers!
PHIL: H-E-R.
[BUZZER RINGS]
-JIMMY: Stanley?
-Willa Cather.
Willa Cather for 25.
Best known for the tragedy-of-blood
genre, this playwright...
[BUZZER RINGS]
-Stanley.
-Thomas Kyd.
Thomas Kyd.
This French playwright and actor
joined the Bjart troupe of actors...
[BUZZER RINGS]
-Stanley.
-Molire.
Oh, I'm afraid I'm gonna
need a full name, Stanley.
Jean Baptiste Poquelin Molire.
What the fuck is this?
God damn. My little fucker. Ha-ha-ha!
I have no idea where he gets this
shit. He's a fucking genius, really.
CHAD [OVER PHONE]:
Seduce and Destroy. This is Chad.
Can I have your phone number?
Is this Seduce and Destroy?
Yes, it is. Can I have your phone number?
Okay, I don't want to order
anything. Uh, you see...
I have a situation, uh, that's just
come up that's really pretty serious,
and I don't know who to
talk to or what I should do,
but maybe you could put me in
touch with somebody if I explain myself?
Uh, we're really only equipped
to take orders here, sir.
I mean, it's just us with the phones,
and that's what we do, you know...
Okay, okay, okay. Could you connect
me with somebody else, you think?
Well, what's the situation?
Okay, great, um...
All right. Let me try to explain
myself without it seeming crazy.
But here I go. I'm... No.
Uh, my name is Phil Parma,
and I work for, uh, a
man named Earl Partridge.
Uh, Mr. Earl Partridge.
I'm his nurse, and he's a very sick man.
He's a dying man, and he's sick,
and he has asked me to help him.
To help him find his son.
-Hello? Are you there? Hello?
-No, I'm here. I'm listening.
Okay. Um, you see
Frank T.J. Mackey
is Earl Partridge's son.
So where are you from originally?
-FRANK: From around here.
-Valley?
-Well, Hollywood, mainly.
-What did your parents do?
Uh, my father... Well,
he was in television.
My mother...
-This is going to sound silly to you.
-Try me.
-Uh, she was a librarian.
-Why does that sound silly?
I don't know. I guess it doesn't.
-Does your mother still work?
-No, she's retired.
-Are you close?
-She's my mother.
Yes, but, uh, I mean, she's a woman too,
so how does she feel
about Seduce and Destroy?
I mean, what does she say?
[FRANK LAUGHS]
Well, she says, uh,
"You go get them, honey."
Uh-huh. And what about your father?
Oh, my father. Unfortunately,
he passed away.
-Oh, I'm sorry. I had no idea.
-No, please.
I wouldn't have brought
that up if I had known.
-That's a very hard thing.
-Please.
Yes, it is, but listen.
I mean, you have to move
forward. The past has its place.
-It was a long time ago, and people die.
-Yeah.
Okay, let's switch gears here. Um...
According to your book,
you ended up at UC Berkeley?
'84 to '89.
-Psychology major.
-That's right.
-Get your masters?
-Hmm? Oh.
-This close.
-Wow.
-That's impressive in five years.
-Cap, can I have some coffee?
Can I get you anything?
-No, no, no, I'm good. Thank you.
-You sure? Okay.
-She's good. I need coffee.
-Ha, ha.
PHARMACIST: Cats and dogs out there, huh?
Must have a lot going on for
all that stuff back there, huh?
You could, uh...
Heh. You could have
quite a party, all that stuff.
You been on Prozac long? Dexedrine?
-I don't...
-Interesting drugs.
Dexedrine's basically
speed in a pill, you know.
I guess a lot of the doctors are balancing
out the Prozac with the Dexedrine, so...
That liquid morphine
will knock you down, out
around, up and down,
someone's not careful.
You can't mix those up, you know.
[RINGS]
Strong, strong stuff here, boy. Wow!
What you have wrong,
you need all this stuff?
-Motherfucker.
-What?
-Motherfucker. You fucking asshole.
-What are you talking about?
-Who the fuck do you think you are?
-I'm just trying...
I come in here. You don't know me.
You don't know who I am, what my life is,
and you have the balls, the indecency
to ask me a question about my life?
-Please, lady, calm down.
-Fuck you too! Don't you call me "lady"!
I come in here, I give
these things to you
you check, you make your phone calls
look suspicious, ask questions.
I'm sick.
I have sickness all around me,
and you fucking ask me my life?
"What's wrong?"
Have you seen death in
your bed? In your house?
Where's your fucking decency?
And then I'm asked fucking questions.
"What's wrong?"
You suck my dick, that's what's wrong.
And you. You fucking call me "lady"?
Shame on you!
Shame on you. Shame on both of you.
CHAD [OVER PHONE]: Why
don't they have the same last name?
Because they don't
have the same last name.
PHIL: I know, and I can't
really explain that, but I think...
I have a feeling there is something,
you know, a situation between them
like they don't know each
other much or well, you know?
Something like they don't
talk much anymore, even.
Uh-huh.
You know? God, does this sound weird?
Ha, ha. I just don't understand
why you're calling me.
Well, there's no number for
Frank in any of Earl's stuff
you know, and he's pretty out of it.
I mean, like I said, he's dying.
Dying of cancer. So...
-What kind of cancer?
-It's brain and lung.
-My mother had breast cancer.
-Oh, I'm sorry.
-Is she all right?
-Oh, she's fine now.
-Oh, that's good.
-It was scary, though.
-Oh, it's a hell of a disease.
-Oh, it sure is.
-Yeah.
-Well, so, uh...
Wait, I'm sorry. So why call me?
I know this sounds silly, and I
know that I might sound ridiculous
like this is the scene of the movie
where the guy is trying to
get ahold of the long-lost son
you know, but this is that
scene. This is that scene.
And I think they have
those scenes in movies
because they're true, you know.
Because they really happen.
And you gotta believe
me, this is really happening.
I mean, I can give you my
number and you can go check
with whoever you gotta check with,
but do not leave me hanging on this.
All right? Please. I'm just... Please.
See... [CHUCKLES]
See, this is, uh, the scene of
the movie where you help me out.
You're great. These are great questions.
-GWENOVIER: Thank you. Good, good.
-This is going great.
See, I thought you grew
up here in the Valley.
Yeah. You know, like I said. Around.
You went to Van Nuys High, right?
I wouldn't say I went. I frequented.
I was misguided, pathetic.
Not the Frank T.J. Mackey
you're so eagerly, uh, wanting
to put on national television.
Because I was swimming in what
was as opposed to what I wanted.
-Where does that name come from?
-What name? My name?
Yeah. It's not your given name, right?
It's my mother's name, actually.
That's good. Good. Done your research.
-And "Frank"?
-Frank is my mother's father.
Oh, okay. That's why.
See, I had some trouble
locating your school records
at, um, UCLA and, uh, Berkeley.
And it's your name change.
See, they had no
official enrollment for you.
-No, no, no, they wouldn't.
-They wouldn't?
No, because I was never
officially enrolled there.
-Was that unclear?
-Kind of.
Oh. God, I wouldn't want
that to be misunderstood.
No, uh, my enrollment
was totally unofficial.
Sadly, I couldn't afford
to pay the tuition up there.
There were three wonderful professors
who let me to sit in their classes.
Their names were Macready,
Horn, and Langtree, among others.
You're welcome to call them if
you like. See, I didn't get a free ride,
so, what we're looking at
here is a true rags-to-riches story.
That's why people respond
so strongly to Seduce
because at the end of the
day, Seduce may not be just
about picking up chicks,
sticking your cock in.
It's about finding out what
you can be in this world
defining it, controlling it, and
saying, "I will take what is mine."
And you happen to get
a little blow job out of it
-then, hey, what the fuck? Why not?
-Ha, ha, okay. There you go.
End of Round One. Excellent
work, ladies and germs.
I think we should take a
look at the scores here.
Kids are up a leg with 1500,
and the adults are
down a little bit with 1025.
So we'll be back for
Round Two in a ring-ding-do.
[MUSIC PLAYS]
Whoa, hello, hello.
Bonus musical question.
And the winner is
Kids.
[AUDIENCE APPLAUDING]
Uh, kids are in the lead. They
get a chance to pull further ahead
if they can answer the following
secret-bonus musical question.
Now, what I'm going to do
is read a line from an opera.
Give me that line back
in the language in which
the opera was written,
and for a bonus 250... Um, 250... Uh, 250
uh, you can sing it. Heh.
Here's the line.
"Love is a rebellious bird
that nobody can tame,
and it's all in vain to call
it if it chooses to refuse."
[BUZZER RINGS]
Yes, Stanley.
Well, that was in French,
and that was from the opera Carmen,
and that goes:
[SINGING IN FRENCH]
-You got some coffee brewing here.
-CLAUDIA: It's not...
[CLAUDIA COUGHS]
It's been on for a bit.
Yeah, I like iced coffee, generally,
but a day like today, you
know, with the rain and whatnot
I enjoy a warm cup.
[CLAUDIA SIGHS]
Do you want a cup?
Is that all right? Just raining
cats and dogs out there.
I'd just as soon not go back in it. Heh.
I don't know how fresh it's gonna be.
Oh, I'm sure it's fine, Claudia.
Do you, um, take cream or sugar?
That would be fine. Um...
So, Claudia, let me just say, so I
can get my role as an LAPD officer
out of the way before
we enjoy our coffee.
I don't like to talk shop over coffee.
I'm not gonna write you up.
I'm not gonna give you a citation here,
but the real problem we have here
is that you got people around you
people who work from home
trying to get some work done,
and if you're listening to your music
that loud, they're inconvenienced by that.
If you had a job, you'd
probably understand, but...
You like listening to your music.
That's fine. That's fine. Um...
You're just gonna wanna
keep an eye on the volume level.
You know, maybe memorize
what number you see on the dial.
If it's the middle of the
day, that's what I do.
I set it at two and a half, and then I
know that's a good listening level for me.
But, uh, you like listening
to your music loud.
That's fine. That's cool. It's
good to rock out sometimes.
But you can't do it every day,
or else you risk damaging
your ears. Seriously.
-You listen to it all the time like that?
-Yeah.
You're gonna drive these people crazy.
Anyway, you get the point.
-Yes.
-Okay.
Um...
Cheers.
-So this boyfriend bothering you?
-I don't have a boyfriend.
-The gentleman who was at the door...
-He's not my boyfriend.
Okay. A lot of times, in
domestic-abuse situations
the young woman is afraid to speak out.
You don't have to be
afraid to tell me anything.
And as a police officer, I can tell you
it goes bad places.
Young woman is afraid, next
thing you know, I'm here on a 187.
It's not... What's a 187?
It's not good. And it's where
situations like this always lead.
It's not my boyfriend,
and it's not anything.
It's over. Really. It's
not. He won't come back.
-I don't wanna have to come back here...
-You won't have to.
You know, I... I wouldn't
mind coming back.
You know, get a look
at your pretty face again.
I'll be right back.
Here you go.
Let's get the jacket off.
It will help you to breathe.
[AUDIENCE APPLAUDING]
I can't fucking do this.
I've, uh...
I think... I'm gonna throw up, I think.
I haven't thrown up
since I was 20 years old.
STANLEY: Cynthia.
BURT: You are the man.
[DICK AND BURT SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
-What's the problem?
-I need to go to the bathroom.
Jesus Christ, Stanley. You can't go now.
You have one minute
before we're on the air.
Now is not the time
to go to the bathroom.
-RICHARD: Why does this always happen?
-Hey.
Excuse me, is there a problem over there?
Mind your own business.
-You better watch your mouth.
-Why don't you mind your own business?
-LUIS: Oh, no, she didn't.
-Cool down. Cool it, please.
Now, Stanley, wait for the
commercial break, then you can go.
-Just hold it.
-LUIS: Where did they get these kids?
Don't taunt the kids.
-I'm trying to be helpful.
-CYNTHIA: Don't start trouble, Luis.
Honey, you haven't seen trouble.
Wait till next commercial break.
-What's the problem?
-Nothing.
Lily! Please!
FRANK [ON RECORDING]:
Order Seduce and Destroy...
-Get away from me, you shithead!
-Okay.
[DOGS BARKING]
Can't afford it? We'll
work out something for you.
Seduce and Destroy will change your life.
Watch out, watch out, watch out.
No.
Don't, don't, don't.
-I'm gonna save you.
-Hi? Hello? Okay.
I guarantee, money-back guarantee...
-Don't eat these.
-This will change your life.
It's gonna help you get
that naughty sauce that you...
-For a low cost of 49.99...
-PHIL: Here you go.
[EARL GROANING]
Come on out of the cold and
order Seduce and Destroy,
for the low cost of 49.99.
We take all credit cards.
-I take Visa, MasterCard...
-PHIL: Out of the trash, out of the trash.
CHAD: Hey, Phil, are you there?
-It's Chad.
-Yeah. Hi, Chad.
Yeah, listen, I'm gonna put you in
touch with Janet, Frank's assistant.
-Okay.
-And she's gonna see what she can do.
Thank you very much, and
good luck to you and your mother.
Thanks, man. You too.
Okay, Janet, are you there?
JANET: Hello?
CHAD: All right, Janet,
you have Phil Parma.
Okay?
I have cancer, Mary. I
have about two months.
I have no time.
It's in my bones. I don't have a chance.
-Oh.
-I'm fucked.
-DIRECTOR: And 15 seconds.
-LUIS: You got any cookies or anything?
[TEAMS WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY]
DIRECTOR: Ten seconds.
And five, four, three, two...
We're back, ready for Round Two.
We're talking to our adult
contestants here today.
Uh, Mim, it says here
that you live in California,
and that you have two kids.
MIM: Right. I have a six-year-old son...
Do you know who I am?
You're a friend of the family, I presume.
What does that mean?
Nothing special. Just
a spoke in the wheel.
You talk in rhymes and
riddles and rub-a-dub,
but that doesn't mean anything to
me. See, see... See, I used to be smart.
I'm "Quiz Kid" Donnie Smith.
I'm "Quiz Kid" Donnie Smith from TV.
It might have been before my time.
MAN: I remember
now. In the sixties, right?
-I'm "Quiz Kid" Donnie Smith.
-Like you said.
Smart kid. You got struck
by lightning at one time, right?
DONNIE: So what?
-I heard about that.
-Did it hurt?
DONNIE: Yes.
But you're all right now.
So, what's the what?
-What?
-That's right.
I used to be smart. Now I'm just stupid.
Ha! Brad, dear, who was it that said:
"A man of genius has seldom
been ruined but by himself"?
Um...
-THURSTON: The lovely Samuel Johnson.
-Ah.
Who also spoke of a fellow
who was not only dull,
but a cause of dullness in others.
DONNIE: The cause of dullness in others.
-Picky, picky.
-Let me tell you this.
Samuel Johnson never
had his life shit on,
and taken from him, and his money stolen.
Who took his life and his money?
His parents? His mommy and daddy?
Make him live this life like this.
A man of genius who
gets shit on as a child,
and that scars. That hurts.
Have you ever been hit by lightning?
It hurts. It doesn't happen to everyone.
It's an electrical charge.
It finds its way across the universe,
and it lands in your body and your head.
And as for "ruined but by himself"
not if his parents
took his freaking life,
and his money, and tell you to do this,
and to do that, and if you don't, well...
MAN: Your parents took your money
that you won on that game show?
Yes. They did.
What does that mean,
"a spoke in the wheel"?
THURSTON: Things go
round and round, don't they?
Yes, they do. They do.
But I'll make my dreams come true.
Sounds sad as a weeping willow.
I used to be smart.
But now I'm just stupid.
Shall we drink to that?
Um, I wanna talk a little bit
more about your background.
You made, um, some references earlier
to, uh, subjective human experiences
and terrible things, and, um...
Actually, I'm confused
about your past, is the thing.
-Is that still lingering? It's so boring.
-Just to clarify...
-Just wanna clear some things up.
-Useless. Mm.
Excuse me. See... Thank you,
Muff. It's a funny thing that...
This is an important element
of Seduce and Destroy.
Facing the past is an important
way of not making progress.
This is something I tell my
men over and over and over.
GWENOVIER: This isn't meant, um...
See, I try to teach my students to ask:
"What is it in aid of?"
-Are you asking me that?
-Yes.
Well, in trying to
figure out who you are...
In aid of what?
Well, Frank, I'm saying that in
trying to figure out who you are...
I have more important things
-to put myself into.
-Well, no, it's all important.
I think this is something important
that you might need to
think about putting yourself into.
-Mm. Not really.
-Um, look, Frank
it's not like I'm trying
to attack you here.
-No.
-I just...
Okay. Hey, this is how you wanna
spend your time, then go, go, go.
But you're gonna be
surprised at what a waste it is.
"The most useless thing in the world is
that which is behind me." Chapter Three.
We talked earlier about your mother,
and we talked about
your father and his death.
I don't want to be challenging,
but I have to ask, um...
I just wanna clarify something.
Something that I understand...
I'm not sure I hear a question in here.
I'm trying to put this
as delicately as I can.
What's the question?
-Do you remember a Miss Simms?
-I know a lot of women.
-I'm sure she remembers me, ha, ha.
-She does. From when you were a boy.
-Yeah?
-She lived in Tarzana.
That's my old stomping ground.
Is this the attack
portion of the interview?
[GWENOVIER LAUGHS]
Is the girl coming in for the kill?
No. This is about
getting something right,
and clarifying answers
to an earlier question.
What question?
I was told that your mother died, Frank.
That's what you heard.
[CHUCKLES]
Do you remember Miss Simms?
-No.
-Well, I talked to Miss Simms
your neighbor and caretaker
after your mother died in 1980,
and in my research
I have you listed as the only
son of Earl and Lily Partridge.
And what I learned from Barbara
Simms is that your mother, Lily
died in 1980.
So, see, it's my understanding
that information supplied
by you and your company,
and the answers to the
questions I've asked is incorrect,
and if I wanna get to the bottom
of who you are and why you are
then I think that your family
history, your actual family history...
Well, this is important.
What is your fucking question?
Well, I guess my question is this:
Why would you lie, Frank?
[CLEARS THROAT]
Kids, adults
I would like you to
put yourself at a picnic.
Uh, place yourself there with
your family and friends, if you'd like.
You'll hear three musical
notes, and you are to tell me
what it might represent
that you would find at a picnic.
The first three notes. Guys?
[MUSIC NOTES PLAY]
[BUZZER RINGS]
-JIMMY: Yes, Todd.
-Well, Jimmy, I know this.
I have perfect pitch, you
see, and that would be A-D-E,
-and that would represent lemonade.
-JIMMY: For 250. Next notes, please.
[MUSIC NOTES PLAY]
[BUZZER RINGS]
-JIMMY: Todd?
-TODD: That's E-G-G, which would be egg.
JIMMY: For 500. And the
third set of notes. Guys?
[MUSIC NOTES PLAY]
-You don't want any water?
-No. I just...
I'm so fucked up right now, Alan.
-There's just so much. So many things.
-Are you on drugs right now?
If I tell you something, if I say
things, then... You're a lawyer, right?
You can't say anything, tell anybody.
It's like a privilege. Attorney/client.
-You understand?
-Not exactly.
Like a shrink. If I go see
a shrink, I'm protected.
I can say things. Oh, fuck.
-I don't know what I'm doing.
-Linda, you're safe, okay? It's all right.
You're my friend. You
and Earl are clients.
Whatever you wanna
say won't leave this room.
You have something you wanna say to me...
I have to tell you something.
I have something to tell you.
I wanna change his will. Can
I change his will? I need to.
No, you can't change
his will. Only Earl can.
No, no, no. You see, um
I never loved him.
I never loved him. Earl.
When I met him... When I started... I met
him, I fucked him, and I married him
because I wanted his
money. You understand?
Uh, I'm telling you this.
I've never told anyone.
Uh, I didn't love him,
but now... I know I'm in
that will. We were all there.
We made that thing.
And the money I'll get.
I don't want it, because I love him now.
I've fallen in love with him
now for real, as he's dying, and...
Uh, I look at him, and he's
about to go, Alan. He's moments...
I took care of him through
this, Alan. What now, then?
JIMMY: Let's listen.
[IN SOUTHERN ACCENT] "Hello,
Mary. How are you and the seven kids?
As you probably heard by now, we
sure gave that Pope a run for his money."
[BUZZER RINGS]
-JIMMY: Mim.
-MIM: Um, that would be Robert E. Lee.
His wife was Mary Parke Custis.
I know he had seven children.
Um, and he would be talking about Pope,
who he defeated at the Battle of Manassas.
JIMMY: Absolutely right,
Miss Mim. Next question.
Come on, come on, come
on. Snap out of it, man.
Come on. Stanley.
[SIGHS]
DICK: Bonjour, Josephine.
Maintenant je suis en gypte.
[BUZZER RINGS]
JIMMY: Yes, Mim.
MIM: Um, that would be
Napoleon speaking to Josephine.
JIMMY: Absolutely
right, for 500. Next voice.
I don't want him to die. I
didn't love him when we met,
and I did so many bad things
to him that he doesn't know.
Things that I want to confess
to him. But now I do. I love him.
Linda, what kind of
medication are you on?
This isn't any fucking
medication talking!
Can you give me nothing?
You have power of attorney.
Can you go in the final fucking
moments and change the will?
I... I don't want any money.
I couldn't live with myself
with this thing that I've done.
I fucked around. I fucking cheated
on him. I fucking cheated on him.
There. There. You're
his lawyer, our lawyer.
I am his wife. We are married.
I broke the contract of marriage.
I fucked around on him many
times. I sucked other men's cocks.
ALAN: Adultery is not against the law.
It's not something you can
use in court to discredit the will.
-Linda. Linda, calm down.
-I can't.
You don't have to change the will.
If you wanna take nothing,
renounce the will when the time comes.
What does that mean?
Where does the money go?
-It goes to the nearest relative.
-What's that? Frank?
No, no, no. That can't happen. Earl
doesn't want him to have anything.
-That's what will happen.
-This is so fucked up.
Linda, stop!
Now, you take a moment, you breathe,
-and one thing at a time.
-Shut the fuck up.
-You want me to help you?
-You need to sober up.
-Now, you must really shut the fuck up.
Now. Please, shut the fuck up.
-Linda.
-I have to go.
-Let me call you a car, Linda.
-Shut the fuck up.
JIMMY: Now, imagine that you
are attending a jam session
of classical composers,
and they have each done an arrangement
of the classic favorite, "Whispering."
Now, we have here the
New World Harmonica Trio
who are going to play, uh...
Uh, three, um... Uh,
variations on the theme
as the, uh... As...
As three classical composers
might have written it.
So you are to name
the, uh, first composer.
Guys?
[HARMONICAS PLAYING
"WHISPERING" IN STYLE OF BRAHMS]
[BUZZER RINGS]
-JIMMY: Yes, Todd.
-Well, Jimmy, that sounded like Brahms.
Uh, a bit like his "Hungarian
Dance Number Six."
That is excellent, Todd.
Next composer, guys.
[HARMONICAS PLAYING
"WHISPERING" IN STYLE OF RAVEL]
[BUZZER RINGS]
Stanley the man.
I don't know the answer.
That is not right.
That's not right, Stanley.
The correct answer is Ravel.
Ravel.
Uh, and now I'm gonna
have our three whistlers, um
please to present
the next, uh, musical...
There were three, uh,
musical sections here,
and this will be the third
section that the whistlers...
Um, and they'll play a piece that's...
It's very recognizable. It's
Chopin, actually, and, uh...
Well, it's taken... It's in the
style of "Marche Militaire."
It's a very recognizable piece.
So if you please just listen to this,
and I'm sure you can identify the, uh...
I'm sort of giving away
the answer here, but...
It's Chopin. I don't mean
to give away the answer.
It's just... Please, just...
Well, sing us a ditty,
guys. A Chopin ditty.
Let's have a Chopin
ditty here. I can't...
-Go to the card. Go to the fucking card.
-Go to the card. Go.
Go to the card.
[SNIFFING]
Okay, I'm back.
JIM: For not a fresh cup,
this is a good cup of coffee.
CLAUDIA: Thank you. What
do you wanna talk about?
I don't know.
-Do you want to talk?
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-Okay.
-Um...
What's your name?
Jim Kurring.
-BURT: Call 911.
-I think I had a stroke.
No, no, no. I'm fine. I'm all right.
-I wanna finish the show.
-BURT: No, we need to call this quits.
-Get your hands off me.
-Let this guy help you.
Look, I just... I'll tell
you what happened.
Call 911. Do it right now, Mary.
I fell down and I couldn't see for a
minute, but I'm okay.
Get your hands off me.
-Did you fucking piss your pants?
-Shut up.
-What happened? What's going on?
-Nothing. Go away.
Don't tell me to go away.
I'm the coordinator for the show,
and you will answer the questions I ask.
-Now, what is going on? You...
-What's the problem?
-Nothing. I'm fine.
-Why didn't you answer those questions?
-I didn't know the answer.
-Bullshit! Bullshit!
You know the answer to every question.
I knew the answers. I'm
not half as smart as you,
so what the hell happened?
-I don't know.
-He pissed his pants.
[WHISPERS] You pissed your pants?
-No, I didn't. I'm fine.
-Stand up.
-I said I'm fine. I'm fine.
Oh, Jesus, Stanley, what
the fuck did you do that for?
I just wanna keep playing.
I'll keep playing. I'm fine.
That's great.
I mean, you know that, to a
performer, that's food, right?
That shows that you love him,
and I'm sure he appreciates it.
Everything's fine. Relax.
Relax, darling. Everything's fine.
I'm okay.
All right, see? I'm all right.
It's pretty fucking stupid,
isn't it? Jesus Christ.
What the fuck do they think out there?
They must be laughing their asses off.
Tell them I got a bad
knee or some fucking thing.
Ha, ha. This is fucking funny.
-What do you guys wanna do?
-Just what I said.
-Are we going to continue with this game?
-Yes.
All right, you look at me. Look at me.
You are two days away from this
record. Okay? Nobody's ever done that.
You get through this, I'll get
you anything you want. Anything.
-You just gotta get through this, okay?
-Okay.
[RICH SIGHS]
Hang in there, buddy. I'm
sorry I squeezed your arm.
Hey. I love you.
[AUDIENCE APPLAUDING]
-Are we doing this?
-BURT: Fucking stupidity.
-Why don't I put the medic on?
-Don't let him do this.
-He's been doing it for 30 years.
-You don't know.
It's a fucking game show, Mary.
[JAW CLICKING]
Hear that?
-JIM: Ah, yeah. Does that hurt?
-No.
-What is it?
-It's in my ear.
It's, um, TMJ.
It's what it's called. Technically.
How about they just call
it, you know, "clicking jaw"?
-"Pain in the jaw," yeah. Ha, ha.
-Yeah. How about that?
-Be easier to remember.
-Yeah. It gets...
I... I don't even know
if I have it, actually.
WOMAN [OVER RADIO]:
15-L-27, 15-L-27, head out to...
I'm sorry.
15-L-27, I'm currently code seven.
I'm sorry. This is my job.
WOMAN: L-27, roger.
MAN 1: William-35, can you see if
you can raise 10-William-28 for me?
MAN 2: Roger. Disregard. It
was just the information passed on.
You were just getting
warmed up. Getting started.
Yeah. I gotta go.
Well, if this joker shows up again,
or you got your music up too loud
maybe we can have another cup of coffee.
If you're not here for a 187.
-No. Do not joke about that, okay?
-Okay.
-I seen too many of those.
-I'm sorry.
No, it's all right. You
were kidding. It's okay.
All right.
Well, you keep your chin up
and your music down, okay?
Yes, I will. It was nice
to meet you, Officer Jim.
-Just Jim.
-Yeah. Good. Okay.
-Okay. Bye-bye, Claudia.
-Bye.
[DISPATCH RADIO CHATTERING]
[SHUTS OFF RADIO]
-What is it? Did you forget something?
-No. No, I'm...
I was... I was wondering...
Man, I feel like a bit of a
scumbucket doing this
since I came here
as an officer of the law,
but I feel like I'd be a fool if I
didn't do something I really wanna do
-which is to ask you for a date.
-You wanna go on a date with me?
-Please, yes.
-Ahem.
-Well, is that illegal?
-Sort of.
Then I'd like to go.
What do you wanna do?
I don't know. I hadn't thought about it.
That's not true. I have thought about it.
I've been thinking since
you opened the door.
-Really?
-Yeah.
I thought you were flirting with me.
You want to go tonight?
I'm... No... I'm off tonight,
yeah. That would be...
-What time?
-8 o'clock.
-I don't get off until 10:00.
-Ten o'clock.
-Okay.
-Yeah.
-Yeah. Fine.
-Yeah. Bye.
[LOCK CLICKS]
GWENOVIER: Frank, I'm really
not trying to attack you here.
I think that if you have something
that needs to be cleared up, well, then...
I was told that your
father is Earl Partridge.
I was told that he left
you and your mother,
and you were forced to take care
of your mother during her illness
that you took care of your mother
while she struggled with cancer,
and that Miss Simms became your caretaker
when your mother finally passed away.
Can you talk about your mother, Frank?
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
No, not true. You know what?
Even if you don't get to pump her
you still need to start
honing your skills on a feminist.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
-You need to do that.
-MAN: I will.
-This is Doc.
-JANET: Doc, it's Janet.
-What's up, Janet?
-I have to talk to Frank. Is he nearby?
-Uh, he's in the interview, Janet.
-Interrupt him.
-Get him on the phone with me right away.
-What happened?
Doc, go get Frank and
put him on the phone.
[GWENOVIER SIGHS]
GWENOVIER: Oh, come on, Frank.
What are you doing?
What am I doing?
Yeah.
I'm quietly judging you.
[AUDIENCE APPLAUDING]
And five, four, three, two...
Yeah?
Oh, boy, what a day. What a round.
Back and in for me,
and the final one-on-one round
to determine who's who today.
Let's check the scores
on the board, shall we?
Well, the kids have an even 2000,
and the adults are way up with 47.
Now, that doesn't mean that this
game is out of reach for the kids.
-Elders, who's the lucky so-and-so?
-It's gonna be me, Jimmy.
[AUDIENCE APPLAUDING]
Come on over, Mim.
I don't wanna go. I
can't do it this time.
What the fuck are you talking about?
You have to go, Stanley.
You're the smartest.
I don't wanna go. Why
can't one of you do it?
RICHARD: If you don't fucking stand up and
get over there, I'm gonna beat your ass.
I'm sick of being the one who
always has to do everything.
-I don't wanna be the one always.
-JIMMY: Kids, I don't even have to ask.
Stanley, get your butt over here.
I'm sick.
I'm sick here now.
I confuse melancholy
with depression sometimes.
-Mm-hm.
-You see?
Why don't you run along now,
friend? Your dessert is getting cold.
-I'm sick.
-THURSTON: Stay that way.
I'm sick, and I'm in love.
THURSTON: You seem the sort
of person who confuses the two.
That's right.
That's the first time you've been right.
I confuse the two, and I don't care.
Hey. Hey!
I love you.
I love you, and I'm sick.
I'll talk to you... I'll
talk to you tomorrow.
I'm getting corrective oral
surgery tomorrow, for my teeth.
I love you, Brad. Brad the bartender.
If you wanna love me
back, I'll be good to you.
I'll be goddamn good for you.
I won't be mad if you
don't know who said what.
I won't punish you if you
get the answer wrong.
-THURSTON: Brad, honey.
-I can teach and tell you...
You have a special secret
crush over there, I think.
Don't treat him too
lovely. He might get hurt.
-You shut up! Mind your own business.
-Gently, son.
I know you don't love me now.
It's a dangerous thing to
confuse children with angels.
Wanna know the common element
for the entire group, like he asked?
I'll tell you the answer,
because I had that one.
I had that question.
Uh, carbon. Carbon.
In pencil lead, it's in
the form of graphite
in coal, it's mixed up
with other impurities,
and in the diamond, it's in hard form.
"Well, all we really wanted to know
was the common element, Donnie,
but thank you for all that
unnecessary knowledge. Ha, ha.
Kids. Heads so full of useless knowledge.
Thank you. Thank you."
The book says, "We may
be through with the past,
but the past is not through with us."
And...
No, it is not dangerous to
confuse children with angels.
[VOMITS]
Yeah. Okay.
Well, that is what I wait for.
I wait for those calls.
And I wait and I pray.
And sometimes Jesus says:
"Jim, I got a surprise for you today.
I want you to meet this young lady, okay?
Now, where it goes
from there is up to you.
And I don't think you're
gonna screw it up, okay?"
And, God, I'm telling you right now
I will not screw it up.
You gave me an opportunity.
I'm gonna treat this young lady right.
I'm a happy cop.
Yeah. It's called jaywalking. Slow down.
Uh, I'm gonna pass, Jimmy.
JIMMY: Stanley, passing
to one of the other kids.
We want Stanley to go, Jimmy.
I don't wanna go.
-Walking towards the elevator, Janet.
-JANET: Fine. Phil, are you still there?
-PHIL: Yeah, I'm here.
-JANET: I wanna ask you one question.
Phil, have you talked to
anyone else about this?
PHIL: No, I haven't.
JANET: Good, let's
keep it that way, okay?
All the security and
whatnot. You understand?
This could be a delicate
situation for the family.
-DOC: What's going on? What's happening?
-JANET: Doc, fuck off.
Phil, hang in just one more minute, okay?
-I'm gonna put you on hold.
-PHIL: Thank you.
JANET: How close are you, Doc?
Richard? Julia?
Kids, what's going on?
I need a player here for one-on-one.
RICHARD: We want Stanley to go,
Jimmy, and we're not sure why he won't.
I always go. I always answer the
questions, and I don't
wanna do it anymore.
What the fuck is he doing?
What's wrong with him?
I have no idea.
[ELEVATOR DINGS]
-I'm getting off the elevator, Janet.
-JANET: Good. Good boy.
DOC: I'm walking down the hall.
[EARL GROANING SOFTLY]
This fucking kid ain't getting
up, and we don't have a show.
ANNOUNCER: Live television,
ladies and germs. Heh.
Little prick.
-What is this, a point? A game?
-What the hell is he doing?
Come on. Get the fuck up, kid, come on.
Time's up.
So that's what you did? You sat it out?
FRANK: You wanted
my time. I gave it to you.
You called me a liar.
You made accusations.
You said:
[AS GWENOVIER] "Well, if I had
known, then I wouldn't have asked."
So it's not an attack.
See, I don't wanna be the sort of
fella who doesn't keep his word,
so I gave you my fucking time, bitch.
-Now fuck...
-Unh!
DOC: It's fucking Janet.
There's a situation on the phone.
FRANK [ON RECORDING]: If you order
now, you can get Seduce and Destroy...
[DOGS BARKING]
...plus videos and audio
cassettes, and a coupon,
for Frank T.J. Mackey's next seminar.
[ALL BARKING]
The indecision of a
child, ladies and germs.
[AUDIENCE LAUGHS AND APPLAUDS]
This isn't funny.
This isn't cute.
See, the way we're looked at...
Because I'm not a toy.
I'm not a doll.
The way we're looked at
because you think we're cute.
Because what?
What? I'm made to feel like a freak
if I answer questions,
or I'm smart,
or I have to go to the bathroom?
What is that, Jimmy?
What is that?
I'm asking... I'm asking you that.
I'm not sure, Stanley.
[GUNSHOT]
[JIM GASPS]
[JIM PANTING]
JIM: 15-L-27, uh, I need some help.
We have shots fired.
DONNIE: It's Hamlet to Claudius.
"The sins of the father laid upon
the children" is Merchant of Venice.
Borrowed from Exodus 25.
JANET: I'm sorry. I didn't know
what else you wanted me to do here.
There was nothing... I asked
him all the right questions.
He's his nurse. He's
sitting there with him.
-I heard your father in the background.
-Wait. He's there at their house?
They're at the house. I asked him the
exact address, and he gave it, Frank.
I know this is really
hard for you right now.
No. You gotta give me
things, Janet. Give me things.
Give me information.
I want the information.
That's what I want.
-That's the information, Frank.
-What did he say?
I am not gonna take care of him.
What does he want? Did he say?
Frank, what the fuck
do you want me to do?
-Listen.
-What I want you to do, Janet
is I want you to do your fucking job!
I am doing my fucking job, Frank.
You fucking get on the phone.
I'm not a doll. I'm not silly and cute.
I'm smart. That should make me something,
so people can watch
how silly it is that he's smart!
I know. I know things.
I know... I know...
I know I have to go
to the bathroom, and...
Take us off the air. Go to the credits.
-Roll the credits.
-BURT: Enough.
God fucking damn it! Son of a bitch!
What the fuck? Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
Stanley, don't do this to me!
Gotta find the gun.
Where is it, now?
Where is it?
All right. All right, let's go.
Where is it? Find it.
Find it.
Find the gun, Jim!
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
[ENGINE IDLING]
-JANET: What more do you want me to say?
-Just give me a second.
You need to make a decision.
-Look, why don't you...?
-Look, just give me a second.
-Give me a second.
-Uh-huh.
Frank?
What the fuck, Frank?
What do you want me to do?
FRANK [ON RECORDING]: I'm gonna
say again. Order Seduce and Destroy now,
and I guarantee, I
guarantee, money-back...
[DOGS BARKING]
[ENGINE IDLING]
PHIL: Linda.
-What are you doing?
-I got Frank. Frank, Earl's son.
-Hang up.
-No, he asked me to get him.
LINDA: Put the fucking phone down!
-Hang it up! Hang it up!
-I can't! I can't!
JANET: Frank, are you there?
I want you to talk to him.
Frank?
I'm gonna put him on.
Hang it up! You don't do that.
You don't call him. You don't know.
To get involved in this business
of his. Of his... Of my family.
This is the family. Me
and him. Understand?
-There's no one else. No one else!
-I was just...
That man. That beautiful man...
His son does not exist.
He's dead. He's dead.
Who asked you to do that?
-Earl did.
-Bullshit!
-He did. Please, I'm sorry, he did.
-Bullshit! He didn't ask you!
He doesn't wanna talk to him,
so fuck you that he asked that!
There's no one but me and him! No one!
I'm sorry. I... He just... He asked me.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Mary, take me out of here.
I got to go home to Rose.
-Just lean on me.
-BURT: Mary, take him home.
-In the back.
-Did we win or lose?
I don't know. We gotta talk.
You lost. They go to the
score the time they called it.
-JULIA: That's not an official rule.
-Not an official rule?
-That's an official rule, baby.
-That's bullshit!
Who says that? In what rule book?
This is different! It's a game show!
-They don't go by fucking sports rules!
-Richard, shut it and cut it out.
If he hadn't pissed his pants, we
would have won this motherfucker!
[ALL SHOUTING]
What did you do with
my goddamn kid, Burt?
Stanley! Get your fucking hands off
me, you boy-producer punk. Hey, Stanley!
[CRYING] Oh, Lord, why
is this happening to me?
God, please help me figure it out.
I'm lost out here.
I don't understand
why it's happening, God.
Please, God.
[SIRENS APPROACHING]
Whatever it is I did, I'm gonna
fix it. I'm gonna do the right thing.
Please, God, help me find the gun.
Uh...
[SIRENS WAILING]
[SOBBING]
[CLAUDIA SOBBING]
[LINDA SNIFFLES]
[EARL GRUNTS SOFTLY]
[SOBBING]
[WHISPERS] I love you.
Uh, listen, Phil.
Um...
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I slapped your face.
Okay? I, um...
I don't know what I'm doing.
I don't know how to do this.
I do things, and I fuck up.
I fucked up.
Can you forgive me?
Yeah. It's all right.
Can you tell him I'm sorry,
for the things that I've
done, that I fucked up?
I'm sorry. Um...
I'm going to turn and walk
away and not look at him,
and not see my man,
my Earl, and tell him, uh...
Tell him, "It's okay. I'm okay."
Tell him, "Thank you for taking care..."
Whole thing is okay with me.
And I know.
[SIGHS]
[AUDIENCE CHEERING AND WHISTLING]
Welcome back from the break.
-How did you guys like those nachos?
-AUDIENCE: Yeah.
Yeah. Oh, yeah. Well, you
are not here for the fucking food.
You are here for me to
enlighten you, to edify you
to send you off into the
now-not-so-unknown future,
so come along with me.
"How to fake like you
are nice and caring."
No, I don't want a microphone.
Now, this...
Ahem, this is quite an
important chapter, as you will see.
But let's get down to brass tacks.
Let's get right down to it, boys.
-Men are shit.
-AUDIENCE: What?
What? Men are shit.
[AUDIENCE MURMURING]
Well, isn't that what they say?
Because we do bad things, don't we?
We do horrible, heinous, terrible things.
Things that no woman would ever do.
[AUDIENCE MURMURING]
No, women, they don't lie.
No, women don't cheat.
Women don't manipulate us.
[AUDIENCE MURMURING]
But you see what I'm getting at.
Oh, yeah, you see what I'm getting at.
You see what society
does? Boy. Little boys, it's:
Wow. Woman.
-We are taught to apologize. "I am sorry."
-MAN: Give it up.
"I am so sorry, baby. I am so sorry."
[SIGHS]
What is it that...?
What is it, huh, that we need?
Is it their pussies? Their, uh, love?
Mommy wouldn't let me play soccer,
and Daddy, oh, he hit
me, so that's who I am.
That's why I do what I do? Heh.
-Fucking bullshit.
-MAN: That's right.
-I will not apologize for who I am.
-MAN: Right on.
-I will not apologize for what I need.
-MAN: Yeah.
-I will not apologize for what I want!
-AUDIENCE: Yeah!
[AUDIENCE APPLAUDING]
Okay. Go to your blue booklets right now.
I want you to turn to page
18 in your blue booklets.
Fuck. This is fucking bullshit!
[GLASS BREAKS]
I want you to go to your
white... Your white books.
That's what I want you to go to.
Go to 23 in your white books.
"How to fake like you are
a nice and caring person."
Phil. Phil.
Hey, come here. Come here.
Uh... Phil... I'm...
-I'm gonna try talk.
-Okay.
And I'm trying to...
-To say something.
-Okay.
Do you know Lily, Phil? Do you know her?
No.
-Lily?
-No, I don't.
Oh.
She's my love, my life, love of it. Yeah.
In school...
I'm 12 years old, in
school, in sixth grade.
I saw her.
Yeah. I didn't go to that school, but...
But, uh, we met.
Uh, my friend knew her.
I said, uh:
"What's that girl? How's that Lily?"
"Oh, she's bad. She sleeps with guys."
[PHIL CHUCKLES]
Yeah, he said this,
but then, sometimes...
And I went to another school, you see.
Uh, but then, uh... [SIGHS]
When high school at an end, what's that?
What is that, uh,
when it gets to the end?
Graduation.
-No, no, the grade. What grade are you in?
-That's 12th.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. So I went to her
school for that grade.
That's grade 12.
And we meet.
She was
fucking like a doll.
Yeah. A beautiful porcelain doll.
And the hips.
The child-bearing hips, you know that?
[CHUCKLES]
So beautiful.
And I cheated on her
over and over and over again
because I wanted to be a man,
and I didn't want her to be a woman.
You know, a smart, free person
who was something.
My fucking mind then.
[PANTING]
So stupid, that fucking mind. Stupid.
Jesus Christ.
What would I think? Did
I think for what I'd done?
She was my wife for 23 years,
and I went behind her over and over.
Fucking asshole that I
am, I'd go out and I'd fuck,
and I'd come home and get in her bed,
and say, "I love you."
This is Jack's mother.
His mother, Lily.
These two
that I had
And I lost.
This is the regret that you make.
This is the
Regret that you make and
the something you take,
and the blah, blah, blah...
Something, something.
-Give me a cigarette.
-Okay.
[SIGHS]
[EARL PANTING]
Uh...
Mistakes like this
you don't make.
Sometimes
you make some, and okay.
Not okay, sometimes, you make other ones.
Yeah.
Know that you should do better.
I loved Lily.
I cheated on her.
She was my wife for 23 years.
[SIGHS]
And I have a son.
And she has cancer.
And I'm not there,
and he's forced to take care of her.
He's 14 years old.
To...
To take care of his mother and...
And watch her die on him.
A little kid, and I'm not there.
And she does die.
EARL: I loved her so.
And she knew what I did.
She knew all the fucking
stupid things I'd done.
But the love
was stronger than
anything you can think of.
The goddamn regret.
The goddamn regret!
[EARL SOBBING]
And I'll die.
Now I'll die, and I'll tell you what.
The biggest regret of my life...
I let my love go.
What did I do?
I'm 65 years old.
And I'm ashamed.
Million years ago...
The fucking regret
and guilt, these things...
Don't ever let anyone ever say to you
you shouldn't regret anything.
Don't do that. Don't. Oh.
You regret what you fucking want. Ah.
Use that. Use that.
Use that regret for
anything, any way you want.
You can use it, okay?
[EARL PANTING]
Oh, God.
This is a long way to go with no punch.
[EARL CHUCKLES]
A little moral
story, I say. Ha, ha.
Love.
This fucking life...
Oh...
It's so fucking hard.
So long.
Life ain't short. It's long.
It's long, God damn it.
[EARL SIGHS]
Goddamn.
[EARL GROANS]
What did I do?
What did I do? What did I do?
Phil. Phil, help me.
[EARL SOBBING]
What did I do?
-Hey, Juan, how you doing?
-JUAN: How you feeling?
Yeah, I think I'm going
to stay on, stick it out.
-Are you sure?
-Yeah.
-Okay.
-All right, good night.
[EARL SIGHS]
[SNIFFS]
[PANTING SOFTLY]
[PHIL SOBBING]
You're so stupid.
[SNIFFING]
[SINGING AIMEE MANN'S "WISE UP"]
[JIM SINGING AIMEE MANN'S "WISE UP"]
[BOTH SINGING AIMEE MANN'S "WISE UP"]
[SINGING AIMEE MANN'S "WISE UP"]
[FRANK SINGING AIMEE MANN'S "WISE UP"]
You know, you know, you know.
Go, go, go.
-Donnie. Oh, Donnie.
-Hello, dear. I need a favor.
[DOGS BARKING]
PHIL: Okay, okay.
Shh. All right, all right. Back
up, back up. Back up, Max.
Back up, Miles. Back up.
-Hello. You Frank? Jack, right?
-FRANK: Hello. How are you?
-FRANK: Are you Phil?
-PHIL: Phil, yeah.
We, uh, tried to get in
touch. We got disconnected.
Stay in, Max. Stay in. Hey, hey, come on.
All right? Please.
-FRANK: I got the message.
-Yeah, I couldn't find you.
I looked through the address books.
There's no number. There's nothing.
[DOGS BARKING]
-Shh. Hey!
-FRANK: is, uh, what's-her-name...?
PHIL: Linda? No, she
went out. She's not here.
Hey, I'm sorry, uh...
You know, I don't know what to do here.
Um, your dad asked me to get in touch
with you, and I didn't have the number.
You know, I called the
number. Do you wanna come in?
-FRANK: Yeah. Hey, Phil?
-Okay. Yeah?
FRANK: I will drop-kick those
fucking dogs if they come near me.
-PHIL: All right.
-Okay?
Come on in. Come on in. This is Blake.
-This is Miles.
-FRANK: Clear them out.
PHIL: Here we go.
All right, he's in here,
so we all go in here. Come on.
Wanna go in?
-No, I just... Stand here a second, Phil.
-Okay.
-Okay?
-All right.
[BOTH SIGH]
Lady.
Hey, lady.
Lady. Lady.
Hey, wake up.
Lady.
What's wrong with you?
[JIMMY SIGHS]
How do we do this, then?
Well, we just do it.
We do it. We figure it out.
We do as we do, I guess.
Do you love me, Rose?
You are my handsome man.
-I'm a bad person.
-Ha, ha, no. No.
I mean
I'm telling you this now, you see...
You see, because I want
everything to be clear and clean,
and I want to apologize for me
and all the stupid things that I've done.
[SIGHS]
I've cheated on you.
I've cheated on you, and it kills me,
and the guilt of what I've done...
I don't want you to think...
Maybe you knew.
I think maybe you've known.
So I hope this is not just for me...
For me to make myself feel
better about what I've done,
but for you not to feel like
you're sitting there like a jerk.
You're the good one.
You understand?
Did you ever go out with
someone and just lie
question after question?
Maybe you're trying to
make yourself look cool,
or better than you are or whatever
smarter, cooler... and you just
not really lie,
but maybe you just don't say everything.
JIM: Well, that's a natural thing.
You know, two people go
out on a date or something
they wanna impress people.
The other person.
Or they're scared they
might say something
that will make the
other person not like them.
-Thank you.
-JIM: Thank you.
So you've done it?
I don't go out very often.
Why not?
I never found someone, really,
that I think I'd like to go out with.
And I bet you say that
to all the girls, huh?
No. No. Heh.
-Wanna make a deal with me?
-Okay.
What I just said
people afraid to say things
no guts to say the things
that are real or something...
-Yeah?
-To not do that.
To not do that that
maybe we've done before.
-Let's make a deal.
-Okay.
I'll tell you everything,
and you tell me everything,
and maybe we can get through all the piss
and shit and lies that kill other people.
Wow.
Huh. "Piss and shit."
[CHUCKLES]
What?
You really use strong language.
I'm sorry.
No, it's fine. It's fine.
I didn't mean... It seems
vulgar or something, I know.
-It's fine.
-No, I'm sorry.
No, it's nothing. I'm sorry.
I'm gonna run to the bathroom
for a minute, maybe, just...
-Okay.
[GABRIELLE'S "DREAMS"
PLAYING ON CAR STEREO]
[LOCK CLICKS]
[SAFE DIAL WHIRRING]
-Okay. Okay.
-Okay?
I'm gonna go in. And,
uh... Are the dogs in there?
Yeah, but they stay back by the window.
-All right, I want you to come in with me.
-Okay.
And I want you to stay away from me.
I want you there in case he needs
anything, because I am not gonna help him.
And, Phil, I will drop-kick
the fucking dogs
-if they come near me.
-Okay.
[FRANK SIGHS]
Earl.
You don't look that bad.
[SIGHS]
You prick.
"Cocksucker." That's what
you used to like to say, right?
"Cocksucker."
But you are. You're a cocksucker, Earl.
It hurts, doesn't it? Huh?
You in a lot of pain?
She was in a lot of pain.
Right to the end, she
was in a lot of pain.
I know because I was there, Earl.
You didn't like illness, though, do you?
I was there.
She waited for your call.
For you to come.
I am not gonna cry.
I am not gonna cry for you.
[FRANK SNIFFLES]
You cocksucker, I know you can hear me.
I want you to know that
I hate your fucking guts.
You can just fucking die, you fuck.
And I hope it hurts. I
fucking hope it hurts.
[KEY CLINKS]
[ENGINE STARTS]
[GABRIELLE'S "DREAMS"
PLAYING ON CAR STEREO]
[TIRES SQUEAL]
[DISPATCH RADIO CHATTERING]
Yeah, her resps are down to
six. Let's get the gurney over here.
DIXON [RAPPING]: Check
that ego Come of fit, I'm a prophet
The professor I'm gonna
teach you 'bout the worm
Who eventually turned to catch wreck
With the neck of a long-time oppressor
And he's running from the devil
But the debt is always gaining
And if he's worth being hurt
He's worth bringing pain in
Do you feel better now
that you've said this?
[JIMMY SIGHS]
JIMMY: I don't know.
Well, I'm not mad.
Well, I am, but I'm not.
You know?
I love you so much, Rose.
I'm not through asking my questions.
Why doesn't Claudia
talk to you, Jimmy?
Why?
Because we've...
We both don't know. What do you mean?
No, I think you know.
Maybe...
I don't.
Say it, Jimmy.
-I wanted to do that.
-JIM: Well...
That felt good, to do
what I wanted to do.
Yeah.
[SNIFFS]
Can I tell you something?
Yeah, of course.
I'm really nervous that
you're gonna hate me soon.
You're gonna find stuff out about
me, and you're gonna hate me.
No. Like what? What do you mean?
You have so much, so many good things,
and you seem so together.
You're a police officer,
and you seem so straight and
put together, without any problems.
-I lost my gun today.
-What?
I lost my gun today,
and I'm the laughingstock
of a lot of people.
I wanted to tell you. I
wanted you to know.
And it's on my mind.
And it makes me look like a fool.
And I feel like a fool.
And you asked that we should say things
say what we're thinking
and not lie about things.
Well, I can tell you that.
This. That I lost my gun today.
I'm not a good cop.
I'm looked down at, and I know that,
and I'm scared that once you
find that out, you might not like me.
-Jim, that was so great.
-I'm sorry.
What you just said.
I haven't been on a date
since I was married, and
that was three years ago.
Claudia, whatever you wanna tell me
whatever you think might scare me won't.
And I will listen to you.
I'll be a good listener to you if
that's what you want. You know?
You know? And I won't judge you.
I know I can do that
sometimes, and I won't.
And I can listen.
And you shouldn't be
scared of scaring me off,
or whatever you think
that I think and on and on.
Say it, whatever it is, and I'll listen.
-You don't know how fucking stupid I am.
-It's okay.
-You don't know how crazy I am.
-I got troubles.
-I'll take everything at face value.
-I'll be a good listener.
-I started this, didn't I? Didn't I? Fuck.
Whatever it is, just say it. You'll see.
You wanna kiss me, Jim?
Yes, I do.
Say it, Jimmy.
I think she thinks
that I may have molested her.
She thinks terrible things that
somehow got into her head
that I may have done.
She said that to me
last time, when it was...
Ten years ago, she walked out the door.
"You touched me wrong. I know that."
Some crazy thought in her... In her head.
Did you ever touch her?
I don't know.
[BANGS GLASS ON TABLE]
-Jimmy.
-I don't know. I really don't.
But you can't say.
-Well, I don't know what I've done.
-Yes, you do. You do.
-But you won't say.
-I don't know.
What? What? Please. Please.
You deserve to die alone
for what you've done.
I don't know what I've done.
Yes, you do.
Rose, if I said that I
knew, would you stay?
-No.
-But I don't know what I've done.
You should know better.
[SOBBING]
[CLAUDIA SOBBING]
Now that I've met you, would you
object to never seeing me again?
-What?
-Just say no.
-I won't say no. Wait, Claudia.
-Claudia, what is it?
-Just let me go, Jimmy.
-What is it? Please, please.
-Please. It's okay. Just let me go.
[PANTING]
[SOBBING]
FRANK [SOBBING]: Why didn't you call?
[FRANK CRYING]
FRANK: I fucking hate you.
God damn you, fucking asshole.
Oh, God, you fucking asshole.
Don't go away, you fucking asshole.
Oh, God, don't go away,
you fucking asshole.
[SIRENS WAILING]
[GABRIELLE'S "DREAMS"
PLAYING ON CAR STEREO]
What am I doing?
What the fuck am I doing?
[SNIFFS]
[SIGHS]
[TV PLAYING INDISTINCTLY]
MAN [ON TV]: Men who are
vain look at their bald spot and say:
"You know, I don't need
anything. I look great the way I am."
Yes. Ladies, if you want
your husband or boyfriend to...
[GABRIELLE'S "DREAMS"
PLAYING ON CAR STEREO]
Oh, fuck.
JIM: What?
What are you doing, dummy?
Oh, brother.
[GASPS]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[PANTING]
[THUD ON ROOF]
[JIM YELLS]
[SNIFFING]
[FROG THUDS]
[SIGHS]
[FROGS THUDDING]
[CLAUDIA SCREAMS]
[FROGS CRASHING]
[CRASH OUTSIDE]
[DOGS BARKING]
[THUDDING]
Oh, there are frogs falling from the sky.
[FROGS CROAKING]
[TIRES SQUEAL]
[SCREAMING]
[SIREN WAILING]
[TIRES SQUEALING]
MAN [ON TV]: You all know
you're not gonna spend $135 for it.
In fact, all you spend here
during this special TV promotion
is just $39...
[CROAKS]
[JIM GRUNTING]
[TIRES SQUEALING]
[FROGS THUDDING]
[GRUNTS]
[GRUNTING]
JIM: Come on. Come on.
[JIM GRUNTING]
[GASPS]
Claudia, it's Mom! Open the door, honey!
Claudia! Claudia, are you there?
Mom! Mom! Mom! Mommy!
Oh, honey. All right. It's all right.
It's okay. It's gonna be all right.
[CLAUDIA SOBBING]
[CAR ALARMS WAILING OUTSIDE]
This happens.
This is something that happens.
[FROGS THUDDING AND DOGS BARKING]
[EARL GASPING]
[EARL GROANS SOFTLY]
[EARL GASPS]
[GASPS]
NARRATOR: And there is the
account of the hanging of three men,
and a scuba diver... and a suicide.
There are stories of
coincidence and chance,
and intersections,
and strange things told,
and which is which, and who only knows?
And we generally say:
"Well, if that was in a
movie, I wouldn't believe it."
Someone's so-and-so met
someone else's so-and-so, and so on.
And it is in the humble
opinion of this narrator
that strange things happen all the time.
And so it goes, and so it goes.
And the book says:
"We may be through with the past,
but the past ain't through with us."
PHIL: I'm sorry, Jack.
It's the hospital calling about Linda.
-Who?
-Linda. She's in the hospital,
and I figured you should probably
talk to them since you're here.
Hello?
Uh-huh. And what...
Okay. Okay.
Uh... is she gonna be all right?
[PHIL SNIFFLES]
FRANK: Where...?
[SOBBING]
DOCTOR: You with us, Linda? Good.
It is Linda, isn't it?
Just relax. That's it.
You'll get through this.
STANLEY: Dad.
Dad.
Dad, you need to be nicer to me.
Go to bed.
You have to be nicer to me, Dad.
I know I did a stupid thing.
So stupid.
Getting braces.
I thought...
I thought he would love me.
Getting braces.
For what?
For something I don't even...
I don't know where to
put things, you know?
I really do have love to give.
I just don't know where to put it.
JIM: A lot of people think
this is just a job that you go to.
Take a lunch hour. Job's over.
Something like that.
[JIM SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
JIM: But it's a 24-hour deal.
No two ways about it.
And what most people don't see
is just how hard it
is to do the right thing.
People think if I make a judgment call
that that's a judgment on
them, but that is not what I do.
And that's not what should be done.
I have to take everything,
and play as it lays.
Sometimes people need a little help.
...Supposed to be real good
at corrective oral surgery.
JIM: Sometimes people
need to be forgiven.
And sometimes they need to go to jail.
Call me about that guy
with the teeth, okay?
JIM: And that is a very
tricky thing on my part
making that call.
I mean, the law is the law,
and heck if I'm gonna break it.
[ENGINE STARTS]
[GABRIELLE'S "DREAMS" PLAYING ON STEREO]
JIM: You can forgive someone.
[FROGS SQUISHING]
Well, that's the tough part.
What can we forgive?
Tough part of the job.
Tough part of walking down the street.
JIM: I just wanted to come here...
To come here and say something.
Say something important.
Something that you said.
You said we should
say things and do things.
Not lie, not keep things back.
These are the things that tear people up.
Well, I'm gonna do that.
I'm gonna do what you said, Claudia.
I can't let this go.
I can't let you go.
Now, you...
You listen to me now.
You're a good person.
A good, beautiful person,
and I won't let you walk out on me.
I won't let you say those things.
Those things about how
stupid you are and this and that.
I won't stand for that.
You want to be with me
Then you be with me.
You see?