There's Illia.
- Hello, Illia.
You're lucky. Your first day here,
you see one of our legends.
Who is she?
- A whore.
But she makes no prices,
and only goes with you if she likes you.
There are those who work
and those who swim.
If you weren't a slave, you'd come in, too.
Here I come.
A Greek is a Greek
because he'll accept any dare.
There's a man. You up there are all slaves.
Hey, Captain...
...that one next to you,
he's a man or a mouse?
Beg your pardon.
Illia, this is Tonio.
He's from Corfu. He's half ltalian.
We won't hold that against him.
I'm told you pick and choose.
Do I have a chance?
Maybe.
- Tonight? 9:00?
At 9:00, the baker.
10:00?
- Sorry. 10:00, the fruit man.
And the butcher?
- At 11:00.
ls she kidding me?
- Oh, no.
Her life is perfectly organized.
She has arrangements
with all those clients.
You like boat rides?
- Anything you say, my little bird.
Let's go.
Where is the American? The intellectual?
He should see this. Call Mr. Thrace.
Mr. Thrace, they are calling you.
There is something amusing down there.
Thank you very much. Goodbye.
There is the purity that was Greece.
Play, Taki. Play and never stop.
Pretty?
Yes.
Thank you very much. Thank you.
Please?
Here's a man who wants to pass.
- Thank you.
Good evening.
- How do you do?
Good night.
- Good evening.
How did you know I was American?
- What you take?
Coffee, please.
American coffee?
- Greek coffee.
Waiter....
What is everybody drinking?
- Ouzo.
Is what men drink.
What are you looking at, friend?
I beg your pardon.
Thank you.
What are you applauding for?
You're making a mistake.
Your dance was beautiful.
If you threw money,
there'd have been a massacre.
Why are you angry? I was applauding.
You'd better go to a fancy cabaret,
or your mother will wear black.
I don't like to be shaken.
I know you're big.
You're going to make me hit you.
Please. I don't want to fight with you.
I came here with love. I love you.
I love you, and I'm fighting with you.
Doesn't anyone here speak English?
I do.
- lllia.
I speak English.
I was dancing, bothering no one...
...and he applauds me as
if I were a ballerina.
Would you please explain to him
that I loved his dance. I was applauding.
Careful, he's a brute.
Jorgo, he's an angel.
My most old client.
I was enjoying, bothering no one--
- Shut up, now.
Jorgo is angry because
you have applauded.
In Greece, when a man dances,
it's for himself.
It makes him feel better in his....
How you say in English?
Soul.
- That's it.
It is for his soul.
He is angry
because you think he is an entertainer.
Come on, Jorgaki.
He applauded because he liked your dance.
Shake hands and be friends.
- Go on.
All right, boys, back to your tables.
Go on. Go enjoy yourselves.
Would you please tell him
that I'm sorry about his nose.
He's sorry he punched you in the nose.
- Wait till he sees his eye tomorrow.
He says,
'Wait to see tomorrow morning your eye.'
I thought so.
Please have a drink with me. You too, sir.
Okay.
- This is lllia.
My name is Armathis.
- Everybody calls him Captain.
I'm very happy to meet you both,
and at the right moment.
My name is Homer Thrace.
- Homer?
My father loved everything Greek.
- A Grecophile.
How well you speak English.
- Eight years in Brooklyn.
Brooklyn? You're kidding.
- The Navy Yard.
Now I work in the yard here, in Piraeus.
Beer.
- Two beers.
I would like three bires.
You are rich?
- No, I'm very poor.
Hey, you are a writer?
I was just making some notes.
- What you are?
Well, I'm an amateur philosopher.
You stay long in Greece?
Maybe. I'm looking for something in Greece.
What?
You won't laugh?
- Why? You look for something funny?
I came to Greece...
...to find the truth.
Our world is unhappy.
Why? Where did it begin to go wrong?
Might not the traces be here?
No society ever reached the heights
that were attained by ancient Greece.
It was the cradle of culture.
It was a happy country.
What happened? What made it fall?
Historians don't satisfy me. Wars, politics....
Something's missing, something personal.
I want to walk where Aristotle walked.
Socrates.... I can't explain it.
I don't know.
I have a feeling I'll find something.
In the camera you look more beautiful.
Your nose is not so big.
Thank you.
It's certain that the old philosophers
often walked around this port.
How thrilling.
Why, that means that Aristotle
might have stood on this very spot.
Yes.
Did you ever think of that, lllia?
- Every day.
I don't think lllia
would have much sympathy for Aristotle.
His opinion of women was rather low.
- He was sick.
Aristotle, sick?
Your eye begins to be pink.
I go to see my friend's nose now.
Very glad to meet you, Homer.
- Likewise.
You're very pretty.
Homer. Bye, Captain.
- Bye, lllia.
Light of my eyes.
- Who can dance like lllia?
The little fellow beat you up?
If I'd really hit him,
they'd close up the place.
Hello, sister. So you are lllia.
- Hello, brother. I am lllia.
Are you busy?
- I don't know.
All right, how much?
I make no prices.
60 drachmas?
- I'll give you 80.
60 drachmas will be fine.
I offered 80.
- I don't care if you offered 180.
Why?
- Because I don't like you.
I don't make it a condition that you like me.
- I make it a condition that I like you.
ls she....
- She is.
How is it possible?
That lovely, gracious....
Captain, maybe that's what I'm looking for.
What luck.
Illia.
The symbol of my quest.
The personification.
In her, the answer to the mystery.
The personal equation
of the fall of ancient Greece.
Sorry, miss. I'm terribly sorry.
It's not that you.... I think you're beautiful.
And I liked so much
what you did in that cafe.
I wanted so much to be with you.
But, I don't know.
I'm nervous.
And you are very nice.
If you don't mind...
I'll just go now.
- I don't mind.
But first we smoke a cigarette.
You give me English cigarette, yes?
Of course.
Do you like music?
This is Greek. Bouzouki music.
Men like this music.
You like?
- Yes...
...and I like you.
When your boat goes away?
- Tomorrow.
You will come back to Piraeus sometime?
I don't know. Maybe.
- Then you come to see me.
I certainly will. The first....
The words of this song are beautiful.
'With such a moon, how can I sing?
'With such a moon,
how make away my sadness?
'Chase away your sadness, palikari.'
'Palikari' is a strong young man.
'And together we go the moon.'
Homer.
The Captain told me where you lived.
- I was sleeping. It's too late.
I'm so excited.
- I'm sorry.
You are the beauty that was Greece.
You are the reason I came to Greece.
- All right, come tomorrow.
Homer Thrace of Middletown, Connecticut.
This may be important.
Think clearly.
See clearly.
Be prepared.
Let's go.
What's your hurry?
- You've got to go back to work.
Thanks for worrying about me.
- Let's not be nasty now.
I don't like you to look at your watch.
- Why not?
Because when we are together....
Bravo.
Usually when a man is ridiculous,
he doesn't know it.
But when he falls on his behind,
he knows it.
Of all people,
the ltalians are the most impulsive.
And my family...
...is the most ltalian of them all.
But you're half Greek.
- With you I am all ltalian.
My father came to Corfu for one day.
A baptism.
He took one look at Corfu and said,
'This is for me.'
He never went back to ltaly.
I had an aunt. She went to the movies.
Rudolph Valentino.
She took one look at him and said,
'That's the man for me.'
She never looked at another man.
She died an old maid.
I have the same blood.
I was going to tell you that I like you.
I feel good with you.
That I want you only for me,
that I don't want you to see other men.
Then you fell on your behind.
- I don't like to be laughed at.
I like you. But if you hurt me,
I'll hit you on the head.
I'd bet you would.
- You'd win.
Then I let go.
- Now we understand each other.
lllia....
- That Sunday voice again.
All right. Let's go.
Where are you going?
None of your business.
- I was just being friendly.
Ask me no questions, I'll tell you no lies.
Listen, tomorrow is Sunday.
- I invite you to my house every Sunday.
We'll have the whole day.
- Let me finish.
Every Sunday is open house
for my special friends.
And tomorrow is not an ordinary Sunday.
It's my birthday.
I've been looking everywhere.
Homer.
That's my friend Tonio.
- How do you do?
How do you do?
You hurt your eye.
- You speak English.
I studied with record, two months.
I invite you both
to my open house tomorrow.
The day after--
- No, the day after begins the festival.
What festival?
Theater. The Greek
tragedy. I go every night.
You like the Greek tragedies?
It's the most beautiful thing there is.
I die.
Bye.
Extraordinary.
How do you do?
You're a heathen.
Your grandfather, your father...
...you, and the children to come.
Do I have to put on a skirt for you to stop?
Even then you wouldn't.
Because you are a mule.
Take this so I owe you nothing.
You love the ancient Greek theater.
Are you follow me?
- I can't get over it.
- Yes.
I don't like that you follow me.
If you like the Greek tragedy,
you like me. I mean....
I know every one
that was ever written. Almost.
I like you very much.
Then may I ask you a question?
- Ask.
How did you become a....
How did you get into your profession?
- One moment.
The only clients
that I permit to ask such questions--...
I'm not a client.
- That's right, you are not.
You would have big problems
with your morals.
Also, your nose is too big.
That's a deal, no client.
How did you become a....
University boys,
I permit to ask me such questions.
We smoke cigarettes,
I make up for them sad stories.
They give me advices,
and all that is very sweet.
But they are University boys.
Not old boy scout...
...with dirty eye.
I guess I deserved that.
I embarrassed you. I'm sorry.
You? Me?
Say, that's French, isn't it?
- Yes.
It means don't be jerk.
French, English, Greek.
ltalian, a little Spanish.
- That's extraordinary.
Where did you learn all those languages?
- ln bed.
So long.
Hello, lllia.
You live a good life.
Fresh air. You make music.
People give you money.
Thank you. Goodbye.
Hey. Why you follow me?
Because I want you to stop being....
- Why?
Because you are the whole world.
Beautiful and corrupt.
You are very crazy.
Good day, lllia.
- Go away, Garbage.
You know who's in that car?
It's the boss. He wants to talk to you.
Don't say I said so.
I think he'd give you an apartment
at half price.
Tell him to drop dead.
No one has ever seen the boss's face.
He will reveal it to you.
I don't have to see his face.
I can spit anywhere.
You looking for a scar?
ls he being disagreeable?
- He's just an errand boy.
Homer, you are wonderful.
Who's the man in the big car?
He owns all a street of apartments.
All the girls in the profession
live in these apartments.
He oblige them to pay enormous rents.
- All the girls?
Except lllia, and he doesn't like that.
Why?
Because I am an independent.
It gives the other girls ideas.
Good day.
- Good day.
Goodbye, Homer.
Something is very funny.
Mr.'No Face' and you.
You both want to put me out of business.
What will you have, sir?
Ouzo.
Order one ouzo.
Happy birthday, and a hundred more.
Thank you.
All this just for me?
- Strange, it's the first Sunday that....
We're going to have a fight.
- Why?
Nobody's coming.
I told them you called off the party.
And the reason?
- Because I want you for myself.
Out.
- Make me get out.
Out. How dare you send my friends away?
I told you. No other man.
No other you.
Not if you were the last man in Piraeus.
I am the last man.
The best man, the handsomest man...
...and the strongest.
Happy birthday. Many happy returns.
Darlings.
A hundred more, lllia.
You've been invited to lllia's open house?
That makes you very special.
I'm gonna report her.
Now we can eat.
Garbage forgot something.
For me?
- No.
Health, lllia.
- Health, little bird.
You know, I could have seen the boss's
face.
You should have.
He's the marble merchant.
- Moron. He's the insurance broker.
If you really want to know who he is....
Whoever he is, he stinks.
Illia, I wanted--
Is the American going to give you
the flowers or keep them?
This vice king.... Might he not hurt you?
He thinks that No Face would hurt lllia.
No, she has too many friends.
They would tear his house down.
- Brick by brick.
Yet, I think I'll have a look at No Face
after the festival.
Good idea.
You want to see my new dress?
lllia, what's playing tomorrow?
- Medea.
lllia, how many times have you seen it?
- Fifteen.
That's extraordinary.
Especially when she has no idea
of what the play is about.
Whatever in the play is unpleasant,
she changes.
How?
- ln her head.
She just rejects anything that to her is ugly.
You like my dress?
Listen to me, Homer.
If you promise not to interrupt,
I'll get her to tell the story of Medea...
...as lllia sees it. But you....
- I promise.
All right, go sit down.
Listen, I know how much you like
to hear lllia tell the stories...
...of the ancient tragedies--
- I'm ready.
Today, in honor of our American friend...
Illia is going to tell
the story of Medea in English.
English is impossible.
- Please.
Is not possible.
Okay.
Medea is a beautiful play,
but for you men, is not much compliments.
The play is about
what a woman suffers for a man.
Once upon a time,
there was a princess from far away.
Her name is Medea.
- That's the best one.
Beautiful, long black hair.
A Greek, he comes.
And right away, Medea crazy for him.
She will listen to nobody. She wants him.
She fights with her father,
her whole country.
Medea was very sweet,
but sometimes she has a bad temper.
Sweet? She was a vicious character.
She was a murderess.
Anyhow, she goes to Greece
to marry this man.
He is a prince.
His name is Jason.
She is good to him.
She gives him two beautiful children.
But he....
Right away,
with a blonde princess in Athens....
You know what.
This Jason is not even a gentleman
to tell Medea lies. No.
He says right to her face
that he wants that other blonde...
...because she is a princess.
And Medea cries and says,
'l am a princess, too.'
Beautiful, how she cries.
Everything she does for Jason.
Even she gives presents to the blonde.
She sends gifts that were poisoned.
But everybody says bad things about her.
They say she is a witch.
There are 12 rich ladies
in beautiful dresses.
But they say bad things about her, too.
Twelve rich ladies? The Greek chorus?
And Medea cries.
I tell you, she breaks your heart.
She is afraid.
She takes the children and she hides them.
But in the end,
Jason sees how much Medea loves him...
...and they get a wonderful chariot.
And she gets the children...
...and they all go to the seashore.
No. The Greek tragedy.
She gives it a happy ending.
She doesn't say Medea killed her children.
- She changed that, too.
Illia's happy. She worked out a way
of living. Let her alone.
I make mistakes in my English?
Not at all.
Sometime I'd like to hear
you tell Oedipus Rex.
I don't like this story. Is very mean.
One thing is very nice.
Always Oedipus is
talking about his mother.
I never saw such a good son
who loves so much his mother.
All right. I tell to my friends now
Oedipus Rex...
...in Greek.
In Greek?
Once upon a time,
there was a Prince from Thebes.
It's impossible. A whore can't be happy.
A whorish world can't be happy.
I'd like to reach her mind.
What do you want to put in her mind?
Reason, in place of fantasy.
Morality, instead of immorality.
I've got to educate her.
To transform her.
Remember what happened to Pygmalion.
- I wouldn't make that mistake.
Illia is lovely.
But for me, she's not a woman,
she's an idea.
She's an outlaw. Yes.
Law must be re-established everywhere.
Don't you see, Captain?
I see you'll have black eyes all your life.
...but let's forget all those bad things.
They hurt his eyes, the poor thing.
But in the end he finds his family...
...and they all go to the seashore.
'And they all go to the seashore'?
- They always go to the seashore.
Boris, Greece is capitalist country, no?
- Yes.
So how in capitalist country
they close up business to go to the theater?
This is explained in a chapter...
...of Karl Marx's
Contradictions In Capitalism.
There is lllia's bus to Athens.
Illia. Who is she? Joan of Arc?
She's got courage,
which some of us do not have.
She's doing fine.
What does she care about us?
She's got heart, which some of us don't.
Hello. What are you doing here, girls?
We're looking for husbands.
And I thought you came to talk to lllia.
It's a democracy, no?
We don't like you to associate with lllia.
She's a bad influence.
Hello, slaves. Hello, Garbage.
Careful, the garbage man.
lllia.
- Not today.
Adonis.
- I brought you some sandwiches.
Have a good time.
Kiss Medea for me.
Good trip.
Are you courting me?
- Seriously.
Something else for you.
The stone seats in the theater are hard.
I'll sit on it and think of you.
Homer. Where are you going?
- With you, if you don't mind.
Wonderful.
- I want us to see Medea together.
That's nice.
All right, girls. Let's go.
I had a dream.
I married a man. He had a little money.
He was 94 years old.
What a relief.
Why are we running? We're early.
We're the first ones here.
If I'm not the first one here, I am late.
But I tell you that Medea killed her children.
- Homer, don't be stupid.
But it's easy to....
She killed them.
Medea herself, does she not say,
'l killed my children'?
And you believe her?
You don't understand the women.
Medea loves her husband, yes?
- Yes.
Her husband is interested
in another woman?
Yes?
- Yes.
So she said to her husband
that she has killed her children...
...to frighten him, to get him back.
No.
- Yes.
She gets him back,
and everybody go away...
...and everybody is happy
and they go to the seashore. And that's all.
If I show you that everything
that was ever written about Medea...
...talks of her killing her children....
If you ask 10 out of 10 people
who saw the play...
...and they tell you it's true,
then by simple logic....
You're a Greek, you should be logical.
- Why?
Because the greatest Greek of them all,
Aristotle, invented logic.
He said--
- Who?
Aristotle--
- Aristotle.
The one that the Captain said thinks...
...men are everything
and women are nothing?
I don't care what he said, Aristotle.
Look around you, lllia.
Greek art was the most harmonious
in the world.
What happened?
What happened to you?
All evil is disharmony.
You are in disharmony with yourself.
You have beauty, grace...
...and you are....
I, American boy scout,
will bring you back to harmony.
Bring me back to Piraeus.
I want to go to sleep.
I'm fighting for your soul. Listen to me.
You make me unhappy.
If what you say
about the Greek tragedy is true...
I don't like the Greek tragedy.
- lf you would only....
And I don't like you...
...because before I met you,
I was crazy about the Greek tragedy.
Is lllia coming for a swim today?
Good day, Captain.
Hello, ladies. How are you, Despo?
Terrible. Is lllia around?
- No.
Hello, Captain. Did you see lllia today?
Who is not looking for lllia, today?
Mr. Thrace, this is Despo, a friend of lllia's.
Mr. Thrace is a writer.
How do you do, darling?
You are friend of lllia. Tell her to help us.
Only for her the girls have respect.
If lllia talks to them, they will listen.
Talk about what?
- lllia can make all the girls say no.
Then he would make
rents not so expensive.
Who?
- Mr. No Face.
Please.
Darling, you are a writer.
You write this in the newspaper?
What?
180 drachmas we pay for rent.
And if a girl try to move out...
No Face make it
you don't move in anywhere else.
You write this in the newspaper?
Yes?
I'll see what I can do.
- Thank you, darling.
Captain, please tell lllia I was here.
Yes, Despo.
- Bye.
There is some more research for you.
Yes.
Captain, did you see lllia today?
Early this morning, briefly.
She was not in a very good mood.
Hello, my weakness.
The most beautiful knee in Piraeus.
- Leave me alone. Bring me a beer.
What's wrong?
Did Piraeus lose the soccer game?
I offer you my very own.
Hello, Captain, all.
No coffee.
Stay far from me.
- lf you'll just--
If you come,
I break that bottle on your head.
She would, too, wouldn't she?
- Come, let's have a drink.
When she gets mad...
...she certainly lights up, doesn't she?
He's improvising.
He's from Crete. They're good at it.
Two ouzo.
Illia has fire in eye
There is thunder in her hand
Don't look
Don't look at her
Or you will be struck blind...
What?
- 'lllia has fire in her eyes.
'Don't look at her or she'll blind you.'
Look darkly at all men
Give poison to them all
Refuse yourself to all men
Except your sweet...
...sweet Jorgaki...
'She says no to everyone,
except her sweet Jorgaki.'
I can't stand honest women
If ever I took a wife
I would want...
...the beautiful...
...the doll...
...the miraculous
Illiaki...
'For him, no honest, no good women.'
What does that mean?
- Whenever he wanted love, he paid for it.
Bravo. You brought back lllia's smile.
Taki, God bless your hands.
Now that you feel better, may I join you?
You, go.
I want to help you. I'm your friend.
- Don't help me. Be an enemy.
Why? Because I told you the truth?
If you don't go away, I'll call Jorgo
and he'll make you another dirty eye.
Call him. I can tell him something.
His song was charming,
but most revealing.
The truth can free him, too.
Don't free him.
- He's a man with a deep problem.
Again, problems?
Yes, all his life he has associated
only with a certain kind of woman.
Know why?
- He likes--
No. The real reason is
that he hates all women.
Jorgaki?
Jorgaki.
And I've no doubt where that stems from.
It's elementary psychiatry.
He hated his mother.
That's true?
You want tell him that?
It might help him.
You are right.
I think you must tell him.
Jorgaki...
...come here, my little bird.
Pull up a chair.
Our friend, who is very educated...
...has studied you.
Go on, Homer.
All your life, you have known only....
No other women.
Tell him why, Homer.
There's a profound inner reason.
By having relations
only with such women...
...you are obeying an irresistible need...
...to degrade all women.
A subconscious revenge
against all women.
Where does it come from?
Why?
You hated...
...your mother.
Hold your hats.
Again.
You heard him.
He said I hated my mother.
Let him come.
He's a sucker for a left.
I don't know what he's saying,
but I don't like it.
Give him harmony.
What are you doing?
One moment.
Let me cut his throat, please.
And don't catch cold.
Thank you.
My mother. I put her on a throne.
'Little Madonna,' I used to call her.
Why are you crying? You were a warrior.
Homer, go home.
I will.
You're barbarians.
You don't need a philosopher,
you need a missionary.
I'm leaving.
Bye-bye, Homer.
Bye-bye.
I'm sorry you're going home.
Why?
- Because it's a defeat.
For you and for me, too.
Have we met?
- You may call me Mr. Face.
I'm in real estate.
Mr. Face?
And are your houses let only to girls?
- Yes.
I have a proposition to make.
May I sit down?
Sure.
You needn't run away.
I, too, exist in the scheme of things.
You can't ignore me.
I don't have to do business with you.
- Of course you do...
...and I'll tell you why.
- Why?
We both would like lllia to retire.
Of course, for entirely different reasons.
You can have an influence on her. I cannot.
So I have my reasons to offer you help,
and you to accept.
Accept what?
Money.
You think you can buy lllia?
- No, I've tried that.
Me?
- The money will be for lllia's time...
...and her education.
I'll be damned.
If you prove to her
that your way of life is better than hers...
...she'll admit it...
...and you'll have won.
- And you.
That's a secondary matter, isn't it?
For you, there is only one question:
are you more interested
that I should make no profits...
...or are you more interested in saving lllia?
I hate your guts.
But I'm more interested in saving lllia.
What a wonderful song.
Lend me 200 drachmas?
- No.
Why?
- I have only 50 drachmas.
I am missing 200 drachmas.
- Why?
Understand? For our boat tickets.
Where are we going?
Italy, of course.
What do we do in ltaly?
We eat spaghetti and we make love.
We see Napoli, we make love.
We make tourism...
...we make love.
We say, 'Good morning,' we make love.
You like that?
- Yes.
We go?
- No.
Someday we will...
...because everything you do pleases me.
The way you rinse that thing...
...pleases me.
The way you walk pleases me.
The way you hang it up pleases me.
The way I put out the light pleases you?
- Yes, that pleases me, too.
The way your shoulder fits into my hand...
...pleases me.
The way your body goes with mine
pleases me.
lllia--
- That Sunday voice again?
Someday, we'll talk about love.
Forbidden. Verboten.
You don't let me talk about love.
You take my tongue away.
Then shut up.
You know,
I have done many things in my life.
I'm not the one to talk about morality.
But tell me, lllia...
...you like your life?
My life was fine before the missionary
and you came along.
I've thrown him out.
And now....
You'll never throw me out.
U.S.?
I said you to go home.
There's a boat leaving in two hours.
I have something to propose to you.
If you don't accept, I'll be on that boat.
Give me water.
Water.
Poor Homer, he comes in Greece...
...and all the time he gets a dirty eye.
Come sit down.
Don't be afraid.
Illia, let me talk to you.
Are you happy?
I am happy.
You like your life?
- I like my life.
You like your work?
- I like my work.
And what if I prove to you
that you're not happy?
Cursed be the hour and the moment--
No, you tell me,
exactly what is it that makes you happy?
The sun, he shines on me.
He makes me happy.
I eat a good fish, he makes me happy.
I touch you. If you feel good, I'm happy.
Everything sensual, everything physical.
You live by the Stoic
and Epicurean philosophies...
...that came after the fall of Greece.
It's so clear.
Not to me.
How shall I tell you?
Illia...
...at one time, Greece was
the greatest country...
...in the whole world.
It still is.
At the height of Greek glory,
there were three great men.
Philosophers.
Socrates, Plato and Aristotle.
I told you, this one I don't like.
- All three of them giants.
They gave their lives to the one question:
What is happiness?
- Really? And what did they say?
They said that the true happiness
comes from the pleasure of the mind.
That the greatest happiness
is the joy of understanding.
Really?
I sat next to you in that amphitheater
when we went to see Medea.
I watched you,
your eyes were shining with happiness.
It's not important that you made a mistake
about the play. We'll talk about that.
But your....
Everything in you
was shining with pleasure.
Beauty that was Greece.
Give me two weeks of your life.
- What?
I want every minute of two weeks.
You'll lose nothing by it.
I'll pay you for each minute.
If in the end of two weeks
you don't begin to think my way...
I'll disappear.
Why you want to do that for me?
You believe you can make me....
Anything.
Maybe when I was a little girl.
Now.
I'll make you see a world
you never knew about. I'll--
Can you make me somebody
who it is good to love?
You'll be reborn.
Illia, two little weeks.
Please.
I give you two weeks.
And lllia ate of the apple of wisdom,
and she knew shame.
Good day, lllia.
- Good day, Spiro.
What will I do with all of those fish?
Last Sunday...
...was dark and dreary.
We hoped this Sunday...
...you'd make a party.
- No, Spiro.
What should I do?
Throw them back into the sea?
- Go on, put them in the fridge.
Spiro.
Come on, take it.
Tell me true. Is your life better this way?
Maybe it's not so much fun, but it's better.
This Homer, you sleep with him?
No, it's something else.
What else is there?
He believes in me. That I can be wonderful.
And I believe in him.
That's what else there is.
Goodbye, llliaki.
Come here.
Here.
Be well, Spiro.
From my window, I send kisses...
...one and two and three and four
And to the port come...
...one and two and three and four birds
I want to have...
...one and two and three and four sons
Who when they become men...
...will be the pride of Piraeus
If I search the world over
I'll find no other port...
...which has the magic...
...of my Port of Piraeus
When twilight comes...
...the port sings to me
And young men and echoes of song...
...fill my Port of Piraeus
No one goes by my door...
...for whom I don't feel love
And those to come tomorrow...
...fill my dreams at night
So, to the jewels around my throat
I add a charm to bring me luck
And now I'm ready to welcome...
...the stranger come from the port
If I search the whole world over
I'll find no other port...
...which has the magic...
...of my Port of Piraeus
When twilight comes...
...the port sings to me
And young men and echoes of song...
...fill my port of Piraeus
These blasted shoes.
Boss.
The whole fleet is pulling in.
They've been at sea for 21 weeks.
Fine, be with you in a minute.
This is for the books and records.
That's very pretty.
That's my personal gift to lllia.
I paid for that myself.
It's still very pretty.
And now I would like to talk to you
about my personal gift to you.
How would you like a punch in the nose?
Is that your good deed for the day?
You're a cynical son of a--
I'm not a boy scout. I'm a working man.
You're a skunk.
Look here, you're not a little boy anymore.
What's bothering you is
not that I smell bad.
You're afraid that some of the smell...
...might rub off on you.
You're damned right.
It's classic.
There shall always be people like you
who will be working for people like me.
And they scream about it.
Get her out.
Excuse me, there was no door to knock on.
Please, I am one of your
tenants. The rents--...
Get her out.
- They are too high. It's impossible.
Put yourself in our place. You couldn't--...
Get her out.
- Bloodsucker.
Someday, I'll see you
without those glasses.
Hide in dark corners, you whore.
That's what you are. You are a whore.
Listen.
With two hands.
Bravo. Miraculous.
What is this...
...a house or a bookstore?
It's my new house.
The happiest house in Piraeus.
Despo, I died.
- Bite your tongue.
I died and I was born again.
You've met Homer?
- Yes.
Is there nothing to drink?
Excuse me.
You must talk to the girls.
When the fleet leaves
we'll have a little money put aside.
With that reserve,
we could hold out and fight No Face.
Once and for all.
Why don't you forget that life?
You have to think of the future.
You're not 18 years old anymore.
I'm better than ever.
The older the chicken, the better the juice.
Listen.
You'll stop working for two weeks.
Homer will pay you.
Homer. How did you know?
I like the reds.
I have something else.
- No.
Hello, darling.
You know my friend Despo.
She speaks English better as l.
Very well he knows me.
We work both for the same man.
What?
- The same man.
What are you talking about?
You died and you were born again?
Well, make a deep breath...
...because you're going to die again.
He works for No Face.
- Are you crazy?
I am crazy, darling.
It's not true.
Darling. It's not true
I see you just now with No Face?
It's not true you see me?
She's mad.
She's dreaming.
- I dream?
How do I know
that present you have for lllia is a vase?
And in my dream, I see much money.
No Face money...
...in yellow envelope in that pocket.
Show me what you have in that pocket.
I want to see what it is in that pocket.
Over the top.
Will you please--...
'Happiness is the joy of understanding.'
- Will you--...
'l think, therefore I am.'
Descartes, French philosopher,
18th century.
Seventeenth.
'The Greek decline went fast
after the death of Alexander.'
'To accept the bondage
under the oriental occupation...
'the Greeks began to live only for pleasure.'
Will you let me explain?
- I let you explain.
The money that you give me
comes from No Face?
I'll start at the beginning.
- Does it come from No Face?
Yes, it did.
Attack.
'Afghanistan is situated
on the borders of lran and Pakistan.
'Population is....' I forgot.
- It's a misunderstanding.
'lceland is country very close to North Pole.
Climate very cold.'
Listen.
- 'Greece is far from North Pole.
'Climate very hot.'
'Many Shakespeare plots
come from Plutarch.'
'The four great tragedies are...
'Othello, Macbeth, Hamlet and King Lear.
'But some critics prefer...
'The Tempest.'
- Please.
Attack.
What? No, not Picasso.
Monsieur Picasso, excuse me very much.
Will you listen?
- You listen.
Calm down.
When you calm down,
you'll understand I'm your friend.
'A friend is one soul in two bodies.'
And that, my friend, is Aristotle.
Come on, Despo. We
have some work to do.
Now we go fix Mr. No Face.
Will you please tell her--
- No.
Not once the fleet goes away.
Now. I swear to you...
...those sailor boys will make like wolves.
Quickly, Mr. Lawyer.
Let's go.
Yes, sir?
I'm the lawyer of these girls.
I have come to pay their fines.
Here they come.
Isn't he handsome?
Such a cute mustache.
- lsn't he adorable?
Your fines have been paid, you may go.
May I talk to my clients alone?
I'm listening.
A big cut in the rents.
- All right.
From 180 drachmas
we'll bring it down to 170 drachmas.
The darling. Isn't he generous?
All right, 160 drachmas. Let's go.
Silence.
What do you want?
I want you to know
that the good old days are over.
130 drachmas.
Little bird, 80 drachmas.
Are you crazy?
- 80 drachmas.
120 drachmas. Last offer. I swear.
- 80 drachmas. Last offer. I swear.
110 drachmas.
- 90 drachmas.
90 drachmas, it's a deal.
Gibraltar...
...a rock.
He stays.
Homer, what did you do to Taki?
He's not a man. He's a catastrophe.
What happened? Captain?
He asked Taki if he could read music.
Taki said no.
He asked Taki, why does he not learn.
Taki said, 'I'm too old.'
So he told Taki, if he couldn't read music...
...he was no real musician
and he never would be.
Perfect.
So Taki began to cry
and said he would never play again.
Homer, when will you learn?
Where is Taki?
- He locked himself in the bathroom.
Taki, come out.
- No.
Taki, open the door. I want to talk to you.
Leave me alone.
Nobody in Greece
plays the bouzouki like you.
You play like an angel.
- Go away.
I'm ignorant. I'll never play again.
Taki, listen.
Those people who made up music notes...
...they made them up so that they could
write down music, no?
What?
You make music. They need the notes
to write down what you play.
If you don't play...
...what can they do with
their notes? Nothing.
Don't you see?
Can birds read music?
No.
So should the birds stop singing?
Is he kidding, brother?
Watch it, boys.
Here we go.
You're beautiful...
...but you're dumb.
I wanted to save you.
Why don't you save No Face?
He need it more than me.
Because you were the symbol.
Is not symbol. Is a woman.
Don't you think I know that, Romeo?
I've been dying to sleep with her.
Homer, is true?
From the first minute.
Is too late.
And now we all go to the seashore.
If anyone will save lllia, it will be Tonio.
Why Tonio?
Because with love, it's possible.