OH, MAN! IS THAT
WHAT I THINK IT IS?
ALL RIGHT, YOU CHEESE DICKS,
WELCOME TO THE 'NAM. FOLLOW ME.
I'LL BE DIPPED IN SHIT! NEW MEAT!
YOU DUDES GONNA LOVE THE 'NAM.
FOR FUCKIN' EVER. THREE HUNDRED
AND SIXTY-FIVE AND A WAKE-UP.
OH, LORD!
GET HIM UP HERE.
SKY SIX, RIPPER SIX.
RADIO CHECK. OVER.
WATCH IT BELOW!
MOREHOUSE, DROP BACK TO FLANK.
♪♪
WHO'S OUR TAIL-END CHARLIE?
EAGLE, EAGLE, RIPPER SIX.
I, SHACKLE, LIMA,
WHISKEY, ALPHA, WHISKEY,
FOXTROT, FOXTROT...
WARREN, MOVE
SANDERSON OUT ON FLANK.
SAY, HOFFMEISTER! YO!
YOU GOT A SMOKE?
NO, MAN, I'M OUT.
SIN LOY, MAN.
BRAVO TWO, SIX. WHAT'S THE DELAY ON POINT?
YOU HAVING COMPASS TROUBLE AGAIN, WOLFE?
COME ON... SHIT!
GET UP. GET UP.
GET A MOVE ON, BOY.
HEY, BOY, WHAT YOU WAITIN' FOR?
AIN'T GONNA BITE YOU.
THAT'S A GOOD GOOK.
GOOD AND DEAD.
FUCKIN' CHERRY.
GET OUT OF THE FUCKIN' WAY!
TWO-FIVE, TWO
ACTUAL, MOVE IT OUT.
SIX SAYS WE'RE JAMMIN'
'EM UP BACK THERE. OVER.
TELL THAT DIPSHIT TO GET FUCKED!
THIS IS TWO-FIVE. BE ADVISED,
WE'RE MOVIN' OUT SHORTLY. OUT.
WHAT THE HELL'S THE
MATTER WITH YOU, TAYLOR?
YOU ARE ONE SIMPLE
SON OF A BITCH.
I'M SORRY, SERGEANT. GET THAT
OTHER CHERRY UP HERE, GARDNER.
AND THE DOC. GARDNER, DOC, UP!
GARDNER, DOC, TO THE FRONT!
GARDNER, UP! GARDNER,
UP! GARDNER, UP!
GARDNER, GET YOUR ASS
UP THE HILL, YOU FAT FUCK!
HURRY UP, BUBBLE BUTT!
YOU ALL RIGHT? ANTS.
I GOT ANTS ALL OVER MY NECK.
YOU GOT SOME RED ANTS.
BITES ARE KILLERS. BLACK
ANTS ARE THE WORST.
HURRY UP, LARD ASS!
I'M SO TIRED!
JUST A LITTLE. DON'T
DRINK TOO MUCH.
I DON'T WANT YOU DRINKING
ANY MORE, ALL RIGHT?
I DON'T WANT YOU CRAMPING UP.
YOU'RE HUMPIN' TOO MUCH STUFF.
YOU DON'T NEED HALF THIS SHIT.
I'LL HAUL IT FOR YOU, BUT NEXT TIME
YOU CHECK WITH ME FIRST, ALL RIGHT?
OKAY. THANKS, SARGE.
ALL RIGHT. YOU OKAY? YEAH.
TWO-TWO, THIS IS SIX.
UNDERSTAND YOU HAVE A BIRD
INBOUND AT YOUR POS AT THIS TIME.
I SAY AGAIN, BIRD INBOUND
AT YOUR POS AT THIS TIME.
BRAVO SIX, BRAVO
SIX, BE ADVISED.
RESUPPLY HELO IS
INBOUND AT THIS TIME. OVER.
GO, YOU PEOPLE! GET
THAT 81 AMMO OFF NOW!
MOVE IT!
♪♪
IT AIN'T D-E-R-E, IT'S D-E-A-R,
AND SARAH AIN'T
GOT NO TWO R's, KING.
DAMN, YOU DUMB!
IT DON'T MAKE NO DIFFERENCE.
SHE KNOW WHAT I MEAN.
SHE DON'T READ TOO GOOD NO HOW!
♪♪
LOOK AT THIS SHIT! PORK AGAIN!
WHY DON'T YOU LET ME HAVE THAT
TURKEY LOAF FOR THIS PORK SHIT?
JUST TODAY. I CAN'T
EAT THIS SHIT, HAROLD!
WHAT YOU BEEN SMOKIN', JUNIOR?
I HOPE MANNY GET
THAT LAUNDRY GIG,
'CAUSE YOUR ASS NEEDS
TO HUMP, HUMP AND HUMP!
HEY, WHITE BOY!
WHAT YOU WAITIN' FOR?
THAT HOLE AIN'T
GONNA DIG ITSELF.
COME ON, BOY. GET YOUR
DICK SKIN ON THAT THING. DIG!
AIN'T GOT ALL DAY. DIG! DIG!
SOMEBODY ONCE WROTE, "HELL
IS THE IMPOSSIBILITY OF REASON."
THAT'S WHAT THIS
PLACE FEELS LIKE, HELL.
I HATE IT ALREADY, AND
IT'S ONLY BEEN A WEEK.
SOME GODDAMN WEEK,
GRANDMA. BOY, DIG, DIG!
THE HARDEST THING I THINK I'VE EVER
DONE IS GO ON POINT, THREE TIMES THIS WEEK.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT I'M DOING.
A GOOK COULD BE STANDING THREE FEET
IN FRONT OF ME AND I WOULDN'T KNOW IT.
I'M SO TIRED.
WE GET UP AT 5:00
A.M., HUMP ALL DAY,
CAMP AROUND 4:00 OR
5:00, DIG A FOXHOLE, EAT,
AND PUT OUT AN ALL-NIGHT AMBUSH OR
THREE-MAN LISTENING POST IN THE JUNGLE.
IT'S SCARY, 'CAUSE NOBODY TELLS ME
HOW TO DO ANYTHING 'CAUSE I'M NEW.
NOBODY CARES ABOUT THE NEW GUYS.
THEY DON'T EVEN WANT TO KNOW YOUR NAME.
THE UNWRITTEN RULE IS A NEW
GUY'S LIFE ISN'T WORTH AS MUCH...
'CAUSE HE HASN'T
PUT HIS TIME IN YET,
AND THEY SAY IF YOU'RE
GONNA GET KILLED IN THE 'NAM,
IT'S BETTER TO GET IT
IN THE FIRST FEW WEEKS,
THE LOGIC BEING YOU
DON'T SUFFER THAT MUCH.
IF YOU'RE LUCKY, YOU STAY
IN THE PERIMETER AT NIGHT,
AND THEN YOU PULL A
THREE-HOUR GUARD SHIFT.
SO MAYBE YOU SLEEP THREE, FOUR
HOURS A NIGHT, BUT YOU DON'T REALLY SLEEP.
I DON'T THINK I CAN KEEP
THIS UP FOR A YEAR, GRANDMA.
I THINK I MADE A BIG
MISTAKE COMING HERE.
MM-HMM. WE GOT
BEAUCOUP MOVEMENT.
THIRD BATTALION JUST GOT
HIT 15 CLICKS NORTH OF HERE.
CHARLIE HAD CLAYMORES
STRUNG UP IN THE TREES.
BLEW A WHOLE FUCKIN'
PLATOON TO PIECES.
BAD SHIT.
YEAH. THEY GOT TWO
LIEUTENANTS AND A CAPTAIN.
JESUS.
ALL RIGHT, SERGEANT, WHO
DO YOU WANT ON AMBUSH?
ELIAS, YOU TAKE YOUR SQUAD OUT.
WARREN, YOU STAY IN,
BUT I'LL NEED TEX AND JUNIOR
FROM YOUR SQUAD. ROGER THAT.
OKAY, MOVE OUT IN 2-0 MIKES.
I THOUGHT IT WAS
O'NEILL'S TURN TONIGHT.
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
TUBBS AND MOREHOUSE ARE SHORT.
FU SHEN IS GOING
ON R & R TOMORROW,
AND YOU WANNA SEND
THEM OUT ON AN AMBUSH?
UH-UH. YOU GOT THE
FRESH MEAT, BUDDY.
THEY DON'T KNOW SHIT, BARNES, AND
CHANCES ARE WE'RE GONNA RUN INTO SOMETHING.
THINK ABOUT IT. THAT'S GREAT.
WHAT DO YOU WANT ME TO DO?
SEND ONE OF MY GUYS OUT TO GET ZAPPED
SO SOME LAME ASS CAN GET HIS BEAUTY SLEEP?
NAH. HEY, O'NEILL, TAKE A BREAK.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE A
PRICK EVERY DAY OF YOUR LIFE.
ELIAS, GET YOUR MEN READY.
GUY'S IN THREE YEARS AND HE
THINKS HE'S JESUS FUCKIN' CHRIST.
O'NEILL, YOUR SHORT-TIMERS
STAY IN, BUT YOU GO OUT.
I NEED VETERANS OUT THERE.
SERGEANT BARNES?
SERGEANT.
I THINK, IN FRONT OF THE MEN, IT'S
NECESSARY FOR ME TO GIVE THE ORDERS.
YES, SIR.
LOOKS LIKE IT'S GONNA RAIN.
IT'S GONNA PISS ON US ALL NIGHT.
GONNA PUT A SERIOUS CASE OF CROTCH
ROT ON THAT UGLY FACE OF YOURS, JUNIOR.
GODDAMN, MAN.
YOU BREAK YOUR ASS FOR THE
WHITE MAN. NO JUSTICE AROUND HERE.
WHAT'S O'NEILL GOT, A NOSE UP
THE LIEUTENANT'S ASS ALREADY?
HOW COME WE ALWAYS
GET FUCKIN' AMBUSH?
'CAUSE IT'S POLITICS,
MAN. POLITICS.
HEY, CHRIS. DID I SHOW
YOU A PICTURE OF LUCY JEAN?
NO, YOU DIDN'T. SHE'S THE ONE
FOR ME, ALL RIGHT, THAT LUCY JEAN.
SHE'S WAITIN' FOR ME TOO.
YEAH, SHE'S REAL PRETTY.
YOU'RE A LUCKY GUY, GARDNER.
NO. YOU GOT A PICTURE OF YOUR GIRL?
I GUESS THAT LEAVES SOME
UNLUCKY GIRL BACK AT HOME, DON'T IT?
TUCK THIS IN. SHITCAN THIS.
DON'T NEED THIS. TURN AROUND.
COME ON.
TEX, YOU GOT JUNIOR AND
TAYLOR HERE ON YOUR POSITION.
GODDAMN IT, ELIAS,
DON'T MESS WITH MY PIG.
I AIN'T GETTIN' GREASED
ON THIS 'BUSH TONIGHT,
SO YOU KEEP THIS SORRY
CHEESE DICK OFF MY ASS.
YOU GOT TAYLOR.
GARDNER, YOU'RE WITH ME.
LOOK, IN CASE ANYTHING
HAPPENS TO YOU,
YOU GET LOST OR SEPARATED,
DON'T YELL OUT, OKAY?
OKAY. JUST SIT TIGHT,
AND WE'LL GET TO YOU.
ALL RIGHT. YO!
SADDLE UP. LOCK AND LOAD.
♪ I COME FROM ALABAMA
WITH MY BANJO ON MY KNEE ♪
♪ AND I'M GOING TO LOUISIANA ♪
♪ MY TRUE LOVE FOR TO SEE ♪
♪ OH, SUSANNA ♪
♪ DON'T YOU CRY FOR ME ♪
♪ FOR I COME FROM ALABAMA ♪
♪ WITH MY BANJO... ♪♪
'COURSE, MOM AND DAD
DIDN'T WANT ME TO COME HERE.
THEY WANTED ME TO
BE JUST LIKE THEM...
RESPECTABLE, HARDWORKING,
A LITTLE HOUSE, A FAMILY.
THEY DROVE ME CRAZY WITH
THEIR GODDAMN WORLD, GRANDMA.
YOU KNOW MOM.
I GUESS I'VE ALWAYS BEEN
SHELTERED AND SPECIAL.
I JUST WANT TO BE ANONYMOUS,
LIKE EVERYBODY ELSE...
DO MY SHARE FOR MY COUNTRY,
LIVE UP TO WHAT GRANDPA DID IN THE
FIRST WAR AND DAD DID IN THE SECOND.
WELL, HERE I AM,
ANONYMOUS, ALL RIGHT,
WITH GUYS NOBODY
REALLY CARES ABOUT.
THEY COME FROM THE END
OF THE LINE, MOST OF THEM.
SMALL TOWNS YOU NEVER HEARD OF.
PULASKI, TENNESSEE,
BRANDON, MISSISSIPPI,
PORK BEND, UTAH,
WAMPUM, PENNSYLVANIA.
TWO YEARS' HIGH
SCHOOL IS ABOUT IT.
MAYBE, IF THEIR LUCKY, A JOB
WAITING FOR 'EM BACK IN A FACTORY,
BUT MOST OF 'EM GOT NOTHING.
THEY'RE POOR,
THEY'RE THE UNWANTED,
YET THEY'RE FIGHTING FOR
OUR SOCIETY AND OUR FREEDOM.
IT'S WEIRD, ISN'T IT?
THEY'RE THE BOTTOM OF THE
BARREL, AND THEY KNOW IT.
MAYBE THAT'S WHY THEY
CALL THEMSELVES "GRUNTS,"
'CAUSE A GRUNT CAN TAKE
IT, CAN TAKE ANYTHING.
THEY'RE THE BEST I'VE EVER SEEN,
GRANDMA, THE HEART AND SOUL.
HEY, TAYLOR. HEY.
CHEESE DICK, YOU'RE UP. WHAT?
YOU'RE UP.
YOU SURE YOU KNOW HOW TO WORK
THE CLAYMORES? YEAH, I'M SURE.
FLICK THE SAFETY OFF AND BANG
ON THAT SUCKER THREE TIMES.
THREE TIMES. I GOT IT.
AND DON'T CATCH ANY Z's ON ME,
BUDDY, OR I'LL SLING YOUR SORRY ASS.
YOU HEAR ME? OKAY.
MAYBE I FINALLY FOUND IT
WAY DOWN HERE IN THE MUD.
MAYBE FROM DOWN HERE
I CAN START UP AGAIN,
BE SOMETHING I CAN BE PROUD OF WITHOUT
HAVING TO FAKE IT, BE A FAKE HUMAN BEING.
MAYBE I CAN SEE SOMETHING I DON'T YET
SEE, OR LEARN SOMETHING I DON'T YET KNOW.
I MISS YOU. I MISS
YOU VERY MUCH.
TELL MOM I MISS HER TOO. CHRIS.
JUNIOR.
JUNIOR. HEY.
ALL RIGHT, MOTHERFUCKER!
IT'S YOUR SHIFT, MAN.
OKAY?
HERE, TAKE THIS.
BLOW THE FUCKIN' CLAYMORES!
TAKE THE SAFETY OFF! GODDAMN IT!
COME ON! TAKE THE SAFETY OFF!
FEED ME, JUNIOR! GET
OVER HERE AND FEED ME!
BRAVO TWO! BRAVO TWO!
MY FUCKIN' ARM!
DOC, GET UP HERE!
IT HURTS!
JESUS FUCKING CHRIST! EASY, TEX!
DOC, OVER HERE!
GARDNER'S HIT! RIGHT THERE!
OH, SHIT. MEDIC!
DOC, TAYLOR'S HIT!
TAYLOR'S HIT!
DOC! DOC! OH, SHIT.
- HOW BAD IS IT?
- DUMB FUCK DIDN'T BLOW
HIS CLAYMORE!
RELAX, MAN, IT'S A SCRATCH.
HOLD THIS ON HERE. DON'T
LIE TO ME, DOC. HOW BAD IS IT?
HE LET 'EM WALK RIGHT UP ON US! HE
WAS SLEEPIN' ON HIS GODDAMN SHIFT!
NO, NO, I DID NOT. BIG HAROLD,
YOU KEEP AN EYE ON HIM.
- YOU DON'T LET HIM
GO INTO SHOCK.
- SHUT UP!
SHUT UP AND TAKE
THE PAIN. TAKE THE PAIN!
RED LEG, RED LEG. BRAVO SIX.
I HAVE N.D.P.s AT
THIS TIME. OVER.
HEY, LITTLE GUY, YOU
GONNA BE OKAY. OKAY?
DON'T WORRY.
BIG HAROLD.
DO YOU KNOW IF YOU'RE GONNA DIE?
DO YOU FEEL LIKE EVERYTHING'S
JUST GONNA BE FINE?
DON'T GIVE ME THAT MORBID BULLSHIT.
YOU'RE ABOUT TO GET OUTTA HERE.
THEY'RE GONNA GIVE YOU
THREE HOT MEALS A DAY.
WHITE SHEETS. THEM
PRETTY WHITE NURSES.
THEY'LL GIVE YOU
BLOW JOBS, YOU PAY 'EM
ENOUGH. I HEARD ALL
ABOUT THEM WHITE BITCHES.
DON'T BABY-TALK HIM, MAN!
THE COCKSUCKER FELL ASLEEP!
- HE LET 'EM WALK RIGHT UP
ON US! HE NEVER DID SHIT!
- JUST SHUT UP, JUNIOR.
- YOU RELAX, OKAY, MAN?
- YEAH.
IT'S NOT SO BAD,
DYIN'.
HOW LONG? HOW LONG?
BIRD'S ON THE WAY, MAN. HANG
IN THERE. YOU'RE GONNA MAKE IT.
COME ON, GARDNER. HANG IN
THERE. YOU'RE GONNA MAKE IT.
COME ON! DON'T QUIT!
COME ON, GARDNER!
HELP ME! DON'T GIVE UP!
YOU ALL TAKE A GOOD
LOOK AT THIS LUMP OF SHIT.
REMEMBER WHAT IT LOOKS LIKE.
YOU FUCK UP IN A FIREFIGHT...
AND I GODDAMN GUARANTEE YOU A
TRIP OUT OF THE BUSH IN A BODY BAG!
OUT HERE, ASSHOLES, YOU KEEP
YOUR SHIT WIRED TIGHT AT ALL TIMES!
AND THAT GOES FOR
YOU, SHIT-FOR-BRAINS.
YOU DON'T SLEEP ON
NO FUCKIN' AMBUSH!
AND THE NEXT SUMBITCH I
CATCH COPPIN' Z's IN THE BUSH,
I'M PERSONALLY GONNA TAKE
AN INTEREST IN SEEIN' HIM SUFFER.
I SHIT YOU NOT.
DOC, TAG HIM AND BAG HIM!
I DIDN'T FALL ASLEEP, SERGEANT.
IT WAS JUNIOR. SHUT
YOUR FACE, CHICKENSHIT.
YOU IN BIG TROUBLE, BOY.
EXCUSES ARE LIKE ASSHOLES,
TAYLOR. EVERYBODY GOT ONE.
KNOCK IT OFF!
WE GOT TWO MEN
NEED ATTENTION HERE.
POLICE UP YOUR
EXTRA AMMO AND FRAGS.
DON'T LEAVE NOTHIN'
FOR THE DINKS.
JUNIOR... TONY. CARRY GARDNER.
MAN'D BE ALIVE IF HE HAD A FEW
MORE DAYS TO LEARN SOMETHING.
HEY, TAYLOR! WHAT'S
IN THE BREEZE?
OKAY. GOT LIGHT DUTY.
THREE DAYS' WORTH.
NO SHIT. TOO BAD WE IN
BASE CAMP, ANYWAY. YEAH.
WHAT DO YOU GOT? BEERS? YEAH.
JUST STOLE ME SOME FROM
THE TOP'S SUPPLY. YEAH?
HE BEEN STEALIN' FROM
US, ANYWAY. HEY, TAYLOR!
ARE YOU BACK? UH,
YEAH, IT LOOKS LIKE IT.
HEY, KING, WHERE'D YOU
GET THOSE BEERS, BOY?
I FOUND IT. OH, YOU "FOUND IT."
YOU'RE GOIN' ON REPORT, SON, NOW.
YEAH, BOTH OF YOU, COME WITH ME.
I GOT A LITTLE JOB FOR YOU.
GOO-O-O-D MORNING, VIETNAM!
I'M ARMY SPECIALIST...
MOTHERFUCKER!
THIS IS THE GREAT SOUND IN...
I'M TOO SHORT
FOR THIS SHIT, MAN.
THEY ALWAYS FUCKIN' WITH US.
NO LETUP.
POLITICS, MAN. FUCKIN' POLITICS.
THAT O'NEILL, HE'S GOT HIS
NOSE SO FAR UP TOP'S ASS...
HE'S GOTTA BE PINOCCHIO.
THIRTY-NINE AND A WAKE-UP. A PAUSE FOR
THE CAUSE AND I'M A GONE MOTHERFUCKER!
BACK TO THE WORLD!
I HEAR YOU, MAN.
BROKE A HUNDRED
THE OTHER DAY. NO SHIT!
NINETY-TWO LEFT TO GO. APRIL 17.
DEROS, MAN. HOME TO CALIFORNIA.
I'M GONNA BE SITTIN' OUTSIDE,
CHECKIN' OUT THE BABES ON THE BEACH.
THE SURFING'S GONNA BE GOOD.
MARCH, MAN, IN TENNESSEE.
SNIFF THE PINES.
SNIFF THAT CROSS-MOUNTED
PUSSY DOWN BY THE RIVER. OOH!
HOT DAMN!
HEY, TAYLOR, HOW
LONG YOU GOT LEFT?
- THREE HUNDRED AND WHAT?
- THIRTY-TWO.
THREE HUNDRED
AND THIRTY-TWO DAYS.
SIN LOY, MY BOY!
I CAN'T EVEN REMEMBER
WHEN I WAS 332, MAN.
YOU GOTTA, LIKE, COUNT
BACKWARDS OR SOMETHING.
YOU KNOW, LIKE,
YOU GOT 40 DAYS IN.
I MEAN, THINK POSITIVE, DUDE.
HEY, TAYLOR. HOW IN THE
FUCK YOU GET HERE, ANYWAY?
YOU LOOK EDUCATED.
I VOLUNTEERED FOR IT.
YOU DID WHAT? I VOLUNTEERED.
I DROPPED OUTTA COLLEGE AND
TOLD 'EM I WANTED THE INFANTRY,
COMBAT AND VIETNAM.
YOU VOLUNTEERED
FOR THIS SHIT, MAN?
YOU BELIEVE THAT?
YOU'S A CRAZY FUCKER.
GIVIN' UP COLLEGE?
DIDN'T MAKE MUCH SENSE. I
WASN'T LEARNIN' ANYTHING.
I FIGURED, WHY SHOULD JUST
THE POOR KIDS GO OFF TO WAR...
AND THE RICH KIDS
ALWAYS GET AWAY WITH IT?
WHAT WE GOT HERE IS A CRUSADER.
- SHIT.
- SOUNDS LIKE IT.
YOU GOTTA BE RICH IN THE
FIRST PLACE TO THINK LIKE THAT.
EVERYBODY KNOW...
THE POOR ALWAYS BEIN'
FUCKED OVER BY THE RICH.
ALWAYS HAVE, ALWAYS WILL.
WOW. I'LL TELL YOU WHAT,
YOU BE COOL, I'LL INTRODUCE YOU
AROUND TO SOME OF THE HEADS.
- WHAT ARE THE HEADS?
- LATER, MAN.
WHAT'S UP, BROTHER?
YOUR HIGHNESS HAS ARRIVED!
HEY, WHAT'S HAPPENIN'?
I THOUGHT YOU WAS
HANGIN' TEN IN CAMBODIA!
LOOK AT WHO'S HERE!
ALL RIGHT!
♪ ONE PILL MAKES YOU LARGER ♪
- WHAT YOU DOIN'
IN THE UNDERWORLD, TAYLOR?
- THIS HERE AIN'T TAYLOR.
TAYLOR BEEN SHOT. THIS MAN HERE
IS CHRIS. HE BEEN RESURRECTED.
♪ AND THE ONES THAT
MOTHER GIVES YOU ♪
♪ DON'T DO ANYTHING AT ALL ♪
♪ GO ASK ALICE ♪
COME IN, TAYLOR.
UH, WHAT? ARE YOU
LAME OR SOMETHING?
♪ WHO'S TEN FEET TALL ♪
GO 'HEAD, OLD MAN. SMOKE IT.
♪ AND IF YOU GO
CHASING RABBITS ♪
♪ AND YOU KNOW
YOU'RE GOING TO FALL ♪
GIMME A HIT. YOUR SHIT'S
IN THE WIND, TROOP. BAAH!
BAAH.
HEY, MAN, WHAT'S HAPPENIN',
BROTHER? WHERE YOU BEEN?
IF YOU'RE GONNA DO THAT
BAAH, YOU BETTER DO IT RIGHT.
BAAH!
YOU'RE WEIRD, MAN.
YOU'RE A CHILD, LERNER. I
DON'T WASTE TIME ON YOU.
♪ AND YOU'VE JUST HAD
SOME KIND OF MUSHROOM ♪
♪ AND YOUR MIND IS
MOVING LOW ♪ FIRST TIME?
YEAH. ♪ GO ASK ALICE ♪
THEN THE WORM HAS
DEFINITELY TURNED FOR YOU, MAN.
FEEL GOOD?
YEAH, IT FEELS GOOD. I GOT
NO PAIN IN MY NECK NOW.
FEELIN' GOOD'S GOOD ENOUGH.
♪ AND THE WHITE KNIGHT
IS TALKING BACKWARDS ♪
♪ AND THE RED QUEEN'S
OFF WITH HER HEAD ♪
PUT YOUR MOUTH ON THIS.
♪ REMEMBER WHAT
THE DORMOUSE SAID ♪
♪ FEED YOUR HEAD ♪
♪ FEED YOUR HEAD ♪♪
♪ WE DON'T SMOKE MARIJUANA ♪♪
MAN, WHERE THE HELL IS EVERYBODY, MAN?
THEY'RE GETTIN'
HIGH, THAT'S WHAT.
BUNCH OF HOPHEADS. THEY
THINK THEY'RE SOMETHING SPECIAL.
LISTEN TO THAT.
THAT'S A BAD JAM.
REDNECK NOISE,
DUDE. THAT'S ALL IT IS.
MAKE ABOUT AS MUCH
SENSE AS YOU DO.
ALL THEM CHUCKS BE RAPPIN'
ABOUT HOW THEY LOSIN' THEIR HO',
SAYIN' HOW THEY AIN'T
GOT NO BREAD FOR BEER.
FUCK THAT HONKY SHIT! GIVE
ME SOME MOTOWN JAMS, DIG IT?
MAN, WHAT ARE YOU
TALKIN' SHIT FOR, MAN?
HEY, JUNIOR, YOU EVER SMOKE
ANY SHIT? THAT'S RIGHT, DUDE.
YOU ALL BE TRYIN' TO KEEP THE BLACK
MAN DOWN AND STRING HIM OUT ON THAT SHIT,
BUT THE TIME BE'S COMIN' WHEN
THE BLACK MAN THROW THAT YOKE OFF.
SIMPLE. FREE YOUR MIND,
YOUR ASS WILL FOLLOW.
YEAH, I COULD DIG IT, MAN.
YOU SMOKE THAT SHIT, EVERYTHING KIND
OF GETS WEIRD, YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
YOU HEAR THAT STORY ABOUT THE
GOOKS PUTTIN' CHEMICALS IN THE GRASS...
SO WE DON'T FIGHT, SO
WE BECOME PACIFISTS?
YEAH, WELL, DON'T YOU WORRY,
BUNNY, 'CAUSE YOU'S A KILLER ANYWAY.
YEAH, BUT I STILL LIKE A PIECE
OF PUSSY ONCE IN A WHILE.
AIN'T NOTHIN' LIKE A PIECE OF
PUSSY, 'CEPT MAYBE THE INDY 500.
ONLY WAY YOU GET SOME PUSSY IS
THE BITCH DIES AND WILLS IT TO YOU,
AND THEN, MAYBE.
HOW'S IT GOIN', BUNNY?
L.T., CHECK IT OUT.
YOU LIKE THAT? TERRIFIC.
I'LL SEND IT HOME. HEY, JUNIOR.
LIEUTENANT. HELLO, SIR.
NEWS IS UP AT 5:00
ON AFEN. STAY TUNED.
WE GOT A BIG ONE
FROM THE FIRST CAMP...
HEY, RODRIGUEZ. THAT'S
QUITE A SHRINE YOU GOT THERE.
THANK YOU, SIR.
YOU, UH, NEED ANYTHING?
NO, SIR. I GOT MY HANDS
AROUND THIS FLYBOY'S NECK.
NOW, THIS GUY IS EASILY
THREE, FOUR TIMES MY SIZE.
NO, NO, 'CAUSE I GOT HIM
IN THE O'NEILL DEATH GRIP.
HE DOESN'T KNOW WHETHER TO
SHIT OR GO BLIND, FOR CHRISSAKE.
WHAT DO YOU SAY THERE,
L.T.? HOW YOU DOIN', RED?
OH, NOT GOOD, NOT GOOD. THIS
COCKSUCKER'S GOT EVERY CARD IN THE DECK.
FULL HOUSE. HUH?
LOOK LIKE YOU'RE DOIN'
ALL RIGHT, SERGEANT.
YEAH, AND I AIN'T
EVEN CHEATIN' YET.
HEY, UH, LIEUTENANT,
SOME KENTUCKY WINDAGE?
OH. THANKS, SANDY.
- PLAY, LIEUTENANT?
- AHH. NAH.
WOULDN'T WANNA GET
RAPED BY YOU GUYS.
WHY'S THAT, LIEUTENANT? WHAT
ARE YOU SAVING UP TO BE? JEWISH?
JEWISH!
VENEREAL DISEASE IS
NOTHING TO LAUGH ABOUT.
I GOTTA RUN. I'LL, UH,
CATCH YOU MEN LATER.
ENJOY YOURSELVES TONIGHT.
WELL, THAT IS ONE
SORRY-ASS MOTHERFUCKER.
WHAT DO YOU SAY THERE,
BOB? GUY LIKE THAT MAKE IT?
YES OR NO. UH-HUH.
UH-HUH. I HAVE TO TELL YOU,
THAT'S PRECISELY WHAT I SAW.
I MEAN, SOMETIMES I JUST
LOOK AT A GUY AND I KNOW,
"THIS FELLA'S NOT
GONNA MAKE IT."
JUST NO FUCKIN' WAY.
COME ON, NOW.
♪♪
♪ DO DO DO DO DO DO DO DO ♪
♪ DO DO DO DO DO DO DO
DO DO DO ♪ COME ON, NOW!
OH, I WANT SOME NOW.
♪ PEOPLE SAY I'M THE
LIFE OF THE PARTY ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I TELL A JOKE OR TWO ♪
♪ ALTHOUGH I MIGHT BE
LAUGHING LOUD AND HARDY ♪
♪ DEEP INSIDE I'M BLUE ♪
♪ SO TAKE A GOOD
LOOK AT MY FACE ♪
♪ YOU'LL SEE THE SMILE
LOOKS OUT OF PLACE ♪
♪ IF YOU LOOK CLOSER
IT'S EASY TO TRACE ♪
♪ THE TRACKS OF MY TEARS ♪
YEAH! ♪ OH, YEAH ♪
♪ I NEED YOU ♪
♪ NEED ♪
♪ NEED YOU ♪
♪ NEED YOU ♪♪
NEW YEAR'S DAY, 1968.
JUST ANOTHER DAY. STAYIN' ALIVE.
THERE'S BEEN A LOT OF MOVEMENT
NEAR THE CAMBODIAN BORDER.
REGIMENTS OF
N.V.A. MOVIN' ACROSS.
A LOT OF LITTLE
FIREFIGHTS, AMBUSHES.
WE DROP A LOT OF BOMBS.
THEN WE WALK THROUGH
THE JUNGLE LIKE
GHOSTS IN A LANDSCAPE.
PSST. PSST!
BUNKER.
WHERE?
BRAVO TWO, BRAVO TWO-FIVE. WE
GOT BEAUCOUP BUNKERS UP HERE. OVER.
TWO-FIVE, TWO. ROGER.
BUNKERS AT POINT. TWO
ACTUAL IS ON THE WAY.
TWO, TWO-FIVE. ROGER
THAT. BRAVO TWO-FIVE OUT.
BRAVO SIX, BRAVO SIX, BRAVO TWO.
BE ADVISED THERE IS A
BUNKER COMPLEX UP FRONT.
WE'RE ON OUR WAY DOWN. OVER.
SEE YOU NEXT WEEK.
BRAVO TWO, THIS IS ALPHA.
BE ADVISED WE'RE IN THE TUNNELS
AND ONE MAN DOWN AT THIS TIME.
TAYLOR, GET YOUR ASS UP ON
THAT FLANK ABOUT 50 METERS.
WASHINGTON, YOU COVER THIS SIDE.
YES, SIR. GET OFF
YOUR ASS, HAROLD.
BUMMER.
OH, CHRIST, LOOK
AT THAT, WILL YOU?
THE TEAPOT'S STILL BOILIN'.
THEY WERE JUST HERE.
THIS IS SPOOKY, SANDY.
LET'S GET OUTTA HERE.
WATCH IT. WATCH IT!
LOOK WHAT WE GOT, SAL.
WE GOT MAPS.
WE GOT S-2 STUFF...
MAN, THIS IS GOOK STUFF!
LET'S GET OUTTA HERE!
NO, SAL, THIS IS IMPORTANT.
THIS IS IMPORTANT.
COME ON. LET'S LEAVE. LET'S GO.
BOOBY TRAP! GET DOWN!
MEDIC!
HOLY JEEZ!
GODDAMN IT.
WE GOT, UH...
WE GOT TWO MEN DOWN,
SIR. THERE WAS AN EXPLOSION.
WE NEED HELP, SIR, ASAP.
MOVE YOUR ASS OUTTA HERE! LET'S
GO! ONE ROUND WILL GET ALL YOU GUYS!
RODRIGUEZ, MOVE
IT! JUNIOR, LET'S GO!
LIEUTENANT! WHAT?
TELL SIX WE NEED ENGINEERS. THIS POS IS
CRAWLIN' WITH TRAPS. THEY'RE ON THEIR WAY.
THE N.V.A. OUT OF HERE HAVE BEEN SPOTTED
IN THE VILLAGE HALF A CLICK DOWN THE RIVER.
SIX SAYS WE GOTTA
GET THERE ASAP. OKAY.
ALSO, LEAVE FOUR MEN HERE AND A
MEDIC, OKAY? MOVE IT OUT. ALL RIGHT.
PULL THE FLANKS IN! LET'S MOVE!
NOW, WHERE'S MANNY? MANNY!
YO, MANNY! HEY,
WASHINGTON! MANNY!
HEY, MANNY! MANNY! MANNY!
WASHINGTON! YO, MANNY!
MANNY, WHERE ARE YOU AT?
WE HAD TO GET TO THE
VILLAGE BEFORE DARK,
SO WE LEFT ELIAS WITH SOME MEN TO KEEP
LOOKING AND TO WAIT FOR THE ENGINEERS,
BUT IT WAS KING WHO FOUND HIM,
ABOUT A THOUSAND YARDS
DOWNRIVER, NOT FAR FROM THE VILLAGE.
IT WAS THE END OF THE MYSTERY.
THE MOTHERFUCKERS.
THE VILLAGE, WHICH HAD STOOD
FOR MAYBE A THOUSAND YEARS,
DIDN'T KNOW WE WERE
COMING THAT DAY.
IF THEY HAD, THEY
WOULD HAVE RUN.
BARNES WAS AT THE
EYE OF OUR RAGE,
AND THROUGH HIM,
OUR CAPTAIN AHAB,
WE WOULD SET THINGS RIGHT AGAIN.
THAT DAY, WE LOVED HIM.
DUNG LAI! DUNG LAI!
THERE THEY GO, SARGE.
CHECK HIM OUT. YEAH.
YOU GOT IT, SARGE.
TUBBS, EBENHOCK, LET'S GO.
GET THAT STUPID
LOOK OFF YOUR FACE!
SGT. O'NEILL, CLEAR OUT
THESE FUCKIN' HOOCHES.
HEY, PIGGY, PIGGY. HEY, PIG.
SPREAD OUT ON THE
RIGHT! WATCH YOUR BACKS!
LET'S GO! MUSTER 'EM UP!
HEY, HEY, HEY! WHAT
YOU GOT HERE, HUH?
LET'S GO! MUSTER 'EM UP HERE!
GET OVER THERE! MOVE IT!
COME ON. LET'S GO.
OVER HERE! LET'S GO,
JUNIOR! BRING 'EM IN!
GET THOSE PEOPLE DOWN HERE!
LA DAI! LA DAI!
GET OUT OF THERE,
YOU FUCK-HEADS! MOVE!
LA DAI MOI!
COME ON!
PUT 'EM IN THE PIGPEN!
SHUT UP! GET BACK! SHUT UP!
GIVE ME YOUR WILLIE PETE.
SHUT UP!
MOVE BACK!
FIRE IN THE HOLE!
SHUT UP!
SHUT UP! SHUT UP!
GET 'EM OUTTA HERE!
OH, FUCK! WE GOT ONE!
LA DAI! LA DAI! GET THE
FUCK OUTTA THE HOLE! MOVE!
GET THE FUCK OUTTA THERE!
LET'S GO! COME ON, MOTHERFUCKER!
BE COOL, BE COOL. THEY'RE
SCARED, MAN. THEY'RE SCARED.
OH, THEY'RE SCARED,
HUH? WHAT ABOUT ME, MAN?
WHAT ABOUT ME? I'M
SICK OF THIS FUCKING SHIT!
COME ON, MOTHERFUCKER! MOVE!
WATCH THIS FUCKER!
FUCKERS DON'T WANT US HERE. WHO
THE FUCK THEY THINK WE'RE FIGHTIN' FOR?
GOT ONE MORE! HEY! HEY! LA DAI!
LA DAI! NO, NO, NO!
DUNG BAN! DUNG BAN!
WELL, WELL. WHAT HAVE WE HERE?
WE HAVE ONE, TWO, THREE,
FOUR MAG .58
CZECHOSLOVAKIAN MACHINE GUNS.
WE GOT TWO, FOUR...
BARNES, THEY GOT ENOUGH RICE HERE
TO FEED A WHOLE FUCKIN' REGIMENT.
SIX-TWO, UH, BE
ADVISED YOU GOT...
SGT. WARREN, YOU BRING THAT
HONCHO OVER HERE. YOU GOT IT.
TUBBS, GET OUTTA
THERE! JUNIOR, BURN IT!
WHAT THE FUCK'S THE MATTER
WITH YOU? I WASN'T GONNA HURT YOU.
DID IT LOOK LIKE I WAS
GONNA FUCKIN' HURT YOU?
WHY DIDN'T YOU LISTEN
TO ME, HUH? WHY?
WHY DIDN'T YOU FUCKIN'
LISTEN TO ME? FUCKIN' STUPID?
YOU STUPID ASSHOLE!
GET THE FUCK UP HERE!
COME HERE, MOTHERFUCKER!
WHAT ARE YOU SMILING AT?
HUH? WHY THE FUCK
DIDN'T YOU LISTEN TO ME?
- DO HIM, MAN! DO HIM!
- WHAT ARE YOU SMILING AT?
YOU WANT SOMETHING TO SMILE AT?
HUH? YOU WANT SOMETHING TO SMILE AT?
MOTHERFUCKER!
- DANCE, MOTHERFUCKER!
- YEAH!
DO HIM, MAN! DO HIM!
DANCE, ONE-LEGGER!
DANCE! DANCE!
HUH? HUH? DANCE,
ONE-LEGGED MOTHERFUCKER!
HEY, MAN, COME
ON. LET'S GO, MAN.
FUCKIN' PUSSY, MAN!
HE'S LAUGHING AT YOU!
THAT'S THE WAY THE GOOK LAUGHS.
YEAH, SURE YOU ARE.
YOU'RE REAL SORRY, AIN'T YA?
YOU'RE JUST CRYIN' YOUR LITTLE HEARTS
OUT ABOUT SANDY AND SAL AND MANNY!
DUNG BAN! FORGET
ABOUT IT, BUNNY, HUH?
LET'S GO. WHAT DO YOU SAY?
COME ON.
DUNG BAN! DUNG BAN!
HOLY SHIT! YOU SEE THAT
FUCKIN' HEAD COME APART, MAN?
I NEVER SEEN BRAINS
LIKE THAT BEFORE, MAN.
I BET YOU THE OLD BITCH RUNS
THE WHOLE FUCKIN' SHOW, MAN.
SHE PROBABLY CUT MANNY'S
THROAT. SHE'D PROBABLY
CUT MY BALLS OFF IF
SHE HAD THE CHANCE.
BUNNY, WE LEAVE NOW, AND
NOBODY SAW A FUCKIN' THING.
YOU UNDERSTAND ME, TAYLOR?
NOT A FUCKIN' THING! FUCKIN' WOMAN!
COME ON, MAN. LET'S FUCKIN' DO HER,
MAN. LET'S DO THIS WHOLE FUCKIN' VILLAGE!
LOOK AT THE SCARS ON
THIS GOOK HONCHO, SARGE.
GET OUTTA HERE, TUBBS.
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH,
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
WHERE'D HE GET THESE WOUNDS?
SAYS HE WAS HIT
IN A BOMBING RAID.
HE'S A DINK FOR SURE!
ASK HIM WHY THOSE
WEAPONS WERE HERE.
HE SAYS THEY HAD NO CHOICE. THE N.V.A.
KILLED THE OLD HONCHO WHEN HE SAID NO.
HE SAYS ALL THE RICE IS
THEIRS. OH, BULLSHIT, LERNER!
WHO THE HELL WAS THE GOOK
WE NAILED ON THE RIVERBANK?
HE DOESN'T KNOW. HE SAYS THAT THE N.V.A.
AIN'T BEEN AROUND IN A COUPLE OF MONTHS.
MAYBE IT WAS A SCOUT OR
SOMETHING, SARGE. YEAH, SURE, A SCOUT.
WHAT ABOUT THE FUCKIN' RICE
AND THE WEAPONS? WHO THEY FOR?
THAT COCKSUCKER KNOWS WHAT I'M
SAYING. HE UNDERSTANDS, DON'T YOU, POP?
GODDAMN RIGHT HE DOES!
- HE'S LYING THROUGH HIS TEETH!
- WASTE THE FUCKER. THEN SEE WHO TALKS.
HE SWEARS HE DOESN'T
KNOW ANYTHING!
HE SWEARS HE DOESN'T KNOW
ANYTHING. HE HATES THE N.V.A.
THEY COME WHEN THEY WANT AND TAKE
THE PLACE OVER. WHAT'S THE BITCH SAYIN'?
I DON'T KNOW. SHE'S GOIN' ON
ABOUT WHY WE KILLED THE PIGS.
THEY'RE FARMERS. THEY GOTTA
MAKE A LIVIN', ALL THAT SHIT. AW, JESUS!
SHUT UP!
SHUT THE FUCK UP!
YOU TELL HIM HE STARTS TALKIN',
OR I'M GONNA WASTE MORE OF 'EM.
TELL HIM, LERNER!
HEY, SARGE!
LET US IN ON THIS, ALL RIGHT?
LET'S GO FOR IT.
LET'S DO THE WHOLE FUCKIN' VILLAGE!
COME ON, SARGE! WHAT ARE WE WAITING FOR?
LET'S DO 'EM! OUTTA MY WAY!
THIS IS HIS DAUGHTER,
RIGHT? RIGHT?
YOU LIE! NO, YOU LIE!
YOU V.C.!
BARNES!
WHAT THE FUCK DO
YOU THINK YOU'RE DOING?
STAY OUT OF THIS, ELIAS.
THIS AIN'T YOUR SHOW.
YOU AIN'T A FIRING
SQUAD, YOU PIECE OF SHIT!
GET HIM, BARNES!
ELIAS, NO! NO, NO!
GET HIM! GET HIM! TEAR
HIS FUCKIN' HEAD OFF!
COME ON, ELIAS! SEND HIM TO
HELL! SEND HIM TO HELL, ELIAS!
GET HIM! BREAK IT UP NOW!
BREAK IT UP, FELLAS!
BREAK IT UP!
COME ON, ELIAS! CHILL!
YOU'RE DEAD, ELIAS! I SWEAR
TO FUCKIN' GOD YOU'RE DEAD!
YOU! YOU'RE GONNA
DO TIME IN L.B.J.!
THIS SHIT WON'T WASH,
YOU FUCKIN' PUKE!
BREAK IT UP! SHUT
UP! BREAK IT UP!
LISTEN UP!
CAPTAIN SAYS TO TORCH
THIS PLACE! YOU HEAR THAT?
TORCH THIS PLACE! BLOW
THE WEAPONS IN PLACE!
ROUND UP ALL SUSPECTED
V.C. AND SHAKE IT UP!
WE AIN'T GOT MUCH
LIGHT LEFT. LIEUTENANT,
WHY THE FUCK DIDN'T
YOU DO SOMETHING?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKIN' ABOUT?
YOU KNOW WHAT THE
FUCK I'M TALKIN' ABOUT!
NO, I DON'T! I DON'T KNOW WHAT
THE FUCK YOU'RE TALKIN' ABOUT, ELIAS!
ALL RIGHT, MOVE IT OUT! LET'S
GO! YOU HEARD THE LIEUTENANT!
MOVE IT OUT! TAYLOR,
LET'S GO, FOR CHRISSAKE!
MOVE IT OUT! POLICE UP
THE WEAPONS! LET'S GO!
COME ON, HAROLD.
FIRE IN THE HOLE!
HEY, HEY, COME ON! MOREHOUSE,
YOU FUCKER! GET OUTTA HERE!
GET THE FUCK OFF! DON'T DO IT!
DON'T DO IT! YOU FUCKER!
WHAT IS THIS, HUH?
YOU A HOMOSEXUAL, TAYLOR?
WHAT THE FUCK IS YOUR PROBLEM?
SHE'S A FUCKIN' DINK! SHE'S
A FUCKIN' HUMAN BEING, MAN!
FUCK YOU! YOU'RE A
FUCKIN' CHERRY, TAYLOR!
FUCKIN' ANIMALS!
ALL OF YOU, YOU'RE
FUCKIN' LAME FUCK!
YOU DON'T BELONG IN THE 'NAM.
THIS AIN'T YOUR PLACE AT ALL.
YOU DON'T FUCKIN'
GET IT, DO YOU, MAN?
YOU JUST DON'T FUCKIN' GET IT.
IT'S OKAY.
GET OUT OF THERE!
FUCK YOU, MAN!
COME ON, GUYS. POLICE UP
YOUR DICKS. LET'S GET OUTTA HERE.
I DIDN'T SEE
ANYTHING, SIR. I DID.
THAT DINK WAS REPORTED TO ME
AS N.V.A. BY SERGEANT BARNES, SIR.
MY REPORT, SIR, WILL
INCLUDE LIEUTENANT WOLFE...
AS BEING WITNESS
TO THE SHOOTING.
ALL RIGHT, ELIAS. STAFF
SERGEANT BARNES.
SIR.
I WANT A FULL REPORT FROM YOU ON
THIS WHEN WE GET BACK TO THE C.P.
YOU GOT IT, DAI WEE,
AND I CAN THROW IN PLENTY OF
EYEWITNESSES IF YOU WANT, SIR.
NOT NOW, GODDAMN IT. NOT NOW.
WE'LL GET INTO THIS WHEN WE
GET BACK TO THE BASE CAMP.
AND I CAN PROMISE YOU SOMETHING.
IF I FIND OUT THERE
WAS AN ILLEGAL KILLING,
THERE WILL BE A COURT-MARTIAL.
RIGHT NOW I NEED
EVERY MAN IN THE FIELD,
AND YOU TWO WILL CEASE FIRE.
STAFF SERGEANT BARNES,
SERGEANT ELIAS, YOU HEAR ME?
YES, SIR. YES, SIR.
NOW, WE'RE GOING BACK
INTO THAT N.V.A. BUNKER
COMPLEX TOMORROW,
THIS TIME FROM THE EAST.
YOU PEOPLE GET SOME REST...
AND BE BACK UP HERE AT THE
C.P. AT 1900 FOR A BRIEFING.
YES, SIR. YES, SIR.
COME ON, MAN.
YOU THINK THESE CHUCKS
GIVE A FUCK ABOUT YOU AND ME?
COULD JUST AS WELL HAVE BEEN
YOU, HAROLD, YOU GOT IN BARNES'S WAY.
AND THAT BUNNY?
THAT MOTHERFUCKER'S CRAZY.
I MEAN, HE SCARES ME, MAN.
HE JUST SCARES ME. LOOK.
YOU BLOODS ARE GETTING
TOO HUNG UP ON ALL THIS SHIT.
THESE GOOKS ARE A LOT
SMARTER THAN YOU THINK.
YOU KNOW, BARNES
KNOWS HIS SHIT, MAN.
THEY WAS N.V.A., EVERY
LAST ONE OF THEM.
NOW HE'S TAKEN
US THIS FAR, RIGHT?
HE'LL TAKE US THE REST OF
THE WAY. I DON'T KNOW, HOMES.
I MEAN, A CHRISTIAN DON'T GO AROUND
A VILLAGE CUTTING OFF HEADS AND SHIT.
SHIT IS REALLY GETTING
OUT OF HAND, MAN.
IT'S BLOWIN' WAY OUT OF CONTROL.
IT SEEMS TO ME THAT YOU DON'T
SEEM TO KNOW THE DIFFERENCE...
THE WAY YOU SHOOT UP
THAT SHIT ALL THE TIME.
I DON'T KNOW, BROTHERS,
BUT I'M HURTING REAL BAD INSIDE.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT, SERGEANT.
ELIAS WON'T BE ABLE TO PROVE A THING.
I MEAN, HE'S A TROUBLEMAKER.
HE... ELIAS IS A WATER WALKER.
LIKE THEM POLITICIANS IN
WASHINGTON TRYING TO FIGHT THIS WAR...
WITH ONE HAND TIED
AROUND THEIR BALLS.
AIN'T NO NEED OR TIME FOR
A COURTROOM OUT HERE.
SARGE. THANKS, BUN.
HOW'D IT GO THERE, BOB?
AAH.
YEAH. THATAWAY, SARGE.
FUCKING ELIAS, MAN.
HE'S A FUCKING RAT,
THAT'S WHAT HE IS.
HE'S GONNA GET EVERYBODY
IN THIS PLATOON IN DEEP SHIT.
SOMEBODY OUGHT TO FRAG HIS ASS.
SO WHAT DO YOU THINK THERE, BOB?
GONNA BE AN
INVESTIGATION OR WHAT?
BOB?
O'NEILL, MAN, YOU
WORRY TOO MUCH.
SARGE WILL TAKE CARE OF IT.
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL NIGHT.
YEAH, I LOVE THIS
PLACE AT NIGHT...
THE STARS.
THERE'S NO RIGHT
OR WRONG IN THEM.
THEY'RE JUST THERE.
THAT'S A NICE WAY OF PUTTING IT.
BARNES HAS GOT IT IN
FOR YOU, DOESN'T HE?
BARNES BELIEVES
IN WHAT HE'S DOING.
AND YOU? DO YOU BELIEVE?
IN '65, YEAH.
NOW,
NO.
WHAT HAPPENED TODAY
IS JUST THE BEGINNING.
WE'RE GONNA LOSE THIS WAR.
COME ON.
YOU REALLY THINK SO? HONEST?
WE'VE BEEN KICKING OTHER
PEOPLE'S ASSES FOR SO LONG...
I FIGURE IT'S TIME
WE GOT OURS KICKED.
DAY BY DAY,
I STRUGGLE TO MAINTAIN
NOT ONLY MY STRENGTH...
BUT MY SANITY.
IT'S ALL A BLUR. I HAVE
NO ENERGY TO WRITE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT'S RIGHT
AND WHAT'S WRONG ANYMORE.
THE MORALE OF THE MEN IS LOW...
A CIVIL WAR IN THE PLATOON,
HALF THE MEN WITH
ELIAS, HALF WITH BARNES.
THERE'S A LOT OF
SUSPICION AND HATE.
I CAN'T BELIEVE WE'RE
FIGHTING EACH OTHER...
WHEN WE SHOULD BE FIGHTING THEM.
COUNTING DAYS AND THE SIX
INCHES IN FRONT OF MY FACE,
NOT MUCH ELSE.
HOPE THINGS ARE WELL, GRANDMA.
TELL MOM AND DAD I...
WELL, JUST TELL THEM.
CHRIS.
HEY, BIG BOY.
I KNOW YOU THOUGHT YOU HAD
THAT LAUNDRY GIG ALL LAID OUT.
I GOTTA PAINT MYSELF WHITE JUST
TO GET ME ONE OF THEM FUCKING JOBS.
IT'S ALL RIGHT. I GOT MY
REQUEST IN FOR A CIRCUMCISION.
I'M GONNA GET MY
ASS OUT OF THIS PLACE.
WHAT YOU GONNA
DO? BECOME A RABBI?
LEECH.
ALL RIGHT. MOVE IT OUT.
DON'T DRINK THAT, ASSHOLE.
YOU'RE GONNA GET MALARIA.
YEAH, I HOPE SO.
LET'S GO.
DOC! GET UP HERE! LERNER'S HIT!
SERGEANT WARREN'S HIT.
WHAT THE FUCK'S GOING ON?
THEY GOT R.P.G.s, MAN. IT'S AN AMBUSH.
THEY WERE JUST WAITING FOR US HERE.
WHO'S ON POINT?
LERNER AND WARREN.
TAYLOR, WHERE YOU GOING?
GODDAMN IT, YOU ASSHOLES.
GET SOME FIREPOWER UP THERE.
READY.
WATCH OUT! ROCKETS!
WHERE THE FUCK IS LERNER?
HE'S OVER THERE BY THE LOG.
6-4-9-4-0-2.
6-1-0-0...
ADJUST FIRE. OVER.
LIEUTENANT, THEY'RE GONNA
GET IN TIGHT UNDER THE ARTY.
I SPOTTED A CUT OVER THERE. LET ME
GET SOME MEN AND ROLL UP THAT FLANK.
I CAN WORK RIGHT UP
ON THEM. GET ME BARNES.
LOOK, ELIAS. WE GOT FOUR DOWN. WHAT DO
YOU WANT ME TO DO? FUCK YOU, LIEUTENANT.
WHERE THE FUCK IS RED PLATOON?
TELL THOSE ASSHOLES
TO GET UP HERE.
ELIAS, WHAT THE FUCK ARE YOU DOING
BACK HERE? LISTEN TO ME, BARNES.
THERE'S HOLES BACK HERE.
THIRD PLATOON'S COMING
UP HERE. WE'RE HERE.
DINKS GET MEN IN THESE HOLES,
THEY GOT US CAUGHT IN A CROSS FIRE.
WE'LL SHOOT EACH OTHER TO SHIT.
SOUNDS PRETTY
FAR OUT TO ME, ELIAS.
I'VE SEEN IT HAPPEN.
YA TRANG IN '66.
THEY CUT US TO FUCKING
PIECES. I NEED THREE MEN.
OKAY, YOU GOT THEM. TAKE OFF.
YOU KEEP POURING
OFF THAT COVER FIRE.
I DON'T WANT TO BE STUCK OUT THERE
WITH MY ASS HANGING IN THE BREEZE.
YOU DON'T TELL ME HOW
TO RUN MY WAR, ELIAS.
NOW, YOU GO CRYING AND RAT-FUCKING
THE BRIGADE ON YOUR OWN TIME.
BUT OUT HERE, YOU
BELONG TO ME. NOW MOVE.
YOU'RE AN ASSHOLE, BARNES.
GET THAT ASSHOLE
O'NEILL UP HERE.
THIS IS TWO. BE
ADVISED WE'LL BE...
STAY DOWN!
AMMO. AMMO.
SARGE!
SHORT ROUND!
FUCKING IDIOT!
OH, GOD!
MEDIC! MEDIC!
GET IT OFF OF YOU. MEDIC!
AH!
MEDIC!
SATCHEL CHARGE!
DOC.
DOC. HELP ME OUT. OH, NO.
JESUS.
YOU OKAY? DON'T LEAVE ME, MAN.
ALL RIGHT? DON'T LEAVE... ME.
HEY, GATOR.
YOU'LL BE OKAY, MAN.
GATOR, YOU'LL BE OKAY.
WAY TO GO, MAN. DROP YOUR RUCKS.
JUST HANG IN THERE. TAYLOR,
YOU'RE COMING WITH US.
PLEASE, DON'T GO.
YOU'RE GONNA BE OKAY.
COME ON! DOC, TAKE
CARE OF HIM, MAN.
REDLEG. REDLEG. RIPPER,
BRAVO TWO ACTUAL.
ADJUSTMENT FOLLOWS. GRID...
YOU IGNORANT ASSHOLE!
WHAT THE FUCK
COORDINATES ARE YOU GIVING?
YOU WASTED A LOT OF PEOPLE UP
THERE WITH YOUR FUCKED-UP FIRE MISSION!
YOU KNOW THAT?
AH, SHIT.
REDLEG. REDLEG.
RIPPER, BRAVO TWO.
CHECK YOUR FIRE.
THEY'RE COMING.
STAGGER YOURSELF
ACROSS THIS LINE.
SHOOT ANYTHING THAT MOVES.
THEY'LL BE COMING
FROM OVER THERE.
ANY ONE OF THEM GETS
THROUGH, WE'RE TRULY FUCKED.
WHERE IN THE HELL ARE YOU GOING?
DOWN BY THE RIVER,
ABOUT A HUNDRED METERS,
IN CASE THEY TRY TO FLANK US.
THIRD PLATOON IS COMING UP TO
OUR REAR, SO WATCH FOR THEM.
HEY, CAN I GO WITH YOU?
NO.
I MOVE FASTER ALONE.
COME HERE.
LET'S LET ARTY DO A
LITTLE BIT OF WORK HERE.
YOU TELL EVERYBODY TO
PULL BACK TO THE CHURCH...
AND LINK UP WITH THIRD PLATOON.
YOU GOT THAT? GOT IT.
WHAT ABOUT ELIAS? IF WE
PULL BACK, HE'LL BE CUT OFF.
YOU JUST HAUL ASS
TOO, LIEUTENANT.
I'LL GET HIM.
TWO ALPHA. TWO CHARLIE.
I GOT TWO OF THEM FUCKERS, MAN.
- I GOT ONE.
- HO CHI MINH
SUCKS DEAD DICKS!
CRAWFORD.
OH, MAN.
KISS MY ASS, MAN. I
NEVER THOUGHT I'D GET HIT.
IT'S A LUNG, BABE. YOU
GOT TWO OF THEM FUCKERS.
- WHERE'S ELIAS?
- SARGE, THERE'S A BUNCH
OF GOOKS CAME THROUGH THERE.
WE GOT THREE OF THEM FUCKERS.
HEY. DID YOU HEAR THE ARTY
SHIFT? WE'RE PULLING BACK.
NOW GET YOUR WOUNDED MAN
AND GET THE FUCK BACK TO CHURCH.
GET GOING. BUT ELIAS IS
STILL OUT THERE, SARGE.
TAYLOR, I'LL GET HIM.
YOU GET CRAWFORD IN. NOW, BEFORE
YOU ARTICLE 15 BOTH YOUR ASSES.
MOVE!
COME ON. MOVE IT.
WE STILL GOT YOU.
COME ON, BROTHER.
MEDIC, WHERE THE FUCK
ARE YOU? KEG IT, MAN.
OH, YEAH. YOU GOT IT. YOU'RE GONNA
BE ALL RIGHT IN A MINUTE, BROTHER.
OKAY, HOLD ON.
TAYLOR, WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
ELIAS IS DEAD.
FALL BACK WITH THE PLATOON.
GET GOING. HE'S DEAD?
YEAH. YEAH, HE'S BACK THERE
ABOUT A HUNDRED METERS.
YOU SAW HIM? WHERE?
HE'S DEAD. THERE'S GOOKS
ALL OVER THE GODDAMN PLACE.
GET MOVING.
LET'S GO. LET'S GO. LET'S
GO. COME ON. MOVE IT.
LET'S GO. LET'S GO.
MOVE IT. MOVE IT.
OKAY, LET'S GO.
YOU OKAY, HAROLD?
YOU'RE ON THE NEXT ONE.
YOU'RE OKAY, BUD.
OH, FUCK!
THEY'VE GOT ELIAS.
WHAT?
BACK DOWN. BACK DOWN THERE.
SNAKE ONE-NINER, FLY FOUR.
THERE'S STILL ONE ON THE DECK
DOWN THERE. BRING IN THE GUNSHIPS.
HOLD YOUR ARMOR.
GUNS, GUNS. PULL OFF.
WE'RE TRYING TO
COME AROUND MY SIDE.
HE KILLED HIM.
I KNOW THAT HE KILLED HIM. I SAW
HIS EYES WHEN HE CAME BACK IN.
HOW DO YOU KNOW THE
DINKS DIDN'T GET HIM?
YOU GOT NO PROOF.
PROOF'S IN THE EYES.
WHEN YOU KNOW, YOU KNOW.
YOU WERE THERE, RHAH. I
KNOW WHAT YOU WERE THINKING.
I SAY WE FRAG THAT
FUCKER TONIGHT.
I GO WITH THAT.
AN EYE FOR AN EYE.
I SAY LET MILITARY
JUSTICE DO THE JOB ON HIM.
COME ON. FUCK THE
MILITARY JUSTICE!
ARE YOU JOKING ME?
WHOSE STORY DO YOU THINK
THEY'RE GONNA BELIEVE? O'NEILL'S?
BUNNY'S? WOLFE'S? BULLSHIT!
YOU TRY THAT, AND BARNES WILL SHOVE IT
RIGHT BACK UP YOUR ASS WITH A CANDLE ON IT.
THEN WHAT DO YOU SUGGEST WE DO?
I SUGGEST, YOU ALL
WATCH YOUR OWN ASSES.
'CAUSE BARNES IS GONNA BE
COMING DOWN ON ALL OF THEM.
YOU JUST GONNA
FORGET ABOUT ELIAS...
AND ALL THE GOOD TIMES
WE DONE HAD RIGHT IN HERE?
SHIT, YOU'RE TRYING TO CURE THE
HEADACHE BY CUTTING OFF THE HEAD.
ELIAS DIDN'T ASK YOU TO
FIGHT HIS BATTLES FOR HIM.
AND IF THERE'S A HEAVEN...
AND GOD I HOPE THERE IS...
I KNOW HE'S SITTING UP THERE DRUNK
AS A FUCKING MONKEY AND SMOKING SHIT,
'CAUSE HE DONE LEFT
HIS PAINS DOWN HERE.
YOU'RE WRONG, MAN. ANY WAY YOU
CUT IT, BARNES IS A FUCKING MURDERER!
TAYLOR,
I REMEMBER WHEN
YOU FIRST CAME IN HERE,
TELLING ME HOW MUCH
YOU ADMIRED THE BASTARD.
I WAS WRONG. WRONG?
YOU AIN'T NEVER BEEN
RIGHT ABOUT NOTHIN'!
DIG THIS, YOU ASSHOLES,
AND DIG IT GOOD.
BARNES HAS BEEN SHOT
SEVEN TIMES, AND HE AIN'T DEAD.
DOES THAT MEAN
ANYTHING TO YOU? HUH?
BARNES AIN'T MEANT TO DIE.
THE ONLY THING THAT
COULD KILL BARNES...
IS BARNES.
YOU TALKING ABOUT KILLING?
HMM?
Y'ALL EXPERTS?
Y'ALL KNOW ABOUT KILLING?
I'D LIKE TO HEAR
ABOUT IT, POTHEADS.
ARE YOU SMOKING THIS SHIT
SO'S TO ESCAPE FROM REALITY?
ME, I DON'T NEED THIS SHIT.
I AM REALITY.
THERE'S THE WAY IT OUGHT TO BE,
AND THERE'S THE WAY IT IS.
ELIAS WAS FULL OF SHIT.
ELIAS WAS A CRUSADER.
NOW, I GOT NO FIGHT...
WITH ANY MAN WHO
DOES WHAT HE'S TOLD.
BUT WHEN HE DON'T,
THE MACHINE BREAKS DOWN.
AND WHEN THE
MACHINE BREAKS DOWN,
WE BREAK DOWN.
AND I AIN'T GONNA ALLOW THAT...
IN ANY OF YOU.
NOT ONE.
Y'ALL LOVE ELIAS.
OH, YOU WANNA KICK ASS.
YEAH.
WELL, HERE I AM,
ALL BY MY LONESOME.
AND THERE AIN'T
NOBODY GONNA KNOW.
SIX OF YOU BOYS AGAINST ME.
KILL ME.
HUH.
I SHIT ON ALL OF YOU.
YOU MOTHERFUCKER!
COME ON, MAN. GO. GET HIM!
GET HIM, CHRIS.
EASY, BARNES. DON'T DO IT, MAN.
YOU'LL GO DINKY
DAU IN L.B.J., MAN.
TEN YEARS FOR KILLING
AN ENLISTED MAN.
TEN YEARS. YOU'LL CLIMB
THE FUCKING WALLS, MAN.
DON'T DO IT.
DEATH?
WHAT DO YOU ALL
KNOW ABOUT DEATH?
THEY SENT US BACK INTO
THE VALLEY THE NEXT DAY,
ABOUT 2,000 METERS FROM
CAMBODIA, INTO A BATTALION PERIMETER.
IT FELT LIKE WE WERE RETURNING
TO THE SCENE OF A CRIME.
ALPHA COMPANY HAD BEEN HIT HARD
THE DAY BEFORE BY A SIZEABLE FORCE,
AND CHARLIE COMPANY HAD
BEEN PROBED THAT NIGHT.
THERE WERE OTHER BATTALIONS IN THE
VALLEY... WE WEREN'T THE ONLY ONES...
BUT WE KNEW WE WERE GOING
TO BE THE BAIT TO LURE THEM OUT.
SOMEWHERE OUT THERE WAS
THE ENTIRE 141st N.V.A. REGIMENT.
CAUGHT THOSE MOTHERFUCKERS TRYING TO PULL
SOME SHIT ON CHARLIE COMPANY LAST NIGHT.
THEY FOUND MAPS ON THEM, MAN.
GOT A FRIEND AT BATTALION.
SAYS THEY HAD EVERY
FUCKING FOXHOLE HERE FIXED ON.
DISTANCES, TREE LINES,
OUR CLAYMORES, EVERYTHING.
THIS IS BAD, MAN.
I GOT BAD VIBES HERE.
I ALSO HEARD WE'RE IN
FUCKING CAMBODIA RIGHT NOW.
CAMBODIA? MAN,
YOU'RE KIDDING ME.
YOU WANTED TO SEE ME, SIR?
YEAH, RAMUCCI.
LOOKS LIKE YOU GOT ELIAS'S
SQUAD NOW. SQUAD, SIR?
I DIDN'T KNOW WE WERE STILL REFERRING
TO THIS PLATOON IN TERMS OF SQUADS.
ALL RIGHT. LOOK. I WANT YOU
TO TAKE THOSE TWO HOLES.
RIGHT THERE AND THERE.
YOU'RE TYING IT OFF WITH
BARNES UP HERE, KING DOWN THERE.
YEAH. BEGGING YOUR PARDON, SIR,
MY TWO HOLES ARE
FAR ENOUGH APART...
YOU CAN RUN A REGIMENT
THROUGH THEM AND NEVER SEE IT.
I GOT FIVE LIVE
BODIES LEFT, SIR.
LOOK, I DON'T WANT TO HEAR
YOUR PROBLEMS, RAMUCCI.
YOU'LL GET NEW MEN ANY DAY.
MEANTIME, YOU MAKE
DO LIKE EVERYBODY ELSE.
I DIDN'T ASK FOR THIS JOB.
I DON'T WANT TO HEAR IT.
- OH, YOU DON'T WANT TO HEAR IT.
- YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT.
I DON'T WANT TO HEAR IT, 'CAUSE TO TELL
YOU THE TRUTH, I DON'T GIVE A SHIT, OKAY?
I JUST DON'T GIVE A
FLYING FUCK ANYMORE.
RIGHT.
I'M GLAD I AIN'T
GOING WITH THEM.
SOMEWHERE OUT THERE IS THE
BEAST, AND HE HUNGRY TONIGHT.
MOTHERFUCKIN' BUMMER.
TEN DAYS AND A WAKE-UP, AND
I'M STILL DEALING WITH THIS SHIT.
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH YOU, MAN?
HOW COME YOU AIN'T
WRITING NOBODY?
WHAT ABOUT YOUR FOLKS?
THAT GRANDMA YOU
WAS TELLING ME ABOUT?
GIRL?
YOU GOT A MOTHER AND FATHER,
DON'T YOU? THERE MUST BE SOMEBODY.
NAH, THERE'S NOBODY.
YOU'VE BEEN SMOKING TOO
MUCH OF THIS SHIT, TROOP.
GOTTA CONTROL THAT.
BRING A MAN DOWN.
I REMEMBER WHEN YOU FIRST
COME OUT HERE TO THE BUSH.
YOU WERE AS GREEN AS A...
DID YOU EVER GET CAUGHT IN A MISTAKE
THAT YOU JUST CAN'T GET OUT OF, KING?
THERE'S A WAY OUT
OF ANYTHING, MAN.
JUST KEEP YOUR PECKER
HARD AND YOUR POWDER DRY,
AND THE WORM WILL TURN.
HOW MANY DAYS YOU SHORT?
NAH, IT'S NOT JUST ME.
IT'S THE WAY THE
WHOLE THING WORKS.
PEOPLE LIKE ELIAS GET WASTED.
PEOPLE LIKE BARNES JUST GO ON
MAKING UP THE RULES ANY WAY THEY WANT.
SO WHAT DO WE DO?
SIT IN THE MIDDLE
AND SUCK ON IT.
WE JUST DON'T
ADD UP TO DRY SHIT.
WHOEVER SAID WE DID, MAN?
ALL YOU GOT TO DO IS
MAKE IT OUT OF HERE,
AND IT'S ALL GRAVY.
EVERY DAY, THE REST
OF YOUR LIFE... GRAVY.
OH, SHIT. SUPER-LIFER.
HEY KING, COLLECT UP YOUR SHIT.
YOUR ORDERS JUST COME THROUGH.
OH, LOOK, MAN.
DON'T FUCK WITH ME.
WHAT DO YOU NEED, A WRITTEN
INVITATION, FOR CHRISSAKE?
COCKSUCKER! OH, WOW!
THE LIFERS DONE MADE A MISTAKE.
THEY CUT ME SOME SLACK, TAYLOR.
GET YOUR PIG TO
RODRIGUEZ. YOU GOT TEN
MINUTES TO MAKE THE
LAST CHOPPER OUT OF HERE.
'CAUSE IF YOU'RE NOT ON IT,
I'M GONNA BE.
TAYLOR, FRANCIS IS COMING UP.
THAT'S GREAT KING.
I'M HAPPY FOR YOU, MAN.
TAKE IT ON HOME
FOR ME, OKAY? YEAH.
YOU GOT MY ADDRESS. YOU KNOW
WHERE YOU CAN GET A HOLD OF ME.
I GOTTA DI DI, MAN. I DON'T
WANNA MISS THAT CHOPPER.
WHEW.
YOU OKAY? YEAH, I'M OKAY.
REMEMBER NOW, TAKE IT EASY.
DON'T THINK TOO MUCH,
AND DON'T YOU BE NO FOOL.
REMEMBER, AIN'T NO SUCH
THING AS A COWARD OUT HERE.
DON'T MEAN NOTHIN'.
MY MAN.
I'LL WALK YOU OUT, MAN.
TAKE IT EASY, KING.
I'M GONNA TAKE IT ANY WAY I CAN
GET IT, BROTHER. I HEAR YOU. LATER.
MY FOOT IS FUCKED-UP, SARGE.
NO, MAN! DON'T TOUCH THIS!
I'VE GOTTA GET ON
THE CHOPPER, MAN.
SO WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
SAYS HE CAN'T WALK.
SHIT.
MARTIN, GET YOUR BOOTS ON.
AND THE NEXT TIME I CATCH YOU...
SPRAYING SKEETER REPELLENT
ON YOUR FUCKING FEET,
I'M GONNA COURT-MARTIAL
YOUR NIGGER ASS.
WELL, THEN COURT-MARTIAL
ME, MOTHERFUCKER!
BUST MY ASS! SEND ME
TO FUCKING LONG BINH!
YOU CAN DO YOUR FUCKING WORST!
YOU WHITE FOLKS HAVE GOT
YOUR LAST CLICK OUT OF JUNIOR!
O'NEILL, GET ME THAT CENTIPEDE.
SERGEANT? YEAH.
THAT LONG, HAIRY, RED AND BLACK
BASTARD I FOUND IN THE AMMO CRATE.
I'M GONNA PUT IT IN THIS BOY'S
CROTCH, SEE IF HE CAN WALK.
I REMEMBER NOW.
HEY! NOW HOLD UP, MAN.
YOU JUST HOLD UP
AND WAIT, ALL RIGHT?
FUCK IT. I'LL WALK. I'LL
FUCKING WALK, MAN!
FUCKING PUSSY, MAN. HEY, SARGE,
I GOTTA HAVE HIM IN MY HOLE?
YEAH. UH, BOB?
I'D LIKE TO SPEAK
TO YOU A MINUTE.
I CAN'T TAKE IT NO MORE.
I CAN'T TAKE IT ANY
MORE. BOB. BOB.
YEAH. WHAT IS IT?
BOB, I GOT ELIAS'S R &
R. IT'S IN THREE DAYS.
I WAS THINKING ABOUT GOING
TO HAWAII AND SEE PATSY.
HEY, BOB, COME ON. I NEVER
ASKED YOU FOR A FUCKING THING.
I WAS THINKING, MAYBE...
WELL, TO BE HONEST WITH YOU,
I WAS HOPING YOU'D PUT ME
ON THAT CHOPPER WITH KING.
WHAT DO YOU SAY
THERE, CHIEF-A-ROONEY?
NAH, I CAN'T DO
THAT FOR YOU, RED.
WE NEED EVERY
SWINGING DICK IN THE FIELD.
HEY BOB. TALK TO ME FOR
CHRISSAKE. SIN LOY, BUDDY.
ALL I'M ASKING YOU FOR IS
THREE FUCKING DAYS HERE.
I AM TALKING TO YOU, RED,
AND I'M TELLING YOU "NO."
SO GET BACK IN YOUR FOXHOLE.
BOB, I GOT A BAD FEELING
ON THIS ONE, ALL RIGHT?
I MEAN I GOT A BAD FEELING.
I DON'T THINK I'M GONNA
MAKE IT OUT OF HERE.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND
WHAT I'M SAYING TO YOU?
EVERYBODY GOT TO
DIE SOMETIME, RED.
OH, SHIT.
GOOD-BYE, MOTHERFUCKERS!
THAT'S THE FUCKING AMBUSH.
THEY AIN'T WAITING TILL LATER.
IT'S FUCKING COMING NOW, MAN.
RIGHT FUCKING NOW.
YOU KNOW, JUNIOR.
SOME OF THE THINGS
WE DONE, MAN...
I DON'T FEEL LIKE WE
DONE SOMETHING WRONG.
SOMETIMES, MAN,
I GET THIS BAD FEELING.
I TOLD THE PADRE THE
TRUTH. I LIKE IT HERE.
YOU GET TO DO WHAT YOU
WANT. NOBODY FUCKS WITH YOU.
THE ONLY WORRY YOU GOT IS DYING.
AND IF THAT HAPPENS, YOU
WON'T KNOW ABOUT IT, ANYWAY.
SO WHAT THE FUCK, MAN?
SHIT. I GOTTA BE IN THIS
HOLE WITH YOU, MAN?
I JUST KNOW I
SHOULDN'T HAVE COME.
DON'T YOU WORRY, JUNIOR.
YOU'RE HANGING WITH
AUDIE MURPHY HERE, MY MAN.
BRAVO THREE. BRAVO THREE,
BRAVO SIX. SEND ME A GRID. OVER.
I CAN'T SIR. WE'RE PINNED DOWN.
THEY'RE IN THE FUCKING TREES.
OKAY, THREE ALPHA.
NOW, CALM DOWN, SON.
I'LL GET YOU A FIRE MISSION
ASAP. SMOKE WILL BE FIRST.
LIEUTENANT'S DEAD. RADIOMAN LOOKS
DEAD, SIR. I DON'T KNOW WHERE THE MAP IS.
THEY'RE ALL AROUND US, SIR.
MOVING IN... HUNDREDS OF THEM.
I CAN HEAR THEM TALKING GOOK.
OKAY, THREE ALPHA. NOW SPOT THAT
SMOKE AND TELL ME WHERE TO SHIFT.
JUST CALM DOWN, SON. HANG
IN THERE. WE'LL GET YOU OUT.
JUST TELL ME WHERE
THE ROUNDS HIT. OVER.
THREE ALPHA, SIX. HOW
ABOUT THOSE ROUNDS, SON?
CAN YOU ADJUST FIRE? OVER.
THREE ALPHA, SIX. IF YOU CAN'T TALK,
SON, JUST KEY YOUR HANDSET TWICE. OVER.
SHIT.
TRIP FLARE. RODRIGUEZ'S HOLE.
R.P.G.
DOC! TAYLOR. FRANCIS.
OVER HERE, MAN.
WHAT THE FUCK'S GOING ON?
RODRIGUEZ'S HOLE JUST GOT NAILED, MAN.
HERE IT IS, MAN. WE GOT GOOKS
IN THE FUCKING PERIMETER.
AW, SHIT. THAT'S IT. THEY
GOT THROUGH ALPHA COMPANY.
ANYTHING BEHIND YOU THAT DON'T IDENTIFY
ITSELF, FUCKING BLOW IT AWAY, OKAY?
AIR STRIKE'S COMING IN.
THEY'RE GONNA BE
LAYING SNAKE AND NAPE.
DON'T GET OUT OF YOUR FUCKING
HOLES. STAY RIGHT HERE, MAN.
FUCK.
THEY'RE PROBING US.
THEY'LL GO DOWN THIS LINE ALL
NIGHT TRYING TO GET THROUGH.
ALL RIGHT, STAY HERE. STAY
COOL. I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
WHISKEY, FOXTROT, FOXTROT.
ECHO, WHISKEY. OVER.
WHO IS IT?
DON'T SHOOT! DON'T SHOOT!
IT'S THE AMBUSH.
OVER HERE, MAN. HURRY!
OH, SHIT. WATER.
THEY'RE ALL OVER THE PLACE.
HUNDREDS OF THEM, MOVING THIS WAY.
THEY WIPED US OUT, MAN.
WE DIDN'T HAVE A CHANCE.
WHERE'S THE C.P.? BACK THERE.
YOU GUYS GET OUT OF HERE. THEY'RE RIGHT
ON MY ASS. THEY AIN'T STOPPING FOR SHIT!
HEY, TAYLOR, MAN, LET'S DI DI.
YOU GO.
THERE.
NOW HOLD IT. HOLD IT.
OUT OF THE HOLE! FAST!
GET OUT OF THE FUCKING
HOLE! THEY'RE GONNA BLOW IT!
LET'S GO! LET'S GO!
FOR FUCK'S SAKE...
FRANCIS, MOVE YOUR FUCKING
ASS! THEY'RE GONNA BLOW IT!
FOLLOW ME.
YOU MOTHERFUCKERS!
DIE, YOU MOTHERFUCKER!
IT'S FUCKING BEAUTIFUL!
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
COME ON, MOTHERFUCKERS.
COME ON! YOU CAN
DO BETTER THAN THAT!
THEY JUST KEEP COMING,
MAN! FUCK THIS SHIT!
GET BACK HERE, YOU GUTLESS SHIT!
THEY'RE USING
R.P.G.s IN OUR SECTOR.
ZIPS INSIDE THE WIRE. I
REPEAT, ZIPS INSIDE THE WIRE.
WE NEED ILLUMINATION IN
THE NOVEMBER SECTOR ASAP.
ALL RIGHT, GET ME
BRAVO RIGHT AWAY.
CHARLIE COMPANY REPORTS HAND-TO-HAND
ON THE PERIMETER. THEY NEED HELP.
OKAY, GET TWO SQUADS FROM ALPHA
DOWN THERE RIGHT AWAY. GO. GO.
WHERE IS THAT
GODDAMN AIR STRIKE?
HEY, YOU PEOPLE. WHERE
THE FUCK ARE YOU GOING?
CAN'T YOU GET ANYBODY?
GODDAMN IT. NEGATIVE CONTACT.
I CAN'T RAISE BARNES, TWO
BRAVO, TWO CHARLIE, NOTHING.
- GET ME SIX.
- BRAVO SIX. BRAVO SIX.
- IT'S DOC.
- PARKER'S HIT. GET HIM IN.
THEY'RE COMING THROUGH
ALL OVER. I CAN'T DO ANYTHING.
WHERE'S BARNES? SHIT, HE'S
DEAD. I THINK THEY'RE ALL DEAD!
GIVE IT UP, DOC. HE'S DEAD.
SIX, L.T., SIX.
CAPTAIN... CAPTAIN, WE'VE BEEN
OVERRUN. WE'RE PULLING BACK. OVER.
GODDAMN IT, LIEUTENANT. WHERE
ARE YOU GONNA PULL BACK TO?
THEY'RE ALL OVER THE PERIMETER.
NOW, YOU BE ADVISED. YOU WILL
HOLD IN PLACE AND YOU WILL FIGHT.
THAT MEANS YOU,
LIEUTENANT. BRAVO SIX OUT.
BE ADVISED, WE GOT ZIPS
IN THE WIRE DOWN HERE.
UH, ROGER YOUR LAST, BRAVO
SIX. CAN'T RUN IT ANY CLOSER.
WE'RE HOT TO TROT AND PACKING SNAKE
AND NAPE, BUT WE'LL MAKE OUR FUEL.
FOR THE RECORD, IT'S MY CALL.
DUMP EVERYTHING YOU'VE
GOT LEFT ON MY POS.
I SAY AGAIN, EXPEND
ALL REMAINING...
IN MY PERIMETER.
IT'S A LOVELY FUCKING
WAR. BRAVO SIX OUT.
ROGER YOUR LAST, BRAVO
SIX. WE COPY. IT'S YOUR CALL.
GET THEM IN THEIR
HOLES DOWN THERE.
HANG TOUGH, BRAVO SIX. WE ARE
COMING COCKED FOR TREETOPS.
BARNES!
NO!
GET ME A MEDIC.
GO ON, BOY.
DO IT.
LOOK OUT, MAD DOG. WE'VE GOT
LIVE GOOKS AT THREE O'CLOCK.
WHAT'S DOWN HERE? LET'S GO.
COME ON, ELMO. MOVE
YOUR FLEA-BITTEN ASS.
HEY, YOU OKAY? YOU ALL RIGHT?
CAN YOU WALK? HUH?
HEY, DOC! WE NEED
A MEDIC UP HERE!
COME ON, ELMO. COME ON,
DOC. WE GOT WOUNDED HERE.
MAN, THAT MUST HAVE
BEEN SOME FUCKING FIGHT.
YOU ALONE HERE, MAN?
YEAH.
THE BUNCH OF FUCKING
FAGGOTS. THEY ALL LEFT ME.
A HUNDRED AND TWENTY-TWO
WOUNDED AND STILL COUNTING.
ESTIMATE 500
VICTOR CHARLIE K.I.A.
A HUNDRED TWENTY-TWO
AND STILL COUNTING. OVER.
- HEY TAYLOR. THAT YOU?
- HEY, FRANCIS.
HEY, MAN. HOW YOU DOING?
I'M OKAY. HOW YOU DOING?
FINE, MAN. JUST
FINE. HEY, DIG IT.
WE TWO-TIMERS, MAN. WE
GONNA GET OUT OF HERE, BOY.
I'M GONNA SEE YOU
IN THE HOSPITAL.
WE GONNA GET A
HIGH HIGH. YES, SIR.
SERGEANT O'NEILL.
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
I'M JUST FINE, SIR.
WELL, THAT'S GOOD 'CAUSE
YOU GOT SECOND PLATOON.
YES, SIR.
YOU READY? YOU BET.
I THINK NOW, LOOKING BACK,
WE DID NOT FIGHT THE ENEMY.
WE FOUGHT OURSELVES,
AND THE ENEMY WAS IN US.
THE WAR IS OVER FOR ME NOW,
BUT I WILL ALWAYS BE THERE...
THE REST OF MY DAYS,
AS I'M SURE ELIAS WILL BE,
FIGHTING WITH BARNES FOR WHAT
RHAH CALLED POSSESSION OF MY SOUL.
THERE ARE TIMES SINCE...
I HAVE FELT LIKE THE CHILD...
BORN OF THOSE TWO FATHERS.
BUT BE THAT AS IT MAY,
THOSE OF US WHO DID MAKE IT
HAVE AN OBLIGATION TO BUILD AGAIN,
TO TEACH TO OTHERS WHAT WE KNOW,
AND TO TRY WITH WHAT'S
LEFT OF OUR LIVES...
TO FIND A GOODNESS
AND MEANING...
TO THIS LIFE.