NO) In the wake of
the Nicaraguan Revolution...
...chaos has descended on El Salvador...
...in Central America.
Today 18 people were killed
and 36 wounded in a fierce gun battle...
...between anti-government
demonstrators and the police.
It started when students, workers,
and peasants linked to the guerrillas...
...occupied foreign embassies
and took over the cathedral in the capital.
(knock at door)
NO) In two months, more than
3,000 people have disappeared.
Government spokesmen attribute this
to left-wing Marxist terrorists...
...while left-wing spokesmen
point to right-wing death squads.
- (woman) You cannot walk in like this!
- (man) You got some money for me? No?
- I have no money!
- I want you outta here. You understand?
- No, we cannot move out.
- Lady, I put up with this shit every month.
I want you, your crumb-snatcher and your
war hero - or whatever the fuck he is -
...I want him outta here.
Fuck your husband! You got no bucks.
Look, no bucks, no Buck Rogers, Boyle!
Just wait till I've had my coffee.
You're disturbing my kid.
- You gotta fix your bitch, Boyle.
- Shit on your paper!
(swearing)
(Sobs)
(Boyle) Good morning.
I've had it!
I cannot live like this no more!
- Hey, Nancy, hi. It's Richard. Listen...
- Richard who?
Boyle. Richard Boyle. Yeah. Listen, I think
it's gonna blow in El Salvador real soon.
If you could get me a new press card and
two grand, I could get some good stuff.
- No Way.
- OK. Well, how about a new press card?
- Forget it.
- Come on, Nancy. Please, man.
We've had it with you. We gave you $2500
on that Lebanon gig and you ended up...
I can't take Muslim nightlife, OK?
- Hey, Alice. How you c:loin'?
- You lose tickets, passports.
You drink too much
and you're a genera! embarrassment, Boyle.
I get you the piece. How about that thing
on the IRA tortured by the Brits in Belfast?
And how about Cambodia?
The last man out, you know.
Sidney Schanberg was having cocktails
at the Plaza. I was gettin' my ass kicked.
How about freezin' my fuckin' nuts off
for you guys in the Khyber Pass?
I got giardia. I was staple-gunned
to the toilet for a week.
- How about El Salvador?
- How about El Salvador? How about it?
- Didn't I call that one?
- Boyle...
- Hey, come on.
- Come on what? Get the fuck outta here.
Not you. Nancy? Nancy, I'm sorry.
Nancy? Nice work, you piece of...
Thanks for my camera,
but I need another favour.
I gotta be at the airport
in an hour for Beirut.
Look, this is serious.
I need one for old times' sake.
You gotta give me 500 bucks
to go to El Salvador. 400 if...
- They'll kill you if you go back.
- I need the money, not a lecture.
OK. 300 bucks.
I'll meet you at Pan Am in 40 minutes.
Great! Here, take the quarter.
In such a fuckin' hurry.
(Siren)
Shit!
Mr Boyle, your license has been revoked.
You're driving without a license,
registration or insurance.
You've got four outstanding
speeding tickets all gone to warrant.
- You've got 43 unpaid parking tickets.
- Jesus!
Nothing is legal about your oar.
- And even your press card is out of date.
- Out of date? Goddamnit.
- I'm taking you in.
- No. I'm not that Richard Boyle.
This... happens all the time.
There's another Richard Boyle.
- Give me your other hand.
- Have some humanity, will you? I just...
- Doc, man, thanks for gettin' me out.
- Come on, get your car.
Look, man, they got Bagel. The Nazis
busted Bagel. He's in dog Dachau.
- Get your car.
- I don't have it. I need 75 bucks to get it.
Shit! I just paid 125 to get you out.
- Stop whining.
- Here. This is all I got.
Now come on before they drop the pellet.
- It's a fuckin' dog.
- It's my dog.
- Faster, Richie.
- I can't, man. I don't even have a license.
They'll throw the key away.
How long's he been there?
I don't know. I left him with some friends.
Yeah, shit friends.
It's not like they're gonna
gas the poor dog, OK?
Man, everything's turned to shit.
Miriam's thrown me out, man.
She says I'm too old to be
a rock'n'roll disc jockey.
She wants me to sell computers
in Silicon Valley. Can you believe it?
I can't take these yuppie women. With
the Walkmans and the running shoes...
...and the 'rather go to the aerobics jazz
class than fuck'. Forget about it.
- They got those pussy exercises, too.
- Latin women, they're different.
They're kind, understanding.
Look at Claudia. She's the greatest.
She doesn't give a shit what I do. Primo.
Best thing about Latin women
is they don't speak English.
Listen, can I crash at your place tonight?
I got no place to go, man. I'll sleep
in your shower. I need a home, man.
You better light up another joint, Doc,
cos I got some bad news for ya.
(Boyle) I don't got a place. We're evicted.
We were gonna stay with you and Bosco.
You mean I gave you my last
200 bucks and I got no place to stay?
That's great. Now what am I
supposed to do, man?
(Doc) I'm in deep shit, you know that?
I should've just left you in jail.
- (Boyle) I'd have stayed in jail.
- (Doc) Move over, move over!
(Boyle) Another yuppie
in a fuckin' Oldsmobile.
(Doc) This town is full of goddamn yuppies!
(Doc) Yuppie town!
Bagel! Bagel?
- Where's my dog?
- What's he look like?
- Oh. Yeah. I know this dog.
- Where is he?
- Bagel?
- Excuse me. Sir! Excuse me!
- Bagel, come here, boy.
- No, that's not your dog. Excuse me.
We had to put your dog to sleep.
We keep the dogs around 14 days.
- We kept him more than 14 days, but...
- You put him to sleep?
- Yeah.
- When's he gonna wake up?
- You killed him. You gassed him.
- No. We gave him an injection.
- It's much more humane, so you don't...
- What kind of humanity is that?
You're a murderer, you know that?
I can't believe it.
That was my only relationship.
My best friend. Seven years.
My marriage only lasted five.
- It's just not just!
- I'm really sorry.
Would you like some puppies?
We got a lot of puppies.
- My dog's leash.
- I'm sorry.
Doc, man, she can't do anything.
Come on. OK? All right?
- (Doc) What's it say?
- (Boyle) "Fuck you" in Italian.
Shit! She's gone back to Italy
to her parents. Goddamnit!
That's too bad, Richie.
Well, at least she left the TV.
It was a marriage made in hell.
I'm sure gonna miss my boy.
Maybe she'll be back.
(Doc) Sure. Who could leave all this?
- (Doc) Where are we goin' now?
- (Boyle) Guatemala.
- Why?
- Why not?
No cops, no laws, sun.
It's cheap. No yuppies.
Great dope.
(Boyle) Look at you. You are like
a walking museum of the '60s.
(Doc) What the fuck are you?
(Boyle) I am a forward-thinking human being.
(Boyle) I know about life. I explore things.
In journalism, you're in touch with reality.
(Doc) You come off with this
journalist bullshit all the goddamn time.
You know that?
(Doc) I haven't seen one goddamn article
that you've written.
(Boyle) I wrote a book,
"Flower of the Dragon".
(Doc) That was ten years ago, Boyle!
- (Boyle) Expose'. It was a big exposé.
- (Doc) Ten years ago.
- (Doc) What have you written since?
- (Boyle) I've written articles.
- (Doc) What articles?
- (Boyle) One in a newspaper in El Salvador.
(Doc) The one in El Salvador? Oh, yeah,
I read that. My whole family read that!
(Doc) Everyone saw that article, Boyle!
(Doc) You said Guatemala, man.
You didn't say anything about El Salvador.
I've never been out of the country.
- They kill people here.
- You believe everything in the papers?
You're gonna love it here.
Give me the joint.
Look, Doc, this is my last chance.
If I can get some good combat shots,
I can make some money.
- So I can pay you back.
- You better pay me back.
Then we'll go to La Libertad,
the best surfing beach in the world.
Kick back for a few months. Be fantastic.
You could live in this country
for 300 bucks a year.
- What the fuck is this?
- Mace.
- Mace for what?
- Wild dogs.
Wild dogs. That's bullshit, Boyle!
- You've lied to me straight through.
- Want me to be honest with you?
No. What the hell you doin' with all these?
Here you could have
a semblance of a life.
- What are all these?
- Give me one. They come in handy.
- You're gonna love it here, Doc.
- I'm goin' home, man.
You can drive drunk,
get anybody killed for 50 bucks.
- I don't wanna kill anyone for 5O bucks.
- The best pussy in the world.
Where else can you get a virgin
to sit on your face for seven bucks?
Seven bucks.
Better be the best pussy in the world,
or I'm goin' home.
- Two virgins for 12.
- You're just lucky I'm fucked up, Boyle.
Drugs, no prescriptions. They got stuff
that keeps you hard all night long.
- All these people wanna do is fuck.
- 12 bucks?
- I think we can get 'em down, don't you?
- Now you're talkin'.
You're such an asshole, Boyle.
You're gonna love this place. Ha!
You're gonna be in pig heaven, man.
(Doc) Why are they blockin' the road?
(Boyle) Stop asking why.
This ain't gringo-land.
Take this. Be dumb, act cool, all right?
- What is this? A tranquilliser?
- A permanent one: cyanide.
- I'm not taking that shit.
- You're gonna be sorry...
...when they out off your balls
and stuff one in each ear.
You're so fuckin' dramatic, man. Jesus!
(Doc) Who are these clowns?
- (Doc) What the fuck...?
- (Boyle) Traffic accident.
(Doc) Jesus, Boyle!
(Doc) Oh, God, man!
(Boyle) Would you relax? It's just some guy.
(Boyle) Shit. Hola, amigo. como va?
(In Spanish) The road to Santa Ana is closed.
(In Spanish) I understand...
...but Colonel Figueroa told me
to give a present to you boys.
(English) Because the road's closed.
They're journalists.
(Boyle) No.
No. Get out of the car.
Si, si, si, se-or.
Whatever you do, Doc, whatever you do,
OK, don't get on the ground.
Jesus Christ. This is fuckin' scary.
- Que' trae?
- No, trae nada.
What?
(In Spanish) You! What's happening?
- They're journalists.
- Bring them to me.
Journalists?
Yo estoy...
- ...esta bien?
- Si.
(In Spanish)
I'm a friend of Colonel Figueroa...
I wrote an article.
- Friends of Figueroa's.
- I'm a friend of Figueroa's.
(In Spanish) Take them.
Is that bad?
(In Spanish) Let's go.
He's a friend of Figueroa's. I was...
$hut up!
(Talking in Spanish)
(Doc) What's goin' on here, man?
- I think they're checking cedulas.
- What's a cedula?
Birth certificates, voting papers. If you
don't have a cedula, you're in deep shit.
(Calls soldier)
(Speaks in Spanish)
(He asks soldier to take prisoners)
Doc, put your hands on your head.
(In Spanish) What's going on?
(In Spanish) We've stopped a truckload
of suspicious campesinos.
(Prisoner) Pleading in Spanish
He's probably a student.
That's the worst thing you can be.
(In Spanish) - Where are your papers?
- At home. I can take you there. Please Sir.
- Let's go. Fast.
(Shouts in Spanish)
(Boyle, Spanish) Look, I'm a friend
of Colonel Figueroa's.
Where the fuck are they takin' us?
I should've never have bailed you out.
- Who are your friends? Communists!
- No, I'm alone.
Take off your glasses.
Shit!
Holy shit! They're gonna
fuckin' kill us now, Boyle.
Goddamnit! I thought you knew your way
around here. They're gonna fuckin' kill us!
- They're gonna fuckin' kill us!
- Stop it! Shut the fuck up! Just be cool!
I don't know what the fuck
they're gonna do!
This is it.
You got any of those tranquillisers left?
(soldiers chanting)
He)', Boyle!
How the hell did you get in here?
- No fuckin' period/stars are allowed.
- I snuck in through Guatemala, Colonel.
You're a damn bastard! You're lucky
you've still got your huevos.
- But you look like shit!
- Grac/as.
Come with me. (Speaks Spanish).
You wash up. You wash up.
You have some drinks, some food.
My amigo here, he write me up
in the American newspaper...
...like the Patton of El Salvador.
You were, Julio. It was the last
great cavalry charge in history.
Your soccer war with Honduras, '69.
All the way to Tegucigalpa.
Not since Attila the Hun have there been
such amazing cavalry tactics.
And this one takes it up the cu/0 real nice.
How about this one?
Does she take it up the cu/0 too?
All right!
Libertad, Doc. End of the rainbow.
I'm sick. My asshole hurts. My dick burns.
(Doc) I don't know how to say this, it's
really been fun travelling with you.
(Doc) I need to catch a plane
out of this place.
(Boyle) You think you're gonna die?
I got the best doctor in town for you.
You have nothin' to worry about
once you meet the broad.
(Boyle in Spanish)
A little of this, too. And this?
We'll put that in, too.
Esto? In el culo?
- It's a joke.
- I'm sick. What the hell's she laughin' at?
Nothin'. She's puttin' everything in there.
It'll clean you out or it'll kill you.
- What about a subscription?
- All you need is an ass. See you later.
Don't pay her anything.
I got credit here. I gotta run.
That's the biggest fuckin' needle
I ever saw! Just give me a fuckin'...
Ow! Son of a bitch!
Sigan, por favor.
Sigan.
(In Spanish) I'm going over there.
Siga.
(orders in Spanish)
I'm going over there.
Ricardo! Ricardo!
(Boyle greets in Spanish)
Did you miss me? Did you miss me, huh?
Very pretty girl.
They said you were dead.
Where's her father?
Disappeared.
Shall we go to your house?
You still drunk? You still crazy?
No. For you I stopped. No more alcohol.
Shall we go to your house?
(In Spanish) It's a magic car.
And this is for you.
Monster!
Do you like this? A television.
OK, Duglas. Come on.
I'll see you at the casa, huh? OK.
At the casa we see the television
(In Spanish) I know you have
another woman in the north.
Another woman? No.
That's over. The other woman.
You're the only one.
Come on. Venga. Por Favor.
(Toad croaks)
(Boyle) Are you, Major Max?
(Speaks Spanish)
(Both speaking Spanish)
Ricardo, back from the dead!
Come estas, eh?
- I like your friend. Dr Rock.
- (Boyle) Dr Rock, e/ medico.
- How bad is it here, huh?
- If I had one of those I'd be better off.
You gotta be goodlookin' and rich.
Yeah, well, my ass hurts.
- Hey, Ricardo, can I have some?
- Yeah. Go ahead.
- Guatemala, no?
- Yeah, yeah. Guatemala gold.
(Doc) Buena caca.
(Boyle) So, Doc,
(Boyle cont.) you wanna be back
in San Francisco?
(Doc) I'm tellin' you, man, everywhere
I turn, just dogs screwing other dogs.
(Doc) Pigs in the street. It's like Baltimore
or somethin', for Christ's sake.
- (Doc) How are we for cash?
- (Boyle) You hungry? Wanna get a hamburger?
(Doc) Maybe just one
before you take me to the airport.
(Doc) I got a life there,
even without Miriam.
I bailed you out of jail. You've owed me
a lot of money over the years.
I wish you'd pay me so we can,
like, part company, you know?
- John. I thought I'd find you here.
- I thought you were dead.
- Dead? Why, do I look that bad?
- Yes.
I heard stories from Guatemala.
They were pullin' your toenails out.
Fuckin' Guatemala. Jesus.
How was Beirut?
- Fuckin' awful.
- Really?
- You gonna eat those fries?
- No, no. Dr Rock, John Cassady.
- That was a great cover for Newsweek.
- Thanks.
So what happened?
How come you split so fast?
From here? I had a little beef
with Major Max's boys.
They weren't too happy about
that torture-chamber story. Waiter!
Major Max? Who's Major Max?
This guy is after you, too,
on top of everything else?
That was a year ago. They don't have
yuppie computers down here.
I'm gettin' outta here. First plane,
I'm outta here. I'm not kiddin' this time.
I've had enough of this shit.
I want my money, Boyle.
- What money?
- The money you owe me. I'm serious.
- No bullshit.
- You've been on valiums too long.
There is no money. The transmission
in Guatemala, gas, whores.
How about the border rip-off?
We had 7O colones.
You know how many we got left?
12. 12 colones, all right?
- How much is 12 colones?
- Four bucks. Three bucks.
- Three American dollars?
- Yeah.
You're tellin' me that's all we got left?
My dog is dead, Boyle!
You know why... Stop doing that!
You know why he's doing that?
This is why. Cos he drinks Tic Tac.
It's 17 cents a bottle, OK?
You can't get rid of the guy. He'll follow
you anywhere. Wanna go to Beirut?
- Tell me what it has to do with me.
- It's your liberal, yuppie bullshit.
It's nothin' to fuckin' do with me, man!
I'm stuck in this country,
I can't speak the language...
...I got the shakes,
and I only got three fuckin' dollars!
I gotta get outta here, man!
Fuck you, Boyle! Fuck you!
Fuck you. Fuck you. Fuck you!
He was this hitchhiker
I picked up in Guatemala.
You know.
- Look, John, I'm really sorry.
- It's on Newsweek.
Look, I'm gonna be honest with you.
I got fired by PNS.
I could use a string down here real bad.
- Could you help me out?
- There's no work here for you.
- Nobody cares about the stinkin' war.
- I care.
They're not just shootin' the Indians.
Last week a Mexican TV guy got
blown away by their paramilitary groups.
They're shootin' at us.
- Why don't you try Angola?
- There's no nightlife.
I can get you out with Figueroa, John.
I got carte blanche with his elite unit.
- You still got the deathmobile.
- Come on, Boyle.
Wanna go out on a little dawn patrol?
Or are you too big
of a media star these days?
Let's go.
(EL PLAYON,
Dump site for death squad victims)
You haven't looked through a lens
in a while, have you, Rich?
Come on, take some pictures.
There's fresh bodies up there.
John, have you got a 24
or a 28 I could use?
You know what made photographers
like Robert Capa great, Rich?
They weren't after money.
They captured the nobility
of human suffering.
That was a great shot in Spain.
The one flying through the air.
Yeah, but it was
more than the bodies, Richie.
He got... why they died.
That's what Capa caught.
He caught that moment of death.
You're right up there with him, John.
You're in his league. You're the best.
You gotta get close, Rich, to get the truth.
You get too close, you die.
Someday I want a shot like Capa.
Someday.
John, I gotta go, man.
We gotta go.
I don't have to tell you
to watch yourself, do I, Rich?
Alvarez's people are staked out
at the cathedral nowadays.
I'll talk to him for you.
And Tom Kelly's the new ambassador.
- Tom Kelly from Cambodia?
- You should check him out.
I know him. He's a good man.
There's a party at the embassy
on Tuesday for the election.
John,thanks.
Cambodia was somethin', wasn't it?
(RAMON ALVAREZ,
Director of Human Rights Office)
(Comforts woman in Spanish)
(Shouts in Spanish)
(MAIN CATHEDRAL, San Salvador)
What's goin' on here?
This is where people
find out about their Disappeared.
Eh, amigo, que pasa aqui?
- What did he say?
- They were kicked off their land...
...by the police so they're here on strike.
- I saw that in Zapata.
Carmen. Carmen!
Carmen Sanchez. Hey, it's Ricardo.
- Richard!
- How are you?
- Como estas? Como te Va?
- Muy bier). Grac/as.
- Donde esta Ramon?
- Ramon esta por aHa.
Ramon.
Ramon. Did John Cassady talk to you
about my going out with the guerrillas?
Ramon... (speaks in Spanish)
(Boyle) Ramon, I need a break real bad.
I did a good story on you last year.
Look, Boyle, I'm not
a travel agency for you guys.
I know that. If Major Max takes power,
you people could use some good press.
Good press? There are 10,000
Disappeared and every day the list grows.
And you, pendejo, talk about good press!
No.
Ramon, I... I got some shots this morning.
Maybe they can help you. From El Playon.
- And I'm sorry, OK?
- (Carmen) Thanks, Richard.
(In Spanish) To the mountains?
Richard.
- Come back next week. I arrange it.
- Thank you, Carmen. Grac/as.
Sister Stan? Hi. How you doin'?
- Fine. Good to see you back.
- Good to see you.
- Cathy's around here somewhere.
- You look awfully busy.
Parents missing, dead, lost.
These are some of the survivors
from the massacre up at the river.
Government helicopters opened up
as they were crossing.
It's very bad now. Very bad.
Madness on both sides.
Cathy Moore. The prettiest colleen
in all of El Salvador.
Boyle, what are you doing here?
Back to see your old girlfriends?
- You ruined all that by converting them.
- I try.
- I'm goin' to La Libertad. Need a ride?
- I can't. I got too much to do around here.
Fudge! It's the wrong piece.
This is for an elbow!
I told Cleveland. This happens
every goddamn time. They promised me.
Come on, now, Cathy.
We'll have another shipment next month.
Anisetta can wait. Can't you, darling?
Ready? One... two...
...three... four... five.
Now you can go to any urban city
and you can make it.
Right?
(TV) Try to halt the infiltration
into the Americas...
...by terrorists and
by outside interference...
...and those who aren't just aiming at
Ei Salvador but I think are aiming at...
...the whole of Central,
and possibly later South America...
...and I'm sure eventually North America.
Can you believe that
a straight man to a chimpanzee...
...is gonna be the next
president of the United States?
- Doesn't that depress you?
- You are starting to depress me.
- I can accept that.
- I can't. I'm tryin' to make some money.
How am I gonna do that
with you yakkin' and hobblin' around?
Just go get somethin' to eat
or go to the pool or meet some girls.
Stay outta my face! Yakkin' all the time.
- Boyle? I thought you were dead.
- Morgan.
Takes more than wishing.
What brings you down here?
- Colonel Hyde?
- Colonel Hyde, Richard Boyle.
You don't remember me, sir?
Pacific News Service.
- And this is Bob Samuels, USA ID.
- How do you do?
- Millicent Davies, USAFL-CIO.
- Hello. How are you?
- Remember me, sir?
- Yeah. I remember.
Last time I heard about you
was when Thieu kicked you out.
But then Mr Thieu got kicked out
after me, didn't he?
I never understood why you guys
like the commies so much.
We guys.
If you were Vietnamese, you'd be working
in a re-education camp pulling turnips.
I never really liked
turnips very much, Colonel.
And I'm not applying for
Vietnamese citizenship.
They don't like
that funny stuff you smoke.
Why, you got some? Colonel, let me
ask you something. It's a big favour.
You think you could get me out
on a Cazadore op? Is that possible?
If I get you out...
...what's in it for me?
- These guys never change, do they?
- Vietnam. You know, Vietnam.
I mean, are we gonna
invade here or what?
I don't know what you're talkin' about.
I was kinda young during all that.
Look, I'm not supposed
to talk to the press, OK?
And you're weird, so fuck off.
I'm not the press.
- You wanna go out with the guerrillas?
- I'll go out with anybody.
I'll go outwith the National Guard,
the muchachos. Want a drink? Yeah.
Something big's in the wind.
Rebels are getting weapons from Nicaragua.
They're gonna make a move,
so any photos you can throw my way...
- We can make life real easy for you.
- That stuff's hard to prove.
- And I hate doin' that.
- I'm not asking you to spook.
Show me your pictures first.
You'll publish them anyway.
They're gettin' their stuff from the black
market in Miami, government troops.
Last year.
This year Castro's got 'em organised.
I'm not messin' around.
This is all Warsaw bloc stuff now.
Jesus. Same old Black Jack Morgan.
Yeah, well, you're not gonna think it's
all one big joke when they take this place.
Nicaragua was just the beginning.
Guatemala and Honduras are next.
In five years you'll be seeing
Cuban tanks on the Rio Grande.
Give me a break. I'm more worried
about Major Max on the Rio Grande.
Major Max may be running things here
pretty soon, so you better watch yourself.
- Jesus. Could you lend me 5O bucks?
- What?
- 5O bucks.
- Tom. Tom Kelly, Richard Boyle.
Ambassador Kelly, hi. I'm Richard Boyle.
PNS. I was the last man outta Cambodia.
After Schanberg. I wrote "Flower of the
Dragon". I'm a friend of Cathy Moore's.
- Nice meeting you.
- Let me just ask you one thing.
Does this Reagan thing pose a problem
for you? I'll just grab a couple of shots.
General, have you met Mr Boyle?
Hello. Nice to meet you.
Boyle. Hi. Thanks.
Boyle. Mucho gusto.
(over nflcrophone)
ABC has projected the next president.
Ronald Reagan.
Peter, I gotta do a standup at ten
boiling all this down.
Well, you could say "With Reagan in the
saddle, the guerrillas are in deep shit."
That's lovely, Peter, but have you seen
the Journal today, by any chance?
It's real rah-rah democracy,
free elections.
I think that's what the networks
are gonna want tonight.
So what's your sign?
- Stop.
- That's really cute.
I thought it was "slippery when wet".
This article and you, Pauline, are 100
per cent and unequivocally full of shit.
Look who's talking!
You and your friend are so full of shit.
- I resent you, of all people...
- I resent what we saw in Santa Ana.
What was that?
A kid shot in the head and hung from
a tank because he didn't have his cedula.
- Know what a cedula is?
- Yeah.
If you're gonna analyse the situation,
analyse it right.
You don't have a cedula
on election day stamped, you're dead.
Democracy. What kind of democracy is it
when you have to vote...
...and if you don't vote
you're branded a Commie subversivo?
People would vote for Donald Duck
or whoever the local cop tells them to...
...because if they don't,
this is what happens.
You're a real fuckin' pro. That's why you
can't last two weeks with the network.
Yuppies. Do a standup from the Camino
Real and think they got the whole story.
"My Two Weeks in El Salvador"
by Pauline Axelrod.
"Whoring and Drinking My Way
Through El Salvador" by Richard Boyle.
Blow-job queen of New York.
Executive suites wall-to-wall.
No wonder you get
your glamour puss on the networks.
Excuse me.
- Look, Pauline...
- Fuck off!
Just be a sport, will ya? I'm an asshole.
I'm an asshole, all right?
Well, you don't have to worry about her.
She's gonna boil down
real good on that roof.
I put 500 mikes of acid in her drink.
- Are you serious?
- Yeah.
With Ronald Reagan
sweeping the elections...
...here at the Camino Real Hotel...
(through megaphone)
Ronald Reagan has been elected president.
(Major Max) Finally we have someone
in the White House with balls.
Yes. The time has come...
...for us brothers.
Former members of Orden.
Patriots of the Maximiliano
Hernandez Brigade.
And brothers of La Mano Blanca.
These fucking priests that are poisoning
the minds of our El Salvadorian youth...
...are gonna be the first to bleed.
They are pigshit.
And this Romero
is the biggest pigshit of all.
A shitfaced desecration of an archbishop.
And with this bullet,
he will be the first to die.
For every one of our people,
we will kill one hundred of them.
We will avenge the deaths...
...of the South African ambassador...
...of foreign minister
Mauricio Borgenovo...
...of Roberto Cuoma, of Colonel Rosario...
...of Gutierrez and Molina,
and of the mayor of El Paraiso.
These subversives that have sold our
country out to the Communists will die.
Erlich, Zaun, Kelly, Duarte,
et cetera, et cetera.
And these pseudo-journalists sent here
by the Zionist-Communist conspiracy...
...to divide and confuse our people...
...they will die.
Now...
Who will be the one...
...among you...
...to rid me of this Romero?
You will be famous.
(TV) As you Well know,
I stand for nationalism...
“law and order, and economic prosperity.
More important, I stand for Church...
...family, and a peaceful Salvador.
Go with peace.
There you go. You like that?
Your tab is way high.
You owe me 400 colones.
- I'm runnin' a restaurant, not a bank.
- I know.
OK? I got an NBC radio gig in the works,
a CNN feed with Cunningham tomorrow.
I'm hot again, OK? Have I ever stiffed you
in ten fuckin' years? Come on.
- I'll pay you the whole thing next week.
- OK. Don't tell Elena. She'll kill me, man.
Besides being a prince, do you think
you could throw in 100 colones cash?
Come on. I don't wanna look like a jerk.
- You're doin' this to me again.
- I'll make it a 750 even.
OK, man.
(TV)..the masters of deception.
Christian Democrat green on the outside.
Moscow red on the inside.
(In Spanish) What a clown!
(In Spanish) Please, Carlos, sit down.
(Boyle) hey, hey.
Carlos. Carlos. Roberto, come on.
Sit down, huh?
Come on. This isn't funny. Come on.
Sientasan, eh?
Fuckin' sit down.
(In Spanish) It's getting dangerous here.
(In Spanish) Yes. We're living in a bad time.
Like 1932 again,
I detect a bad feeling in the air.
- Boyle. Boyle.
- Yeah.
This stuff's like white lightning.
You keep drinking that stuff, you're gonna
end up in the street beggin' for bottles.
(In Spanish) You and your friends
are real clowns.
Why don't you entertain us some more?
- But you'd look better without your balls.
- I'll out yours off if you don't watch out.
Who are you, huh? Get off the fuckin' car!
Hey, hey, hey! Hey, shut up, Doc.
Muchacho cabron.
(In Spanish)
How about some beers for everybody?
(Sings) V/vas la v/da momento a momenta
Get in the car, Doc. Cervaza Suprema/
Cerveza de qualidad.
Get in the car, Doc.
(In Spanish) Let's go to the beach.
I got my pickup truck.
Me with you? Not even to church.
Why don't you ask your mother?
Hey! Hey, hey, hey!
Hey, what are you doin'?
Jesus!
Amigo, cerveza.
Cerveza suprema. Cabron.
Get in the car. Doc, get in the car.
Cerveza, amigo.
No es problema. Es tourista.
Where'd you get
all those marks on your face?
Couldn't keep your hands off
the old blackheads in high school, huh?
Doc, get in the car.
Americana, tour/sta stup/do.
Excusa me, amigos.
Buon gusto con Ias cervezas.
(Shouting in Spanish)
OK. Cerveza! Viva sa Vida.
Momento a momenta.
un re/oj para m/s amigos.
(a watch for my friends)
No es problema.
You can drop me here.
Where are you going?
(In Spanish) I'm going up with the guerrillas
in the mountains.
- What will your parents say?
- She knows.
It's not safe here any more.
I 90, OK?
You gonna join them?
Va ya con D/os, amigo.
In my country, amigo,
there is no more God.
(Maria) They took Carlos and Dr Rock!
They saw the marijuana!
I'll take care of it. Go in the house.
I'll take care of it. Maria.
You have to do something.
It's my brother!
I know he's your brother! Now get in
the fuckin' house! I'll take care of it!
Fuck!
Perdon e, sen ores.
Es para e! capitain.
Buenas noches. Buenas noches, senor.
Coma esta usted?
El Capitain? Es para usted, Senor.
- No, no, no, it's OK.
- Senor, it's OK?
- Buenas noches.
- Es para usted.
- (Doc) Boyle, get me the fuck outta here!
- If you wanna live, Doc, shut up.
Que pasa?
(In Spanish) They're marijuanos. Subversives.
Esto?
Es bueno. Si, es verdad.
Guapo. Es verdad.
Mira. Mira.
- Que? Es para mi?
- La television de Dr Rock.
Si. Es para usted.
Es Iibro? Si? El gringo?
Doc, just get outta here. Go, man. Go.
(In Spanish) And this one?
No, he's a bad kid. No respect.
He stays here. Or you stay as well.
Es para mi!
El otro no?
Carlos, just say cool, man.
I'll get you out, OK?
- Hello, Cathy. How are you?
- Fine.
- You look a little tired.
- No, I'm fine.
- Ambassador Kelly. Richard Boyle.
- Good to see you again.
- You remember me from the party?
- I do.
I'm sorry. I had actually written
two articles about you in Cambodia...
...just before the fall of Phnom Penh.
I was the last American journalist out.
Schanberg was chasing his Pulitzer prize.
I was almost getting cholera but we saved
1100 refugees from the Khmer Rouge.
- Terrible what they did to that country.
- Yes, sir, it was.
Were you one of the people writin'
'em up as the good guys for a while?
Yes, sir. I'm afraid I was wrong on
that one. But a lot of people were.
If these guys in the hills took power...
...the Pol Pot incident
would look like a picnic.
Are they as bad as Major Max
and the Mano Blanca?
I don't know. We got
a pathological killer on the Right...
...God knows what on the Left,
and a gutless middle.
Anyway, Boyle, about your problem here.
Carol checked with the National Guard,
the police, the regular army.
Nobody seems to know
anything about this boy. We think...
With respect, Ambassador, they're lying.
He didn't just disappear. Nobody just
disappears in El Salvador. They got him.
- Have you checked with Human Rights?
- The Human Rights Office?!
They rearranged this kid's molecules
and they took their time!
He is dying out there while
we're talking. He's just a kid!
- He's just a kid!
- Richard...
- Richard, please calm down.
- I'm sorry.
Ambassador, look. His sister is
my girlfriend. She's on the shit list.
I gotta get a cedula for her. They could
come tonight, take her away and kill her!
Richard, Richard!
That doesn't have anything to do with us.
You know the laws of this country.
She's gonna have to go back to her home town.
- Where's she from?
- Morazon. She can't get near there.
If she does, the guards'll kill her
as a suspected G. Fuck!
All right. I'll do the best
I can, but it's very tough.
There are thousands of people in this
predicament. Everybody wants a cedula.
Let me ask you this.
- What if I married her?
- Richard, you're already married.
Sir, I know you're very busy.
Thank you very much.
But that's in the States.
Suppose I just married her?
- I'll do whatever I can.
- Thank you, sir.
- Maybe you could talk to immigration?
- Just let me see what I can do.
We want to see you
at the Christmas party.
Maybe I could keep in touch with you
and we could talk over some ideas?
- I give up on you.
- What do you mean, you give up?
- Every time I get...
- He liked me, this guy.
- What's goin' on?
- I gotta get a cedula for Maria.
Maria.
Maria, they can't find Carlos yet,
but the American ambassador is involved.
The thing is, though,
you are in great danger.
Without a cedula, they can grab
you at any time, comprende?
So I've been thinking about something,
and what I think we should do...
Marry me.
What?
We could have a family together.
Duglas, Reina, you and me...
- And Carlos, what about him?
- And Carlos too, when we find him. Si?
- You already have a wife.
- No, no. That's been over for six months.
I got a divorce. I never told you.
- Hi, Boyle!
- Just a second.
- Hey, Peter.
- Atlanta's gonna give you a shot!
- No!
- If you fuck up this time...
Not a chance. That's great, Peter. Thanks.
Right. Well, I want
some real stuff on the Gs.
- Sure you're set with Alvarez?
- We're like this.
OK. You got a camera, the crew and
the Arena press conference tomorrow.
- Right. Major Max.
- He's gonna declare for president.
I'm going to Venezuela,
so you'll have to cover for me.
That's great! Listen, could you
lend me 50 bucks, man? I'm a little low.
You don't change, do you, Boyle?
Let's see what we've got here...
Get out of it!
- 200 of them. You owe me.
- 200 colones.
- Out of my own pocket...
- Right.
- ...so no whores.
- OK.
- Do a good job, Boyle. See ya.
- You're a mensch. You're great.
- Entonces, si or no?
- No.
Por que no, mi amor?
- Soy una mujer Chato/ica.
- So what?
- I can't marry a divorced man.
- Oh, God!
And you, Richard,
are a bad Catholic in all ways.
How am I a bad Catholic?
- You're living in sin.
- No, no, no, I'm not.
- You drink.
- OK, once in a while I drink.
You sleep with many women.
- You smoke marijuana.
- That was Rock's.
And you lie. You scheme and scam.
What is good or decent about you?
What redemption can you expect?
Well, none, I guess, but look...
OK, you got a point.
I am a fuckin' weasel, there's no doubt.
But think about this.
If I went to church - I haven't been in 3O
years - but if I went and took confession...
If we took Communion together...
redemption. That would be great.
We could go to Archbishop Romero.
He likes me very much.
I could become a lay Catholic worker.
It'd be wonderful. I could get a basket...
I feel good about this. This redemption
thing is good. I feel cleansed already.
- You want some of this?
- No. No more marijuana.
I'm gonna talk to Archbishop Romero.
Maybe he could annul
my marriage to Claudia.
She was a Commie atheist anyway.
I'm gonna talk to him about this seriously.
Very good man. He's a man of the people.
He's a man of God.
They say he's gonna win
the Nobel peace prize.
Hey, what's this?
Another demonstration, Boyle?
Calm down. Take it easy.
Stop! Stop, please!
I have orders to evacuate the plaza
in five minutes. Do you understand me?
I have permission.
- Why don't you stop the repression?
- No matter. Five minutes or violence.
Why don't you do something
about the disappeared?
Violence! You understand me?
Stop the repression!
Do you follow in the way of Christ?
Not exactly. I mean, in my heart, yes...
...but I've done a lot of, you know...
...cardinal sins and I've drunk a lot
of alcohol and done some drugs.
I've weaselled around a lot in my life,
trying to get the edge...
...but basically I would say
that I'm a good-hearted person.
I haven't really done anything
malicious in my life.
I haven't done anything
very great in my life either.
I tried to do some things,
tried to find some truths.
And I do love this woman.
For her, I could...
- Are you willing to change for her?
- For her, yes.
I mean, not just... I would...
If God gave me this woman...
...then there must be a God.
So, if he knows what's right,
then I would do what's right by him.
Just repent. Change your ways.
That's gonna be a little tough.
You love this woman,
you will be willing to change.
OK. I can still drink and take a few hits
of a joint once in a while? That's OK?
Twelve Our Fathers, ten Hail Marys,
an act of contrition.
That's it?
Ask the Lord for forgiveness...
...from your heart.
From my heart?
If I'd known this, I would have
come earlier, before 33 years.
- You should have come earlier.
- I'll come back.
Next time, don't wait so long.
(In Spanish)
The governing junta has good intentions
with their promises of land reform...
...and their desire to control the so-called
paramilitary forces in the army.
But, sadly, it is a failure...
...because the power
within the junta is the army...
...and the army itself is an
obstacle to the reign of God.
They know only
how to repress the people...
...and defend the interests
of the rich oligarchy.
I have called upon
the United States, repeatedly...
...to stop military aid to this army...
...until it satisfactorily resolves
the problems of the Disappeared...
...and submits itself to civilian control.
When a dictatorship seriously
violates human rights...
...and attacks the common good
of the nation...
When it becomes unbearable
and closes all channels of dialogue...
When this happens, the Church speaks...
...for the rights of the victims
of the violence!
We are poor.
The people in Washington are so rich.
Why are they so blind?
My children.
You must look to yourselves...
...in this sad time for Salvador.
I wish to close with an appeal
to the men of the army...
...and in particular, the National Guard.
Brothers, you are a part of your people.
Yet you kill your own
brothers and sisters.
But before a man may kill,
the law of God must prevail.
And that law says "Thou shalt not kill".
No soldier is obliged to obey
an order against the law of God.
Violence on all sides is wrong.
Violence is wrong.
In the name of God, and in the name
of this suffering people...
...whose laments rise to heaven
each day more tumultuous...
...I beg you, I ask you...
...I order you in the name of God...
...stop the repression!
(murmuring)
(Organ music)
(priest gives blessing)
(curses 'm Sparflsh) Pisado! Hijo de Puta!
(screaming)
(gunfire)
Esta muerto.
(In Spanish) Arrest him for the murder
of Archbishop Romero!
(through microphone) You W/// note
I did not agree with the bishop.
He sometimes got carried away
with his politics.
He did not understand
that with the Left in power...
...there will be no Church in this country,
and he will be out of a job.
But in my book, it was the subversives
that killed him. No question!
To provoke this atmosphere, this chaos.
(Boyle) It is rumoured that you
are the head of the death squads...
...terrorising the country.
Would you care to comment?
Los escuadrones de Ia muerte.
- I think you're pressing your luck, Boyle.
- Nice goin'.
I really resent that question.
Fuck off.
Why do you never ask
the communists this?
They are not the only victims.
We have victims, too.
Senor, there are
no death squads in El Salvador.
The outrage of the people
against the Communist threat...
...cannot be stopped
or organised by anyone.
(Pauline) Sir! Sir, the polls show you
trailing the Christian Democrats.
Are you sure you can still capture
both the Catholic and the woman's vote?
That's bullshit.
Do you mind? I'm gonna buy it
for my sister. That's great, huh?
Here he comes.
Mr Gomez! A question, please!
(In Spanish)
Get that piece of shit out of here!
(Gomez curses in Spanish)
Come on! What are you
gonna do about it?
- Gomez!
- Think about your image.
I'm gonna cut your balls off, Boyle!
Do it yourself!
Hi, are you guys from Washington? Huh?
You're a real pro, Boyle.
Doc! Where's Maria?
Boyle! Boyle!
- They found Carlos, man.
- Where?
He's fucked up. Over there, man.
He's really fucked up bad.
- Maria, please.
- Don't touch me!
- It's not my fault! He was acting stupid.
- Because of you he changed!
(In Spanish) Since you arrived
I have nothing but problems!
(Boyle) It wasn't my fault!
Great goin', Boyle. Have a drink.
Damn it.
I really love her, man.
She and the kids are the only decent thing
I ever fuckin' had in my whole life.
I don't know why I'm livin' any more.
Come on.
(Boyle belches)
- All I got is ten.
- 15.
Come on! I was only in there for five
minutes. The guy kept interrupting me.
I would have been outta there faster
if he didn't interrupt me. All I got is ten.
OK, ten.
Aie!
- (Cathy, assuring girl in Spanish)
- Si.
Aie!
Un mas, pero Tic Tac, por favor.
No, no. Yo page en dos menses.
' 'Prom/s/0 ' '.
- You asshole.
- Interest 50%. 50% interest.
You know what you just said? You said
you'd pay her in two menstrual cycles.
Mama Monch, este reloj, eh?
2,000 dolares Americanos, eh?
Por un Tic Tac y dos cervezas eh?
Dos Cervezas!
Feliz Navidad.
Carmen.
José.
I'm sure you don't need it,
and I can't say I approve...
...but Merry Christmas, Richard.
Oh! Get over here. Get over here.
Get over here!
Oh, Richard.
Cathy, talk to Maria.
I gotta get Maria back.
Talk to Father Paul. She'll listen to him.
Richard, you're 42 years old. You're old
enough to be her father. Forget her.
- I'm in love with her!
- I love you, Richie.
Father Paul has to follow
the papal orders. There's...
Agh!
I hate that. I hate when you do that.
So much. I...
- What about your other wife and kid?
- She left me. She took my kid.
So what are you gonna do?
Bring Maria back to the States?
What's she gonna do up there, Richard?
Sell snow cones on Fisherman's Wharf?
Down here, she has a purpose,
she has a reason.
- In gringo-land, she's a fish out of water.
- I know...
And besides, asshole, you don't have
enough money to support her or your kid.
I need to talk to you about my whole life.
It's such a mess. I'm disgusting!
Richard, what are you doing here?
- You're not making it as a journalist.
- I'll make it again.
I will make it... again.
The white hand has been
painted on the parish-house wall.
The altar boy is dead.
And the fuckin' Peace Corps
has moved out.
I love it here.
I just can't go back.
I know. I love it here, too.
- Will you have dinner with me?
- No.
- Tomorrow night?
- No. I really can't.
Besides, you smell.
I gotta go to the airport tomorrow.
Two of the nuns are in from Nicaragua.
- Sometime?
- Maybe.
OK, you... you be careful
on that road to the airport, OK?
Yeah.
Wait a minute. I'll walk you to your car.
Merry Christmas, Richard.
- You be good.
- I will.
I don't trust you.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye.
Oops.
Gringo.
What do you say you and I take
a walk down by the beach, gringo?
I'm not going to the beach with you.
And I'll tell you something else.
I'm not only a fuckin' Irishman, I'm a...
I'm a fuckin' Viking.
I'll take as many of these creeps
to fuckin' Valhalla as I can!
(In Spanish) Stop. I want this asshole alive.
You got a big mouth, Boyle. Major Max
is the person for you. Come to the beach.
Come on, cocksucker! You're gonna have
to kill me. You ain't takin' me alive!
Agh!
(Shouts in Spanish)
You wanna play a fuckin' game, Boyle?
Yeah.
OK. First I'll take your arms.
Then I'll take your legs.
Then I'll take your balls.
Sounds like a fun game?
Deialo! Dejalo!
OK, Cocksuckers.
How do you like these odds, huh?
Por favor.
(In Spanish) He's worthless.
You are an important man.
A photograph for me, please?
OK.
Gracias.
Bueno.
Enough!
Let's go. We'll take care of him later.
Gracias.
Boyle, I'll be back for you.
P/nch/ gringo, marijuana cabron!
(laughs)
Up yours, too, Jack.
There we go.
- How was Nicaragua?
- Oh, bad. There's no gasoline.
People have to line up
for hours to get their food.
The war has been very destructive.
But on the other hand, there's been no
political execution of the Somazastias.
I can't believe this. Looks like police.
Get your passports ready, sisters.
(Siren)
We have done nothing.
I am a very good friend
of Ambassador Kelly.
You're going to be in a lot of trouble
when he hears about this.
The fiesta is just beginning, hey?
Vamos!
(Pauline) The bodies of four American women,
missing since Tuesday...
...were found here today
in a roadside grave...
...25 miles east of San Salvador.
The victims were identified as...
I just heard that five guards did it for
15 colones and a bottle of Tic Tac each.
They got this clown, the mayor,
to sign the death certificates.
- Will he talk?
- Not if we can't keep him alive.
- What are the chances of that?
- Slim to none, and he knows it.
He had no business signing
death certificates without an autopsy.
I want one now, and I wanna know if
those bullets are rebel or government!
You knew Cathy pretty well, didn't you?
What do you think? Rumour has it
they may have run the roadblock...
...and there was an exchange of gunfire.
- The doctors won't do it because they...
- They don't have the surgical mask.
OK, pal. OK. All right!
(In Spanish) Why don't they
have their surgical masks?
I'm recommending we cut off all aid.
Sir, they were coming in from Managua.
They were Communist-oriented.
Maybe they got spooked at the roadblock.
Maybe they were packing,
and it got out of control.
Pistol-packing nuns, my ass!
I knew Cathy Moore.
You can't sell me that shit.
Sir, General Garcia has assured me
of a complete investigation.
That's great. We'll let the fox
investigate the chicken coop.
You must think I'm pretty stupid.
I know all about you. Reagan's little
transition team came here last month...
...to talk to Major Max without checking
in with me. It's all going in my report.
Whatever you did, you gave a clear signal
to the Arana people, and it resulted in this.
(Spanish) We want to do a real in-depth
and sympathetic portrait...
For the first time,
our four armies are united.
We now control the northern third
of Chalatenango province in the west...
...and Morazon province in the east.
We're asking government troops to join
our offensive, and the people to rise up.
We will take all major cities:
Santa Ana, San Vicente, San Miguel.
Then San Salvador will fall.
- When, Captain?
- Before Reagan.
Then you think you're ready?
With 4,000 troops, take all of El Salvador?
The odds are the Pentagon
won't let that happen, sir.
The will of the people and the march
of history cannot be changed.
Not even by the North Americanos.
- (In Spanish) What does it say?
- Leticia cleans her gun.
- Be careful on your way out of here.
- Don't worry. I've been doing this a while.
- Thanks, huh?
- OK. Bye-bye.
This doesn't show much.
I really stuck my neck out for you, Boyle.
You're not too popular around here.
Where were these taken?
I can't tell you that.
But it's mostly old stuff:
...shotguns, bolt-action rifles,
captured Belgian FLNs...
...120 Mike-Mikes ripped off
government troops.
- Any anti aircraft stuff? Any SAMs?
- Nothing.
- Buenos dias, Guillermo.
- Buenos dias, Jorge.
OK, so what about it? How about
a cedula for my woman and her two kids?
There's not much here,
or you're not telling us everything.
- What about recoilless rifles, RPGs?
- They're in shit shape. They get nothing.
When are you gonna
believe what you see...
...and not what military intelligence
tells you to think?
We got AWACS, infrared, statements
from a detecting FRAN commandant...
...and enough military intel to prove...
...that this ain't civil war,
but outright Commie aggression.
You guys have lied about
that from the beginning.
You have not presented one shred
of proof to the American public...
...that this is anything but
a legitimate peasant revolution.
So don't preach to me
about military intelligence.
Not after Chile and Vietnam.
I was there, remember?
- I personally resent that kind of shit.
- Then resent it, OK?
You lied about the number of advisors
here, about the trainers here on TTY...
...about switching
"humanitarian" assistance money...
...to Salvadoran military coffers.
You said this war can be
won militarily. It can't.
- Of course it can!
- Calm down, Boyle. I'm sorry.
I'm not listening to this wino
journalist's left-wing Commie crap.
We know where his sympathies lie.
I don't even see why we're talking to him.
Look, Richard. You saw Marti.
- We know they're starting an offensive...
- Hey!
I'm not a fuckin' spy for you guys.
Left wing, Colonel? Well, maybe.
But I'm not a Communist.
You guys never ever seem
to be able to tell the difference.
I love my country as much as you do.
You are the ones who trained Major Max
in the Police Academy in Washington.
You trained Jose Medrano and
Rene Chacon. You trained them...
...how to torture and kill. You sent them
here, and what did Chacon give us?
He gave us the Mano Blanco.
What are the death squads
but the brainchild of the CIA?
- You run with them, they're anti-Moscow.
- Bullshit!
You let them close the universities,
wipe out the best minds here...
- Bullshit!
- ..wipe out the Catholic Church.
You let them do it
all because they aren't Commies.
And that, Colonel, is bullshit.
You've created Major Frankenstein.
- We can control him.
- Like you control the Major Maxes...
- Well, look who's here.
- ..in Chile and Guatemala and Argentina?
What about Pol Pot and Castro?
Are they any better?
Pol Pot and Castro?
I don't know if they're better.
All I know is that some campes/no
who can't read or write...
...or feed his own family,
has to watch his kid die of malnutrition.
Do you think he gives a shit
about Marxism or capitalism?
It was that kind of thinking
that lost us Vietnam, this guilt shit.
You liberal assholes! What the hell
do you think the KGB's doing?
Is that why you're here?
A post-Vietnam experience -
you need a rerun or something?
You pour 120 million bucks
into this place...
...turn it into a military zone,
so you can have chopper parades?
- You're blowin' it out your ass.
- You just bring misery to these people.
I don't wanna see another Vietnam. I don't
wanna see America get another bad rap.
I lost my hearing in this ear over there.
What did I do that for?
$15 a photo from Pacific News Service?
I did it because I believe in America.
I believe that we stand for something.
For a constitution.
For human rights - not just for a few
people, but for everybody on this planet.
Jack“.
...you gotta think of the people first.
In the name of human decency, which we
Americans are supposed to believe in...
...you gotta at least try
and make a just society here.
Look, Richard,
it's all part of our national plan.
We do do a lot of good down here.
I'm often asked by people like yourself
to examine my conscience.
- Every now and then, I do examine it.
- What do you find, Jack?
That whatever mistakes
we make down here...
...the alternative would be ten times worse.
Maybe I'll just forge
a cedula for my girlfriend.
They're on the house.
Boyle!
There's something that you should know.
My Salvo counterparts
are mighty pissed...
...about muy ma/o per/od/stas
going out with the terrorists.
If they can catch one of 'em,
they'll make a lesson out of him.
I'll get out of your hair, OK? Just get me
a cedula for my girlfriend and her two kids.
Getting a cedula for your whore
is the least of your problems.
Personally, I don't give a shit
if they kill you or not.
I happen to hate the species
you belong to.
But I'm telling you, they're serious.
If I were you, I'd get my rubber shoes on
and get to the airport.
You're gonna fit in here really well,
you know that?
You sound just like another gangster.
Dumb fuck!
A panning shot for the beginning
of the interview, OK?
(Pauline) Could you tell me
your name, please?
(Soldier) Sorry, we can't speak to the press.
Thank you, Private. Appreciate it.
- Can you tell me your name, please.
- I'm sorry, ma'am. I cannot.
- How about saying where you're from?
- OK. Long Island, New York.
Thanks. Welcome to El Salvador.
What do you think so far?
It's not bad, but I'm anxious
to watch the Giants game.
- Know where a TV is?
- I dunno. Maybe you'll get a hold of one.
Excuse me, Colonel.
Hi. I'm from A&S News.
Can you tell me if this signals a build-up
of US combat troops in El Salvador?
Ma'am, these are not combat troops.
They are trainers, officially authorised
by Congress. I have no further comment.
Thank you, sir. This is Pauline Axelrod,
A&S News, San Salvador.
Listen. You've got one thing going for you.
Maria still cares about you. She does!
If I were you, I'd straighten out my act
and go back to that woman on my knees.
Doc, please.
All right. Just trying to help you.
DQC!
- Wilma, hi! How are you?
- Fine.
- Boyle, did you meet Wilma?
- Hola.
- Wilma from the Panama Club?
- Yeah. She's straightened up her act.
Hey, look at this. Bagel II.
- Like the dog?
- That's great, Doc.
- Come on...
- She wants to take me shopping.
- Can you do something about the drinks?
- Yeah. A couple of bucks...
- What's this?
- She had a long career.
Thanks, Doc.
- Hey, Rich! You still got your wheels?
- Yeah.
The G's just hit Santa Ana.
- Wait! John! I gotta stop in La Libertad.
- No.
- I gotta see Maria.
- Then go without me.
- All right. Come on.
(honks horn)
(Spanish) Can we take photos?
Go ahead, yes.
(gunfire)
Son periodistas!
Periodistas!
Periodistas! Don't harm us'.!
Que pais?
- Que pais?
- Periodistas! Estados Unidos!
John!
Look.
John. John, wait!
Wait! John!
John!
- You fuckin' fool! You're not that magic.
- Today I am, Boyle.
The Sandinistas have entered the war.
Major equipment is being unloaded.
- Possibly troops, too.
- Any backup on this?
There's no time. Santa Ana has fallen,
and the country's split in half.
The situation is deteriorating faster than
expected. El Salvador will fall in 48 hours.
24. Their air force
has got no ammo, no gas.
We either restore military aid now
or go to phase three.
The 82nd Airborne is on alert...
...and the Marines are in position
on the Ranger.
- What do you wanna do, sir?
- I won't get steamrollered into anything.
- Now, substantiate this Nicaraguan stuff.
- Sir, we can't. That would take days.
Sir, if we don't give
the order to evacuate soon...
...I can't be responsible for the safety
of the embassy or the American community.
Tom, we all know you'll be leaving here
in a couple of days. That's not the issue.
The issue is do you want
to go down in the history books...
...as the man who lost El Salvador?
That's hardly the issue here.
We're talking about human lives here!
We're not playing some computer game.
Jesus, history books!
GQd!
The line is dead, sir.
Where the fuck are the Americans?
Sir, you have a decision to make.
All right.
OK.
I'll recommend that we restore
all military aid.
Give the order to release
the fuel and armaments at Ilopango.
Yes, sir.
(Spanish) Figueroa's coming!
Figueroa's broken through.
They're coming! Tanks!
Don't let Figueroa pass!
I'll hold the front.
- What about the prisoners?
- I'll take care of them.
- My 120's fucked up.
(engine approaching)
Tanks?
- Panhards.
- Shit.
John, can you lay
two more rolls of Tri-X on me?
(gunshot)
(In Spanish) No pictures.
This your sense of justice?
(Spanish) It's necessary.
Get them out of here.
You've become just like them!
It's war! If you don't have
the stomach for it, get out!
(In Spanish) I never hurt anybody!
Please, in the name of God...
(gunshot)
You've become just like them!
Fuck!
Can you believe this?
John!John,no.
John!
John!John!
Oh, Jesus. God! Oh God, John.
(machine-gun fire)
Don't move. Don't move. Don't move.
Breathe out. Breathe out.
Can you breathe? Can you breathe?
Can you breathe? OK.
I got the... I got the shot, Boyle.
You got the shot.
- Take it to New York.
- I'll get it to New York.
Got it.
Oh, God. Oh, Jesus. God.
John, you got the magic shot.
You got it. You're the best.
We did it, didn't We? We did it.
Come on, man. Don't wipe it
on your thing. Clean it.
- Rich, you OK? You all right?
- Give me a valium, will ya? Anythin'.
- Here. I got somethin' for you.
- Papa, que pasa?
Here. There's two.
Goddamn, it looks horrible.
Hey, where are you goin'?
Where are you goin'?
Oh, great. Is that OK?
It's all right. It'll be all right.
Look, I got some good news for you.
Look what I got.
The bruja gave me some cedulas
for Maria and the kids.
She did a pretty good job, man, really.
And look. I got your exit visa forged, too.
She kind of fucked up on that, but I think
it's gonna be all right. I think it'll work.
- Good.
- Look, you gotta get outta here, man.
The police were at Roberto's
last night lookin' for you.
They said you were
in the country illegally.
Roberto said he thinks you're dead.
So you got to get outta here.
OK.
When we get there, hang back.
If there's any trouble, call Kelly.
If Kelly's gone, Morgan'll help.
- Got it?
- OK. I heard you the first time.
Doc, I'm tellin' you, take care of yourself,
man. Don't stay here too long.
- Hey, come on.
- They kill people here.
What? You believe everything
you read in the papers?
- I'll miss you, Doc.
- Yeah, yeah.
Shit. Yeah, I'm gonna miss you, too.
Is that my watch? Give it to me.
I'll need it at the border.
You cheap son of a bitch.
You say hi to gringo-land for me.
Adios, hasta Iuego. Via con... dos.
- Vaya con Dios.
- (Doc) Vaya con Dios.
You guys be careful.
Jefe!
- Que pasa?
- Cheque esto, jefe.
It's fake.
All right. Look, I'm not gonna bullshit you.
It was a rush job.
I have to get back to America.
I'm a very important journalist.
Newsweek. Understand? Newsweek.
Time. CBS. Big shots.
Importante.
Per/od/sta importante Americana.
(Maria pleads in Spanish)
Maria, Maria.
- Where's he going?
- Te/efono.
Capital.
God. I have an important
appointment in the capital...
...with Ambassador Kelly
and Mr Jose Duarte.
Why don't you hold that? And, um...
A donde vas?
(Continues in Spanish)
(Spanish) Check this bastard's cases.
I'm a big fan of the Raiders, actually.
- He's got loads in here.
- Check the cameras.
The ambassador. You know,
United States embassy. Hello? Hello?
(Boyle) Mira. Am/go de Major Max.
(In Spanish) I like the White Hand a lot.
(Sings) Tremble, tremble, Communists.
With the instincts of animals.
The Mano Blanco doesn't hate you.
But you make trouble for Mr Gomez.
- Gomez is a friend of mine.
- That's why he wants you dead.
(In Spanish) Shut up asshole!
What's in your boots?
Do not move bastard!
Oh, God. Not that film!
That's the best war film of the year!
Shut up asshole!
Cassady died getting it,
you motherfucker!
Fuck you! He died getting that film!
Fuck you! Fuck you, Cocksuckers!
Boyle is about to fuckin' die.
And if he does, man, if he does...
...your next job'll be in Redonda
counting fuckin' spears! Understand?
Get the fuckin' ambassador
on the phone now!
A qui. A den fro.
Me gustan Ios huevos rancheros.
OK, I'm not kidding.
I got $50,000 in traveller's cheques.
They're hidden, like,
two kilometres from here.
You lie, stupid gringo.
(In Spanish) Do not fuck with me.
Don't castrate him in here.
You'll make a mess.
(Guards arguing in Spanish)
Yeah, well, you tell General Martinez that
I am still the ambassador for another day.
I want those people outta there now
or I'll make it the worst day
of his fuckin' life.
Fuck it. Let's get it over with.
(cocks gun)
(Clicks)
Chinga to madre, que pasa con este
Are you kidding?
(In Spanish) It's not working.
Why didn't you clean it?
- It's not my fault boss.
- It is not my rifle.
(cocks gun)
Chinga tu madre.
Pedro! Cometiste un error.
No ha hecho nada.
(In Spanish, explaining)
Hap/do!
Muchas gracias.
A little American trick here.
You know what that means?
It means you're all stupid Cocksuckers.
Vamos a brindar
por los huevos rancheros.
I hope you get anal herpes.
Next.
- Where have you been, sir?
- Just to Nogales for the afternoon.
- Did you take the roast out of the oven?
- Yes, honey. I took care of it.
- When are we going to Disneyland?
- Disneyland. I don't know. Next month.
- This kid is spoiled, I'm tellin' ya.
- OK. Next.
- Come on.
- Where have you been, ma'am?
- (Boyle) Todo es muy b/en mi amor?
- (Maria) Yes.
(Maria) I always dreamed
to come to California.
(Boyle) It's a wacko joint.
Not like El Salvador.
You can be what you want here.
You can do what you want.
Long as you got the money.
I'll get some of my Salvador stories
published. I could write a story on John.
I think we're gonna be OK. Yeah.
I think we're gonna be OK.
Why are we stopping here?
Ladies and gentlemen, don't be alarmed.
Just a routine immigration check.
- May I see your ID, sir?
- Yeah, sure. Will a driver's license do?
Just took the wife and the kids
to Nogales for the day.
- Is that right? Are you his wife?
- What is he saying?
- Of course she is. Is there a problem?
- May I see some sort of identification?
What is he saying?
- Papeles. Passaporte. Carta Verde.
- No tengo nada!
What is the problem here? She's with me.
She's been through hell in El Salvador.
I'm a journalist. She's my researcher.
So I don't understand
what the problem is here.
Will you come with me, please?
Bring the children.
Venga con migo
y traiga Ios ni-as, por favor.
Please.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
What are you doing?
- Sit down, sir. Please.
- Officer, wait a minute.
- Sit down.
- OK, but I just wanna tell you she's...
Richard, OK, stop it. I go.
- I go. Take care.
- Maria, wait.
I go. I'll be all right, OK?
Just take care of yourself.
Vamos, Duglas. Nos tenemos
que ir a casa. Vamos rapido.
Maria! If you send her back,
they will kill her.
They will rape her and they will mutilate
her if you send her back there. Maria!
If you send the kids back,
they'll kill 'em too!
- You don't know what it's like there!
- You're under arrest.
- You have no idea what it's like there!
- Move it!
You have no idea!
Maria!
Checkpoint. Three illegals:
one female Latino and two children.
Bringing 'em in.
One WMA. One Boyle, Richard.
Birth date: 2-26-43.
Check. Ten-four.
Get him in.