Miss Susan.
Miss Susan?
- Just five more minutes, Bessie.
- No, ma'am. Now!
But, Bessie, I feel absolutely
sklonklish.
You sklonklish yourself
down to breakfast.
I'm getting the judge
up right now.
- I'm up.
- Sklonklish.
When I went to school they
taught us to speak English.
Judge Turner?
Judge Turner.
- Five more minutes.
- Breakfast is ready, Your Honor.
- What time is it?
- It's a few minutes past 8.
- Is my sister up?
- Yes, Miss Margaret.
She was feeling a little
sklonklish today,
but I got her up.
Next time she tells you she
feels sklonklish,
you tell her not to be a clunk.
Thanks, Your Honor. I dig you.
- Good morning.
Good morning, dear.
Hello?
Hi, Jerry.
No, we have to listen to
a speech this afternoon.
Good deal, Neil.
Susan, your breakfast
is on the table.
Hang on a second.
Sorry I'm late, sis.
- Did you sleep well?
- Oh, sklonklish.
Don't be a clunk, Miss Susan.
- You've been coaching her.
- Someone has to protect her.
Margaret, you know the case
you were trying?
The man who ran away
with a 16-year-old girl?
- What did you give him?
- Three years.
That'll cost me $3.
I always bet you won't
sentence people.
That's ridiculous.
How have you been doing?
You've cost me a fortune.
If you're interested in a more
exact science,
spend time on geometry.
I don't consider geometry
a part of life.
Mr. Roberts does.
You're his first student to
define a triangle
as two women crazy about one
man.
Mr. Roberts is definitely
decadent.
Is he?
- Margaret.
- How much?
Only $3. Just as an advance
on my allowance.
You're already working on 1949.
But no more betting.
Thank you very much. I wonder
why you're so good to me.
You know I'd die for you,
only sometimes it's hard
living with you.
The call of the wild.
I've got to go.
- You haven't eaten breakfast.
- Thanks. Bye.
I can't talk now.
- Bessie.
- Yes, ma'am?
Have you been following the case
about the man who ran
away with the girl?
Yes, ma'am, I have.
As a matter of curiosity,
do you think my sentence
was too severe?
No, I would have given him 10
years.
- Would you?
- I certainly would.
Thank you, Bessie.
I was just curious.
That must be the judges.
Yes, I mustn't keep them
waiting.
Oh, thank you.
- Your Honor.
- Oh.
- Goodbye, Bessie.
- Goodbye, Miss Margaret.
Exit woman, enter judge.
More's the pity.
Uncle Matt, I take exception
to your innuendo.
I'm no problem to you.
You should concern
yourself with Susan.
Nothing wrong that the
firm hand of a man
in the house wouldn't cure.
If you'd listen to me,
you wouldn't have this problem.
And I've been telling you
I will not put up...
...with your constant attempts
to get me married.
Come in.
Good morning, good morning.
Good morning, Margaret.
Good morning, Herr Doctor.
- Good morning, Chamberlain.
- Margaret, I have a present.
I found a copy of the rare old
English writ of exigi facias.
Thank you, Tommy.
If that's the night-blooming
exigi facias,
you can put it in a vase and
water it.
You seem a little truculent this
morning.
Physician, heal thyself.
See you later, Margaret.
I'm not as much interested
in the woman getting married...
...as I am in making sure
that she marries the right man.
I don't think he likes me. It's
a sixth sense
one acquires in the district
attorney's office.
Uncle Matt has a personal life
beyond his job as court
psychiatrist...
...and occasionally
they become confused.
Yes, I guess so.
Speaking of combining work and
pleasure...
...I understand you're reviewing
the Richard Nugent case.
- I have an interest--
- You know I don't like that.
If your gift is in the nature of
bribe--
Oh, put it out of your head.
But this man has given us great
difficulty--
You'd go where you were going,
and I'll go where I was going.
Very well.
But remember, absit invidia.
- We're ready, Your Honor.
- All right, Mac.
Raise your right hand.
Do you swear the evidence you'll
give in this matter...
...of The State vs. Richard
Nugent
shall be the truth, so help you
God?
- Yes.
- Step up to the bench.
- Go ahead.
- We picked up Richard Nugent...
...in the Vampire Club on a riot
call.
When we got there, there was a
free-for-all,
and Nugent was at the bottom of
it.
Which of you is Nugent?
Mr. Nugent isn't here.
I'm representing him.
Is he in the hospital?
No, Your Honor. He's out on
bail.
Does he know the hearing was for
9 a.m.?
Yes, I'm sure he'll be here.
He must have been unavoidably
detained somewhere.
If he's not here in a few
minutes...
...I'll issue a bench warrant
and forfeit his bail.
- But--
- I'll hear the witnesses.
- May I have your name?
- My name is Anthony Herman.
I work at the Vampire Club.
- In what capacity?
- To maintain order.
I throw people out
that raise a disturbance.
What happened last night?
I got back from the house where
I had to maintain order
on a gentleman who said our
music stunk.
When I returned to my usual
post, I became aware of loud
activities and screams.
As I rush over to maintain order
a straight left catches me,
as you can see.
A short time later, I'm informed
that the disturbance is over.
There's one thing I remember.
Mr. Nugent was the center of the
disturbance.
But you didn't actually see him
fighting?
He was fighting. If I get my
hands--
- The whole thing was your fault.
- Shut up.
Quiet in the courtroom. Quiet.
- Your name?
- Miss Agnes Prescott.
Go on.
I'm also employed at the Vampire
Club as an entertainer.
A modern singer of modern songs.
I've known Mr. Nugent for some
time.
I posed for him. In costume.
I posed for Mr. Nugent too.
In costume.
- Shall I continue, Your Honor?
- By all means.
Last night, Mr. Nugent dropped
in to renew our acquaintance.
While we were having words at
his table...
...we were accosted by this
lady, which I resented.
Harsh words were exchanged, and
Mr. Nugent came to my defense.
- That's a lie. I knew him first.
- Don't call me a liar.
- Please. Everybody's listening!
- Just a moment.
Your client Mr. Nugent
has exactly 60 seconds.
Mr. Nugent's lack of punctuality
is no surprise to the district
attorney's office.
Indeed?
Chamberlain has an interest in
this case.
This is the third occasion
Nugent has been involved
in a public disturbance.
I object to these remarks.
They're intended to prejudice
the court.
I think only the facts in this
case should be considered.
Your Honor, I feel it's
important--
It's important I consider
only the evidence presented in
this matter.
- Very well, Your Honor.
- Don't sulk about it.
I'll move over, lady.
Good morning.
- Good morning, Walters.
- Morning.
- Good morning.
Morning.
May I assume that this is Mr.
Nugent, the defendant?
I'm frankly and honestly
delighted, Your Honor.
Is it all right for us to go
ahead?
Well, I'm sorry, but--
I hope we haven't inconvenienced
you.
- Oh, no. It's just--
- I know. Your watch is slow.
Stopped. Forgot to wind it.
I don't know if you work on
schedule, but this court does.
9:00 means 9:00.
Yes, sir. I mean, yes, Your
Honor.
Let's get on with this.
Did you go to the Vampire Club
last night?
Yes.
I'm doing a series of paintings
on Americana...
...and I'm including a nightclub
scene.
Creating a nightclub scene
would seem more appropriate.
However, there's some doubt
as to how the fight actually
started.
Well...
Agnes had finished her spot.
That's a theatrical term.
It means her routine, her
performance.
Thank you.
Well, we were having a drink
when Florence...
- We've met.
- ...appeared.
She... On a couple occasions,
Florence has posed for me.
I stopped by his table to say
hello, this cut-rate canary...
...apparently resented my
appearance.
I prefer to hear Mr. Nugent's
version.
Thank you.
Florence's escort appeared.
I suppose you met him too.
He objected to Florence coming
to my table.
Florence insisted on not being
disturbed.
One thing led to another.
Tony slapped Florence, and I
slapped Tony.
He was only defending
American womanhood.
Get that.
Florence attempted to stop the
fight.
Agnes scratched Florence.
Florence...
Anyone who remembers a fight
punch for punch is lying.
I don't remember.
Your Honor, Mr. Nugent's been
in escapades before...
...but never through any fault
of his own.
The fact that he's a painter
of contemporary American life...
...often places him in
circumstances that seem unusual.
This court should not give Mr.
Nugent privileges
just because he's an artist.
I wasn't suggesting that, Your
Honor.
The DA's office would like him
held for trial.
Based on the evidence, I see no
reason.
Everyone participated in this
fight.
Everyone's equally guilty,
and everyone's equally innocent.
I suggest you all go home, nurse
your wounds
and be less emotional in the
future.
Thank you, Your Honor.
May I go?
You just got here.
Don't you like our court?
Sure, I like it fine, only I'm
due to give a lecture today.
Really? What are you lecturing
on?
America as I see it.
Should be very interesting.
Mr. Nugent, I've met your type
before.
In fact, I sentence them every
day in the week.
If you're brought here again,
you won't be dealt with so
leniently.
In future,
I suggest that you confine your
painting to still life.
Case dismissed.
- Next case.
- Don't press your luck.
I wish we didn't have to have
this thing today.
I hate lectures.
Look, if your coach told you
to get plenty of exercise...
She's a lap-happy chick
compared to that square from
Delaware you run around with.
Is it okay for Saturday night,
Susie? You promised.
Promises are the hollow shells
of undone deeds.
Well, for gosh sakes,
what's that supposed to mean?
You're a nice boy, Jerry,
but you're callow.
I'm not too callow to buy you
sodas
when your allowance runs out.
Don't create a scene.
I'm not good enough because
you're looking for a knight in
shining armor.
I'm competing with something
medieval.
Don't be a stupe.
Students, members of the
faculty,
our high school is honored...
...in having as guest lecturer
a man who will speak to us...
...about the classical tradition
of painting.
He's well-qualified to speak
to us about painting...
...because, in my opinion...
...he is one of America's
foremost exponents of painting.
Students, I know you will
express your enthusiasm
for his appearance here today.
And so, with no more ado,
I present Mr. Richard Nugent.
And, as we know,
many people think of art as
something pretty stuffy.
Don't let them kid you.
True art has something for
everyone.
Great art unites the masses
in every age in every country.
He's handsome.
I suppose so, for an older man.
If you think art isn't
functional,
think in terms of history.
Each age, each era becomes
visual to us when the artist...
...recreates it in stone, bronze
or on canvas.
The essence of art is
simplicity.
If I wanted to capture the
feeling of America...
...it wouldn't be necessary to
go looking for mountains
or fields of grain.
I'd try to put America on canvas
in a picture of one of you.
In your denims with the cuffs
rolled up
and the shirt open at the neck.
You'd be young, eager and proud
because of what's ahead of you.
You're the kids who, in a few
years,
will run our factories, our
farms, our businesses.
You'll be voting to make this
country
a place were there's good will,
freedom...
- ...opportunity and tolerance.
- You feeling all right?
If I were gonna do a portrait of
you, I'd try to convey all that.
Thank you.
Mr. Nugent. Mr. Nugent.
My name is Susan Turner.
I'm a student here.
- No!
- Yes.
I loved your speech.
- Thank you.
- Goodbye, Mr. Nugent.
Well, nice to have met you.
But you don't understand.
I have to interview you.
- You what?
- For the school paper.
I'm editor in chief.
- Shall we go somewhere private?
- I'd like to, but--
It isn't every day that we have
a famous artist here.
I bet you've had a terribly
interesting life.
Not very. Could we do this
later? I have a date.
- Then you're not married.
- No.
I knew you weren't.
You just couldn't be.
- Oh, I've had some offers.
- It's this way.
- We can talk in here.
- Yes, but don't you see? I--
Please?
- Have you ever been married?
- No.
- Have you ever been in love?
- Yes, I have.
Tell me, what kind of paper
does this school run?
- All the students read it.
- I'll bet they do.
You probably have no idea
what an unusual person you are.
I can see it.
I'm really much older than I
look.
These are merely the vestments I
don...
...as a concession to our
outworn educational anachronism.
But I know what the artistic
soul is like
and how keenly it can suffer.
Did you have many ordeals
before you became a success?
- No, I--
- You can talk to me.
I want you to think of me
not as a newspaperwoman...
...but as a friend.
Well, in that case, I'll tell
you.
I did suffer.
When I was 10, my parents
had a double-suicide pact.
They made it.
I was sent to an orphanage.
Some days they didn't beatme.
Then one night I escaped.
I ran away to New York.
- I used to steal.
- What did you steal?
- Beg your pardon?
Crusts of bread and things.
One time I stole a valise.
There were paints and
paintbrushes inside.
So I began to paint.
Then they got me.
I was sent to a reform school,
but I escaped again.
- Go on.
- Back to New York.
A wealthy society lady saw my
work, fell in love with me...
...and sent me to art school.
The rest is history.
How wonderful.
How terribly wonderful.
Well, now, if you'll excuse me,
I must rest.
Of course.
Goodbye, Miss Kilgallen.
Turner. Susan Turner.
By the way, remember what you
said about painting one of us?
- America and the waving grain?
- Yes, I do.
Well, do you think I'd make
a good model?
You're not quitting the
newspaper game?
That's merely a stopgap.
My family wants me to study law
but I don't wanna be a Portia.
Portia? Your family can
straighten that out.
Well, my attitude is that one
female judge
in the family is enough.
Did you say your name was
Turner?
Right. My sister is Judge
Margaret Turner.
- Nice to have met the family.
- What about my posing for you?
- What about young America?
- Fine.
Then you think I'm ideal?
You'd make a good model some
time.
- Thanks for the interview. Bye.
- Not goodbye, au revoir.
Au revoir.
- Something wrong?
- That picture. It's hideous.
It's a very nice picture.
It has absolutely no simplicity.
It's so, so busy.
True art should unite the masses
in every age in every country.
Who lectured at school today?
What does that have to do with
it?
Last month you wanted to be a
designer.
Then a naturalist gave a lecture
and you wanted to be the first
female deep-sea diver.
Last week, you wanted to be a
psychiatrist.
Now our painting's offensive.
What does this artist look like?
He's wonderful. I interviewed
him.
I've never seen anyone in armor
before.
Very few people have, Susan.
But you don't know how wonderful
he is.
He's had to lie and cheat and
steal to get somewhere in life.
That makes everything just
dandy.
What's the name of this shining
knight?
- Richard Nugent.
- Richard Nugent?
- Have you heard of him?
Heard of him?
We have a permanent courtroom
set aside for him.
How dare they allow him to
lecture in a public school!
What are you so excited about?
All he did was talk about art,
and he was very good.
I suppose there's nothing wrong
with his lecturing
if it's sponsored by the school.
Have you ever thought of me as a
model?
I can't honestly say that I
have. Why?
Dickie wants me to pose for him.
Oh, isn't that nice?
Dickie?
Don't be unreasonable. He's a
fine man. You don't know him.
I know enough to advise you
to go back to deep-sea diving.
- I don't need your advice.
- I'm your sister and guardian.
I'm acting in your best
interests.
- I'll be an old maid.
- Only until you're 18.
When a suitable man comes along,
I'll happily see you married.
And you'll probably make him
pass a lie-detector test first.
You forget about Mr. Nugent.
Easy for you to say. Why don't
you write out a court order?
- Good evening, Mr. Chamberlain.
- Is the lady of the house in?
The lady of the house is
practically out.
Hello, Your Honor.
Only a moment, Tommy.
- Are you all right?
- Oh, I'm fine. Just fine.
- I'm sorry about our--
- It's all right.
It was really nothing.
I'm just fine.
I'll be home early. Be a good
girl. See you in the morning.
Goodbye. Have a good time.
Do I detect an air of trouble?
I never enjoy quarreling with
Susan.
She's entitled to growing pains,
isn't she?
Yes, but Susan's growing pains
are rapidly becoming a major
disease.
Can I be of any assistance?
What apartment is Mr. Nugent in?
He isn't in any apartment.
- Doesn't he live here?
- Sure, but he isn't home.
Anything I can do for you?
- Thank you. I'll wait.
- He expecting you?
I'm going to pose for him.
Do you want to wait upstairs?
Do you think it would be all
right?
Sure. I'll take you up.
- You're new around here.
- Yes.
- I'm 15.
- I'm 17.
That's okay. I like older women.
Mademoiselle.
Here we are.
Some layout, huh?
This is where he lives.
I'd like to hang around,
but got work to do.
Make yourself at home.
When did you first discover she
was gone?
About dinnertime I went to call
her.
- What time was that?
- Quarter past 7.
- She leave a note?
- I didn't find any.
- Any signs of a struggle?
- Oh, no!
Stop conducting this like an
investigation.
- Bessie, you may go.
- Thank you, ma'am.
You're the assistant DA.
Do something.
I gotta have some clues.
We only have a description.
Have you checked the hospitals?
Hospitals, airports, bus
terminals.
- You call her friends?
- Hours ago.
She had a date with a boy, Jerry
White.
When he got here, she'd already
gone.
Hello? It's for you.
Hello. Yes, Chamberlain
speaking.
No, she was alone.
Yes, keep a man there. And,
Keighly, check the morgue.
Right.
I'm sorry. It's just routine.
I remember an important murder
case. The body--
If anything's happened,
I won't forgive myself.
- I shouldn't have quarreled.
- What about?
It was nothing. I told her she
can't pose for Richard Nugent.
She said she didn't need my
advice, that she was...
--aggravated by the
imponderables
of international currency
fluctuations--
Hello, Mr. Nugent.
Dickie, hello.
Come on, let us in!
And now we bring you Del
Minelli.
And that sensational swoon tune
"Fast Ride in a Patrol Wagon."
Tell me exactly what happened.
If I knew exactly what happened,
I wouldn't be here.
Give me a rough idea.
Where were you when they finally
let me use
the phone here last night?
I had not anticipated your
winding up in jail.
I have a life of my own, you
know?
I'm sorry. I hope I haven't
inconvenienced you.
- Oh, not at all.
- Sleep well? A good breakfast?
- Let's have the facts.
- Sit down.
Get a load of this.
I got home to my apartment last
night.
That much I know.
And this girl was there.
At least I think she was there.
I guess she was. I don't know.
- Judge Turner's sister?
- Yes, that's the girl.
- Young girl?
- What did you say?
- Too young.
Nugent, why don't you tell me
the truth?
I am telling you the truth. Now,
would you be quiet for a moment?
That's what happened last night.
Nobody listened to me.
I couldn't explain. Please.
All right. I got home
to my apartment last night.
I went up to my bedroom,
took off my dinner coat.
Wanted to be comfortable,
put on a robe.
Came downstairs, turned on the
radio,
got a nice highball...
...opened a book,
sat down to read the book...
...when up popped this little
girl.
Now, the little girl popped up.
There's a banging at the door.
Everybody yelling. Somebody
busts in.
Everybody starts talking.
Don't listen to an explanation.
They're mad!
Did the girl explain why she was
there?
Yes. Well, she tried to explain,
but they wouldn't really let her
explain.
She kept trying to say she'd
come up there
to be a model or something.
Did you or did you not invite
her up there to be a model?
Well, yes, in a roundabout way,
I guess I did. I guess I did.
She said I told her I was gonna
paint her as young America.
Did you tell her that?
Oh, I told that to 500 little
girls.
Well, let's not go into that.
You're charged with hitting
the district attorney.
Did you or did you not hit him?
I hit him. That's right.
But at the time I hit him,
I did not know he was the
assistant district attorney.
If I had known he was the
assistant district attorney...
...I would have hit him.
He said some bad things, some
very bad things.
Wouldn't let me explain. Kept
pulling my arm.
Wouldn't let the girl explain.
And that sister of hers,
that's a mountain of ice...
...a gallon of poison.
Jumping to conclusions!
Control yourself, now. Control
yourself, Nugent.
I'll see what I can do for you.
Worse comes to worse, maybe I
can get your sentence reduced.
But you've got to remember,
coherently,
exactly what happened.
Sure.
If you talk like this in front
of a court...
...you'd get 20 years.
- Oh, my...
- Officer, I'm ready to go now.
Coherently, exactly.
See you later. You'll know me.
I'll be dressed like a lawyer.
High school. High school. Little
girl.
Model. I...
Mr. Nugent, you got a visitor.
This is Dr. Beemish.
- Mr. Nugent?
- Just a second. Just a second.
- Now, let me see.
- I am the court psychiatrist.
Come back in an hour. I'll be
crazy by then.
I'm here to help you.
The only thing you're suffering
from
is a case of being an innocent
bystander.
- Sit down, doctor.
- Thank you.
- May I offer you a drink?
- No, than--
- Cigar?
- No, no. I'm fine, thanks.
- This cell comfortable?
- Well, I don't know.
I haven't anything to compare it
with. This is my first time.
Well, on the whole, I think
you'll find our
Western penology system is quite
modern.
Well, that's a load off my mind.
Tell me, what can they do to me
if I kill a judge?
I understand how you feel.
I'm aware that Judge Turner
appears to be a dominant woman.
But her dominance is actually a
retreat.
We call it a manifestation of
the Oedipus complex.
As Menninger points out...
...traumatic events seem to...
The only traumatic event she
needs
is a good smack in the jaw.
She's my niece.
But you're absolutely right.
Judge Turner's ready for you,
doctor.
Oh, thank you.
You just leave things in my
hands, Mr. Nugent.
I daresay you'll be surprised at
the results.
Daresay.
I have a plan.
Just had a talk with Nugent. He
seems to be quite a nice fellow.
Were you talking to the right
man?
Why, certainly.
About 6 feet, broad shoulders,
blue eyes.
- He has brown eyes.
- Oh, has he?
Have you made definite plans
about him?
It isn't my case.
Judge Treadwell is reviewing the
evidence,
and whatever he does is all
right with me.
Well, I hope Treadwell doesn't
go too far.
I won't be responsible for
Susan.
You were saying?
Susan thinks she's in love with
this man.
If things take its normal course
this will be just an adolescent
attachment for an older man.
She'll soon forget him.
But if they send him to prison,
it will martyr him in her eyes.
This will turn into a tragedy
she'll never get over.
Oh, nonsense.
You don't understand Susan.
She's not like other children.
She's old for her age and
levelheaded.
She's above that sort of
silliness.
I'm sorry to bother, but this
lady came to visit Mr. Nugent.
She claims to be your sister
and his mother.
- Susan.
- I just wanted to talk to him.
About the steel business.
She baked this.
Thank you, Melvin.
What's happening to you?
I'm in love with him.
Don't you realize that?
If I lose him, life has no
meaning.
I love him.
How about a reversal?
You win.
Come in.
Here's Mr. Nugent.
Hello, Richard.
Well, you don't look any of the
worse for wear.
- Prison agrees with me.
- Mr. Nugent, I have good news.
You're going to hang me.
I'm afraid I'm the one
who ought to be hanged.
- Won't I sit down?
- Please do.
- I believe you know Dr. Beemish.
- Yes.
- This is Judge Treadwell.
- How do you do?
How do you do?
You know Assistant DA
Chamberlain.
Yes, nice to see you again.
Sorry about that
misunderstanding.
Forget it. Just a bit of temper.
- That's very generous of you.
- Not at all, Nugent.
I'm afraid I lost my temper too.
I hope you'll pardon me.
Oh, that's all right.
I thank you for holding this
preliminary hearing in camera.
Perfectly all right, Chester.
In view of Mr. Nugent's
reputation...
...I see no reason for exposing
him to unnecessary publicity.
I think this little incident
can be straightened out...
...if the assistant DA doesn't
wish to press charges.
I wouldn't want to see a man
of Mr. Nugent's talents in jail.
Well, thank you.
I guess I'm free to go then.
- Thank you.
- Just a moment.
I believe Judge Turner has a
suggestion.
- Anything.
- Yes, it isn't really much.
You see, I'm a little worried
about Susan.
Oh, yeah.
She's become quite enamored of
you, Mr. Nugent.
Well, it's...
We were wondering if you'd mind
helping us by taking her out.
Oh, I'd be glad to...
- Doing what?
- Being her beau.
Just until she gets over you.
You see, Dr. Beemish says she
mustn't feel
you're being martyred.
Does he? Let Dr. Beemish take
her out. Let her get over him.
I'll bet there's no law that
says I've to go out with kids.
No one's forcing you. We were
hoping you'd want to cooperate.
Why should I?
Because your attitude will
have...
...a decided bearing on the
other charges against you,
...if the assistant DA chooses
to press them.
Press what?
I only punched him in the nose.
Mr. Walters, if you were a judge
and a man had enticed a
17-year-old girl...
...to his apartment to paint her
portrait,
and when her family protested...
...brutally assaulted the
assistant DA,
what would you do to this man?
- I'd give him 20 years.
- Exactly what I'd do.
- Which side are you on?
- You haven't proved it.
- We will.
That's up to the jury.
Mr. Walters, if you were a judge
and this man realized
this girl was unfortunately in
love with him...
...and agreed to help her get
over him...
...wouldn't you be inclined to
be lenient?
I would.
- I think I'd drop the charges.
- Exactly what I'd do.
What do I have to do?
You'll see Susan as often
as we deem proper.
As soon as your fatal
fascination wears off,
you're free to go on your way.
And what if it doesn't wear off?
It will.
Mr. Nugent, don't have
any illusions about this matter.
I'm doing this against my better
judgment.
I would just as soon my sister
were going out with an actor.
Judge Turner doesn't exactly
mean that.
Just wondering.
She means as head of the
psychiatrist...
...that I've recommended you
as a vital therapy measure.
That's great.
Recommended for children.
Get him.
This row's reserved for the
faculty and
important members of the student
body.
- I hope you like basketball.
- Crazy about it.
Good evening, Susan.
Geometry getting straightened
out?
Yes, Mr. Mittwick.
- Your handkerchief.
- Thank--
You must be a new boy. We'll be
running into each other.
I gave a lecture here on art.
Oh, yes, yes, yes.
You're in Miss Hallop's class.
Excellent teacher, excellent.
There they go!
S-S-S-U-N...
...S-S-S-E-T.
S-U-N-S-E-T.
Sunset, Sunset, Sunset!
We had a much better team last
season,
but our star center graduated.
Too bad.
Our new center needs more
experience.
Oh, at least.
He used to be sort of
a boyfriend of mine.
- What?
- Oh, until I met you.
You mean that fine-looking young
man who smiled at you?
Number 7?
Yes, that's the one.
He's just a child.
- Is he in love with you?
- Oh, I suppose so.
But you needn't be jealous,
Richard.
He's really terribly
unsophisticated.
- Christoff for White.
- White out.
Sit it out for a while and get
your mind back on the game.
Yes, fine figure of a man.
I'd like to meet him.
That can be arranged.
That's a great game you're
playing, Mr...
- Jerry White. Richard Nugent.
- How do you do?
Usually my game is much better,
but it's off lately.
You know, personal troubles.
It's too bad that when schools
depend on their athletes,
certain athletes are concerned
with their own problems,
instead of beating Peebe High.
I don't know, Susan.
Why don't we get together,
talk it over?
Why not join us for a drink--?
A soda after the game?
- You mean that?
- Certainly.
Well, gee, I'd love to.
Thanks, Mr. Nugent.
I'm better now. Sure would
like to get back in the game.
- All right, go in for Barthman.
- Thanks.
Team! Team!
Fight, fight, fight!
- White for Barthman.
- Barthman out.
One for Sunset!
What a player!
Thank you.
You know, I feel sorry for
Jerry.
You do? Why?
I used to play a lot of
basketball as a kid.
- I'll bet you were wonderful.
- Not nearly as good as Jerry.
I know a champ when I see one.
He's off his game because of
you.
- You think so?
- I know so.
It's awful what a woman can do
to a man. Look at history.
- Caesar and Cleopatra.
- Napoleon and Josephine.
All of them.
Behind every defeated man,
there's a frustrated love.
- You're right.
- You bet I'm right.
And I promise, all my life,
never to hurt you.
- It was a tough game.
- Oh, hello, Jerry.
But we won.
Certainly, through no help from
you.
You're wrong, Susan, I thought
he played a splendid game.
- No, he didn't.
- He did.
No, I didn't.
- What will you have?
- I'm not very hungry.
I'll just have a double
Sweetheart Flip.
Aren't you supposed to be in
training?
Sometimes a man just doesn't
care.
You see? I know how you feel.
You do? Well, I may as well
level with you, Mr. Nugent.
When Susan told me about you and
her, I was sore.
- Can you blame me?
- No--
When I saw you tonight, I wanted
to take a poke at you--
- Jerry
- Let me finish.
Then I said to myself,
"Let's be civilized.
"This is life. If Susan feels
that way,
it's all right with me."
That's big of you, Jerry,
and very generous.
- We can still be friends.
- Of course we can.
- No matter what happens.
- That's how I feel.
Dick and I will treasure your
friendship.
If I can do anything for either
of you, just call Jerry.
If we can do anything for you,
all you have to do is ask.
Yeah. Get in touch, you know.
Call up.
Well, I guess it's goodbye,
Jerry.
- I guess it is.
- Guess it is.
- Oh, and Susan?
- Yes, dear?
It isn't becoming for you to
call me
"dear" and "darling" and all
that.
- Why, darling?
- Now, stop that.
Listen, the basketball game was
fun tonight, but it can't go on.
Yes, I know.
The season's over next week.
No, no, no, Susan.
Wait a minute.
I mean, the whole thing can't go
on.
You got me into all this
trouble. Came to my apartment.
You told your sister I asked you
to pose.
Well, that's true in a way.
That isn't so, and you know it.
Let's not argue about it.
The point is, everyone has the
crazy idea that you love me.
I am.
Look at me.
Susan, I wouldn't say this to
many people,
but I'm old enough to be your
father.
You're so right, dear.
You've got to realize that this
isn't proper for either of us.
You're so right, dear.
- Well, it's not only--
- Step.
Thanks. It's only gonna
embarrass me,
but it's gonna embarrass you
too.
You're so right, dear.
Susan, you're not paying
any attention to me.
You're so right, dear.
Well, good evening, Susan.
Good evening, Nugent.
Glad to see you kids home early.
We're not home yet. We will be.
Did you have a good time?
Was the game fun?
How would you like a cigarette?
- I'm not allowed to smoke yet.
- Sorry I haven't any bubble gum.
Good night, Tommy.
By the way, we're having a
birthday party for my niece.
We'd love to have you come.
She'll be 6.
- How's your jaw?
- Fine, why?
Because the worst I can get is
90 days.
- Temper, temper.
- Dickie, please.
Well...
Toodle-loo, kids.
Hello, Margaret.
Hello, Susan.
Good evening, Mr. Nugent.
- Good evening.
- That's the new dress.
- Yes. Like it?
- Oh, it's beautiful.
It's too bad you'd to go to that
dreary dinner for some lawyer.
It was a very nice party.
- Did you enjoy yourself?
- We had a sensational time.
Better turn in now. School
tomorrow.
- You have to get up early.
- Yes, of course.
Good night, Dickie.
Good night, Susan.
- Good night, Margaret.
- Good night, dear.
Good night, Dickie.
Good night, Susan.
Well, good night.
Good night.
That is a beautiful dress, and
you look wonderful in it.
Thank you.
You said that gracefully.
Perhaps the result of practice.
You said that ungraciously.
I had that coming.
Got a moment?
Yes.
That's right.
My mother was quite a remarkable
woman.
She taught piano.
Funnily enough, children liked
to take lessons from her.
Well, anyway...
I read books she didn't want me
to read
and didn't read books she wanted
me to.
I'd say that was a perfectly
healthy, normal attitude.
One day, I found a book that
had a very racy title.
So I sneaked it up to my room,
started to read it.
I kept reading for a long time.
It was awful dull.
I kept on with it.
Then suddenly I discovered...
...mother had stuck a philosophy
book...
...underneath that paper cover
with the racy title.
Anyway, I waded through the
thing, hoping for the best.
Although I never did come across
anything exciting...
...I learned a lot about
philosophy.
I suppose that's one way of
learning.
Yeah, isn't it? Well, I learned
something else, simple but true.
Never judge a book by its cover.
All is not gold that glitters.
Things may not be what they
appear to be.
That's very interesting, Mr.
Nugent.
My father was a judge.
When he gave me a book about
law,
I knew it was gonna be about
law.
Yes, yes.
And when you meet a man who's
labeled "artist"...
...you know he's gonna be all
you think an artist is gonna be.
Concerning you, I sat in
judgment on a series of facts...
...not on your character or
biography.
I just took the long way to say
that
when I said that was a beautiful
dress...
...and you look wonderful in
it...
...I sincerely meant it.
I'm sorry.
I've never been subjected
to so much charm before.
Well, I'm afraid we're wasting
a perfectly beautiful moon...
...and I'm keeping you up.
Good night.
We'll see you Saturday. You're
taking Susan to the picnic.
Yes, yes, yes, I'll be here.
Don't worry.
With my very best Saturday
picnic charm.
Good night, Your Honor.
Good night.
- Hi, Jerry.
- Hi, Mr. Nugent.
What are you doing here?
You know, it's hard to get Susan
out of your system.
I know how it is.
Why don't you go inside?
I'm not welcome inside.
Don't be silly. She probably
doesn't know you're here.
She put me here.
I'm a square in Susan's social
circle.
It's not her fault, I guess.
It's her uncle, Judge Thaddeus.
- Have you met him yet?
- No.
He's something fierce.
I walked in and said,
"Mellow greetings, ukie-dukie."
- He almost blew a fuse.
- What's wrong with that?
Guess he's been around lawyers
so long,
he's forgotten how people talk.
Sure. "Mellow greetings,
ukie..."
- You going to the picnic?
- Well, I was, but--
How'd you like to use my car?
- You're kidding.
- No. I'd like to borrow yours.
- Does it run?
- Oh, sure.
- Where are the keys?
- You don't need a key.
- Well, here are mine.
- Jiminy. Thanks, Mr. Nugent.
See you at the picnic.
Boy, she sure is a honey.
Just a later model.
That must be Richard Nugent.
And who the devil is Richard
Nugent?
He's older. He's come to take
Susan to the picnic.
- I think you'll like him.
- How do you know?
I haven't seen him yet!
Hi! Mellow greetings,
ukie-dukie.
Dickie!
Ready, voot? Let's scoot!
You remind me of a man.
- What man?
- The man with power.
- What power?
- The power of hoodoo.
- Hoodoo?
- You do.
- Do what?
- Remind me of a man.
- What man?
- The man with power.
- Good morning!
- Power of hoo-- Greetings.
- Are you out of your mind?
- What?
- What are you doing?
- I don't dig you.
What are you whispering about?
Hi, Uncle Matt! How's the light
operator?
May I present my great-uncle,
Judge Turner.
- How do you do, judge?
- This isn't a pump handle.
He's sharp.
You remind me of a man.
- What man?
- The man with the power.
- What power?
- The power of hoodoo.
- Hoodoo? Do what?
- You do. Remind me of a man.
Remind you--
He is an associate justice
of the state supreme court.
Better than working
for a living.
Aren't we gonna be late for the
picnic?
Yes, we are.
I'm your little pepper shaker.
The hot rod's outside.
Come on, Thaddeus.
- You remind me of a man.
- Hoodoo.
- No, I'm supposed to say that!
- All right, go ahead.
- But that's Jerry's car.
- Just looks like it.
- What's this?
- Friend made it. A voot-eight.
Eight more payments and it's
mine!
You expect me to ride in that?
- Throw your frame in!
- I wanna talk to you.
- No, there's no time--
- I'd rather stay home.
There's no time for talk now.
Come on, come on.
- Here's the basket, here.
- Thank you.
Hot vooterenie!
- Nice car you got here, Richard.
- Thank you.
I just hope you come up
before me sometime.
Must run in your family.
- Hello, Tommy.
- I've been waiting for you.
- I'm sorry. We were delayed.
- Look out for your thumb.
It's the junior set.
Hello, Uncle Thaddeus.
- How do you--? My back.
- Can I get something for you?
Yes. Get me a seat that doesn't
bounce.
We can eat lunch over there.
Come on.
I'm as hungry as a bear.
Let's join the ants.
Ladies and gentlemen!
First events of the afternoon
are the novelty races.
Open to adults, parents and
friends.
Come on, everybody, win...
I used to be good at these as a
kid.
Well, why not get in?
It's open to parents.
- I'm not a parent.
- Too old, Chamberlain?
- Of course not.
All right, then, I will.
- How about you?
- Don't be silly.
Dickie, you must.
I want a medal.
- Get her a medal.
- Oh, too old?
To run in a sack race?
Nothing to it.
Then go in there
and show them, Dickie.
All right, I will.
- Hold that.
- Hold this.
Snap it up, boys.
Give the man his sack.
Let's go to the finish line. I
wanna see Dickie comes in first.
Coming, Uncle Matt?
No. You go ahead. I'll wait
here.
Two more lanes open!
Who'll step up?
Thank you, gentlemen!
Step right up and get yourself
a sack.
Okay, Jack, you all set?
All right, steady now.
Ready, gentlemen?
On your marks, get set...
All right, ladies and gentlemen,
we're set for the start...
...of the spectacular
three-legged race...
...one of the most hilarious
events of the program.
Now, come on, you folks down
the sidelines,
pick out your favorite...
...and cheer him down to the
finish line!
All right, Jack.
On your marks, get set...
Hey, hey, hey!
Hold up, hold up. Not so fast.
All right, everybody, we're all
set
for the spoon and potato race.
On your marks, get set...
Disqualified! You've got to
cross the line on your feet.
On your marks, get set...
- Come on, Dickie.
- Come on, Dickie!
Come on.
Ladies and gentlemen, this is
it!
This is the main event of the
afternoon.
You are about to witness
the spectacular obstacle race.
A supreme test of skill,
stamina and endurance.
Come on, Dickie, stand up.
I can't pin it when you're
sitting down.
- Haven't you had enough?
- Not for me.
- We've just begun to fight.
- Just begun to fight.
Hold these medals, Uncle Thad.
I don't want any excess weight.
Everybody get ready!
All contestants report to the
starting line.
Come on, Dickie,
I know you can win this time.
- Sure. Sure.
- This is the last call!
- Hi, Mr. Nugent.
- Where have you been?
I've been trying out your super
jalopy. Hi, Susan.
Hi, Jerry. Now remember, Dickie,
you've got to win me that cup.
Good luck.
- You going in the race?
- Yep.
- May the best man win.
- He will.
I'm beginning to worry about
him.
Why? He's got courage. A man's
man.
- I hope he wins.
- Come on, now. Everybody ready.
- For Susan's sake.
- Of course.
Everybody line up.
Let's go down to the finish
line.
--In the obstacle race.
All right, all you contestants,
take your places on the
starting line.
And remember, anyone who fails
to take a single obstacle...
...is disqualified.
On your marks, get set...
Keep going, Mr. Nugent.
Keep going, Mr. Nugent,
keep going.
Keep going.
Excuse me, I slipped.
You pushed me.
- It was nothing. Just a race.
- Congratulations, Mr. Nugent.
Everybody over to the bandstand
for the grand award!
- You were wonderful, Dickie.
- The grand award, that's you.
Oh, sure. Grand reward.
Thanks a lot, Jerry, for letting
Dickie win.
That's okay.
Pay the boys Saturday.
Seventy-five cents a piece.
Anyone else, they'd charge a
buck.
- I'll pay you too.
- I don't want your money.
Some things just can't be
bought.
You know, Jerry, at times
you're really very nice.
Quiet, please. Quiet, everyone.
It gives me great pleasure to
present
this beautiful trophy and
medal...
...to that great athlete and
winner of the feature event...
...Mr. Richard Nugent.
I don't know how this happened
to me.
But I guess I owe it all to
clean living, proper outlook...
...and the help of my friend.
What a wonderful day.
What a wonderful picnic.
Oh, I feel wonderful.
Uncle Thaddeus, let's dance.
No. No.
Susan, your youthful exuberance
is very tiring.
Margaret, I'm going upstairs
to take a hot bath.
Life.
You'd better rest for a while.
You've had a busy day...
...and you're going to a dance
tonight.
Quite right.
But I would like this day to
never end.
I'd like everything to stay
suspended, beautiful.
Well, you can leave everything
suspended after I sit down.
- I'll take it, Margaret.
- No, I think you'd better go up.
All right, sis.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing's wrong.
A very odd thing happened to me
today, Uncle Matt.
I think it's very simple to
explain.
Optical illusions have been
known to...
Or the power of suggestion
through Susan...
These things have been...
Well...
What happened to me
was a combination of the heat...
...a hurried lunch and the
excitement.
Of course.
It was a question of me
thinking I saw him. Understand?
Sure. That's perfectly clear.
The same--
In view of this, it occurred to
me that...
Mr. Nugent.
...Mr. Nugent's been sweet about
Susan.
We shouldn't embarrass him
further.
- What if Susan--
- Susan's romance is adolescent.
I think she'll get over it. I
think we owe it to Mr. Nugent--
I'd like to talk this over with
him.
I think that's quite--
I don't think it'll be a good
idea to have him here.
With Susan in the house,
we couldn't talk freely here.
- Naturally--
- It wouldn't be proper...
...to invite myself to his
apartment.
Oh, no--
So the obvious thing to do is
arrange a convenient place.
Something public, sophisticated
and...
Well, we can talk things over.
Yes.
- I'd have to give that--
- Thank you for talking to me.
You've cleared things up.
It's all right. I appreciate
your confidence.
It's extraordinary how simple
problems are
when you don't let emotions run
away.
- True, true.
- Where's the telephone?
Hello?
Yeah.
Oh, anything wrong with Susan?
Oh, can't go, huh? Sorry to hear
that.
Will you tell her? Yeah.
With you?
Yeah, I'd be delighted.
Do you want me to come over
there?
Oh, I see. Yeah.
You wouldn't want to come here,
would you?
Oh, naturally.
We can meet any place you say.
Yeah, we can celebrate my
triumph.
Well...
No, I'm not too tired to dance.
Do you dance? I mean--
Well, okay, anything you say.
Well, let's see now.
I know the headwaiter at the
Tick-Tock Club. How about that?
Fine. Sure, okay.
Come in.
- Hello.
- Hello, Nugent.
Come on in.
Last time I saw you, you were
underwater.
You all right? You didn't get
hurt?
I keep myself in excellent
physical condition at all times.
- How do you feel?
- Splendid.
To the victors belong the
spoils.
You made a good race of it,
Chamberlain.
I don't think I like it there.
The reason I'm here is that I
want to let you off the hook.
Here, hold that a moment. What
hook?
I know taking Susan out was a
nuisance.
It wasn't good for Susan,
and it was a strain on Margaret.
Which one are you concerned
about?
If I had to indicate my
preference, I'd choose Margaret.
Who's your tailor?
The coach was kind enough
to furnish them to me.
Oh, I had it there, didn't I?
Nugent...
...I have something important
to tell you.
I've decided to drop charges
against you.
Let me see this.
I say, I've decided to drop
the charges against you.
Dropped my medal. Dropped it.
- Help me look for it.
- Yes, yes.
We can forget the whole thing.
You won't have to come around.
You look silly in that coat.
Doesn't go with the clothes.
Let's stick to the subject.
You're a free man now.
You're free. It's possible we
won't see each other again.
Found it. What did you say?
It's possible we won't see
any more of each other.
Chamberlain, you've put me in a
position
where I'm forced to make a
confession.
About Margaret?
No. No, about Susan.
- I'm madly in love with her.
- You're what?
I don't know how it happened.
Perhaps it's something she said,
or how she looked
or something she wore.
All I know is that I'm happy
when I'm near her, that I--
Well, you're a man.
You must have felt what I feel.
- It's love. Love!
- It's preposterous.
- The child's only 17.
- Yes, but she'll be 18 soon.
We'll wait for our chance at
life.
Spring and autumn.
Stop it. You're complicating the
issue. I forbid it.
This is something no court of
law can stop.
It's bigger than you, than me.
You're just what I always
thought you were.
You're irresponsible.
L'amour, my friend, I'amour.
We'll see about "I'amour, my
friend, I'amour."
Of course, it's not the kind of
wine we got before the war...
...but I think that she
would rather like it.
Anyway, it's the best
we can get nowadays.
Thank you, Alex.
I just wanted to make sure.
- Is that the mademoiselle?
- No, no, no.
- Hey, that isn't--
- I'm awfully sorry.
I'm sorry, but the polish,
the best we can get nowadays.
Oh, that's all right.
Oh, perhaps that's mademoiselle?
No, no, no.
I wish we had blue flowers.
She would like them.
We can get blue flowers,
but it will take time.
Well, I'll try to fix these.
Alex, that's the best you can
get any day.
- Hello.
- Hello. Hello.
I didn't know.
I should have checked.
- I'm sorry, no black tie.
- That's all right.
That's a beautiful suit,
and you look wonderful in it.
They're lovely. Thank you.
- Yellow's my favorite color.
- I thought so.
Now, isn't that sweet?
I can't tell you how glad I am
that you--
That we're here.
Our relationship's been such an
odd one...
...I thought it might be fun for
us to try a new background.
Would you like to give your
order now?
Later.
How about a drink in the
meantime? Champagne?
Yes.
The time is now, Alex.
- Shall we dance?
- Love to.
- Now, my father was a bachelor.
- Really?
Wait a minute. Wait till...
Wait until I finish.
He was a bachelor until way into
his 30s.
He always said he'd know who
he's gonna marry
the moment he met her.
Then he met my mother.
He put his arm around her,
and that was it.
Just the way she felt in his
arms did the trick.
They were married three days
later.
That's a very romantic story.
They were happy all their lives,
apparently had nothing in
common.
I told you, she was a piano
teacher,
and he was a flag decorator.
- A what?
- Flag decorator.
He was a good one, until he fell
off
Newark City Hall, broke his leg.
Your family sounds like fun.
You must have come from a nice
family.
It shows in your face.
Well, my family weren't quite
that impulsive.
Father courted Mother through
high school,
college and law school.
Fourteen years after they met,
they got married.
They had a lot in common.
They were both attorneys.
You feel nice in my arms.
I imagine if Mother and Father
hadn't had much in common...
...they needn't have waited 14
years.
It could have happened suddenly,
romantically.
Dickie!
- Oh, hello, Agnes.
- You didn't congratulate me.
- Should I?
- It's my birthday.
Congratulations.
Nugent, what do you say
we let bygones be bygones, huh?
- Hey, don't I know you?
- Yes, we've met.
Where did I meet you?
Was it Dickie's apartment?
- No, you remember Judge Turner.
- Oh, well, of course.
Well, yes. Well, you got to be
friends, huh?
Leave it to Dickie.
He knows all the angles.
If it's too crowded,
we'll go to the table.
It's too crowded.
- Happy birthday.
- Goodbye.
Goodbye.
Now, there's a guy who never
goes out of a girl's mind.
He just stays there like a heavy
meal.
- What am I like?
- Orange juice.
- I'm terribly sorry about that.
- It's nothing.
I'm sure you didn't know she'd
be here.
Are you sure you're sure
I didn't know she'd be here?
- Yes, why?
- Well, I was just wondering.
I've given up jumping at
conclusions.
- Good.
- Hello, Dickie.
- Hello, Jolly.
- Cigarettes?
- No, thanks.
- All right.
Cute kid.
I did a magazine cover of her.
- She's nice.
- You can't walk in like this.
- It's absolutely forbidden.
- Susan!
I don't intend to create a
scene.
You should be ashamed of
yourselves.
I'm too young to be deceived by
treachery.
- Have a drink?
- Lemonade.
- Sit down.
- I don't intend to stay.
And some chocolate ice cream.
Wonder how I found out where you
were?
- What's on your mind?
- You know what's going on.
You told me Dickie was sick,
exhausted from the picnic.
I went to Dickie's apartment.
They told me where he was.
And here I am, and here you are.
I demand an explanation from
both of you.
- Aren't you being childish?
- I'll be anything I want.
Joey will buy you and the judge
a drink.
I owe it to you for being so
nice to us.
We'll be here time enough
to drink one down.
Oh, garçon!
This party's on me. Bring
chairs.
I don't believe we've been
acquainted.
Susan Turner--
Agnes and Joey.
This your daughter, judge?
No, it's her sister. Her older
sister-- Margaret's sister.
- Got plenty of room, sweetheart?
- Sure.
You look like mother and
daughter.
Sisters look alike too.
I hate my sister.
Oh, I just love birthdays.
Birthdays are the best.
Maybe Mr. Rosenheimer
can come over here.
No matter what you say,
I intend to wait here.
- Nobody said anything to you.
- Cute hat you got on.
- I don't intend to take it off.
- I didn't ask you to.
Bring another round of the same.
Put it on my check.
- Very good.
- Take these. We're not eating.
- Just drinks.
- Oh, yeah--
- Hello, Jerry. Glad to see you.
- I doubt if anyone's glad.
- You weren't invited, Mr. White.
- Meet Agnes and Joey.
I love kids with floppy hair.
It's so casual.
Suppose you're wondering how I
got here.
If she isn't, I am.
It's getting to be quite a
party.
- All is not gold that glitters.
- You said a mouthful. Remember--
Just a minute. Just a minute!
I haven't got much time left.
I went to see you, Susan, 'cause
I got word I'm being drafted.
I went to the house. You were
gone. I went to Mr. Nugent's--
- Yes, we know the rest of it.
- I just want to say goodbye.
You don't have to make a big
thing about it. The war's over.
But guns go off by accident. A
fellow could trip on a bayonet.
I know. Going away, not seeing
your loved ones for years.
You're a fine boy, Jerry,
and a good friend.
Possibly Mr. Nugent doesn't know
how good.
You don't have to tell me about
Jerry.
Maybe I could tell you things.
How loyal he is, and how he made
sure
you won that race this
afternoon.
Race? Where were you this
afternoon?
- It doesn't concern you.
- What are you talking about?
- You shouldn't say that.
- A woman scorned is a fury!
- What are you drinking, bub?
- I'll have an eggnog.
Just a second. Jerry--
Bring an eggnog.
What do you've to do with my
winning?
Two eggs!
What did you have to do
with my winning--?
Me? Joey, you shouldn't have
done it.
Joey's the cutest thing.
Oh, thank you.
Did you frame it
so I could win that race?
He only did it because he knew
how I loved you.
- I forbid this kind of talk.
- Life's complicated.
- Too complicated.
- Good evening.
Sit down.
You're in time for cake.
Thanks. I will.
Wondering how I got here?
I went to your house--
You went to her house, found her
gone.
You were suspicious
and went to my apartment.
You'd make a good detective.
- I don't like him.
- Nor do I.
- The name is Chamberlain.
- Hello.
- How do you do?
- Get him. "How do you do?"
- Know what you're doing?
- Of course.
- It might interest you--
- Know what you are?
- You're a regular Blackbeard.
- Bluebeard, dear.
- A rose by any color.
- Everybody's excited.
Nobody's excited!
I want you to know.
Only this afternoon, he told me
he's madly in love with Susan.
Oh, Dickie, did you, darling?
I did, yes. But I was only
kidding.
- Don't kid Susan for any reason.
- You stay out of this.
Everybody's so unhappy. Why
don't we have a drink and cake?
- I don't feel like eating.
- Chamberlain, you know--
It's too public to continue this
discussion.
- Mister, you have my chair.
- There are other chairs.
I realize that. I suggest you
occupy one.
- Do you love me?
- I want my chair.
- You're a cute child--
- I'm busy.
- I can't say I love you.
- I want my chair.
She spent $4.50 to make sure
you won that race.
That's too bad.
You can have the cup!
That victory of Nugent's was a
frame-up?
For the last time, I want my
chair!
Happy anniversary, Mr. and Mrs.
Overholtz.
Look at this. It's their
anniversary.
Congratulations.
It's your anniversary, my
birthday--
I don't want any trouble.
I just want my chair back.
- Oh, stand up.
- And for that matter--
Please sit down.
You can have the medal.
What happened?
Always saying the wrong thing.
- Shall we fight this out?
- No. We're too excited.
- Sit.
- Right.
- I'm getting out of here.
- So am I.
Now, now. Wait a minute.
I've had enough of this and you.
- You attract trouble.
- There you go, jumping again.
Shut up!
Thank you for a lovely evening.
Well, thank you. Thank you!
If I was so disposed,
I could make trouble for you.
You may be a regular guy,
but I don't know.
I hope this fixes your kettle of
fish.
I came to buy you a birthday
drink,
and you ruined my birthday. You
ruined it!
Joey got me a birthday cake
and you ruined everything!
Come on, Joey.
Let him pay for the drinks.
I'd punch your nose if I wasn't
afraid you'd break my jaw.
Oh, I'm awfully sorry, Mr.
Nugent.
Will there be anything else?
For instance?
Well? It's your move.
Been your move for several
minutes.
I was just a little concerned
about Margaret and Susan.
They're old enough
to take care of themselves.
And you just made a stupid move.
Susan.
Susan!
- Why does she do that?
- I should find out what's wrong.
Your queen's in danger.
- Margaret.
- You and your psychology!
I will not stand for this
excitement!
Your queen's still in danger.
What's wrong?
A great deal. I'm talking to
Margaret.
That's impossible unless you
break her door down.
This is a conspiracy!
Do you intend to finish this
game?
Now, Thaddeus...
I can't stand it. I've gotta
talk to Susan!
It's late. Come back in the
morning.
This is a fine way to treat a
veteran!
Thaddeus, you're old enough
to control yourself.
- Margaret, I wanna talk to you.
- You keep out of this!
If you're leaving, you might
take something more than a doll.
- I hate you.
- Susan, you can't mean that.
I do. My own sister,
stealing the man I love.
- You're not being fair.
- The other woman.
It's not like that at all.
Why not send me to prison,
get me out of the way?
I'm old enough to fight for my
own happiness.
Anyway, I saw him first!
I couldn't help overhearing.
I had my ear to the door.
This is your fault.
You created this situation.
You told Susan to come to that
nightclub.
Calm down. Be sensible.
Did I or did I not
send you to find Margaret?
- You didn't. It was my own idea.
- That's beside the point.
I didn't send Tommy or Jerry,
and you're both hysterical.
Will you go to your room?
Lemme talk to Susan.
I have nothing to say to anyone.
I will not make a statement of
any kind at this time.
Unpack those clothes and hang
them up.
I'm strong enough to take you
over my knee
and give you the spanking you
deserve.
You wouldn't dare.
I have no intention, however, of
doing so
if you'll be sensible. Now, sit
down.
Sit down!
I think your infatuation for Mr.
Nugent is a childish one...
...and you've been unfair to Mr.
Nugent, Margaret and to Jerry.
You're going to get sensible
about the matter.
- I am.
- You are?
You're going to listen to me.
And you're going to do
just as I tell you.
- Margaret?
- Come in, dear.
I've just had a long talk with
Uncle Matt.
Yes.
And I see things much more
clearly.
After all, Richard is too old
for me.
When I'm 42, he'll be 60.
Jerry's going to look handsome
in his uniform, don't you think?
I think.
I've decided to renounce Richard
for Jerry.
That's very sensible of you.
Now that you have a clear field
with Richard
I think you ought to patch
things up.
I've acted very childishly,
and I'm sorry, really sorry.
If I had a million sisters,
I'd want them all to be exactly
like you.
You're saying that because I'm
sklonklish.
Because you're smart.
- Good night.
- Good night, dear.
You know, in many ways...
...I think this has made
a bigger woman of me.
I'm not interested in any of
your psychological mumbo-jumbo.
But you're being too cold about
this.
Look at it from the emotional
point of view.
I don't deal in emotions, but in
facts.
And the conclusions I draw are
depressing.
Well, depressing or not, you're
in love with Richard Nugent.
I'm quite weary,
and I want to go to sleep.
I'll discuss this with you in
the morning.
Good night.
Very well.
I thank you for one thing,
straightening Susan out.
It's perfectly all right.
- Good night.
- Hi.
- How did you get in?
Door was closed. I opened it
and came in.
Open it. Go out.
You and Margaret are having
trouble.
- None of your business.
- In a way, it is.
Don't forget, I started this
whole thing.
- I won't.
- Where are you going?
- Africa.
- That's far away, isn't it?
It all depends. If you're in
Arabia, which is where I'll be
before going to Africa, you're
pretty close.
All right. But you're making a
mistake.
You can't run away from
yourself.
The trouble is you're in love
with Margaret.
- Don't be ridiculous.
- Look at the facts. First--
Facts. I'm an artist. I deal in
emotions.
My emotions say get out of here.
What do your emotions tell you?
- Fine.
- All right.
But I've got a plan.
I've had enough of your plans
and your family.
I was carefree before I met all
of you.
I've been in trouble ever since.
I'm going to be carefree again.
- Now, buzz off.
- All right.
If you run across Professor
Smedley in Johannesburg...
...give him my regards.
He's a cousin of ours. Just a
fifth cousin.
Beautiful morning, simply
beautiful.
- Isn't it?
- Yes.
Wonderful weather for flying.
- Isn't it?
- Yes.
Thing is, it'll give you a
chance to relax for a few days.
Uncle Matt, I think I'd better--
You better take me home.
Oh, well, that's ridiculous.
I think it's ridiculous I'm
packing up for three days,
running away...
...because of a very silly man.
Well, darling,
let bygones be bygones.
And if by chance your paths
should ever happen to cross...
- ...well, that's another thing.
- They better not cross.
For the time being, you just
do what Uncle Matt tells you.
Last few weeks,
you haven't been doing so good.
This morning, I talked you into
taking a plane trip.
You could talk the devil
into going to church.
- Keys, please.
- Be right with you.
Go ahead, dear, I'll take care
of the baggage and the tickets.
Attention, please.
Porter wanted at the main
information booth.
I'm sorry, but I'm sure we can
get you on the next flight.
Thanks.
Judge Turner's reservation,
please.
All right, sir.
Thank Mr. Martin for arranging
this.
It was an emergency. I do
appreciate it.
Thank you.
Beemish, where's Margaret?
I don't know. I'm looking for
her now.
- You know she's leaving?
- Oh, yes.
It's Nugent's fault. I see him,
he'll get 10 years.
I got a warrant for his arrest.
- If you take my advice--
- I don't want your advice.
Now, where's Margaret?
Well, I don't know. She should
be here.
You watch that entrance,
and I'll watch here.
Let me know the instant she
arrives.
Sure, sure.
So long, Jebby. Thanks.
Have fun. Stay out of jail.
Well, here you are, darling.
Maybe I ought to have second
thoughts about this.
Don't start that again. You just
go away and have a good time.
I'm sorry I can't wait to see
you off,
but I have to get back to the
office.
Thanks, Uncle Matt.
I don't know what for, but
thanks.
You're welcome. Happy landing.
Bye.
TWA's Constellation, flight 60,
Super Sky
Chief is ready for immediate
departure.
Passengers will board the
flight to...
I'm Dr. Matthew Beemish.
I'm the city psychiatrist.
I'm glad to know you.
I'm observing a patient. I need
your help.
Who is he?
That blond fellow with
the brown suit and hat.
He's harmless, but he might
create a scene.
What's his trouble?
He thinks he's
the assistant district attorney.
He goes around arresting people.
Oh, poor guy.
You'd think he'd at least
want to be a desk sergeant.
I'll try to handle him.
I wanted you to know, in case.
I'll be around.
- Have you seen Margaret?
- No, I haven't yet.
- I want to tell you a story.
- I don't want to hear any story.
- Nugent! Let's get him!
- Wait. You're making a mistake.
- I'm not.
- You're sure about this?
It will give me pleasure
to put him where he belongs.
Officer.
I want you to arrest someone.
You don't want to arrest people.
- What?
- Be a good boy and go on home.
I'm the assistant district
attorney.
- Sure you are.
- Tell him who I am.
He is the assistant district
attorney.
Now, ain't that nice?
You blockhead. I'll do it
myself.
- You don't wanna bother anybody.
- Having trouble?
I'm the assistant district
attorney.
Sure he is. Now, just take it
easy. Relax.
We'll make you district attorney
in charge
of the assistant district
attorneys.
I'll report you. Get their
numbers.
- I'll get a pencil, be back.
- Come on.
I'm the assistant district
attorney!
Wait! Where you taking me?
Leave me alone.
- Thank you, sir.
- Margaret Turner.
- Nugent, Richard.
- Thank you, sir.
You remind me of a man.
- What man?
- A man with the power.
- What power?
- The power of hoodoo.
- Hoodoo?
- You do.
- Do what?
- Remind me of a man.
- What man?
- A man with the power.
What power?
Give up?
Give up. Let's go.