'The voice you hear
is not my speaking voice...
'but my mind's voice.
'I have not spoken
since I was six years old.
'No-one knows why. Not even me.
'My father says
it is a dark talent,
'and the day I take it into my head
to stop breathing will be my last.
'Today, he married me
to a man I've not yet met.
'Soon, my daughter and I
shall join him in his own country.
'My husband said
my muteness does not bother him.
'He writes, and hark this, God
loves dumb creatures so why not he!
'Were good he had God's patience...
'for silence
affects everyone in the end.
'The strange thing is
I don't think myself silent.
'That is because of my piano.
'I shall miss it on the journey.'
Take her hand, come on.
You're with me.
I've got the lady.
You go ahead.
Paddington Station.
Over here, my lovely!
All right, lads, unbutton your muftis.
Piss like a tom.
Jesus Christ,
whose bloody coffin is this?
Christ, it's heavy!
Hold it!
Fuck them. Well, just leave them behind.
It's what they fucking want.
Aye, very good. Leave them
and be lynched for the pleasure!
It's a bit rough out there. Could be they
can't get through you in this weather.
Do you have things for shelter?
She says, "Thank you."
Does your mother prefer
to come on with us to Nelson?
She says, "No." She says, she'd rather be boiled
alive by natives than get back in your tub.
You be damn fortuned I don't smack
your puppy gob, young missy!
Damn lucky!
We're all ready now, sir.
Mother, watch out!
The hens! Are they all right? Here.
Look, I'm a very big moth.
Will it catch fire?
I'm not gonna call him Papa.
I'm not gonna call him anything.
I'm not even going to look at him.
Are we stopping?
Shall we stop?
We must get on.
Miss McGrath? Alisdair Stewart.
You'll have to wake yourselves.
I've got men here to carry your things.
Well, I see you've got a good many boxes.
I'd like to know what's in each...
Can you hear me?
Well, that's good.
Yes, that's good.
What's in this one?
You're small.
I never thought you'd be small.
And this one? This is very large.
- What's in it, then, a bedstead?
- It's my mother's piano.
Baines, tell them to carry in pairs.
Take all the boxes, table
and the suitcases.
What do you think?
She looks tired.
She's stunted, that's one thing.
And the big case?
No, no. Just the trunks
and the boxes as I explained.
- No, it can't come now.
- It must. She wants it to come.
Yes, so do I. But there are too few
of us here to carry it now.
Too heavy!
What, you mean you don't want your
clothing or kitchenware to come?
Is that what you mean?
We can't leave the piano!
Let's not discuss this any further.
I'm very pleased that you arrived safely.
But we must know if they can
come back directly for it.
Could I apologise for the delay...
After they've taken the other things.
Might I suggest that you prepare
yourself for a difficult journey.
The bush will tear clothing, and
the mud is very deep in places.
What do they think they're doing?
We don't have time for this.
What's the matter?
Why are they stopping?
That's the way to the
burial grounds. It's tapu.
They want more money. They're
trying to make two days out of it.
No.
No, they know another track
to the side of this.
Septimus, now take that off!
Take that off!
Watch your feet! Mind your feet!
- Septimus! Please stop it!
- Stop it!
- Stop, please! You'll tear it!
- Oh, the tag is broken.
Septimus, now stop!
You'll tear it. Be careful.
Arm down.
If you cannot have a ceremony together...
...you'll have at least a photograph.
Careful. The lace is most fragile.
My real father was
a famous German composer.
They met when my mother was
an opera singer in Luxembourg.
Why?
I want to be in the photograph.
Going to leave the cloth here?
No, no. It is just to keep
the chair dry.
We must have slipped on the planks.
They have gotten very greasy.
Get in that chair.
Pull the tarpaulin off.
I am sorry it rained.
We have not light enough inside.
- Shall I have the umbrella on this side on t'other?
- On t'other! On t'other!
Can you take this, please?
And sitting...
...very still.
And where did they get married?
In an enormous forest
with fairies as bridesmaids...
...each holding a little elf's hand.
No, I tell a lie. It was in a small
country church in the mountains.
- Which mountains are those, dear?
- The Pyrenees.
I've never been there.
Mother used to sing songs in German,
and her voice echoed across the valleys.
- That was before the accident.
- And what happened?
One day, while my mother and father
were singing together in the forest...
...a great storm blew up.
But, so passionate was the singing...
...that they didn't notice.
They didn't stop as rain began to fall.
And when their voices rose for the final bars
of the duet, a great bold of lightning...
...came out of the sky and struck my
father, who lit up like a torch.
At the same moment my father
was struck dead...
...my mother was struck dumb.
She never spoke another word.
Oh, dear!
Not another word?
Well, from the shock. Yes.
It would be. Terrible.
Terrible.
Terrible, terrible.
Sorry.
I have to go away for some days.
Some Maori land I'm interested in
which I may buy very reasonably.
Well, I hope you'll spend the time
to get settled in. And perhaps...
...in some ways...
...we could start again.
All right?
I'm not able to read.
Please take us back to
the beach where we landed.
I am sorry. I can't do that.
I don't have the time.
Goodbye.
I can't take you there.
I can't do it.
Mumma! Mumma, watch me! Look!
Mumma! Mumma!
- Hello, there.
- Hello.
Well, you've stopped combing your hair which
is a good thing. It was looking overdone.
You see, these're the slits
of the heads will go through.
Show him, Nessie.
The Reverend's going to use animal blood.
No doubt it'll be very dramatic.
- Very dramatic.
- Tea!
Morag...
...what would you think if someone...
...were to play a kitchen table?
Like it were a piano.
Like it were a piano?
It's strange, isn't it?
I mean, it's not a piano.
It doesn't make any sound.
Biscuits!
No, no sound.
I knew...
...she was mute
but now I'm thinking...
...perhaps it's more than that.
I wonder if she's not brain-affected.
Shush!
- No sound at all?
- No. It was a table.
Well, she was very violent with the gown.
She tore off a chunk of lace.
I've had been here to see it. I'd have sworn you
she'd have used her teeth and wiped her feet on it.
It hasn't come to anything yet.
It's simply a concern, that's all.
Yes.
Yes, of course. A concern.
There's something
to be said for silence.
Indeed. Cotton?
With time, I'm sure
she'll become affectionate.
Sure, there's nothing so easy to like
as a pet. And they're quite silent.
# The grand old Duke of York
He had ten thousand men #
# He marched them up and up
and marched them down again #
Those 80 acres across the stream,
what do you think of them?
I don't have any money.
What are you on about?
I'd like to make a swap.
- What for?
- The piano.
What, the piano on the beach?
- It's not marshy, is it?
- No.
Baines the music lover. I never would have
thought. Hidden talents, George?
I'd have to get lessons. It
wouldn't be much use without them.
Yes, I suppose you would.
Ada can play. I have it in a letter
that she plays very well.
She's been playing
since she was five or six.
What on?
Well, on... on your piano.
That's the swap.
What's she saying?
She says, it's her piano
and she won't have him touch it!
He can't read! He's ignorant!
He wants to improve himself,
and you'll be able to play it.
Teach him how to look after it!
You can't go on like this!
We're a family now. We all
make sacrifices, and so will you!
You will teach him,
and I will see to it!
A Broadwood!
A fine instrument!
I've not seen one here...
...nor in New South Wales
where I've tuned 200.
They like their pianos there.
Scent?
And salt, of course.
Mother says she can't stand to
teach piano with it out of tune.
So, I'm to do scales.
I hope you've scrubbed your hands.
It's in tune.
I was teaching!
Mom would like to see what you can play.
I'd rather not play.
I want to listen, and learn that way.
Everyone has to practise.
I just want to listen.
Lovely.
Oh, but tell me again.
Was he your teacher?
How did you speak to him?
What happened?
Why didn't you get married?
Shall I kiss you good night?
Get out! You need a bath!
Out! Bad dog!
Move! Go on!
Bad bloody dog!
Ada, wait. Wait.
Do you know how to bargain?
There's a way
you could have your piano back.
Do you want it back?
You want it back?
You see...
I'd like us to make a deal.
There's things I'd...
...like to do while you play.
If you let me,
you can earn it back.
What do you think?
One visit for every key.
Your dress?
Skirt?
For every black one?
That's a lot less. Half.
All right, all right.
Then the black keys.
Poor baby!
What horrid little person
put you in the rain...
...and shoved you with a stick?
Hmm, baby? Huh?
You're all right with moi.
Scissors.
Thank you.
Nessie! Put that down
and come and put your hand out.
Oh, no. Use Mr. Stewart.
- No, no, no. Go on, Nessie.
- Nessie, please!
All right, Mary, come along.
Down here.
- Come on, girl.
- All right, then!
Down here. Put out your hand.
Now.
No, no. Put out your hand. Here.
Look, look! You're being attacked.
No, there you go.
With the blood,
it will be a very good effect!
Here, Flynn!
Flynn, Flynn, Flynn!
Flynn, Flynn! Bad boy!
Bad, bad boy!
Flynn, you want to be in trouble?
Flynn! Flynn!
I want to speak to my mother.
I don't want to be outside.
I want to watch.
I'll be very quiet!
I won't look at him!
- Be very careful.
- Careful.
I hardly need to give one to you,
but here you are, anyway.
Don't be late.
You will see that there're two times. And
since you're accompanying a performer...
...you will need to make the earlier time.
Wait!
How are the lessons going?
Is he getting on all right, then, is he?
She seems quietened down.
Is she more affectionate?
Ah, well. Slowly, slowly.
Lift your skirt.
Lift it higher.
Higher.
Higher!
Lift it higher.
You no worry, Peini.
- I save you.
- I have a wife.
I save her, too!
- Where's your wife?
- My wife?
She has a life of her own,
in Hull, England.
Must be ugly... for you to run away.
You need another wife.
Undo your dress.
I want to see your arms.
Play.
Two keys.
"I shall listen hard at rehearsal...
...because I live too far
to come often."
Which sign is the word "rehearsal"?
I can't imagine
a fate worse than being dumb.
To be deaf.
Aye. Deaf, too? Terrible! Awful!
To tell you the whole truth, mother
says most people speak rubbish...
...and it's not worth the listen.
Well, that is a strong opinion.
Aye. It's unholy.
What do they say? Are they selling?
Offer blankets for half the land.
Twelve.
Offer the guns, Baines.
Offer the guns.
What do they want the land for?
They won't do anything with it?
They don't cultivate it,
they don't burn it back. Nothing.
I mean, how do they
even know that it's theirs?
Thought I might as well
mark it out as we agreed.
Yes, why not?
Well, Ada says
you're doing well with the piano.
I'd like to come and hear you play.
- What do you play?
- Nothing just yet.
No?
Ada, four keys.
Why five? I just want to lie.
All right, all right, five.
# Early in the month of May #
# The angels were sweetly singin' #
# A young man on his deathbed lay #
# For love of Barbara Allen #
We're running late!
If you haven't got your lip colour on,
can you line up behind Rose, please?
- You all been to the lavatory?
- Yes!
I want no running on the stage!
They're bringing in extra chairs!
Do not touch the blood!
Look who's here?
The musical Mr. Baines!
What are you going to play for us
tonight? "Twinkle, Twinkle", George?
How about a little tinkle-tinkle, George?
Perhaps you would like to turn pages
for Nessi. She's playing for the children.
I'm in costume.
I'm very pleased
you've taken up the piano.
Now, where's this song?
George, excuse me.
How about "Mary Had A Little Lamb"?
Or a polka?
Come on, Geroge, what's it to be?
Fools.
Come on, George. Move along.
Ladies and gentlemen,
could you take your seats, please?
We're about to begin.
# Early in the month of May
# The angels were sweetly singin'
# A young man on his deathbed lay
# For love of Barbara Allen
# Out of there sprung a red rose full
# And out of it a briar
# Then they flew up
to the high church wall
# Till they could go no higher
# And then
they came in a true love's lock
# The roses and sweet briar #
And so the young maid came upon...
...each and all of
Bluebeard's missing wives.
Their severed heads still bleeding...
...their eyes still crying!
Slow down, Nessie. Slow down.
But hush!
Who comes?
I am home early, my sweet wife!
Where art thou?
Oh! Husband!
- What a surprise!
- Yes, wife!
A surprise, indeed!
- So now you know my secret!
- No! No!
You, the youngest...
...and sweetest...
...of all my wives...
- No!
- ...must be prepared...
...to die!
No! No! Wait!
I shall not wait!
Bare your neck!
Chief, I'd like to introduce you.
This is Mrs Williams...
...this is Mrs Parsons, this is
Mrs Reid, this is Miss Palmer...
...and this is Miss Kerr.
Very... very nice.
Do what you like.
Play what you like.
I want to lie together
without clothes on.
How many would that be?
Yes. Ten keys.
What the clock say, Missa Tewart?
Never behave like that.
Never nowhere.
I'm greatly shamed!
You've shamed these trunks!
I know why Mr. Baines
can't play the piano.
You missed some here.
She never gives him a turn.
She just plays what she pleases.
And sometimes she doesn't play at all.
When's the next lesson?
Tomorrow.
I have given the piano back to you.
I've had enough.
The arrangement...
...is making you a whore
and me wretched.
I want you to care for me...
...but you can't.
It's yours. Leave.
Go on, go.
Stop right there!
This isn't yours. What are you
doing with the piano? Hmm?
He's given it to us.
Put that down. Put it down!
You're cunning, Ada.
I've seen through you.
I'm not going to lose
the land this way. Stay there!
Hori George don't wanna see nobody.
He's sick.
You got the tupeka for Hira?
No.
Baines.
Baines... Baines, look.
I don't think you should
have given up the piano.
I'll make sure you're properly
taught. Music on sheets and so on.
I don't want to learn.
- You don't want to learn?
- No.
But our bargain...
I can't afford the piano
if you mean me to pay.
No, no payment.
I have given it back.
I'm not sure I want it myself.
It was more to your wife that I gave it.
Oh, I see.
Well...
I expect she will appreciate it.
This is all I have.
Bring that back!
Is it all right?
Why don't you play something?
What will I play?
Play a jig.
- Do I know any jigs?
- Play a song then.
Why won't she play? We get the
thing back, she just wanders off.
Keep playing.
Wait! Wait!
Why? Why can't I?
I shan't practise and I don't care!
Blast and damn! Bugger her!
Bloody... bloody... bugger her!
Let her fall face down
in boiling... bloody... mud!
Let a mad dog bite her till she bleeds!
Where is your mother?
- Where's she gone?
- TO HELL!
So, what brings you here?
Did you leave something?
I've not found anything.
Does he know something?
The piano was not harmed?
It arrived safely?
Would you like to sit?
I am going to sit.
Ada...
Ada.
I am unhappy...
...because I... want you...
...because my mind has seized on you
and can think of nothing else.
This is why I suffer.
I...
...am sick with longing.
I don't eat. I don't sleep.
So, if you've come
with no feeling for me...
...then go.
Go.
Get out.
Leave!
What?
Whisper it.
Now you are going I am miserable.
Why is that?
Ada, I need to know what will
you do. Will you come again?
Wait...
I don't know what you're thinking.
Does this mean something to you?
I already miss you.
Ada...
...do you love me?
Come tomorrow.
If you are serious, come tomorrow.
Mumma, stay still!
MUMMA! MUMMA!
THEY'RE PLAYING YOUR PIANO!
Here, Papa.
You shouldn't have gone
up there, should you?
I don't like it, and nor does Papa.
We can play cards if you like.
She's asleep. Look.
One night she was found
on the road to London.
Grandpa said her feet were cut very
badly. She couldn't walk for a week.
Ada.
Alisdair, is it because of our play?
Have the natives aggressed you?
Well, I'll have to say.
You have done the wrong thing here.
You've put the latch on
the outside. You see.
Now when you close the door...
...it will be the Maoris
that lock you in. You see.
With the latch on that side,
you are quite trapped.
Quite trapped.
We have just come from George Baines. They
have taken him over. No wonder he is leaving.
He got in too deep with the natives.
- They sit on his floors as proud as kings...
- ...but without any shred of manners!
He's quite altered. As if they've been
trying some native witchcraft on him.
Well, tomorrow or the day after he'll be gone.
So Baines is packing up?
Well, he's nothing to pack, but he's
leaving. And it is just as well.
Nessie has foolishly grown fond of him.
We have had some tears.
Stop it! Stop!
STOP!
I am frightened of the way back.
We must leave in good light.
Will we be safe?
Oh, yes. If you leave now,
I'm sure of it.
Nessie, hold this.
You know, I am thinking of the piano?
She does not play the piano
as we do, Nessie. Up! Up!
No. She is a strange creature.
And her playing is strange...
...like a mood that passes into you.
Up!
Now, your playing is plain and true
and that is what I like.
To have a sound creep
inside you is not at all pleasant.
What's that?
It's a pigeon.
I should have waited.
I want to touch you.
Why can't I touch you?
Don't you like me?
Come on, Lucky! Who's gonna be
my friend? I'm coming to get you!
We must... get on.
I've decided to...
...trust you to stay here.
You won't see Baines?
Good.
Perhaps with time...
you might come to like me.
Stop complaining, I said.
And be quiet.
You just have to be naked until
I finish washing and drying your clothes.
I don't mind if you're cold.
Be quiet!
No, we're not supposed to visit him.
What?
# The grand old Duke of York
He had ten thousand men
# He marched them up
to the top of the hill
# And marched them down again
# And when they're up, they're up
# And when they're down,
they're down
# And when they're only halfway up
They're neither up nor down #
Crooked, Mister Tewart.
Crooked.
Mother want me to give this to Mr. Baines.
I thought maybe it was not
the proper thing to do.
- Shall I open it?
- No. Give it to me.
Why? I trusted you!
I TRUSTED YOU! I TRUSTED YOU!
D'YOU HEAR?!
Why do you make me hurt you?!
We could be happy.
YOU MAKE ME ANGRY! SPEAK!
YOU LIED TO ME!
SPEAK! OR, BY GOD,
YOU WILL ANSWER FOR THIS!
DO YOU LOVE HIM?!
DO YOU?!
- IS IT HIM YOU LOVE?!
- SHE SAYS... NO!
MOTHER!
Mumma!
You give this to Baines.
Tell him if he ever sees her again,
I'll take off another..
...and another and another...
- Mumma!
- RUN!
What has happened?
Hush, hush!
What is it?
You are not to see her,
he'll chop her up!
What happened? Tell me.
TELL ME!
Where is she?
Ssh! Quiet down! Quiet down!
Where is she?!
HE CHOPPED IT OFF!
What did she tell him?
- I am going to crush his skull!
- NO! NO! NO!
He'll chop them off!
You pushed me too hard. You cannot
send love to him. You cannot do that.
Just even... even to think
about it makes me very angry.
I meant to love you.
I clipped your wing, that's all.
# We will be together #
# You will see it will be better #
Are you hot? My sweet love bird.
Are you feeling better?
What?
Look at you.
It's your face.
I've had that face in my head
hating it.
But now I'm here seeing it...
it's nothing.
You have your marks.
You look at me through your eyes.
You're even afraid of me.
Get up.
Baines...
...has Ada ever spoken to you?
You mean in signs?
No. Words.
Have you ever heard words?
No. Not words.
You never thought you heard words?
I heard it here. I heard her voice.
There in my head.
The lips didn't make the words.
But, yet, the harder I
listened... the clearer I heard her.
You punished her wrongly.
It was me... my fault.
She said...
"I am afraid of my will...
...of what it might do.
It is so strange and strong."
She said...
"I have to go. Let me go.
Let Baines take me away.
Let him try and save me."
I wish her gone. I wish you gone.
I want to wake up...
...and find that this...
...was all a dream.
That's what I want.
It was a terrible shock.
Oh, dear!
No. She needs it. She must have it.
- What did she say?
- She said, "Throw the piano overboard."
It's quite safe. They are managing.
She doesn't want it.
She says it's spoiled!
I've been given the key.
I'll have it mended.
Please, Ada. Ada!
You'll regret it. It's your
piano, I want you to have it.
- She doesn't want it!
- Sit down!
- Throw it over!
- Stop!
All right, we'll throw it over.
'What a death.
'What a chance.
'What a surprise!
'My will has chosen life.
'Still, it has had me spooked,
and many others besides.
'I teach piano now in Nelson.
'George has fashioned
me a metal fingertip.
'I'm quite the town freak,
which satisfies.
'I am learning to speak.
'My sound is still so bad
I feel ashamed.
'I practise only
when I am alone and it is dark.'
'At night I think of my piano
in its ocean grave...
'...and sometimes of myself
floating above it.
'Down there everything is so still
and silent that it lulls me to sleep.
'It is a weird lullaby,
and so it is...
'It is mine.'
"'There is a silence
where hath been no sound
where no sound may be
"'In the cold grave,
under the deep deep sea."'