After weeks
of campaigning on the road,
Tony Blair and his family
finally strolled
the few hundred yards
to the polling station
this election day morning.
Amongst the Labour faithful,
up and down the country,
there is an enormous sense of pride
in Mr. Blair's achievements,
and the confidence
that he is about to become the
youngest prime minister this century.
- Have you voted yet, Mr. Crawford?
- Yes, ma'am.
I was there when they opened.
First in line. 7:00.
I don't mind telling you,
it wasn't for Mr. Blair.
- You're not a modernizer, then?
- Certainly not.
We're in danger of losing too much
that is good about this country as it is.
There is
a growing sense of excitement.
This really could be
the beginning of a new...
I envy you being able to vote.
Not the actual ticking of the box,
although it would be...
Well, it would be nice
to experience that once.
But the sheer joy of being partial.
Yes. Of course, one forgets that,
as sovereign,
- you're not entitled to vote.
- No.
Still, you won't catch me feeling
sorry for you.
You might not be allowed
to vote, ma'am,
But it is your government.
Yes.
I suppose that is some consolation.
Good morning.
- Shall I draw the curtains?
- Yes, please.
So, did you stay up all night?
Yes, ma'am.
And was it as expected?
Yes, ma'am. Mr. Blair,
by a landslide.
Oh, I see.
They've stopped
the traffic completely
for Tony Blair's first day of power
in London.
You've got the ceremonial,
the tourists, the official,
and you've got a lovely summer's day.
Tony Blair waving to the crowds,
people waving to them there.
I guess most of them do know
it's the Prime Minister in waiting.
Lining the streets there.
The Prime Minister's
on his way, ma'am.
To be, Robin. Prime Minister to be.
I haven't asked him yet.
He's a hard one to read, isn't he?
Yes. On the one hand,
his background is quite Establishment.
Father a Conservative,
educated at Fettes
where he was tutored by the same man
as the Prince of Wales.
Well, we'll try not to hold that
against him.
On the other, his manifesto promises
the most radical modernization
and shake up of the constitution
in 300 years.
Do you think he's going to try
and modernize us?
Well, I wouldn't put it past him.
He's married to a woman with known
anti-monarchist sympathies.
You may remember her curtsy
the first time you met.
It could be described as "shallow".
I don't measure the depth of a curtsy,
Robin. I leave that to my sister.
And the atmosphere at Downing Street
is expected to be very informal.
Everyone on first name terms
at the Prime Minister's insistence.
- What, as in, "Cal| me Tony"?
- Yes, ma'am.
Oh, I don't like that.
Have we sent him a protocol sheet?
Funny, I'm actually rather nervous.
Why?
You've met her often enough before.
I know, but never one-to-one,
and never as Prime Minister.
Well, just remember,
you're a man that's just been elected
by the whole nation.
But she's still, you know, the Queen.
The audience room is upstairs.
When we reach the audience room,
I will knock.
We will not wait to be called,
we shall go straight inside.
Standing by the door,
we bow from the neck.
I will introduce you,
the Queen will extend her hand.
You go to her, bow again,
then shake her hand.
Couple of other things.
It's "ma'am" as in "ham."
Not "ma'am" as in "farm."
And when you're in the presence,
at no point must you show your back.
- The "presence"?
- Yes, sir.
That's what it's called
when you're in Her Majesty's company.
Would you like to sit there, Mrs. Blair?
Mr. Blair, Your Majesty.
How nice to see you again, Mr. Blair.
- And congratulations.
- Thank you, ma'am.
- Your children must be very proud.
- I hope so.
- You've three, haven't you?
- That's right.
Oh, how lovely. Such a blessing,
children. Please, do sit down.
Thank you, ma'am.
Have we shown you how to start
a nuclear war yet?
No.
Oh, first thing we do, apparently.
Then we take away your passport
and spend the rest of the time
sending you around the world.
You obviously know my job better
than I do.
Yes, well, you are
my tenth prime minister, Mr. Blair.
My first, of course,
was Winston Churchill.
He sat in your chair
in frock coat and top hat.
He was kind enough to give a shy
young girl like me quite an education.
I can imagine.
With time, one has hopefully added
experience to that education,
and a little wisdom.
Better enabling us to execute
our constitutional responsibility.
To advise, guide, and warn
the government of the day.
Advice which I look forward
to receiving.
Yes, well, we'll save that
for our weekly meetings.
If there's nothing else, I believe
we have some business to attend to.
Of course.
Your Majesty,
my party has won the election,
and so I come now to ask your
permission to form a government.
No, Mr. Blair.
Mr. Blair, I ask the question.
The duty falls upon me,
as your sovereign,
to invite you to become Prime Minister
and to form a government in my name.
And if you agree,
the custom is to say, "Yes".
Yes.
Mrs. Blair, how lovely to see you again.
And congratulations.
You must be very proud.
- Yes.
- And exhausted, I imagine.
Where will you
be spending the summer?
- France.
- Oh, lovely.
You'll be in Balmoral, I expect.
Yes. Yes, |can't wait.
It's a wonderful place.
You know, my great,
great-grandmother Victoria said of it,
"In Balmoral, all seems to breathe
freedom and peace"
"and make one forget the world
and its sad turmoils."
- Your Majesty.
- Oh, excuse me.
There's some
breaking news, Your Majesty.
Oh, really?
- Yes, we need to know how to respond.
- Oh, yes, of course.
I'm so sorry, we're going
to have to leave it there.
Not too short, was it? Fifteen minutes.
One doesn't want to be rude.
No, ma'am.
Morning, sir.
"Thank you very much for coming.
Now fuck off."
- I know. What was all that about?
- God knows. Diana.
Whatever it is, it'll be something
to do with Diana.
Princess Diana
embroiled in more controversy
as she pulls out
of a meeting with MPs.
Princess Diana moved today
to patch up her relations
with the former royal nanny.
Princess Diana flew to Milan today
for the memorial service
for the murdered Italian
fashion designer Gianni Versace.
Where, tonight,
another royal controversy sparkles.
After finding herself embroiled
in her second controversy this week.
I am not a political figure.
Princess Diana sailed out
into the Mediterranean
in one of Mr. Mohamed Al Fayed's
yachts today...
with his son.
Quarter of a million pounds
for the photographs,
which appear to show
the couple embracing.
Once again,
her judgment's under scrutiny.
Earlier today,
they visited a local jewelry shop.
Robin Janvrin.
What?
- Tell Sir Guy I want everyone in, ASAP.
- Sir.
Ma'am?
Yes?
- Ma'am, Mr. Janvrin is here to see you.
- What?
What the...
Good evening, ma'am.
I'm sorry to disturb,
but I've just had a call
from our embassy in Paris.
It's the Princess of Wales.
Why? What's she done now?
I see. Who are we speaking to there?
Right. Well, keep me updated.
It's Diana.
She's been in a car accident in Paris.
Is it serious?
Apparently Dodi Fayed is dead.
Let's just recap on the details
of those injuries, Maxine.
Yes, Nick. What they're saying is that
the Princess is in the intensive care
unit of a southeast Paris hospital.
She has concussion,
a broken arm and...
What was she doing in Paris?
I thought she was supposed
to be in London.
Oh, you know what she's like.
Charles, isn't this awful?
The British Prime Minister, Tony Blair,
has been awakened and is being...
What are you going
to do about the boys?
- Let them sleep until we know more.
- Yes, that's sensible.
I should go to Paris. I told my people
to start organizing a jet.
- What, a private one?
- Yes.
But isn't that precisely
the sort of extravagance
they always attack us for?
How else am I supposed
to get to Paris at this time of night?
The airport at Aberdeen will be closed.
Charles. Charles, dear.
Use the Royal Flight.
They keep one plane
on permanent standby
in case I should kick the bucket.
No, Mummy. That's out of the question.
This isn't a matter of state.
What are you talking about?
Diana is no longer a member
of the Royal Family.
She's not an HRH.
This is a private matter.
She's mother to your grandchildren.
- What is happening now?
- I don't know. I can't hear.
Everyone's shouting.
- Thanks for coming in.
- The ambassador in Paris.
Good evening, sir.
Yes?
The Princess's bodyguard
is said to be badly injured.
I have just spoken to our ambassador
in Paris, ma'am.
I'm afraid it's not good news.
No!
No.
No, no, no, no.
Diana, Princess of Wales,
has died after a car crash in Paris.
The French Government
announced her death
just before 5:00 this morning.
What have I got on this week?
You're writing your maiden conference
speech as Prime Minister.
Well, let's cancel everything else.
This is going to be massive.
Her death was confirmed
by the French interior minister...
I'd better make a statement
in the morning.
Well, you'll be pleased to know I've
already started coming up with ideas.
God, she's only been dead an hour.
Or would you prefer I didn't do my job?
At some point later on
today, I shall have to go to Paris.
You try and be very, very brave, Wills,
all right?
Because it's what
mummy would have wanted.
They're going to go back to sleep.
Try, anyway.
My private secretary's office have
found a travel agency
open in New York that will
sell me a flight to Paris with an hour's
stopover in Manchester.
Perhaps now you might like to consider
whether it's still an extravagance
to bring back the mother
of the future King of England
in one of our planes?
All right. Of course.
John, I don't want the boys
to see the news and get upset.
First thing in the morning, I want
the radio taken out of the bedroom
and the television
taken out of the nursery.
Yes, ma'am.
- Well, well, well.
- Yes.
Are you all right?
Your sister called from Tuscany.
Well, I hope you told her to come back,
cut her holiday short.
I did.
I can't imagine she was pleased.
That's putting it mildly.
- What did she say?
- Something about
Diana managing to be
even more annoying dead than alive.
Just make sure you never let the boys
hear you talk like that.
Of course.
Something to help you go down.
No, I think I'll write my diary
a little longer.
Fine. I'm going to bed.
We've heard nothing
official from the Palace yet.
We still don't know
when we're going to get
any further statements
from inside the Palace
or, of course,
when the Royal Family are due back.
And that's how she will remain
in our minds, our hearts
forever.
Okay? Got it.
Well, where Will you do it?
We'll do it at the church
- on the way in.
- All right. I'll organize it.
Viscount Althorp,
Diana's brother, had this to say...
Hang on. I want to watch this.
This is not a time
for recriminations, but for sadness.
However, I would say
that I always believed
the press would kill her in the end.
But not even I could imagine
that they would take
such a direct hand in her death
as seems to be the case.
It would appear that every proprietor
and editor of every publication
that has paid for intrusive
and exploitative photographs of her
has blood on his hands today.
Not the press, mate.
You've got the wrong villain.
Tony.
Got to go.
You about to speak to the Queen?
Yeah.
Ask her if she greased the brakes.
Now, now.
Thanks.
Hello?
Putting you through,
Prime Minister.
- Oh, right. Okay.
- Please hold.
Is the Prince of Wales with the boys?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Good. And he's going to Paris?
Yes.
I'm sorry to disturb, ma'am. Ma'am.
But I've the Prime Minister for you
from his constituency.
Lucky you.
Thank you, Robin.
I'll take it in the study.
- Good morning, Your Majesty.
- Prime Minister.
May I say right away
how very sorry I am
and that the thoughts and prayers
of my family are with you
at this terrible time.
And with the princes, in particular.
Thank you.
Is it your intention to make some kind
of appearance or statement?
No. No, certainly not.
No member of the Royal Family
will speak publicly about this.
This is a private matter.
We would all appreciate it
if it could be respected as such.
I see.
I don't suppose anyone's had time
to think about the funeral yet?
Well, we've spoken
with the Spencer family
and it is their wish,
it is their express wish,
that this should be a private funeral
with a memorial service to follow
in a month or so.
Right.
And given that Diana was no longer
a member of the Royal Family
we have no other choice
but to respect their wishes.
I see.
You don't feel that, in view of her
high profile and popularity,
it might be an idea to pay tribute
to her life and achievements?
Or even just to her as a mother?
Well, as I said, it's her family's wish.
And the public, ma'am?
The British people?
You don't think a private funeral might
be denying them a chance...
A chance to what?
To share in the grief?
This is a family funeral, Mr. Blair,
not a fairground attraction.
I think the Princess has already paid
a high enough price for exposure
to the press, don't you?
Now, if there's nothing else,
I must get on.
The children have to be looked after.
Of course.
Well, goodbye, Your Majesty.
Her instinct is to do nothing.
Say nothing,
- and give her a private funeral.
- Are you surprised?
She hated her guts.
Well, I think it's a mistake.
They screwed up her life. Let's hope
they don't screw up her death.
Where can I get a black tie?
Oh, the chaplain called.
He wanted to know whether we should
make any changes in the service.
Any special mention of Diana.
What did you say?
- Well, I told him not to change a thing.
- Quite right.
I think the less attention
one draws to it, the better.
- For the boys.
- Yes.
But I think maybe we should find some
company for them,
some young people-
I'll take them for a long walk
this afternoon.
- Up Craggy Head.
- Yes, but no guns, Philip. It is Sunday.
And we're going... We're going, in fact,
I believe to Sedgefield,
the Prime Minister's constituency,
Where he is about
to make a statement.
Yes, the Prime Minister, coming now
with his wife, Cherie.
Yeah, well, apart from that...
He's on. Alastair, he's on. Come on.
Her own life was often,
sadly, touched by tragedy.
She touched the lives
of so many others
in Britain, throughout the world,
with joy and with comfort.
The people everywhere,
not just here in Britain, everywhere.
They kept faith with Princess Diana.
They liked her. They loved her.
They regarded her
as one of the people.
She was the people's princess.
And that's how she will stay,
how she will remain,
in our hearts and in our
memories, forever.
Bit over the top, don't you think?
The Prime Minister
paying his own tribute
to the Princess of Wales.
"The people of Britain," he said,
"kept faith with Princess Diana.
"They loved her.
She was the people's princess."
Did we remember the Royal Standard?
Yes, sir.
- And flowers?
- Yes, sir.
Good, because if we leave it to
the royal undertakers,
they'll bring her back
in a wooden crate.
- Hello?
- This is Lord Airlie.
May I speak with
the Prime Minister, please?
One moment, please. Lord Airlie.
The Lord Chamberlain
in charge of the funeral.
You're meeting him at the airport.
Lord Airlie.
Good afternoon, Prime Minister.
It's my job to organize
all the ceremonial events.
There is simply no precedent
for the funeral of an ex-HRH.
Perhaps we should plan
for any contingency.
Yes, I propose a meeting
at 10:00 tomorrow morning.
At Buckingham Palace.
Officials from all three palaces,
representatives from the Spencer
family, the emergency services.
And would you send
some of your people?
Absolutely. Of course.
"Precedent"?
Where do they find these people'?
Thank you, Airlie.
Brigadier Sir Charles Wilton,
Household Division.
Air Commodore Wessex,
Queen's Flight.
Prime Minister.
I'm so sorry, sir.
And if there's anything I
or my government can do...
They stood up as we drove past
in cafes, in restaurants,
removed their hats.
This was Paris,
one of the busiest cities in the world
and you could hear a pin drop.
I imagine it will be the same here.
The Palace would still prefer
to see this as a private funeral.
What are your feelings on that?
I...
I think that'll present
us with difficulties.
So do I.
My mother, the Queen, comes from
a generation not best equipped.
She grew up in the war.
I think what we need,
what this country needs,
is a more modern perspective,
if you follow?
Balmoral is...
I think I understand.
An aircraft
of the Queen's Flight
brought the Princess's body
home this evening,
where the Prime Minister, Tony Blair,
had gathered with members
of his government.
A single black hearse
crossed the tarmac
and a Royal Air Force Guard
of Honour moved slowly forward.
Has anyone heard
from the Spencers yet?
Have they made up their minds
when the funeral will be?
The Prince of Wales had
accompanied the body back from...
Oh, I don't know.
Nobody tells me anything.
President Clinton
was with his wife
when he heard the news last night.
We liked her very much.
We admired her work for children,
for people with AIDS,
for the cause of ending the scourge
of landmines in the world...
On our walk today, one of the ghillies
said he'd seen a large stag
up Craggy Head.
This is a very difficult time...
He reckoned 14 points.
We haven't had one as big as that
on the estate for years.
No. Quite.
And I was tremendously impressed...
Anyway, I thought it might be
a good distraction
- for the boys.
- What? Stalking?
You don't think
that's a bit soon, do you?
I think anything that gets them outside
is a good idea.
In 1981 brought
glamour to the Royal Family.
But as their relationship deteriorated,
she became
an increasingly unhappy figure.
The couple divorced
in August of last year.
It was the love story that brought
crowds onto the streets.
They came to see the Queen,
of course, and the Prince,
but most of all
they came to see Diana.
I'm going to bed.
But the seemingly perfect fairy tale
was destined not to...
I'll ring the Lord Chamberlain's office.
Say we're going
to send representatives
to the meeting tomorrow morning
at 10:00.
Thank you, Stephen.
She gave us so much.
Why couldn't we have given her a little
something and left her alone?
It just hurts me so much.
I've never experienced
anything like this. I can't...
I think I'm... I keep waiting to wake up
like it's a bad dream.
Right, it's 10:00.
Let's get started, shall we?
And thank you all for coming
at such short notice.
I think we all agree that this is an
extraordinarily sensitive occasion
which presents us with tremendous
challenges: logistically,
constitutionally, practically,
diplomatically, and procedurally.
Oh, Christ!
After 18 years of opposition,
I am proud to stand before you
as the new Prime Minister
of our country...
Labour Prime Minister.
I want to set an ambitious course
to modernize this country,
to breathe new life into old institutions.
To make privilege
something for the many, not the few.
Flipping heck!
You think the Royals are nutters?
You should meet their flunkies.
Two and a half hours on whether
she should be carried in a hearse
or a gun carriage.
Anyway, you got raves in the press.
This lot call you,
"The nation's mourner in chief."
This lot says you're the only person
who's correctly judged the mood
of the country.
Hello?
Even the Mail was impressed.
"People's princess," mate.
You owe me.
- Gordon, for you.
- Te|| him to hang on.
Alastair.
So have they come to their senses?
Is it gonna be a public funeral?
Yeah. Saturday. It's a Whopper.
- The Abbey, the works.
- Great.
Has anyone told the Queen yet?
I don't know. No doubt some flunky
will be dispatched
groveling on all fours.
Are you game?
Do you think it's wise for the boys
to go stalking so soon?
Anything that gets
them into the fresh air is a good thing.
Maybe they shouldn't take their guns.
I mean, if a photographer
were to see them,
it might send out the wrong signal.
If there is a photographer out there
he could be the first kill of the day.
I see Mr. Fayed was buried last night.
At midnight. No cameras, no fuss.
Very dignified.
Why do they do that?
Why do they bury their bodies
so soon after the death?
Islamic tradition.
Something to do with the heat.
Stops the body decomposing.
Yes, come in.
Good morning, ma'am. Ma'am.
Yes, Robin. What can we do for you?
Ma'am, there was a meeting
at the Palace this morning.
About the funeral
arrangements, yes.
The Lord Chamberlain faxed over
these plans for you to consider.
There is now
general agreement, ma'am,
that a public funeral
would be more appropriate.
I see.
And what form will this funeral take?
At the moment, they're suggesting,
and, of course, these are early days,
basing it on Tay Bridge.
- Tay Bridge?
- What?
Tay Bridge is the codename
for my funeral.
Indeed, ma'am.
But it would be for
practical reasons only.
It's the only one
which has been rehearsed.
The only one that could be
put together in time.
But I supervised those plans myself.
Indeed, and the Lord Chamberlain
was at pains to stress
that the spirit of the occasion
will be quite different.
For example, the suggestion is
that instead of 400 soldiers,
400 representatives
of the Princess's various charities
march behind the coffin.
And instead of foreign heads of state
and crown heads of Europe,
the guests would include a sprinkling
of actors of stage and screen,
fashion designers,
and other celebrities.
Celebrities?
Was there, was there anything else?
No, ma'am.
Oh, yes, one other thing.
The Police Commissioner
was keen that you consider
the idea of a condolence book.
It would give the growing crowds
something to do,
make marshaling them easier.
Oh, yes. Yes, of course.
Oh, and the flowers.
What flowers?
The flowers outside
Buckingham Palace.
At the moment they're blocking
the path through the main gate
and it will make things difficult
for the Changing of the Guard.
Oh, fine. Then just move them away.
Actually, the Lord Chamberlain
was wondering
whether we shouldn't leave the flowers
and send the Guards
through the North Gate.
Oh, yes. Yes, of course.
Yes, quite right.
Stephen Lamport on one.
Who?
The Prince of Wales's
private secretary. Balmoral.
He says it's urgent.
It's all right.
Good morning.
Good morning, Prime Minister.
The Prince of Wales has asked me.
To thank you again
for your kind words yesterday.
Not at all.
The Prince feels that
you and he are both modern men
of similar mind.
Who could work well together
at this difficult time.
Well, please thank His Highness,
and assure him he can count
on my full support at all times.
Was that it?
Yes.
Goodbye.
Bizarre.
- Why is Charles doing this?
- What?
Creeping up to me like this?
Banging on about being modern.
He did it at the airport when he asked
me to deal with his mother.
Because he knows that if the Queen
continues to get it wrong over Diana,
then the Royals will become
public enemy number one.
And he's terrified
of being shot, apparently.
Who, Charles?
His people have already been on to us
to ask for extra protection.
Well, he probably thinks
that if he's seen to be on our side,
then that'll leave the Queen
in the firing line.
What? So it's okay for his mother
to take the bullet and not him?
What a family.
- Wait. Where are they?
- They're up at Craggy Head.
Come on. Yes.
I'll come with you.
- Go on. In you go.
- Do you want me to drive?
No. Certainly not.
I thought you were going to get
a new one of these.
What for? It's perfectly all right.
I was thinking last night what Diana
might have done
had it been me that died
in the tunnel in Paris.
She would certainly have taken
the boys to Paris.
I rather regret not doing that now.
And expose them to the media?
No, that would have been a dreadful
thing to do.
No, they're much better off here.
It's private, they're protected.
Whatever else you may have thought
of Diana, she was a wonderful mother.
She adored those boys,
and never let them forget it.
Always warm and physical.
Never afraid to show her feelings.
Especially whenever a photographer
was in sight.
Yes, she may have encouraged all that,
but, still,
that was always
the extraordinary thing about her.
Her weaknesses and transgressions
only made the public love her more.
Yet ours only make them hate us.
Why is that?
Why do they hate us so much?
- Not us, dear.
- What?
Yesterday, when we brought the coffin
back, there was a noise, a bang.
I don't mind telling you,
I thought it was a gun.
I thought someone
had taken a shot at me.
Think I'm going to walk back.
I don't feel like stalking.
- Are you sure?
- I'll take the dogs.
Walkies? Yes!
Who knows the way home? Come on.
Do you think
you will ever be Queen?
No, I don't. No.
Why do you think that?
I'd like to be a queen of people's
hearts, in people's hearts.
But I don't see myself
being Queen of this country.
I don't think many people would want
me to be Queen, actually.
When I say many people, I mean the
Establishment that I'm married into,
because they've decided
that I'm a non-starter.
But by the time...
Charles and I had a talk
in the car today.
He was good enough to share with me
his thoughts on motherhood.
What did he say?
How wonderful Diana was.
That's changing his tune.
What a natural.
That's precluded you, effectively,
from becoming Queen.
They see me as a threat of some kind.
Oh, for God's sake!
Maybe he's got a point.
Maybe we are partly to blame.
Oh, I can't watch this.
No, no. Wait, please. No, leave it.
Because I don't go by a rule book.
Because I lead from the heart,
not the head.
And albeit that's got me into trouble
in my work, I understand that...
We encouraged the match.
We signed off on it, both of us.
You were very enthusiastic, remember?
She was a nice girl,
then.
And I was sure
he'd give the other one up.
Or at least make sure his wife
toed the line.
Isn't that what everyone does?
Is it?
Do you think
Mrs. Parker Bowles was a factor
in the breakdown of your marriage?
Well, there were three of us in this
marriage. So it was a bit crowded.
Four months later...
I can't bear it anymore.
If you're watching, I'll sleep next door.
Early start tomorrow.
- Any luck with your stag?
- No.
But close.
A couple of hundred yards at one point.
One of the boys even got a shot off.
We'll get him tomorrow.
See you in the morning.
Not to worry.
Night-night.
And her struggle with
the eating disorder, bulimia.
And her obsession with the belief.
That Charles continued to love
a woman he'd fallen for years before,
Camilla...
The good news is that
the Palace has agreed
- to video screens in the Royal Parks.
- And the bad news?
- Crash barriers.
- What about them?
Well, they're now predicting
more than two million people
will descend on London
and there aren't enough barriers
to line the route.
So, we've gone cap in hand
to the French for theirs.
And there's something else
I think you should see.
- Can we run that piece again?
- Of course.
You're gonna love this.
I find their behavior very disgraceful.
What do you think, madam?
I think it's disgusting that they've
not appeared or said a word
relating to all this.
- Look, I know all this.
- Wait for it.
Not to have a flag up.
I think it's a disgrace
on the whole Royal Family.
Okay, the Queen's not in residence
today, but where the hell is the flag?
You see what I'm saying
about the Establishment?
Don't tell me there isn't a flag flying
at half mast over Buckingham Palace?
She was their King and Queen.
Dodi, them two were together.
- It was a fairy tale come true.
- God!
Will someone please save these
people from themselves?
- Fine, I'll call Balmoral.
- Planet Zog.
Because as Prime Minister,
I've really got nothing better to do.
Come on, dogs. Come on.
Those firelighters all right? Bit damp?
Oh, well, I brought some stew
just in case.
I think it's lamb.
We could always have that cold.
No, we'll be all right.
Stay.
Robin had a call
from the Prime Minister
who expressed his concern.
About what?
About the flag
above Buckingham Palace.
He thinks it should be flying
at half mast.
And I hope Robin told him there isn't
a flag above Buckingham Palace.
There's the Royal Standard,
which flies for one reason only,
to denote the presence of the monarch.
Since you're here the flagpole is bare,
which is as it should be.
Isn't it possible that, for some people,
the Royal Standard is just a flag?
And that the flagpole being bare
sends out the wrong signal?
No, that's not the point.
The point is,
it's more than 400 years old.
It's never been lowered for anyone.
Your grandfather didn't get the flag
at half mast when he died.
And if your mother died tomorrow,
she wouldn't either.
Yes, Granny, but sometimes,
in a situation like this,
one has to be flexible.
It is just a flag.
"What about the Union Jack?"
was Mr. Blair's next suggestion.
- For Heaven's sake.
- The next thing he'll be suggesting
you change your name to Hilda
and mine to Hector!
Who does he think he's talking to?
You're the Sovereign,
the Head of State.
You don't get dictated to.
You've conceded the idea
of a public funeral.
You've opened up the Parks.
That's enough!
The boys.
You wait. In 48 hours,
this will all have calmed down.
Well, in one sense it's comforting.
For the first time, my parents can see
what it's been like for me
all these years,
being up against her popularity.
But they're still making the mistake
of thinking the Diana they knew
from living and dealing with her
will eventually be the one seen
by the public, but it won't.
The two Diana's, the public's and ours,
bear no relation to one another at all.
I've been thinking,
the flag of Saint George's is
at half mast over Highgrove?
Yes, sir.
Well, make sure we get a picture
of that in the papers, will you?
I'll get on to the tabloids.
Call in a few favors.
What about a statement of gratitude
to the crowds?
Something heartfelt
from myself and the boys,
thanking people for all the flowers
and so on.
Right.
Di was wonderful because she
stood up to the Establishment.
We have no one doing that now.
She said, you're detached,
elitist people,
we are paying millions of pounds
to be better than us,
and you've gotta get out there
amongst the people.
We have a wonderful new
Prime Minister in England, Tony Blair.
A compassionate young man
who, after 18 years
of Establishment Tory rule,
it's such a breath of fresh air.
And I feel he will do something
about this in England, I really do.
I bet you this'|| be
the first stirrings of...
What?
I don't know.
Something more interesting.
You know, maybe this time
people will finally have seen them
for what they actually are.
Which is?
A bunch of freeloading,
emotionally retarded nutters.
- That's just absurd.
- Why?
They live in a ludicrous cocoon
of privilege and wealth.
- And they don't pay tax.
- Yes, they do.
Not on all their income.
The Queen alone costs us what,
thirty, forty million a year?
Look, if you want to have
a serious conversation about this...
- I do.
- About the constitution.
- We don't have one.
- About ways in which we,
as a government,
could phase out hereditary privileges,
then fine.
If you're gonna leave,
will you take the plate?
But, you know, spare me the whole
"off with their heads" thing.
- Why?
- Because it insults your intelligence.
The Queen cannot be expected
to change.
It's unimaginable,
this country being a republic.
- Certainly in her lifetime.
- Why?
Because no one would wear it.
No one wants it.
It's just
daft.
- It's not a mother thing, is it?
- What?
Well, if she were alive now,
your mother would be
exactly the same age.
I mean, you were always saying
how stoical she was.
Old fashioned, uncomplaining,
lived through the war.
Oh, come on.
Who does that sound like'?
I'm gonna do the washing up.
That's the stalking party off.
Right. We'd better have a look
at those papers.
"Show us there's a heart in the
House of Windsor," says The Sun.
"It's proof the Royals are not like us,"
the Mirror.
"Time to change the old guard
at Buckingham Palace," Express.
"One can't help wondering
whose advice they are taking"
"for it's clearly the wrong advice."
I'll try not to take that personally.
"People have been yearning
for a change in this country." Good.
"The result is a quiet revolution
now taking place,"
"led by the real modernizers,
the British people."
Revolution? Who wrote this?
Where does this come from?
Where does it come from?
You just won a huge landslide majority.
And people want to see a change.
Why? What did you think it meant?
Hurry up, dear. Your tea's getting cold.
- Is that it?
- Yes, ma'am.
Just the letter of condolence to
the widow of the ambassador to Brazil.
Good. Thank you.
Tea! Oh, good.
Mr. Janvrin, the Prime Minister wishes
to speak to Her Majesty.
Ma'am.
Apparently, the Prime Minister
is on the phone for you.
Tell him to call back.
No, no, it's all right. I'll take it.
Prime Minister?
Good morning, Your Majesty.
Sorry to disturb.
But I was just wondering whether
you'd seen any of today's papers?
We've managed to look
at one or two, yes.
In which case,
my next question would be
whether you felt
some kind of response
might be necessary?
No.
I believe a few over-eager editors
are doing their best to sell newspapers,
and it would be a mistake
to dance to their tune.
Under normal circumstances,
I would agree.
But, well, my advisers have been
taking the temperature
among people on the streets,
and, well, the information I'm getting
is that the mood
is quite delicate.
So, what would you suggest,
Prime Minister?
Some kind of statement?
No, ma'am.
I believe the moment for statements
has passed.
I would suggest flying the flag at
half mast above Buckingham Palace.
And
coming down to London
at the earliest opportunity.
It would be a great comfort
to your people
and would help them with their grief.
Their grief?
If you imagine
I'm going to drop everything
and come down to London
before I attend to my grandchildren
who've just lost their mother,
then you're mistaken.
I doubt there is anyone
who knows the British people
more than I do, Mr. Blair,
nor who has greater faith
in their wisdom and judgment.
And it is my belief that they will,
any moment, reject this...
This mood which is being stirred up
by the press,
in favor of a period of restrained grief
and sober private mourning.
That's the way we do things
in this country.
Quietly. With dignity.
That's what the rest of the world
has always admired us for.
If that's your decision, ma'am, of
course the government will support it.
Let's keep in touch.
Yes. Let's.
Bloody fool.
And now your tea's gone cold.
Tony. Robin Janvrin on one.
He was listening in.
Robin.
I understand how difficult
her behavior must seem to you.
How unhelpful.
But try and see it from her perspective.
She's been brought up to believe
it's God's will,
she is who she is.
I think we should leave God out of it.
It's just not helpful.
She just won't have seen
anything like this since the abdication.
And I cannot emphasize enough
what effect that had on her.
Unexpectedly becoming King
as good as killed her father.
I'm afraid she's in a state of shock.
This public reaction
has completely thrown her.
All right.
But first we have to deal
with these terrible headlines.
I'll see what I can do with the press.
I'm most grateful, Prime Minister.
But I can't promise anything.
It's not me they want to see.
Ask Alastair to come and see me,
would you?
Okay.
And cancel what I'm doing tonight.
- Good morning.
- Your Majesty.
- Morning, ma'am.
- Thomas, where have they gone today?
- Up to Aberganny Reach, ma'am.
All that way.
Remind me, that's right at the fork?
That's right, ma'am.
You follow the track for about a mile,
past Glen Horach,
- and then you come to...
- The river.
One of the lads will drive you.
No, no, that's all right,
I'll manage, thank you. Thank you.
- Ma'am.
Bugger it!
Stupid!
- Hello, Thomas?
- Hello, ma'am.
I'm afraid I've done something
rather foolish.
I've broken the prop shaft
crossing the river.
Are you sure, ma'am?
Yes, of course I'm sure.
It's the front one, not the rear.
Lost the four-wheel drive.
Don't forget, I used to be a mechanic
during the war.
And are you all right?
No, no, I'm perfectly all right.
- We'll come out straight away.
- Oh, would you?
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Yes, I'll wait by the car.
You are kind. Bye.
Oh, you're a beauty.
Go on.
Go on!
I've just been told
there's news crews outside.
Waiting for you to come
and speak to the people.
- Yes.
- What's all that about?
I told the Queen's private secretary
I'd do what I could
to help with the press.
Why?
Don't you think she deserves it?
Sitting up there on her 40,000 acres.
Yes, but allowing her to hang herself
might not be
in our best interests either.
Besides, I think there's something ugly
about the way everyone's started
to bully her.
The first thing
that you obviously think about
is the rest of your family. And I think...
When is she coming
to London, Mr. Blair?
- Well...
- She is our figure head.
- She is our head of this nation.
- She is,
and her thoughts are with us all.
She wanted me to pass on to
the people here, crowding around us...
With a moment to spare,
the Prime Minister
went down Downing Street to have
a word with some of the ordinary...
- How are the boys?
- Not so good tonight.
A lot of slamming doors.
I think they saw the papers.
Oh, no.
I'll take them out early again
tomorrow morning.
Let them take it out on the stag.
What do you think of the way
the Royal Family has behaved?
- They've made a serious mistake.
- Pardon?
They've made a serious mistake.
Why, what do you mean?
Well, they should've came...
They should've...
The family should have come down
to Buckingham Palace
on Sunday afternoon. All of them.
That girl has been left on her own,
she's on her own up there,
and the place is empty.
Oh, please.
Sleeping in the streets
and pulling out their hair
for someone they never knew?
And they think we're mad?
Have you seen
the latest funeral guest list?
No.
I suggest you keep it that way.
A chorus line of soap stars
and homosexuals.
Apparently, Elton John
is going to be singing.
That'll be a first
for Westminster Abbey.
Condolence books are now
being signed in our embassies
in every major city in the world.
And in London alone,
the number has reached 40.
It reminds me of one of those films.
A few of us in a fort.
Hordes of Zulus outside.
So it's vital you hold firm.
Stick to your guns.
You wait, they will come
to their senses soon. They have to.
Come on, move over, cabbage.
Good morning.
It's 6:00 on Thursday
the 4th of September,
I'm Penny Smith.
And I'm Matthew Lorenzo.
As the first people start camping out
on the route of Princess Diana's
funeral cortege,
questions are being asked
about why the Queen
hasn't addressed her subjects
at this time of national grief.
And this is what the
newspapers are saying this morning.
The Sun, "Where is our Queen?
Where is her flag?"
The Express, "Show us you care,"
picture of a grumpy Queen.
The Mail, "Let the flag fly at half mast."
And inside, "The Queen should be here
to show her respects."
But the flip side is, "Blair more
popular now than Churchill. Shock."
But did any of them pick up
on our statement of support?
Well, just the one.
Statements of support
don't sell papers.
Right.
Ma'am? Ma'am?
The Prime Minister for you, ma'am.
I'm afraid he's rather insisting.
I'll take it in the kitchen.
Good morning,
I'm so sorry to disturb you.
I'm just expecting a phone call
to be put through here. Out!
There it is.
Thank you kindly.
- Good morning, Prime Minister.
- Good morning, ma'am.
You've seen today's headlines?
Yes, I have.
Then I'm sure you'll agree
the situation has become
quite critical.
Ma'am, a poll
that's to be published
in tomorrow's papers
suggests that 70% of people believe
that your actions have
damaged the Monarchy.
And that one in four.
Are now in favor of abolishing
the Monarchy altogether.
As your Prime Minister,
I believe it is my constitutional
responsibility to advise
the following.
Is Queen Elizabeth up yet?
Mummy?
One. Fly the flag at half mast
above Buckingham Palace
and all other Royal residences.
Two. Leave Balmoral and fly down
to London at the earliest opportunity.
Three.
Pay respects, in person,
at Diana's coffin.
And, four.
Make a statement via live television
to my people and the world.
Swift prosecution of these matters
might, he felt,
just might avert disaster.
You will have to talk to
the Lord Chamberlain about all this.
I have, and to Robert Fellowes, and
it seems they both agree with Mr. Blair.
I see.
Something has happened.
There's been a change.
Some shift in values.
When you no longer understand
your people, Mummy,
maybe it is time to hand it over
to the next generation.
Don't you be ridiculous.
Remember the vow you took?
"I declare that my whole life,
whether it be long or short,"
"shall be devoted to your service."
Your whole life.
That is a commitment to God
as well as your people.
But what if my actions
are damaging the Crown?
Damaging it?
You're the greatest asset
this institution has.
One of the greatest it has ever had.
No, no.
The problem will come when you leave.
But you mustn't think about that now,
- and certainly not today.
- Oh, Mummy.
You must show more strength.
Reassert your authority.
You sit on the most powerful throne
in Europe.
Head of an unbroken line that goes
back more than a thousand years.
Do you think any of your predecessors
would have dropped everything
and gone up to London
because a bunch of hysterics carrying
candles needed help with their grief?
As for that silly Mr. Blair,
with his Cheshire cat grin...
Mr. Janvrin on the phone for you, sir.
Yes?
What?
I can't hear!
Well, that's madness. The whole thing!
Bloody madness!
I've just been told.
You've decided we're to follow
the Prime Minister's advice.
I just want to say I
admire...
I think it's the right decision.
Let's hope we haven't left it too late.
These are historic shots
that we're witnessing.
Clearly the Queen
has had a change of heart.
She's clearly responding to the need
to feel that the Royal Family
is somehow engaged.
These are flowers that have been
brought to the gates of Balmoral
so that she can actually see
some token of what's been expressed
down here in London.
Fish fingers, do you want any?
Be right there.
Thank God for that!
I'm afraid they're a bit burnt.
FFrom CNN International.
This is World News, with
Ralitsa Vassileva from CNN Center.
Britain's Queen Elizabeth will deliver
a televised address Friday.
The Royal Family has been accused
of not showing enough remorse
over Princess Diana's death.
Where are the boys?
Have they already left?
Yes.
They left for London
after breakfast, with Charles.
It's not right, you know.
No, but further discussion is no longer
helpful either.
Oh, Well.
I suppose it does give the ghillies
time to find another stag for the boys,
- now theirs has been shot.
- What?
Haven't you heard?
He wandered over
to one of the neighboring estates
where one
of the commercial guests got him.
Really?
Which estate?
Here's your box.
There's some policy unit stuff here
that's important.
And have you seen the papers?
No, I thought I'd give them the miss
today. Of course I've seen the papers.
Not bad, eh?
"Your Majesty, come down to London."
"Who
says so?" "Tony Blair."
Mr. Father of the Nation.
Ma'am.
- Good morning, ma'am.
- Morning.
Is it His Lordship you've come to see?
No, no, no, please don't disturb him.
No, I've come on another matter.
I hope you don't mind.
There he is.
He's a beauty, isn't he?
An imperial, ma'am.
Fourteen pointer.
- He was wounded.
- Yes.
We got our guest in very close,
had him lined up perfect.
And, Still...
An investment banker, ma'am,
from London.
I'm afraid the stalkers had to follow
him for miles to finish him off.
Let's hope he didn't suffer too much.
Please pass my congratulations
to your guest.
I will, ma'am.
- God bless you, ma'am.
- Thank you.
Ma'am.
Yes, Robin?
I've done a draft
of your television address.
Thank you.
Was there anything else?
No, ma'am.
Landing in 15 minutes.
I've got the Queen's speech.
All sorts
of things could've gone wrong.
- Should I give Tony a copy?
- No, let me have a look at it first.
Okay. He's next door.
These scenes that began last night,
beginning to atone
for the hurt of the previous week.
And the anger,
as somebody said earlier,
perhaps was just that
people grieving need
to target their anger at somebody.
And Royal protocol might have been
the thing, it got in the way.
But Royal protocol is being swept
aside en masse today.
God bless Diana!
Looked very serious,
Her Majesty and the Duke.
Normally it is a happy occasion
when they arrive here,
and normally when they're out
at the front here.
It's days like Trooping the Colour
or VE Day or VJ Day.
This is a tragic occasion.
It looks as though
the Queen is about to...
She is. She's getting out of the car,
Wes, and is going to talk to people.
It's extremely unusual,
this is almost unprecedented.
I think perhaps the last time
the Queen was among her people
outside the Palace
was the day that war in Europe ended.
It's really, isn't it,
as if the public
and the Royal Family, the Monarchy,
have had a quarrel this week and now
it's being healed in some measure.
Like a family spat. Not unlike
the family spats that they could
acknowledge with Diana.
I mean, dear Jennie is quite right
to say that whatever the
professional ups and downs between
the Queen and the Princess...
They sent a copy
of the Queen's speech.
Might want to scrape
the frost off it first.
And I think the Queen is very
generous in recognizing that
her eldest son wasn't always
the easiest chap to be married to.
I phoned them
with a couple of suggestions
to make it sound like it came
from a human being.
Yeah, all right, Alastair.
She was indifferent...
Well, at least the old bat has finally
agreed to visit Diana's coffin.
You know, when you get it wrong,
you really get it wrong.
That woman has given her whole life
in service to her people.
Fifty years doing a job
she never wanted.
A job she watched kill her father.
She's executed it with honor,
dignity, and as far as I can tell,
without a single blemish,
and now we're all baying for her blood!
All because she's struggling to lead
the world in mourning for someone
who threw everything she offered
back in her face.
And who, for the last few years,
seemed committed 24/7
to destroying everything
she holds most dear!
Hello. Would you like me
to place those for you?
No.
These are for you.
For me?
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Ma'am.
There's been a last minute addition
from Downing Street.
They're suggesting adding
"and as a grandmother," here.
Right.
"So what I say to you now
as your Queen, and as a grandmother."
"I say from my heart."
You think you can say it?
Do I have a choice?
They're ready for you, Your Majesty.
Just to confirm. This is going out live.
Fine.
And you'll be at the front
of the 6:00 news on all the channels.
Yes.
Thank you.
- Okay, nice and quiet.
- Ten seconds, everyone.
We cross now live
to Buckingham Palace
for the Queen's tribute
to Princess Diana.
Since last Sunday's dreadful news.
We have seen, throughout Britain
and around the world,
an overwhelming expression
of sadness at Diana's death.
We have all been trying
in our different ways to cope.
It is not easy to express a sense of loss
since the initial shock.
Is often succeeded by a mixture
of other feelings:
disbelief, incomprehension, anger,
and concern for those who remain.
We have all felt those emotions
in these last few days,
so what I say to you now,
as your Queen, and as a grandmother,
I say from my heart.
Heart? What heart?
She doesn't mean a word of this.
That's not the point.
What she's doing is extraordinary.
In good times and bad she never lost
- her capacity to smile and laugh.
- That's how to survive.
Listen to you.
A week ago you were
the great modernizer
making speeches about
the "people's princess."
Now you've gone weak at the knees.
And especially for her devotion
to her two boys...
You know, I don't know why
I'm so surprised.
At the end of the day, all Labour Prime
Ministers go ga-ga for the Queen.
What?
Millions of others who never met her,
but felt they knew her,
will remember her.
I for one, believe that there are
lessons to be drawn from her life
and from the extraordinary
and moving reaction to her death.
I share in your determination
to cherish her memory.
I hope that tomorrow,
we can all, wherever we are,
join in expressing our grief
at Diana's loss
and gratitude for her all too short life.
May those who died rest in peace,
and may we, each and every one of us,
thank God for someone who made
many, many people happy.
Diana's coffin, now on the move.
The short distance
from St. James's Palace
to her home at Kensington Palace
for the final night
before her burial tomorrow.
It's incredible, less than a week.
Who could have
imagined such scenes?
Diana was the very
essence of compassion, of duty,
of style, of beauty.
A very British girl
who transcended nationality.
Someone with a natural nobility,
who was classless,
and who proved, in the last year,
that she needed no Royal title
to continue to generate her particular
brand of magic.
I would like to end by thanking God
for the small mercies
he's shown us at this dreadful time,
for taking Diana at her most
beautiful and radiant
and when she had joy
in her private life.
Above all, we give thanks for the life
of a woman
I'm so proud to be able
to call my sister,
the unique
the complex, the extraordinary,
and irreplaceable Diana.
Whose beauty,
both internal and external,
will never be extinguished
from our minds.
So, off to see your girlfriend?
Now, now.
You know, I hope she shows you
some respect this time.
It's quite a debt of gratitude
she owes you.
Mr. Savior of the Monarchy.
I doubt she'll see it that way.
- Robin, good to see you.
- Prime Minister.
Tony, please.
The Prime Minister, Your Majesty.
- Do sit down.
- Thank you.
It's good to see you again
after what's been quite a summer.
I'm referring to your visit
to India and Pakistan
where your comments
on ending historic disagreements
went down very well.
And the Commonwealth
Heads of Government Meeting...
I spoke to the Prime Minister of Malawi
and he was saying
how much he appreciated
your tough stance on Nigeria.
I meant to tell you at the time,
but you were being
monopolized rather.
I imagine those occasions
must be quite difficult.
Twenty-four heads of government,
each clamoring for a private audience.
Also, we haven't had a chance to speak
since that week.
And I wanted to offer my apologies.
Whatever for?
In case you felt manhandled
or managed in any way.
No. Not at all.
I don't think I shall ever understand
what happened this summer.
Well, the circumstances were
exceptional, ma'am.
And in the end you showed
great personal strength,
courage, and humility.
You're confusing humility
with humiliation.
That's not true.
You didn't read the cards.
On the flowers outside the Palace
that Friday.
I actually think history will show
it was a good week for you.
And an even better
one for you, Mr. Blair.
But there are 52 weeks
in the year, ma'am,
and 2,500 in the time
since you've been Queen.
And when people come to assess
your legacy,
they won't remember those few days.
Oh, really?
You don't think that what affection
people once had for,
for this institution
has been diminished?
No. Not at all.
You're more respected now than ever.
I gather some of your closest advisers
were less fulsome in their support.
One or two.
But as a leader, I could never have
added my voice to that chorus.
Because you saw those headlines
and you thought,
"One day, that might happen to me."
And it will, Mr. Blair.
Quite suddenly and without warning.
So, shall we get on
with the business in hand?
Oh, look.
Oh, I do love this time of clay.
Shall we walk while there's still light?
You know the clocks go back
next week, it'll be dark before 5:00.
I do hope you're a walker.
- I am.
- Good.
I always think these meetings have
a far greater chance of success
if the Prime Minister is a walker.
As a matter of fact
it's how I think best, on my feet.
You know, I've never been one
for sitting around endlessly.
A good walk and fresh air
sorts everything out.
One in four, you said,
wanted to get rid of me?
For about half an hour.
But then you came down to London
and all that went away.
I've never been hated like that before.
And that must have been difficult.
Yes.
Very.
Nowadays, people want glamour
and tears, the grand performance.
I'm not very good at that.
I never have been.
I prefer to keep my feelings to myself.
And, foolishly, I believed that was what
the people wanted from their Queen.
Not to make a fuss,
nor wear one's heart on one's sleeve.
Duty first, self second.
That's how I was brought up.
That's all I've ever known.
You were so young
when you became Queen.
Well...
Yes.
Yes, a girl.
But I can see
that the world has changed,
and one must modernize.
- Well, perhaps that's where I can help.
- Oh, no.
Don't get ahead of yourself,
Prime Minister.
Remember, I'm the one
supposed to be advising you.
Come on, dogs.
So, tell me, Mr. Blair, what might we
expect from your first parliament?
Well, Ma'am,
top of the list is education reform.
We want to radically
reduce classroom sizes.
Oh, yes. Yes, we must.
Create a much lower
teacher-pupil ratio.
Yes, it will be difficult to achieve...