THE OFFICIAL STORY
Freedom, freedom, freedom!
Hear the sound of broken chains
See noble equality enthroned
Their worthy throne was unveiled
By the United Provinces of the South
- And the free ones of...
To the great Argentine people, hail!
MARCH 14th 1983
Gentleman, please.
Silence, please.
I'm Alicia Marbet Ibañez.
Some of you already know me.
This course studies
"Argentine History".
We will be covering
the social and political
institutions from 1810 forward.
We'll have three hours per week
which isn't much.
And let me warn you:
I don't like wasting my time.
I believe in discipline.
And I don't give away A's.
As some might recall, right?
Understanding history is preparation
for understanding the world.
No people can survive
without memory.
And History is the memory
of the people.
That's how we'll tackle
this course.
Here, madam!
Wait, use the towel.
I can put my head
under water, look.
No no no, don't!
You'll get water in your ears.
I'm making a foam suit.
Do you bathe naked too, mommy?
Rinse off Gaby, or we'll
be here forever.
Sing, so I'll know you
haven't drowned.
OK!
In the land of I don't remember
I take three steps and I'm lost
One step this way
I wonder if I may
One step over there
Oh, what a big scare
I'm sorry Ma'am.
The train broke down again.
- How's your sister?
- Fine.
How are you Gaby?
I'm fine.
Mommy cooked my meat.
I'm sure it tastes better
than mine.
Ma'am, Mrs. Luisa called
to remind you about
your high school reunion.
Cross out Rodrigo. Did you?
Not yet, he might still make
amends with Dolores.
He won't, he's already got
a new girlfriend. Cross him out!
Did you cross him out?
Dolores is lucky to have such
a devoted friend.
What does "divided" mean?
It is regrettable how some
news media abuse their rights.
By preaching destabilization,
they encourage subversive ideas.
- You're still here?
- Hi.
Don't you have to get dressed?
A kiss?
Oh, you bought it.
It's beautiful!
Gaby will love it.
It's so real! Touch it!
What are you doing here?
Off to bed.
It was quite a scare!
My wife's afraid I'll get
a heart attack.
With these things you can't
neglect the smallest detail.
If you neglect details,
that's your problem, Macci.
I just did as I was told.
By whom?
Come on, Doctor! By you!
Ibañez and Dante
set it all up with my men.
We advised, Macci.
We're just consultants.
- We thought you couldn't make it.
- My apologies.
- What about Elvira?
- She's home grounded.
What's my friend being grounded for?
Or is it classified?
Oh, at home she calls the shots.
Just some liver trouble.
- Hello, Ibañez.
- Hello, General.
Your wife Miller?
Lost her already?
My maid's cousins were sent to
Tucuman or thereabout.
She wasn't even told
if they're dead or alive.
We lost the war a year ago!
We lost a battle,
not the war dear.
Don't tell me it's dragging on!
I was in Spain last week with
Ballesteros, a businessman
and a lifelong socialist.
Guess what he said?
"We were better off opposing Franco."
Now that they're Government
they don't know whom to blame.
It's useless! 25 years trying to
teach him that
talking business at the table is
bad manners and spoils digestion.
Who's talking business?
Politics, then. Far worse.
We women are to blame too,
for not steering the conversation.
Tell me about your baby boy Regina.
I've heard he's huge.
Oh, he's gorgeous.
He weighed 9 pounds at birth!
Unbelievable!
It must be the combined genetics.
Whom do you suspect Miller?
Oh no!
My mother was very tall. Actually...
How about you Roberto,
were you at your daughter's birth?
No, I'm more like your husband.
We're a different generation.
I think it's Alicia
who's from another generation.
You're rather old fashioned,
aren't you?
Yes, I am.
That child must be
four or five now, isn't she?
She'll be five soon.
You two are really quite different,
aren't you, Roberto?
Maybe that's the secret!
Yes, I imagine
it must be somewhere!
I think she's unbearable.
And she thinks you deserved
better than a barren woman.
You think Andrada never told her?
She totally knows!
Pretending an interest
in the American's kid.
"How about you Roberto,
were you at your daughter's birth?"
Oh, Alicia, you're blowing it
out of proportion.
What does she care if the stork
brought Gaby or the gypsies.
She doesn't!
But she knows I do!
She's just like her husband.
He always seems to imply
that anyone who disagrees
with him is out!
And since she can
only fire the maid,
she wrings our guts instead.
Did you notice?
She called the yank a cuckold,
Regina a bitch, you a sorry fellow,
the husband rude, me an idiot.
All in one sentence!
She picks on everyone except
the General.
She does have her limits,
you must admit.
'The gaucho Moreira opens the door
ready for his last fight.
The officer and his soldiers
repel his violent onslaught bravely.
But, overcome by his brutal assault
they retreat into the corridors
through the back exits right & left.
A terrified Sergeant Chirino
hides behind the well.
Moreira, thinking he's alone,
attempts an escape.
Seeing him climb the fence,
the sergeant
charges with his weapon.
Feeling the chill
of the bayonet in his back, Moreira.'
Bravo, Chirino!
Hang on! Moreira fires
his pistol at the sergeant.
Oh, sir, no!
Yes! He's only a cop!
'Moreira is badly wounded!
Vincenta enters
through the left.'
Who plays Vincenta?
Cullen! Come on Cullen!
Cullen is a faggot!
"Make way, cowards!"
- You brute!
- Cowards.
"Seeing him, she flies to him,
collapsing with grief."
"A distant voice announces
his death sings these verses:
"I'm staking all my lucky
on my lasso, because a love
that is born Creole
is not repelled by death.
Because a weather-beaten
and sturdy gaucho."
Good morning.
Literature meets History.
Good morning, gentlemen.
Good morning, Professor.
You know Macarena's mother
can't leave kindergarten.
She says she has to stay
there all day.
Today, she wanted to leave
and Maqui wouldn't let her.
She clung at her leg,
crying and crying
I wouldn't miss it
for the world!
But you're never late!
How are you?
Oh, just this once
I have to leave early!
- You look gorgeous! Love the dress!
- Doesn't she look great?
The latest style.
You've lost weight!
Me? I started dieting
half an hour ago.
Still wearing your hair long.
How old-fashioned!
You'll never guess
who sends you regards.
Anna?
Yesterday
Tomorrow
I ran into her at the supermarket.
She looks like our grandmother.
Her skin's very fair and
thin skin wrinkles early.
That's not the problem.
She's been through so much.
Her son was sent to the Malvinas war.
Her last remaining son.
What about the others?
The eldest married and left.
All her children
turned out subversive.
That's how she raised them.
How do you know
they were subversives?
Well they were taken,
surely for good reason!
- What are you talking about?
- Let's change the subject.
Anna, how's your son?
- He must be all grown up.
- He turned 17 in February.
Pablo is 17 years old?
My God, Anna, you're old!
Clara and I were pregnant
at the same time.
They called us the "captive globes".
Doesn't Clara ever come?
She went to Caracas 5 years ago.
Wasn't that when you left?
I left 7 years ago.
7? Really?
1976, shortly after
the military coup.
I am single.
Single, never.
Impossible. Nobody would tolerate.
You're back for good?
I don't know yet.
We can't all choose between
the tough caviar of exile and home.
So don't expect us to pity you.
I've thought a lot about you,
these years.
- Did you?
- I swear.
You were like an obsession.
And when I saw you,
it all came back to me.
Because you look the same.
Exactly the same.
After all these years.
After all those things
and you look exactly the same.
The same as when you
brown-nosed the monitor
and gave me
2 silver salt-cellars
when all I owned was a mattress.
The same.
So now, Dora
worthless schoolmate
unforgettable bitch,
why don't you go fuck yourself?
Why do you live
in such a far away country?
Do you have children?
One, but he's grown up.
He doesn't like bedtime stories.
My daughter's hair is ugly,
looks like a broom.
Will it grow if I cut it?
Enough chatter, lights out, Gaby.
Just a little longer.
One more story.
The one about the invisible paint.
The paint makes things invisible.
For instance, we paint
your bed and it vanishes.
So mommy will think
you're sleeping in mid-air.
Mommy, is she like Dolores?
Is she your "divided friend"?
That school building was hideous!
Clara used to call it "the jail".
That's right!
Like where you're
teaching now, right?
No, Roberto. Please, no.
It was built around the same time.
Bars on the windows, right?
That's true.
I hadn't realized.
Gaby is adorable.
She says
I'm the "divided" friend.
She can't pronounce devoted.
She loves the word,
she's wearing it out.
Are you staying?
I don't know yet.
You're looking good.
First time I see you in a skirt.
Europe did you good, didn't it?
It smoothed you around the edges.
"'Here I am in Caracas
18 pounds too fat
for a romantic victim,
so it dawned
on my 3 teenagers daughters that
between them and freedom
stood their idiot mother
starving myself and running
3 miles a day
around my tiny bed!'
Only to become a fit fatty
without a man in sight."
"Forty years old!
How did I get here
without realising?"
The fatty!
Well, we're just peachy!
At fatty's we used
to drink eggnog.
I got sick.
Did I tell you?
No, I didn't.
The day I turned 40, Roberto
took me to a fancy restaurant.
Very expensive.
And I...
I got food poisoning!
3 days in bed!
Christ, 3 days in bed!
The doctor came. Never felt so ill.
You and Roberto are OK?
Yes.
Then everything's fine.
It's nice to come back to this.
Why didn't you tell me
you were leaving?
Not even a note.
I didn't exactly have time
to throw going-away parties.
Why such a hurry?
Should we get drunk on eggnog?
Disgusting!
Why won't you tell me?
Did you know my apartment
on Laprida Street?
I didn't.
There was a poster of Gardel
on the door.
They ripped it to pieces.
They stormed in,
threw a sweater over my head
and trashed the place.
They took me in a car,
pushed me down with their feet.
They hit me with a rifle butt.
I woke up naked on a table,
they gave me shocks with a picana.
At some point someone
examined me with a stethoscope.
He told them to stop.
I'm not sure if it was that day.
I lost sense of time,
something inside broke.
Something that can't be fixed.
I still wake up
in the morning gasping for air.
I'm hanging there and they shove
my head into a pail of water.
After 7 years I still choke.
When I got out of there,
they said I'd been there for 36 days.
I had lost 27 pounds
and I'd undergone full treatment.
At first,
I was spared being raped.
You know why?
Because the guy who came to my home,
the only guy whose face I saw,
he smiled at me and said:
"I'm going to keep you for myself."
Later I would recognise his voice
every time he came around
asking if they'd kept me for him.
I'm terrified I'll hear his voice
on the street, in the subway.
But why?
Why did they do that to you?
Why?
I don't know.
At first they asked about Pedro.
I told them the truth.
I hadn't seen him in 2 years.
And they'd ask again.
So I'd tell them again,
"Not in 2 years."
And again they asked.
Again I told them, and I got
electric prodding and drowning.
What had Pedro done?
Pedro was involved.
He might have been already dead
when they questioned me.
Did you report it?
What a good idea!
It had never occurred to me!
To whom would
I have reported it?
But you hadn't done anything.
What do you mean "to whom"?
That place was crowded.
Sometimes I didn't know if it was
me screaming or somebody else.
There were pregnant women
who lost their babies there.
And others were taken away,
but they returned alone.
Their babies went to families
who bought them,
no questions asked.
Why are you telling me this?
I never told anyone.
I wrote about it once
for the commission.
Oddly,
I feel guilty.
Ok, ok.
Gaby.
You scared me!
Off to bed, let's go.
Much of Moreno's work
exemplifies his republican spirit.
For instance,
his decree for suppressing honours,
which he issued after December fifth
when an officer,
apparently wasted,
inebriated,
whose name I don't remember.
Never mind. Continue.
This officer...
The text book only says that he
"praised Saavedra excessively."
I think he called him
"Emperor" or something.
Anyhow, he gave him titles
that weren't democratic.
What does it say about honours?
They were suspended.
Of course.
Do you remember Moreno's words?
- Does anyone remember?
- I do, Ma'am.
He said that no members
of the Junta should have distinctions
other than the place
at which they happened to sit at.
He also says, in that document,
"no inhabitant of Buenos Aires
drunk or asleep, may speak
against his country's liberties."
Very good, Duran.
Can anybody else quote Moreno's
work that illustrates
his republican spirit?
I do!
Well I do.
Well...
There was this article
he wrote for "La Gaceta“
about the freedom of the press.
Your name?
Ferkovich.
Why don't you stand up
and tell us about it?
Oh, I can't really quote it.
I don't know it.
I don't know anything by heart.
My old man says
if I studied things by heart
I'd never learn anything.
A sensible man, your father.
Tell us in your own words.
If publishing the truth is forbidden
lies and poverty will triumph
and ignorance.
They didn't kill him just because.
Whom?
Moreno. They didn't dump him
in the water just because.
It wasn't just because.
They had to throw people overboard
when they died offshore.
On long sea journeys,
they had no way
of preserving corpses.
But Moreno was poisoned.
It isn't true?
Well that's a theory.
Some people believe it.
But there's no proof.
There's no proof because
History's written by murderers!
I'm Horacio Costa.
Mr. Costa, please step outside.
This is a history class,
not a debate.
Whoever wishes to talk
raise their hand for permission.
Without discipline there's
no teaching and no learning.
Are you a phony magician
or a real one?
A real magician.
Can't you see?
He's a real magician.
Are there cold Cokes, Rosa?
The fridge is bursting!
And so am I!
If your mother-in-law doesn't
leave the kitchen, I'll quit!
You'll quit?
Who'll put up with your cooking?
Where are the Cokes Alicia?
I bet my wise-ass brother
won't show up until it's over!
He's meeting
with some out-of-town people.
Too bad you couldn't
convince your father.
Dad's stubborn.
He won't give in if Roberto doesn't.
Tell him Dad's dying to see Gaby.
Or does he meet out-of-town
people on Sundays, too?
Sometimes I think of Gaby's mother,
it scares me.
- Scared? Why?
- Ma'am, I quit!
Accept her resignation, Alicia,
before she changes her mind.
Now, like we did with the balloon?
Yes or no?
It happens to be
your daughter's birthday!
Nothing. It's fine.
Everything's fine.
Baby, are you sad?
Don't cry, my baby.
Let's go to bed.
You'll go to sleep. Won't you?
Sleep well. You want
your mommy to stay? Fine.
Don't cry any more.
Your mommy's here. See?
It's all right, my little one.
It's all right.
My little one is sleepy.
Why is my little one sleepy?
Because the sandman is here.
Look at those toys
your cousins brought you.
What happened, my love?
Did you hurt her?
What'd I tell you?
We didn't touch her.
We ran in and
she started screaming.
We didn't hurt her.
Remember our talk?
She got scared.
We didn't see her.
What was?
She got crazy?
No, dad, please!
Can't she play,
isn't she big enough?
I can't believe
it's been five years.
That day you came home very late.
Remember? Like today.
You didn't know how to hold her.
You carried her like a puppy.
At the time,
I let you talk me out
of going to the hospital.
Now I think I shouldn't have.
I should have gone there.
Don't dear.
Who was that woman in the car?
Who was she?
A nurse.
What was the doctor's name, Haifel?
I can't remember.
Why should I remember?
The doctor who gave you Gaby,
and you forgot his name?
We agreed we'd never talk about it.
Did you pay them?
Alicia...
The mother, or the doctor?
Why bring this up now?
Because you said she'd agreed.
How do you know for sure?
Did you see her at the hospital?
Answer me, Roberto.
Don't be angry.
Maybe she didn't even know
her child was being taken away.
What is it you're asking?
What the hell are you asking me?
How do I know what I'm asking?
I don't know.
I always feel wrong
on this particular day.
Won't we ever tell her the truth?
You realize,
we celebrate our date, not hers.
We celebrate the day
you brought her home.
We celebrate the registration day.
That's her birthday.
"Since conceived without freedom
the absurdities of our fathers,
ingrained by time and custom
will continue to be respected.
Let us for once break inertia
on our outdated opinions.
By forgetting our self love,
may we know the truth."
- Wait, idiot, let's see how it ends.
- Listen, Horacio!
“Truth, like virtue, contains
its own rewards.
Discussing and revealing it,
brings out its shining splendour."
"If restrictions are imp...
If speech is restricted,
the soul will vegetate like matter."
Sit down!
"And the lies, the worries,
the bigotry and ignorance."
Artemi, pull that down!
Take that down!
I won't ask who did it.
Because you all saw it!
"And ignorance."
So, you'll all paying
for the pranksters.
"Provoking division among people
and causing
their continued abasement,
misery and ruin."
You'll know better next time.
"Mariano Moreno, La Gaceta
de Buenos Aires, June 12, 1810."
What if you decided
to be late for once?
Why would I?
To have coffee with me,
for example.
I'm sorry, Benitez,
I'm in a hurry.
I'm due downtown.
Can I hitch a ride?
I'd like to talk to you.
How about that coffee?
Not now, Benitez.
What do you want?
A little fling, perhaps?
Are you insane?
What a temper!
If I had
asked you to bed,
what a row you'd make!
What?
Oh, nothing of the sort.
Don't get your hopes up.
I'm returning to you a report
you left
in the principal's office.
It's about a student, Costa
who's talking nonsense
in class.
Why do you have it?
I'm friends with the secretary.
How dare you?
You think you have the right...
Oh I don't!
Not at all.
I took the file because
I know the score.
Because his passion
could cost that idiot
more than detention.
And because you too
deserve another chance.
That class,
they're so impertinent.
Just today they covered
the blackboard with news clippings.
Frankly, I don't know
what they want. Here.
They want to inform you.
Why did Cuyo University fire you?
Because I'm dangerous.
I wasn't fired though.
They payed a visit
in my absence,
and shredded every paper I had.
I got the message all by myself.
And these lists,
with all the missing people,
even babies,
could be true?
I mean, it could be like with you:
New job.
Relocated. Right?
What do you care
whether it's true.
How is it your problem?
It will end. it will end.
This habit of killing.
It will end. It will end..
It's always easier to believe
it's impossible, right?
Because if it were possible
it would require complicity.
Of people who refuse to believe,
even as it stares them in the face.
Here's Costa's report,
in case you want
to file it again.
FAMILIES OF THOSE MISSING
FOR POLITICAL REASONS
Freedom, freedom, freedom!
The missing.
Tell us where they are.
Tell us where those
kidnapped babies are!
You army bastards!
What have you done
with those missing?
The foreign debt and the corruption,
are the worst shit
our nation has put up with!
And what about Malvinas?
Those boys who never came back!
We must not forget them..
That's why we must fight.
RETURN ALL CHILDREN
BORN IN CAPTIVITY
TO THE LEGITIMATE FAMILIES
THE GRANDMOTHERS
OF THE PLAZA DE MAYO
- Dante, please.
- Just a minute, Macci.
Tell Ibañez it's ready, and
there's an extra 5% reimbursement.
I can't, now.
I think your figures are wrong.
Get that old man out of here
or Andrada will kill us!
We're very busy today.
I didn't know you were here!
Wait for me inside.
No. Better make
an appointment for tomorrow.
What's the matter?
I wanted a word with you.
Remember I have to go?
We should be leaving.
I can't wait any longer,
and you know it!
I must see Andrada.
I'm not going to jail!
Why would you go to jail?
What's wrong with you?
Jail is for crooks.
This is a civilized country.
And you have friends.
Let's see if Andrada can see you.
What a fuss over a subpoena!
Coming with me to the airport?
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
I'll handle it.
Don't miss your flight. Call someone.
Whom?
Do we have the tickets?
Tell him we'll get even.
You've been married for ages,
haven't you?
And you still come to see
him off. Touchy!
You're a teacher, aren't you?
I teach history.
It can't be easy teaching
history in high school nowadays.
Kids aren't what they used to be.
What do you think
of today's youth?
Is there any hope?
My nephew, he's 16 years old
and he doesn't believe
that San Martin crossed the Andes.
I know it's silly, but don't go.
I'm afraid to be alone.
It's just a routine trip!
What's wrong?
Not now.
We'll talk when you come back.
Mr. Ibañez!
I'd like to make a trip with you.
How about Bolivia.
Let's go on a trip when you return.
We haven't traveled in ages.
Take care of Gaby.
How was she?
Grumpy because you're going away.
Takes after her mother!
After her mother?
God knows what that might be!
There you go again!
It's that, isn't it?
We'll miss our flight!
I have to go!
Stop thinking about it.
It's pointless. Stop thinking!
Mommy, there's a note in my notebook.
It says you need to
buy me pencils, crayons
and an eraser. But no sharpener
because in a week they'd be
so so tiny so you
couldn't hold them.
Must I chase you
all over the place?
Are you sick?
Are you going to die?
Come on.
Finish you dinner.
When is Daddy coming?
In a week.
Like this?
Like this. The other hand. All five.
Day after, after, after tomorrow.
Gaby, let go of my face.
Eat your dinner.
Come on. Let's go eat.
Eat! It's late.
This meat has fat.
I'm not eating it.
I cut off the fat.
BIRTH CERTIFICATE
How do they get meat from the cows?
- First they kill them.
- Do they shoot them?
Gaby, eat up.
I get tired of chewing so much.
DELIVERY ROOM
Dr. Jaifer. With a final "R".
He left 3 years ago.
3 years?
Do you know where he is now?
No, I wouldn't know.
Try in the Admin Office,
they might know something.
Are you all right?
I was Gaby's age..
I sat on
Grandma's rocking chair.
I couldn't understand
what took them so long.
They were both killed
in a car accident.
Poor Grandma.
She made up this trip.
She faked letters.
For years I waited for them,
sitting there
in that rocking chair.
I thought
that Daddy and Mommy
had abandoned me.
It wasn't until I grew up
and saw their grave
that I started to forgive them.
I was always so gullible.
But not now.
If I don't know who Gaby is.
It's as if nothing is real.
We weren't planning on
telling her she's adopted.
Sometimes she asks
about her grandparents
and about their grandparents.
All the way back to God.
She says that God is "bionic".
Because He can see us
although we can't see him.
And it's true.
I always thought
that her mother didn't want her.
But, now...
I never took anything
from anyone before.
God trusted her to you, Alicia.
It is His will.
Why do you doubt
His infinite wisdom?
Do not offend the Lord.
Do not reject what was given to you.
I don't reject her!
You've shown piety
and compassion.
You've protected her from evil
and the dangers ahead of her.
What dangers?
You know the truth, Father!
Won't you tell me?
You have not sinned
but your covenant with
the Lord has been damaged.
You can help me, Father.
"I shall not destroy the cities
for the sake of righteous men.“
Father, you know everything
that happened. Right?
God merciful father
that it reconciled
Tell me the truth, Father!
You know.
You have to tell me the truth!
You were with Roberto
that day weren't you, Father?
I absolve you of your sins.
I don't need absolution!
I need the truth!
Thank the Lord
because He is good.
His mercy is eternal.
The Lord has forgiven your sins.
Go in peace.
Alicia, Rosa took her home.
Gaby had a slight fever.
We called you several times.
You may dress her now.
No!
I can dress myself!
Of course you can, young lady!
My mistake, thinking I was
talking to a little girl.
What does it say here, Doctor?
"Ortolani sign."
The luxation of the hip
she was born with.
You remember we spoke about it?
Bring her when she's actually ill.
And stop throwing away your money.
You told me it was likely
that she was
a firstborn, because
of this ortolani sign. Right?
Yes. It's possible.
And that the date of birth
could be determined according to
the day the umbilical cord fell off.
These facts are generally noted.
The weight, height, etc.,
are also in the records. Right?
Cullen!
Cullen, the answer.
The second one.
Marcelo almost smuggled me
into this job.
Leave me alone!
Is Roberto coming back on Saturday?
Plus you didn't come here
to discuss your husband, right?
Gaby is adopted.
Remember how you spoke
of babies that were given
to families, no questions asked.
I couldn't have children.
I had every treatment there was.
Then this opportunity
came through Roberto's office.
I asked no questions.
And now, I don't know whom to ask.
Roberto won't tell me a thing.
But I'm getting stuff together.
I found out the hospital
where she was born.
I know the approximate date,
her weight and height.
I know she had
a type of hip dislocation here.
You're going to help me, Anita.
Come with me to the hospital.
Remember how we always went
everywhere together. Even to pee!
Please go back to the archives.
They sent me here.
You send me back there!
Excuse me, ma'am.
But you're the one
who sent me to the archives.
They say that you must have it.
I told you we don't have
the 1978 records.
Ma'am, those are this year's records.
Not much help, dear?
It's sad when one has to add bad
service to one's troubles, right?
I'm also looking for my family.
Maybe we can help each other?
No. It's not that.
Aren't you looking for a baby?
Yes.
Lamb of God, who takes away
the sins of the world.
Be merciful on us.
Lamb of God, who takes
away the sins of the world.
Have mercy upon us.
Lamb of God, who takes away
the sins of the world.
Grant us peace.
Poverty is not shameful.
Just as wealth is not an honor.
But it's better to be rich.
That depends
on what you had to do to get there
and what you're willing
to do to keep it up.
All right,
but if you don't steal.
The thieves on TV aren't
the only kind, you know.
So you'd rather be poor, Grandpa?
I can't help it.
But I do like having
a clean conscience.
A vermouth, for old time's sake?
My dear sister-in-law,
you're not hitting on me,
are you?
You must get plenty of offers.
With my looks!
You know how women fall
head-over-heals over a starving
widower with a broke factory
and 3 kids, forced to go back
to living with his folks.
My picture's on the cover
of the top magazines!
"Most Eligible Man of the Year."
OK. Name one woman who's
ever refused you.
You're kidding!
But I'm cautious.
I never dive into an empty pool.
Still, there was one
who rejected me.
Cecilia rejected me.
I jumped in twice.
Twice she said no.
But finally, she couldn't resist.
Roberto, how could you?
I scold the kids for teasing animals!
- Did you use the washing machine?
- Yes, son. Thank you.
Oh, Mom.
Don't be mad.
It's just that I'm grateful
every time I use it.
I'm so happy that you came.
But you have to promise me...
Why me? Why don't you
make them promise?
That's between me and them.
Have you read those things
on the paper lately?
Those announcements?
They say there are missing babies.
So, what about it?
Has anyone said anything?
No. Nobody said anything.
- But there's a chance.
- A chance!
Just think.
Mother! Let's eat?
Your dad and your brother
are well liked in the neighbourhood.
They're highly respected.
I know.
Did you talk to Roberto?
Maybe Roberto doesn't know either.
See, it's warm enough
to eat on the patio.
You were right, son.
But the radio predicted bad weather.
The clouds scared me.
There's no teaching your mother.
She believes anything they say.
When have we been wrong
about the weather, my son and I?
And by your "son" you mean
Enrique, right?
It's a habit. He lives here.
And, come to think of it...
When have you ever look up
at the sky to forecast?
Only if it's raining dollars!
Let it rain dollars!
Another helping?
I can't win!
They work me up every time.
Roberto, your Mom's talking.
You, Mom, even Gaby.
They work me up
until I take the bait!
I made it with prawns,
just the way you like it.
Let's see, how it started
this time. Right, the weather!
Even Mom took the bait
with the weather.
Kids, 90 play!
Why the hell do you ask us over?
Go play in the backyard. Go on!
Dad, he has a point this time.
Listen, Enrique.
You can stick your defence
right up your ass!
You understand?
Can I say something?
Go on! Go and stare at the clouds
with Daddy and calculate the winds.
Can I say something?
Yes, talk!
It was a bad joke, in poor taste.
But it was just a joke!
Can't one make a joke
about one's son?
- Just hilarious, Dad!
- I'm talking!
I'm your father,
I raised you better than this.
Your brother's too fond of wine.
And you...
You're too fond of money.
But your brother never gets drunk.
He prefers other things to wine.
And you...
We'd probably get along
better if you were a drunk.
Of course, you'd love me
dearly if I were a failure.
The whole country's collapsed,
everybody went down except
the sons of bitches,
the thieves,
they hit the jackpot!
And you'll die believing that.
Won't you?
You'll never admit
that you're a spectacular failure!
You and your kind!
What's going on?
Roberto, please!
You continue to use
40-year-old machinery.
The world moves on, you know!
And it crushes those
who stop to stare at the clouds!
How dare you blabber
on such immoral bullshit
while people are starving?
Starving? Who's starving here?
Who the hell is starving?
Tell me!
You continue to stuff your mouth
with high-flown words,
reciting old anarchist bullshit!
The Spanish Civil War is over.
And you lost it!
You lost it!
You want me to feel guilty
because I'm not a loser.
Oh, no, no! I'm not a loser.
Get that into your heads!
I'm not a loser!
And this other war?
The war you and your bunch won.
Do you know who lost it,
brother? The kids.
Kids like mine.
They'll be paying
for the dollars that were nicked.
And they'll repay them
by not eating and not studying.
Because you certainly won't.
Hell no! Why should you?
You're not a loser!
MURDERED IN THE WOMB
FOUND MURDERED
Wait. There's something here.
Between March 15 and 20. Right?
More or less.
Although the girl is younger.
You're sure it's that hospital?
In La Plata.
And the anatomy data,
size of skull, thorax
they should all be
in the hospital's archives, right?
Well, no.
But we don't have that data.
Even if we did, it wouldn't help.
We've nothing to compare with.
Or do you have something
to compare them against?
No.
Patience, gentlemen.
It won't be long now.
A drink, Dante?
Yes, why not?
Not me. I need a steady
hand to beat this guy.
May I use the phone?
How is Andrada supposed
to telephone if you're using it?
- Just a quick call.
- Go ahead, use it!
Andrada won't call, anyway.
He says "Gelby"
instead of Gaby!
So teach him!
Mommy will kill us if you're
not in bed soon!
Why isn't she home yet?
- Can I wait up for her?
- Just a while.
Then I'll eat all your food.
But you already ate!
This food isn't for little girls.
Daddy, men don't cook.
Women do.
Did you take your medicine?
One more, General, and it's over!
It seems you're winning.
Who plays to lose?
I like to see him enjoy it.
Give me a kiss.
Your mother seems
to have abandoned us.
Truth is I can't get worked up
about cards any more.
Too much going on.
Get off the phone.
She's not picking up.
I think I'll have to leave.
At noon she took the boy to her
mother's and hasn't returned.
Be patient, Argentine women
are one of a kind.
Rosa, turn the heat down
and keep stirring.
I can smell the gravy
setting from here.
That's the secret the nose.
All I know how to cook
is a barbecue.
That's all they ever teach us
in the country.
I can't picture my dad
making gravy.
If I did only
as my father did before me...
My daddy!
How would there be
any progress?
I for one wouldn't be sitting
on the Board of Directors!
I'm sorry.
I didn't know you were celebrating.
Celebrating what?
There's nothing to celebrate.
Something came up.
I'll tell you later.
I think Andrada
will hang us out to dry.
All of us, except the Yank,
who's probably his partner.
What? I don't understand.
What happened?
That's what I'm wondering.
What's up with your hair lately?
"This counter-revolutionary
persecution
contrary to the ideals of May
was aimed at exterminating
the patriots
who tried to extend
throughout America
the influence of the
liberation of the Rio de la Plata
like a knife-bearing arm
that struck Monteagudo's back
and sliced Castelli's tongue
to silence him.
The ensuing battle between
Unitarians and Federalists."
Mr. Costa, what is it you
say here about Castelli?
They cut his tongue
in jail, so he wouldn't talk.
What is your reference?
What do you mean?
In what book did you read that?
You only believe
what's written in books?
For events that happened over
150 years ago it seems wise
to refer to existing documentation.
Seriously, Costa.
The protagonists are dead!
Moreno and Saavedra, Monteagudo
and Pueyrredón, Dorrego and Lavalle
Rosas and Mitre, and poor Castelli,
not only mute, but dead!
Therefore, unless you're some
sort of medium,
I'll ask you to supply
literary references, since you're
so passionate
about historical research.
That's an A minus.
- Hello.
- Hi, how are you doing?
I like your hair down.
I look kind of Wild.
Then I'm partial to wild ladies.
You're all over the place.
I played against myself and won.
So?
So what?
Are your students
still raising hell?
Of course.
Well, you keep
throwing burning matches...
it makes sense to expect
explosions around you.
Explosions all around, exactly.
What's happened?
Everything seems
to be falling apart.
It is!
It's all falling apart.
Yes?
But not everything.
Let's not get our hopes
up too high.
Although you people are
ready to swallow the bait.
Tea perhaps.
And this is just the beginning.
Much to your people's regret.
No.
Benitez, who are "you people"?
There's nothing more touching
than a guilty bourgeois lady.
To quote an old dear friend of mine:
Why don't you go fuck
yourself a little?
Julieta's mommy says to call
her to arrange a playdate.
I don't want to go.
She made fun of Macarena.
Oh, why?
- They were so stupid!
- "Baby! Baby!"
But we stood up for her,
Teresa, Diana and me.
We don't see each other much.
Oh, damn it!
That stupid Rosa keeps
rearranging the furniture!
Aren't you drinking
too much lately?
A blind man wouldn't last
two days in this house!
How nice, how nice.
Today I called at 8 o'clock
Rosa said you dropped Gaby
and went out again.
What are you up to?
I'm scared.
Scared of what?
If I ask, will you answer me?
Could Gaby be
a missing mother's child?
Where do you get these ideas?
What a silly idiot I am! Of course!
The moment I saw her,
I knew we were headed for trouble!
Anna has nothing to do with it.
It's all over the newspapers!
She lived with a subversive!
I don't understand
how she managed to come back
and go about her business freely.
Who lived with a subversive?
Why do you think she left?
Why?
You knew who Pedro was?
No. I didn't know.
She told me that they'd been
separated the last 4 years.
She hadn't seen him for 2 to years
when they took him.
Of course she'd say that!
And you knew about it?
You knew?
How come you knew?
What do I know, Alicia!
I must have heard it from you.
Are you angry?
No, my love, I'm not angry.
Rosa can't braid my hair,
but you can.
That's because when I was
your age I wore pigtails too.
I don't know who took that one.
Probably the old man.
Look at the crystal clear water
in that stream.
You can see his foot
clearly under the water.
He looks skinny, but he was strong.
She could read already. Look.
They were barely 5 years old.
See the tiny scar on her cheek?
Yes. Unless you knew,
it looks like a smudge.
They were playing with the Diaz boys.
They weren't used
to playing with girls.
So when the old man wasn't looking,
they threw a rock at her.
It bled a lot but she didn't cry.
And he threw the 4 Diaz
boys into the water. All 4!
He fought with them, head-on.
That's how he fought.
Then he sat down next to her
to keep her company.
They had never met before.
But after this,
nobody could separate them.
Nobody.
Braulio took this photo.
It was his birthday
and they gave him a camera.
He took pictures of everything.
He shot the whole roll,
sneaking up on you with the camera.
She still wore pigtails, see?
We used to call her "twiggy"
because her legs were so skinny.
Such innocence! They thought
because they sat behind the table
nobody could see them.
It's hard to believe,
they were already engaged.
She kept giggling
on their wedding day.
It was probably nerves.
She said her shoes pinched.
It was her first time in high heels.
She was 19.
The judge who married them
spoke these lovely words.
Too bad she couldn't stop giggling.
He looks bigger than he is.
It's the suit.
A factory pal lent it to him.
It was tight at the shoulders.
As soon as it was over,
he took it off and returned it.
Here they'd been
married for one year.
You could hardly
tell she was pregnant.
We were all there
because it was a Sunday.
We all brought something
for the barbecue.
We helped unload the bricks
and stuff for another wall
because they only had one brick wall.
See?
You see,
some neighbours who saw
them being taken away
said that the fire might
not have been intentional.
But since they destroyed everything
and there was only one brick wall.
There was nothing left.
Nothing.
Only these four pictures of them.
And our memories.
I'm not saying that she is...
But the dates more or less match,
don%they?
And then looking at this picture.
You realize this girl of yours...
could well be my granddaughter.
Don't cry.
It doesn't do any good.
Take my word for it.
Why are you here?
Your secretary said I'd find you
here. We need to talk.
Right now I'm busy.
Some other time I'll gladly see you.
Believe me I'd rather not.
Alicia won't return my calls.
How about that!
Good for her!
Is the ship sinking?
Do you know
what's gotten into Alicia's head?
I know what ideas
you're trying to put in her head.
Don't be an idiot!
Had I that kind of influence
on her she wouldn't have married you!
Of course not! You'd have found
her a husband like yours!
Your lot should all be wiped clean.
Like garbage!
Didn't they do just that!
Swept and buried them!
Like garbage!
Did you know who Pedro was?
He was just like you
but in the opposite field!
Hence the mutual hatred.
Hatred?
Why should he hate me?
Actually you're better!
He'd never have asked that question.
So, you're innocent, right?
You had nothing to do with any of it?
Maybe you ratted on me,
to ingratiate yourself
with some friend?
I would've done so gladly.
Who told you?
Who?
So he's disappeared.
Yes, Rolo. He disappeared.
Vanished.
Gone forever!
Nothing. Nothing.
I'm laughing at us.
Who would denounce him, Rolo,
if they can't prove any of it?
Everything's fine. The girl's asleep.
The maid's asleep. Relax.
I'm sorry.
Stop. Why are you telling me this?
No! I have nothing to do with it!
I'm telling you.
I had nothing to do with it.
Nothing.
You offered to pick her up
at preschool.
Because you couldn't make it.
But it's 11:30 pm Alicia!
No pardon, no amnesty.
We want them alive.
Now it's become imperative
that they appear alive,
and the culprits are punished.
We want our children!
They took them alive.
We want them back alive.
FAMILIES OF THE DETAINED
AND MISSING
AND HER BABY BORN
IN CAPTIVITY
We need to know
where the missing people are.
If Gaby's your grandchild,
what do we do?
It's strange
I always thought that
I would do anything
to hold on to...
That I'd be capable...
of anything as long as...
As long as everything
remained as it was.
Strange, isn't it?
As long as I didn't lose what I love,
yet here I am.
Rosa, can you come in please?
- Hi, love.
- Hello dear.
I'd like you to meet...
- Not now. I'm busy.
- Please.
Mrs. Reballo, my husband,
Roberto Ibañez.
- Hello.
- How do you do?
Reballo.
I knew a Reballo back in college.
A lifetime ago.
We're not from town.
Sara could be
Gaby's grandmother.
What?
Are you out of your mind?
What's this, a trap?
In my own house?
What's the matter with you,
you poor idiot?
Do you realize what you're doing?
What is it?
You're scared?
What do you want?
Do you want to get rid of the girl?
There's no need to give her off
to the first looney on the street.
Get this old bag out of here.
Out of my house!
Get this out of here!
Well, I'm leaving.
Tomorrow, will you call me
or should I call you?
I'll call you, Sara.
See you tomorrow.
I don't get it.
What's gotten into you?
What do you want to do with Gaby?
- I want to know.
- What do you want to know?
Why she was given to you?
What did they do to her mother?
Is she alive?
How would I know?
What am I? A torturer?
And why should we care?
We should care. It concerns us.
You're too scared
to look that woman in the face.
I don't want to look at her.
I want nothing to do with them!
Do you know who they are?
How could you know?
You don't know
what's under your nose!
Of course I'm scared, you idiot!
You idiot.
Some very serious things are
happening. Andrada's missing.
And I'm in it up to here!
The General is raving mad!
He says he's going to make them pay.
We might lose everything.
We might lose Gaby.
That one's on you! You!
What if it is true?
If the parents are whom you said.
Would it change anything?
Would it?
She's already lost a mother.
You want her to lose another one?
Is that what you want?
Listen...
I know how much you love the girl.
We're raising her properly,
aren't we?
- She's better off with us.
- Then it's true.
Who brought that old woman here?
Who?
You don't even care if it's true.
Well I care!
I'm not doing this to Gaby!
I took her home,
because I want to know
if Gaby's her grandchild,
or someone else's grandchild.
The grandchild of someone
who hasn't the strength
to walk around the plaza
with a poster.
Gaby's not here.
Where is Gaby?
- Where is Gaby, Alicia?
- Horrible, isn't it?
- What's horrible?
- Not knowing where your daughter is!
- Where's my daughter?
- At your mother's house!
Where's my daughter?
I had Rosa take her
to your folks so we could talk.
Let me go, Roberto!
Let me go!
Hello.
Yes, mother.
No, I was in the other room.
Nothing. Nothing.
Tell her to say goodnight
to me first.
- Hello, Daddy.
- Hello, my love.
Can I talk to Mommy?
She's not...
- Call her.
- She's coming.
Will you sleep there?
With grandma and grandpa.
Fine.
But I want to sing to Mommy.
If...
If you sing loud she'll hear you.
U know it by heart. Listen.
In the land of I don't remember
I take three steps and I'm lost.
One step this way
I wonder if I may
One step over there.
Oh what a big scare
In the land of I don't remember
I take three steps and I'm lost.
One step backward fast
And that'll be my last
Because I no longer know
Where my other foot will go
Daddy? Did you hear me?
Did you like it?
Yes. I liked it a lot.
I'm sleepy now.
Here's a kiss.
Here's one for you
and one for Mommy.
Good night.
Should I hang up, Daddy?
Yes, my love. Hang up.
Good night, Daddy.
Good night, love of my life.
In the land of I don't remember
I take three steps and I'm lost
One step this way
I wonder if I may
One step over there
Eclair Media