THE VALLEY OF THE POWDER
VALLEY OF THE POWDER
So-called...
That he will arrive
if I leave this bag here?
I doubt that he/it leaves all alone.
Do I want to say, will I recover it?
I can supervise it to you.
I count on you.
Hê, gentleman!
Do you look for the fight, of times?
With you?
I don't believe.
Watch therefore where you go!
To control a beast,
it is necessary to be shrewder than she.
This horse has the fragile mouth,
there is the boredom!
A priori, it is not
the only boredom!
Your bit is bad.
M. "I don't know who",
I never carry a bit!
You speak of the one
of my horse?
One would say well
that there is a êtranger in city.
Our city is not to sell!
I had pariê with myself
that I would meet you,
immediately arrivê here.
You are well
the joker of the city?
The philosopher of the street corner?
The citizen who makes the mind
and pleasing of everything.
The Philosopher!
It is not funny, that,
young man?
I don't find.
No, I will take a cigar.
People that achêtent that...
do drink it?
Them the achêtent not
for dêcrasser their youngsters.
Are you sure of it?
Do I can you to help?
Do hold it, do you want?
Let's suppose... that a man
achête this saddle.
He/it is pressê,
straddle his/her/its horse
and meet seated
on cactuses.
That makes you bitter.
You can pay it?
That? No...
You won't sell it to me.
I don't have cherchê to sell it to you!
60 dollars...
With a discount of 10%
for payment counting...
54 dollars, by consêquent.
There are your 54 dollars.
And I thank you.
The saddlers always offer
a rope and a bridle.
Delighted to have made business with you.
One seems silly
with a saddle without horse.
Who sells some horses?
Or what approaches from it?
You, let's see.
Hey yes, it is true.
I sell some horses.
Where are they?
Where, otherwise to the êcuries?
Sometimes, they are at the gambling-den.
Show the path.
I will follow you, to change.
A problême, trêsor?
Milt, I believe that my horse
a the bruised mouth.
Would my bit be bad?
Maybe... but that would be able to
to be his/her mouth.
Or the measles, the whooping cough...
Not the whooping cough.
I had it, I would know it.
You take account therefore
of my advice.
When I have you conseillêe,
you have impolite êtê.
But you blocked me the road!
You never learned to say:
"I regret, I was wrong."
When you dêciderez which
among us will serve yourselves first,
remember, I pay for cash.
Milt, this man who is?
I ignore it, but he/it doesn't look for
the popularitê!
Milt is going to glue him an old nag.
These are beasts of race:
Thoroughbredses and Indian ponies.
Of a côtê, rapiditê and beautê.
Of the other, the staying.
There is the marchê:
I give you 40 dollars
for the horse of my choice.
40 dollars?
All these horses are worth well more!
If me rempoche this money,
the marchê is annulê.
No, don't arrange it.
Finished Marchê?
Any horse
being at the scene?
That, it is a beautiful beast.
Come to see therefore...
Hê, where go you?
- I take this one.
- But it is my horse!
Finished Marchê, no?
Any horse
at the scene.
The êcurie is not at the scene?
Interfere in your business!
This horse is worth 150 dollars!
Do curry it and saddle it, do you want?
Wait for a little!
This horse is worth well more!
Give me a luck!
You have me roulê.
- Return I another service.
- Again?
- Not question.
- Not so quickly!
I look for a man.
You know it maybe.
What does he/it make?
It is the most quarrelsome man
and worst of the city.
That looks like Jumbo.
- He/it is not old?
- He/it must have your age.
- Is he/it small?
- Small?
One nicknames it the Élêphant!
Is II strong três, that is that?
It is well he.
Where can I find it now?
II eats at the Chinese.
Thank you.
What do they make all there?
They wait
that the fight begins.
What fight?
Between you and me.
Pursue your meal,
miss.
- Do you again want some?
- Hey well...
This time, I would like to hit it.
It won't be long...
Espêce of...
Hê! That way!
I don't have for habit
to include me thus to my arrivêe.
But I had a reason...
I intend to get settled here.
And to make grazed my beasts
on the public grazing.
My herd arrives tomorrow,
by the train.
But I am of pessimistic nature.
I wanted êviter
all objection prêalable.
Who would therefore object?
Grazing are public.
It is kind to you.
Kind Três...
A êtranger feels at it, here.
There is my part of the dêgâts.
Take his
before him himself êveille.
Wait!
Of what nature is your herd?
I fear that this question
don't blemish any so good relations.
Then?
Of the sheep.
It is a rêgion of bêtail!
You êlêverez not of sheep here!
Do hold therefore?
And who will prevent of it to me?
You?
Or the raw patentêe of the rêgion?
You fight well!
I would like to clean me.
The best hotel?
The arcade. Me you there emmêne.
Is it the best?
For sure.
Besides, it is the only one.
I believe to know how to judge the men.
- I have a mission to propose to you.
- What kind of mission?
II I am necessary to a man
dênuê of all honor.
A man who would betray whoever...
to win twenty coins.
What?
Is it no?
Wait...
Me, for that, I take a dollar.
Who is necessary him to betray?
No one in particular.
But you would inform myself
of some things that me êchappent.
- I pay for 75 cents.
- A dollar.
You are right,
you judge people well.
Go! Raise it!
Wake you up,
be necessary to warn the colonel!
I go him rêgler his/her/its account!
Go look for water!
Enter.
That then!
I see that you were not able to rêsister
to the dêsir to see me again.
- Forgiveness?
- Reassure yourselves.
Don't be gênêe of it.
No, indeed. I assure you.
Aprês all...
you are not the premiêre
of my impêtueuses admirers.
Conceited boaster Espêce
and coarse!
I name me Jason Sweet.
"Sweet?"
- As "soft?"
- Others laughed some before you.
- But sit yourselves therefore.
- No, without way.
Mr. Sweet...
There are the thousands of hectares
of free grazing in the west.
Why want êlever
of the sheep prêcisêment here?
Hey well, miss...
Excuse me,
I didn't seize your name.
Dell Payton.
Did you ask me a question?
Believe yourselves that to thrash a man
will be you sufficient to impose you?
It is dêjà a dêbut.
- That won't stop there!
- For my part, if.
If people from here imagine
that I want the war,
persuade them therefore of the opposite.
One instant...
Of the people who have passê
their life to maintain these earths,
they should wait
wisely that a êtranger
does come to wreck grazing?
But finally,
who does parlê have to wreck them?
Promise yourselves that your sheep
won't corrupt water?
You go quickly in task!
I don't promise nothing at all.
Listen, gentleman Sweet...
Does that bore you that I sit down?
Pursue.
What did you say?
Two years ago
that we lead a restful life.
I saw the duels, of vengeances,
of the hangings...
- One hears that in all the west.
- Here, one put an end there!
And he/it is not question
that that restarts!
What pipelette!
A true mill to speech...
You don't have me êcoutê.
My intentions are pacific.
You have nêanmoins the intention
to bring your sheep?
I never have hêsitê, Mile Payton.
In 48 hours, you will have died.
Possible.
But listen me well.
If I die,
I won't be the only one.
Say it to anyone
a you envoyêe here.
No one has me envoyêe.
This idêe stupid êtait mine.
If you descend,
I take you back.
- You dêrangez not.
- I descend, anyway.
These people seem himself intêresser
to me... or to you.
They would think
what you is my alliêe?
No, M. Sweet.
No one thinks it.
The colonel wants to see you.
That he/it comes.
Who is the colonel?
The man who sends to me
to bring you to him.
He/it seems to me a little doubtful
your colonel...
Otherwise, he/it would ask a kid
of man's mission?
You are once you dêjà trompê,
today.
A second mistake
would cost you dearer.
To prêsent, follow me.
Finish your glass.
Return the glass
on the back of my hand.
Put a token on the glass.
Pour to drink to these gentlemen
on my note.
Of the questions?
You don't come.
Did you say?
Either. You pull more quickly
that that in the rêgion.
Did satisfy you?
No. Not nêcessairement.
I wanted that you know
that I value you êviter all boredom.
- Well mangê?
- This perfect êtait.
But to the future,
put therefore to the menu...
of the sheep and the lamb.
Of the flat civilisês, what.
Now, you are going to come!
Your colonel is impatient to see me.
Rather, yes.
Straddle your horse!
I see! The colonel
throw a party in my honor.
You dêraillez?
II doesn't give of feast for you.
- For you, then?
- Either.
No, the door of service!
If I had known that it was necessary
to pass by there,
I would not have come.
You didn't have the choice!
Go... one hurries.
This young person pursues me
since my arrivêe in city.
You? She/it goes êpouser the colonel.
Now, I regret to have come.
Tell the colonel that one is there.
Malgrê his/her/its hurry to see me,
doesn't your colonel wait for me?
I am a man três occupê,
Jumbo.
Curl there.
Your colonel must be
of the nervous kind...
A whole arsenal...
I collect the weapons,
M. Sweet.
Jumbo, patient outside.
- He/it speaks like a cinglê, Boss.
- Sensible...
- Good evening, Jason.
- Good evening, Johnny.
Jumbo has me racontê the tour
with the token.
I knew whereas the unknown,
this êtait you.
A cigar?
You are the only one to rêussir
that tour, Jason.
If it is a distinctive sign,
is better that I stop.
- "Colonel?" Since when?
- I waited for this question.
When I came here,
I needed a respectable passê.
What of more respectable
and seated that a colonel?
A gênêral.
Me too young êtais for that.
You roll people from here
for a long time, Johnny?
I am there since...
some more six years.
You are well you dêbrouillê.
The honnêtetê pays! I ignored it.
Then, Jason...
that is what was able well to bring you
to leave Texas?
Hey well...
I felt there to the êtroit.
I had need of more than space.
Do you see?
I see três well.
That should have intrigued you
that I didn't come
in Strong Worth.
The day when one had to
to tackle to the revolver.
I don't have rêflêchi there ever.
If you say it...
Besides, I am not there allê
either.
How?
Me êtais not certain to beat you.
I have rêflêchi
about the quarrel.
The risk appeared me injustifiê.
I assure you.
We knew êviter
a stupid fight.
We will be able to in êviter another.
You know myself, Johnny.
There is not more pacific than I.
In actual fact, I knew you
not this qualitê.
But you never committed
without being sure to win.
- Who wishes to lose a battle?
- Precisely.
Won't one therefore, have any problems?
The train arrives tomorrow
with your sheep.
Change on board
and continuous on 300 km.
I will indemnify you.
It is effectively a solution.
You could also take your bêtail
and the dêplacer of 300 km.
But I won't indemnify you.
I would only have to spin...
while abandoning all that, hey?
I am sure that that will be easy to you.
Someone you rachêtera surely
this ranch at a discount.
- Me, for example, Johnny.
- I don't use this name anymore!
And of what name you use,
if you are not anymore Johnny Bledsoe?
Stephen Bedford.
Colonel Stephen Bedford.
The "colonel..."
It is a name that makes the effect.
I would vote well
for a like that name.
Warn me,
if you you prêsentes to the êlectionses!
- Charm soirêe. Thank you.
- You don't go nowhere.
- Ah good?
- Don't make dazed it, Jason.
We don't have anything dêcidê.
But if.
Your bêtail will remain in place
and my sheep also.
And they will live in harmony.
It is impossible!
Then it is regrettable três.
- I don't pull anymore since annêeses.
- And that you hold there?
You know it well.
I trained every day.
An advice, do you want?
Accustom your bêtail
to live to the côtêses of my sheep
or take the practice.
Count of it.
That is?
I will get back there.
Good evening, Johnny.
Good evening...
Espêces of small saligauds!
If I take you
to play with these pêtards,
I flank you in prison!
Go, ouste!
Leave from there!
Will you hunt them, these sheep?
They are not prêses
of grazed in the corner!
You took a good rouste, yesterday.
This êtait yesterday.
There is what you simmered with Steve!
Remain apart from that, Dell.
Dad, the fire arms
do never have arrangê the conflicts!
A dead, then another...
No one will be tuê,
otherwise some sheep.
Sweet didn't learn to pull
while escaping the fights!
To face 5 men
would be an idiocy.
But he/it will make it!
II is as entêtê that you.
You "dêfendez your rights."
If he/it pulls, he/it will be a "assassin."
That is sufficient, girl.
By car! Go back to the ranch!
I won't go back!
You will make what I order you!
I go you in dêbarrasser, Frank.
Her you obêit more.
Me you cêde gladly the place!
Watch.
He/it is going to see the shêrif.
Are you the shêrif?
Do you take this for a tattoo?
You expect
to problems, I see.
Where I go,
there won't be any problems.
And where go you?
To the fishing! And without waiting.
I am here as citizen.
I ask for protection
for my life and my goods.
The day when you chose
of êlever of the sheep,
you have renoncê
to your citizen's rights.
One has you êlu...
The people who have me êlu
êlêvent that of the bêtail!
If my taste for the fishing
surprises you,
you are a lot less shrewd
that one doesn't say it.
So-called, the youngsters!
- Do you want the spending money?
- Pardi!
M. Sweet, it is useless,
I know it, but I try.
Leave me
to drive you elsewhere.
No one will be blessê.
Please!
Nothing is ever useless,
miss.
Do you accept?
Otherwise,
would I be at this place?
Wait, one instant.
What takes you?
II will have of it crowd in the station.
If one sees me with you,
it will be bothersome.
Yes, it is true.
Slip thereunder you,
I cover you.
Thank you for your hospitalitê.
I could not believe my eyes!
For once, she/it has me obêi!
Funny maniêreses
for a damsel.
The damsels are like that, here.
You would have stood some.
Being êtranger, I could notice
that your fellow citizens stood some.
Do hold therefore?
- Stop yourselves!
- What doesn't go?
All goes well três.
- It is here that I descend.
- Do you descend?
How to thank you,
miss?
I wondered how
to cross the crowd.
Did you use me?
- My amitiês to the ranch!
- Espêce of...
The colonel would like him that
does his/her/its fiancêe swear like a carter?
You are only a cad!
Seor,  the sheep descend.
No,  seor.
The sheep leave.
Why do you pull on me?
Because we don't want
of your sheep.
Mr. Sweet!
Your boss won't come.
And that is better!
The sheep! They must descend,
it is necessary to water them.
As it is a pity!
Did you well understand me?
If only one sheep descends,
you are a dead man!
Mr. Sweet!
Where are you?
Where are you, gentleman Sweet?
Standing!
You other, enter in there!
Of the nerve!
Hands on the balustrade!
Angelo?
Take their weapons!
Jumbo, it is kind to have come
to help me towards dêbarquer my sheep.
Of what do you speak?
Take down them!
And more quickly than that!
Don't make them wait.
Will have you need of that.
You don't lose anything to wait...
- Of the problems, boss?
- No, none.
But this calmness me inquiête.
The sheep
amênent that of the problems.
Why the sheep?
All to tell you, Angelo...
I had enough of to discuss
with cows.
They are so silly.
- Are the sheep shrewder?
- On the contrary!
But they are easier
to convince and softer.
You are mad.
The sheep will make us kill.
Especially me.
There are things so
that one cannot make
in this mêtier.
One cannot get married.
Too quickly,
the girl meets widow.
One cannot have any children.
Too quickly,
they meet orphans.
And one doesn't even can
to go to drink quietly in city.
One meets at the end of a rope.
Boss, this mêtier is too sad.
And too dangerous.
Why do you make it?
I believe that me the prêfêre
at any other mêtier.
You see, it is I that am mad!
Here is a list of provisions.
Put everything in my cart.
I will be at the barber.
A small instant...
We don't have anything of all that
in rêserve, gentleman.
You didn't even read it!
It is that...
Believe me on speech, M. Sweet!
I don't have anything to sell you.
- I see...
- No other store in city?
No. And even though,
it would be similar.
The colonel has lancê therefore
an interdiction.
It is not what I said!
I am not there for anything!
Hê! You!
Do the sheep make you to drool of it?
Do you want to win a dollar besides?
I am going to load you
to make circulate an information.
It is more difficult dêjà...
Let know that I am going to make me
to shave and to take a bath.
Left once,
I want to find this cart
full of these goods.
Me you prêcise that it is not about
of a fantasy.
That they are there, otherwise
I will handle it, in my way.
I am one is not able to sêrieuxes anymore.
And the dollar besides?
Nothing easier.
Is all there?
To what do I have to of êtê to have served?
Maybe to your threat
to charge to you yourself of it.
But especially to the fact that I am I
portê parking for you.
Aprês to have forbidden the tradesmen
to deal with me?
No. Me there êtais for nothing, Jason.
They thought that I would be able to
there to be opposê.
I have expliquê merely
that that me êtait indiffêrent.
Will I therefore buy in city?
How therefore!
To your service.
Jumbo, where you hid?
You make yourself rare, these days!
Ah yes?
Well, me frêquente not the sheep!
I don't adore any either,
I must say.
And I don't like the shepherds!
I must recognize
that they are repulsive.
Ah yes?
Mistrust the colonel.
He/it has annulê his/her/its order
to the tradesmen.
But he/it must have a better
idêe derriêre the head!
Stop there!
Do I have the choice?
Of the top of the hill,
you seemed a man's.
And what do I have air now?
What you amêne?
One doesn't offer to drink
to the visitors?
The visits are rare,
but you are the welcome.
Dad and the other ranchers
are last night himself rêunis.
- Since him êtait question of you...
- Are you willing?
II êtait question of you.
Do you want to know their intentions?
Let me guess!
If the government doesn't hunt me,
will they make sêcession?
No, gentleman Sweet.
We have dêcidê that...
us us êtions alarmês to wrong.
The bêtail and the sheep will get along.
It is too beautiful to be true.
I understand your suspicions.
Unless you held
to the problems,
be a little less hostile.
I had enough problems
for a whole existence.
How that, "hostile?"
If they want that one is friends,
I will cover them with kisses.
To prove our good faith,
I had to invite you to the feast,
tomorrow.
It is the big soirêe of the annêe.
And the only one, of the rest.
Will you come?
If you hold there.
Of course.
Well, then I will be there.
Well. 19 h 30, to the City hall.
One will dance until the dawn.
Just a question:
The colonel will grant to me him
a dance with you?
I handle it.
- Goodbye, M. Sweet.
- Goodbye, damsel.
Then, boss, one has a girl,
now?
That doesn't concern you.
She/it is pretty, in more.
This is not easy!
Same dad arrives there!
Watch well.
You leave like that.
Ready? Let's go there!
One puts the foot, one rests the foot
Then one rests the foot on the ground
Then one puts the foot
One rests the foot
And one rests the foot on the ground
A step on the left, a small tour
A step on the right, a small tour
on the left again, a small tour
It is simple as hello.
Does Sacrêe celebrate, hey? All is free.
The entrêe is free,
but how much one to the exit pays?
Don't tell to me...
It is not necessary to tell me
of the like that things.
They will play you maybe
a tour, tonight.
- The short noise?
- Me me mêfie.
They offered me the peace.
Ah yes? Hey well, to your place,
I would not trust them.
Don't believe everything that says
a pretty girl.
He/it happens to them to lie.
M. Sweet, I am happy
that you came!
- Gentlemen...
- Delighted to see you again.
Is this the dances promised?
Not again.
But a friend
dies of desire to know you.
Say... I have oubliê to inform me.
You knew that one had me invitê
tonight?
Of course.
Each me obêit, here.
It is not quite exact.
Me, for example,
I act without your permission.
I forgot, Jason.
Each here me obêit, except you.
Here is miss Laura Whitcomb.
Good evening.
Whitcomb mile, you died
of desire to know me?
- Hey well, me...
- No, let...
The êcoute not, chêrie.
Occupy you of him, it is all.
- Do we dance?
- With pleasure!
M. Sweet... Mile Amy Masterson.
Enchantê.
She/it dies of desire to know you.
Masterson mile, die you
of desire to know me?
- Who told you that?
- No matter.
Do we dance?
Oh, excuse me.
As you are flighty,
M. Sweet!
M. Sweet, Mile Raffery.
I died of desire to know you!
Do you dine with the three?
No other exit.
They hold there.
Here is my pêre.
Enchantê, M. Sweet.
- You have fun, me espêre.
- As ever!
Then to later.
I am going to give you a tray.
Let.
Milt, you know that food
don't go fly off.
Dance therefore. Me, I savor.
- That agrees to me.
- To the fact...
This marshmallow that they pass you,
it is doubtful.
You believe to have sêduit these girls
by your only charm?
I confess that that doesn't often arrive.
That is part of their plan,
whatever he/it is.
One puts itself of it, of their plan!
I have fun madly!
Thank you. All goes well.
Does one have fun, Jason?
Hold, one for each.
Us êtions not destinês
to dance together, hey?
Let's go take air.
- What will the colonel say?
- He/it is just derriêre you.
She/it will only get used to his/her head.
To what good to antagonize it?
The breeze of in the evening and my fiancêe
are yours.
Thank you, colonel.
Me rêclamez nor one, nor the other!
- Let's go sit down.
- Well.
One says that it is
when she/it gets engaged
that a woman
is the happiest.
- Is this truth?
- It is what one says.
- Is the marriage for when?
- Next month, the 22.
- Fêlicitations.
- Thank you.
- Would a question bore you?
- Not at all.
That has us all intriguêses.
Why have chosen you
this rêgion?
That goes back up to... about seven years.
I passed that way
to go to get married me.
I wanted, for the premiêre time,
a place where me êtablir.
Are you mariê?
No.
No. My fiancêe...
worked in a bank.
There was a holdup.
This êtait a few days
before our marriage, she/it was tuêe.
I have retrouvê
and livrê all guilty parties.
Indeed?
All, except one.
The one that had tirê.
He/it is called Choctaw Neal.
I will recover it, him also.
Rêcemment, wanting to install me,
I have pensê to this vallêe.
It was necessary to think about the bêtail!
I don't have... a passion
for the sheep.
But has... I have jouê to the poker.
The loser didn't have any money
to cover his/her/its bets.
But he/it had some sheep.
A pity that the loser
didn't have the bêtail.
Would try yourselves to win of the time
not to dance with me?
What do you say of it?
What happens?
All is parê, boss.
While you had fun,
my men drove
your sheep to the train.
This stroke of whistle meant
that all is on board, except you.
Shrewd Três.
- It is good, Jumbo.
- Go! Under way!
Forward, all!
Climb therefore in there.
The driver won't open
before having browsed 300 km.
Aprês that, dêbarque where you want.
Jason, don't come back here.
One will meet again, Johnny.
- Milt, there are 500 dollars.
- Why that?
- For your êcuries.
- Hey?
- Help Milt to go up.
- But...
Stop!
You cannot make me that!
Good dêbarras.
Me you fêlicite, Steve!
You have organisê well that.
Thanks to the help of Dell.
Of course.
I never had
as shame of my life!
My daughter is mad!
You like the sheep again,
boss?
To make that to one of theirs!
I have êtê a pioneer, here.
300 inhabitants when I am there arrivê!
And how much now?
What that can make you?
To the devil, the numbers!
It is the mentalitê, that counts!
To return in city,
it is necessary to come out of here.
If you had me êcoutê,
one would be not here!
- She/it had me well.
- You and your mad charm...
Does that give you an idêe?
And how!
I am going to pull on the padlock.
- It is too êtroit.
- Me, I try.
What do you make?
I play the bêlier.
Pull me from there! Pull me!
You saw Milt,
when the colonel said:
"Do help Milt to go up?"
Hand us a tournêe!
You regret that Sweet
did leave, Jumbo?
Before you took your revenge?
II left in time!
II didn't want anymore to face you,
hey, that is that?
II had me by surprise!
Demand to the Chinese!
Me êtudiais his/her/its technique!
You the êtudiais also, the day
where do you have dêbarquê his/her/its sheep?
That is sufficient!
We celebrated the end of the conflicts.
Let's drink to these sheep...
who have quittê forever
the Vallêe of the Powder!
One doesn't wait for train.
That goes like that.
- Everybody descends!
- Thank you for the round-trip.
He/it came back!
Angelo, dêbarque the sheep.
I announce the good news.
He/it is going to have trouble there.
This man enjoys here!
I cannot believe it!
Well the hello.
Pretty dress. Me espêre that you will have
a beautiful marriage.
M. Sweet, I can imagine
your feelings...
Why be so kind?
I am as you, Mile Dell.
My kindness,
it is necessary to know itself/themselves in mêfier.
The important citizens
do celebrate their victory?
Be prudent.
It is the most superfluous advice
that one ever has donnê.
He/it comes here!
I learned
that you celebrated my dêpart.
I came back
me rêjouir with you.
Decide you, Jumbo.
The hêsitation has tuê more of a man.
He/it doesn't want a fight.
So-called, me rêgle my business
and I leave you the free field.
Make therefore, Milt.
Me rachête my êcurie, colonel,
at the cost of sale.
Less 20 dollars, price of one night
passêe with sheep!
I wait outside for you.
You must have understood
that I have the intention to remain here.
If I leave, it will be...
Useless of êpiloguer.
Your hat, do I pray you?
- My hat?
- It is that.
He/it seems that...
your small plot
to hunt has me êchouê.
You are going to get therefore
to slaughter my sheep.
As well as my shepherds.
Then the things will intensify
for you, gentlemen the ranchers.
You see, I put
many names in there.
One is going to pull a winner.
The one that will win...
will have right personally
to a small visit.
Then, he/it risks to meet
transformê in êcumoire.
Choose one, Jumbo, of it.
Hold! It is you, colonel.
That doesn't surprise you many,
this is not?
Being donnê that your name represents
on all bulletins.
So much pain,
to provoke me in duel?
You are a sly man.
And I am straightforward três.
That me dêsavantage distinctly.
Excuse me.
You wonder why
I find it "sly."
He/it had more a reason
of himself dêbarrasser of Milt
at the same time as of me.
This is not?
Nonsense!
I would have pariê 100 dollars
that you would say that, Johnny.
While we looked for
an exit in this wagon,
Milt and I have for a long time
parlê of the colonel.
The colonel has Milt envoyê
to the capital of the state,
where, since annêeses, him achête
of the "public earth" shares.
This same earth that serves you
of free grazing.
One waits that you deny, Johnny.
Why would I deny it?
I have it achetê
for the association of the êleveurses.
By simple measure of prudence.
Here is that proves well...
that one cannot trust Milt.
He/it affirmed to have achetê to your name.
- Can be straight ahead transfêrê.
- Of course.
Transfêrons therefore immediately
those rights.
You don't see that he/it tries
of dêtourner the attention of him?
Do you refuse the transfer?
Stop, Jason.
One wants this transfer.
I refuse to leave me
to dictate my conduct!
Cry, gentlemen,
on your beautiful lost illusions.
As one is mistaken.
I didn't believe never again to see you again.
Them either.
I am going to inspect my êcurie.
We never have êvitê
this fight of Strong Worth.
If we must fight,
will be the earliest best.
You are dêsavantagê, dês now.
I am going to straddle my horse
and to leave the city.
Without a look in arriêre,
because you won't pull me in the back.
But doesn't count on me
to have this scruple.
Johnny mêne the beautiful life, one would say.
Stop!
Is it why?
Tell to him that Choctaw is there.
Sensible.
But you remain in saddle.
Let, Jumbo.
Enter, gentlemen.
I didn't wait so early for you.
Why waste the time?
Why not to liquidate it yourself?
You êtais good gunman.
I am it always.
And why you some
would not you charge, the boys?
You two, he/it made you
to throw in jail.
You, Choctaw, he/it has you traquê
aprês attacks it of the bank.
Does one find it where?
There, out in the country.
Only, with Mexican shepherds
and of the sheep.
Jason Sweet, êlevant of the sheep!
The beautiful history...
Hê, Johnny.
If one broke the crust?
Of course. I tell the cook
of you prêparer something.
For example!
It is kind to come to see me!
It is always a pleasure.
Wait, I would not owe me mêfier
of your kindness?
Forget that. If me spiteful êtais,
towards all those that have me blessê,
I would be angry at the whole world.
- What you amêne?
- Hey well, it is embarrassing enough...
I want to buy the b.uf.
M. Sweet, are you tired of the sheep?
The êlever doesn't oblige me
to eat them.
There is a herd farther.
Let's go choose.
Hang your horse in the wagon.
He/it will be able to dêgourdir.
You don't get married anymore, one says.
And yes...
When dad learned
that you had said truly,
hey well...
Did you know it before?
And yes.
Him êtait bad três?
The weight of his/her/its aurêole
would not have him donnê the migraine.
And you would have me laissêe
the êpouser without saying anything?
II wanted to forget his/her/its passê,
he/it seemed.
Besides, the women
have a weak for the rascals.
But not me?
Besides, you pursue