Jimmy, how are you?
Billy, it's good
to see you.
Admiral Sims,
General Mitchell.
We've met.
Mitchell,
you know Admiral Gage?
We've exchanged
correspondence.
This is Commander Landsdowne
of our lighter-than-air service.
His dirigible
will patrol the area
during maneuvers.
I know
the commander.
General Mitchell.
I'd like to
clearly state, Billy,
that I'm extremely
and utterly impartial...
in your dispute
with the navy.
That's why
the general staff
assigned me...
to decide whether
to allow you to
carry out this mission.
I assume you have
no objection to me.
I wouldn't want
a fairer judge.
Very well, then.
Admiral, will you state
the navy's position?
That battleship
is the primary target
of our maneuvers.
The air service believes
that it can be sunk
by aerial bombardment.
The navy denies this...
and asks that they
be allowed to sink it
with naval gunfire.
Why does the navy feel
the ship can't be sunk
from the air?
That ship
was once the pride
of the German navy--
the battleship
Ostfriesland.
The British called her
"the unsinkable Dreadnought."
Are you aware
of these facts, General?
Yes, sir.
Would you care to fly
back to Langley Field?
I'll show you exactly
how I intend to sink her.
Yes, I'll be glad to.
Gentlemen.
What'd you think of that?
All hits or near misses.
Quite impressive.
We'll send that scow
to the bottom
in nothing flat.
Somebody's burning!
Someone's burning!
Look! He's burning!
Call out the crash truck
and the ambulance!
Why doesn't he
use his parachute?
We have no parachutes.
[ Siren Wailing ]
[ Siren Continues ]
[ Coughing ]
Are you all right,
Bob?
Yeah, I--
I guess so.
I'm a little singed
around the edges.
Here.
What happened?
It's that fuel line.
I smelled gas
in the cockpit
when I took off.
Why'd you go up
when you knew
something was wrong?
General,
if it isn't one thing,
it's another.
Today it was that fuel line.
Yesterday
it was an oil pump.
And last week
I almost lost a wing.
And yet I'm luckier
than a lot of the guys.
Now you see, Jimmy,
why I need money so badly.
She certainly could
use some improvements.
But that's not
an impressive weapon,
any way you take it.
It can be. Come here.
I'd like to show you
something.
Halt!
Sentry, this is
General Guthrie.
Give me a hand,
will you.
Where'd you get those?
I had Ordnance
make it up for me.
One ton
of cast T.N.T.
You're not trying to tell me
that your planes can carry
a 2,000-pound bomb.
Of course they can.
They'll sink the battleship
as though it were a tin can.
Let's be realistic,
Billy.
A 2,000-pound bomb
is not practical
under wartime conditions.
Maybe you'll
get it in the air,
but never to the target.
That's exactly
what I want to do.
Give me a chance,
and I'll show you
it can be done.
On a staged exhibition, maybe,
but never in combat.
How high do you want to fly?
I'd like to come in
at a thousand feet.
You know as well as I do that
anti-aircraft will knock down
any planes lower than 5,000.
Anti-aircraft?
In a real fight,
our pursuit ships
would be in there
strafing their decks.
I have to be realistic
in this, Billy.
After all,
we have performance figures
on our guns.
But the airplane
is an unproved weapon.
I'll prove it to you
if you'll let me.
One of these days,
half the world will be
in ruins from the air.
I want this country
to be in the other half.
If I sink that ship,
we may have
a real air force.
Where's the money coming from?
There's not enough to go around
for the army and navy now.
Forget them.
The next war will be fought
in the sky anyway.
No war is won
until a bayonet is put
to the throat of the enemy.
The foot soldiers
won the last war,
and they'll win the next.
In the end,
it's the infantry
who will lead the way.
Yes, and we'll
blast the road for them.
Your attitude isn't
helping your case any.
I'm sorry, sir.
Well, then,
let's forget the next war.
I'm in a war right now.
My boys are dying
every week...
in these obsolete,
moth-eaten, antiquated
flying machines.
Let me get in there
and prove that
we're entitled to live.
Billy, this test
is supposed to simulate
wartime conditions.
If you come in
at a low level...
and drop a bomb too big
ever to be practical,
you're simply
staging an exhibition
for your own purposes...
and you'll give
the wrong impression.
Now, in order to be fair
to both sides, I'm going to
give you two cracks at her.
But you'll have to come in
at 5,000 feet and carry
only the thousand-pound bombs.
Five thousand feet?
Why, that'll rig it all
in favor of the navy.
I'm sorry.
Those are your orders.
Have you a car
available to take me back?
Yes, sir.
I'd like somebody
to tell me...
why the taxpayers
of this country should
throw their money away...
on a useless
military toy
called the airplane.
The theory is, Senator,
it might come in handy
in time of war.
War is a serious business,
Congressman Reid,
and it's got to
be taken seriously.
The taxpayers don't want
their money wasted on
a lot of silly kite-flyers.
One six-inch naval gun
is worth the entire
air service.
Exactly, and I think
it should be reduced to
its realistic proportions--
an entertainment unit
for holiday parades
and state fairs.
[ Laughing ]
If we have another war,
Senator, I hope
you fight it personally.
Gen. Mitchell has signaled,
requesting permission
to commence bombing.
Has he reported his altitude?
He's at the
5,000-foot level, sir.
[ Bombs Whistling ]
[ Explosions ]
[ Laughing ]
He didn't even scratch her.
I knew he couldn't sink her.
Sink her? He didn't
even touch her.
- After all, the British fleet
couldn't sink it.
- I knew he could never do it.
General,
I want new orders
for tomorrow.
In what way?
I want to use
2,000-pound bombs.
We've been
over that before.
Request denied.
You're dismissed,
gentlemen.
But, Jimmy,
with 2,000-pounders...
I don't have to
hit the ship.
Water concussion will
blow her bottom out.
I can prove it.
A 2,000-pound bomb
is an unrealistic weapon.
Make your run
as before.
I'm not going out there
and make a fool
of the air service...
in front of
40 foreign nations
and the world press.
You will carry out
your orders.
Let's--
Let's postpone the run.
Let me off the hook
till I can figure something out.
I think it would be
most unfortunate if you
were to sink that ship.
What?
Twice during my lifetime
this country's
gone to war...
with an army untrained,
unequipped and unready.
I don't want to go to war
that way again.
But I might have to
if you can make Congress believe
this country can be defended...
by airplanes alone.
You will attack
from 5,000 feet
with 1,000-pound bombs.
Good day, Billy.
Go on, go on.
What's going on,
boys?
We've been talking.
What about?
We've come
to the conclusion...
that we're just not
getting anyplace.
I see.
And?
And...
there just doesn't seem
to be any future, sir.
Everything seems
kind of hopeless.
So we've decided
to ask your advice...
if we should resign
from the service.
You want me to tell you
to quit flying?
Sure, the planes
are no good and--
and the pay is small,
but 20 years from now
San Francisco will be
just a few hours from New York,
and New York
will be a bombing run
from Berlin.
The whole--
The whole world
will be in the air.
[ Airplane Passing Overhead ]
Go ahead and quit
if you want to,
but don't ask me about it.
[ Buzzes ]
Oh. Billy.
Come in.
Oh, I-- I didn't think
you'd gone to bed yet.
I'm sorry I woke you.
Go on back to sleep.
No, no, come in.
Billy!
What are you doing
in Washington?
Well, I-- I didn't
mean to disturb you.
I've just been
driving around,
thought you might be up.
I'd better go.
Don't be silly.
Can I get you
anything?
No, thank you,
Margaret.
[ Chuckles ]
I wouldn't be
very good company
tonight.
You look tired.
Why don't you sit down.
I'll get you a glass of milk.
I know how you feel,
Billy.
It was tough luck
about the ship.
Well, it's not only
the ship.
The whole thing
has fallen apart.
My boys came to me tonight.
They want to quit.
All of them.
I'm not surprised.
We all get a little discouraged
at one time or another.
I've been thinking
maybe I've been wrong
about everything.
Maybe men
weren't meant to fly.
That doesn't sound
like you, Billy.
When I got
to be a general,
I thought,
Now I'll be able
to do things,
change the whole works.
But they're
out to stop me.
There's always
a bigger general.
[ Scoffs ]
General Yesterday.
No, thank you, Margaret.
I really don't care
for anything.
You go back to bed,
and I'll go where I belong.
Now, Billy,
drink this
and relax.
You can't
possibly sleep
the way you are.
Sleep?
[ Chuckles ]
There's a little job
I have to figure out
for tomorrow--
how to sink
a great, big, steel-covered,
unsinkable battleship...
when my commanding officer
has made it impossible.
You can't blame Guthrie
for that, Billy.
He's just going
according to rules.
That's the way we all
have to work-- by the book.
You know that.
Sure.
We go by the book.
Suppose some other country
throws away the book.
Then where are we?
I've got to open their eyes
to what can happen.
I've got to
sink that battleship.
You can't do
the impossible.
I can try.
Zach, will you
call Langley Field,
ask for Russ Peters,
tell him to get the boys up
and say I'm on my way
back there now.
Now? Oh, can't you
wait till morning?
No, there's--
there's something
I've got to do tonight.
And you know what?
I'm scared to death.
But Zach'll tell you
that's normal
for a flyer.
Billy, what are you
going to do?
You'll hear about it.
Don't forget that call,
will you, Zach?
Good night, kids.
Good night, Billy.
Night, Billy.
What is this
all about?
I don't know.
Call came
from Washington.
What's up,
General?
There's been a change
in orders, boys.
We go in at low level today
with 2,000-pound bombs.
Hey, now you're talkin'!
That's more like it!
When do we start?
How did you work it,
General?
Never mind.
Get the ordnance men out
and start loading.
General.
Is this really
on the level, sir?
Did new orders
really come through?
You heard what I said,
didn't you?
Yes, sir.
General.
This is a strange
time of night for orders
to come out, sir.
Are you sure
you're not just
doing this on your own?
Don't you worry
about that, Russ.
You just get out there
on the field
and get those planes ready.
Okay?
Yes, sir.
What are they doing?
They're dropping down
for a low-level attack.
But that's
against the rules!
Did you
authorize this?
Absolutely not.
[ Shouting ]
[ Explosions ]
[ Bombs Whistling ]
How was that for
a military toy, Senator?
[ Laughing ]
[ Airplanes Passing ]
"General Mitchell's
whole course
has been so lawless,
"so lacking
in reasonable teamwork,
"so indicative of
a personal ambition for
his branch of the service...
"at the expense
of everyone with whom
he is associated...
"that his actions
render him unfit for a high
administrative position...
"such as he now occupies.
"The secretary of war
hereby directs...
"that Brigadier General
William Mitchell...
"be relieved
of his command
in the air service...
"and be assigned to duty
at Fort Sam Houston, Texas.
"To accommodate
his new duties,
General Mitchell
will revert
to the rank of colonel."
Would you excuse us,
gentlemen?
Progress is necessary...
in an army, Billy,
but you've first
got to have an army.
There's no progress...
if your officers
are undisciplined.
I put my star on the line
for something I believe in,
and I lost.
Your contribution
is on record, Colonel.
It won't be lost.
I hope not, sir.
But there's more
at stake than me.
It's the air service.
It's a new weapon,
a big one.
The biggest
in the world.
Put me down
another step.
Make me a captain, sir,
but let me stay
in the air with my boys.
[ Sighs ]
Sorry, Billy.
Anything else?
No, sir.
It's not so bad
in Texas, Billy.
I've been there.
Yes, sir,
General.
Without a doubt,
your fort ranks
at the top of the list...
of the military
establishments we've
visited on our tour.
That's right,
General.
That's mighty fine
of you gentlemen.
A little more,
Congressman?
No, thank you, General.
There's a request I'd
like to make though.
Certainly, Mr. Reid.
There's one of your officers
I'd like to talk to.
Could I see Col. Mitchell?
Mitchell? Why, of course.
I'll send for him
right away.
No need to take him
away from his duties.
I just want to say hello.
If somebody could
show me where he is,
I can find my way back.
Why, of course,
of course.
It is recommended...
that said shed be located
within 20 yards
of the machine shop...
and be of
sufficient capacity...
for the storage
of spare parts as well.
Suggested dimensions are--
Thanks very much.
I'll find my way back.
Frank!
What are you doing here?
I'm on a junket.
Thought I'd drop around,
see how you are.
[ Chuckles ]
Well, I lost my stars,
but I still have all my buttons.
Gee, I'm glad to see you.
How are things in Washington?
Give me the news.
There hasn't been any
since you left.
Sergeant, take these
to Major Anderson.
Tell him
they're okay.
Yes, sir.
How are all my boys?
Have you seen them?
The ones that are left
are all right.
Have you seen Russ Peters?
I haven't heard
from him lately.
He's all right.
He's better off
than you are.
This climate must remind you
of your Philippines campaign.
Nobody's shooting
at me here.
The heat should be great
for your malaria.
I haven't had
a chill all summer.
Say, Frank, do you know
if the army's ordered any of
those new Ford Tri-motors?
I know. No.
They're a wonderful
airplane.
Isn't there something
you can do about it?
They won't listen to me.
What areyou
gonna do about it?
All I can do.
I'll write another letter
to headquarters.
I write one every day.
Sometimes two.
Ah.
Billy, they just put up
a new building in Washington
for letters like that.
It's built in the shape
of a wastepaper basket.
I'm the man
that can fill it.
It's disgraceful
what they're doing
to you, Billy.
You may not know it,
but you've got
plenty of friends,
and I'm speaking
for all of them.
Give us the word, and--
I'm sorry, Frank, but politics
and the army don't mix.
All right, if you can't
tolerate politics in the army,
how about outside the army?
Why don't you quit
and run for the Senate?
Wisconsin would elect you.
You could take
your father's old seat.
He was a great senator,
and you'd be
every bit as good.
With you in the Senate
and me in the House,
we'd squeeze an air service
out of them that'd
blacken the sky with planes.
I'm not a politician,
Frank.
I don't want to
turn the air service
into a political football.
Besides, how would I look
in a winged collar
and a frock coat?
I'd look great,
wouldn't I?
Billy Mitchell,
I don't know why
I bother with you.
You won't do anything
that makes sense.
We're both professional men.
You work by your rules.
Let me work by mine.
Some rules.
It's the same set of rules
that has your boys falling out
of the sky in flaming coffins.
They're dying
by those rules.
But at least
they go quick.
You're just
sitting around here
rotting away.
[ Chuckles ]
I must be too stupid
to understand the military mind.
I guess you have to be
born with one.
[ Door Opens,
Closes ]
Well...
so long, Billy.
Don't get
writer's cramp.
Sergeant,
cancel my reservation
to Milwaukee.
Yes, sir.
Check the train schedules
to Washington, D.C.
I'm taking my leave
there.
Good afternoon, sir.
How do things look
today?
Not very good, I'm afraid.
Now, listen here.
For two weeks
I've been trying
to see General Pershing,
and for two weeks you've been
telling me to come around again
in a couple of days.
I want
a definite appointment
with the general,
and I want to
talk to him today.
I'm sorry, sir.
General Pershing
has been very busy.
If I may suggest you try
some other department--
You told me that before.
And I've tried.
They've all referred me
back here.
Gen. Pershing
is the only one
who can help me.
Colonel, a great many people
want to see the general.
You must realize his time
is extremely valuable.
I'm here to try to
save lives, not time.
And if you'll forgive me
for saying so, Colonel,
I think the lives of flyers
are equally as important
as the general's time.
Gen. Pershing has an important
staff meeting scheduled
for the remainder of the day.
Thank you, Colonel.
You're welcome, sir.
Hello,
General Pershing.
I'm glad
I ran into you.
I have nothing
to say to you, Billy.
[ Doorbell Buzzes ]
Billy!
Hello, Margaret.
Well, there's been
a few improvements.
Including you.
You're prettier than ever.
How's Zach?
He's fine.
He'll be home later.
Oh, my, it's good
to see you again.
We've missed you.
And needed you.
I'll set another place.
Can't stay for dinner.
I have to catch a train
for Texas.
We heard you were in Washington.
I tried to drop around sooner,
but I couldn't
get off the flypaper.
I hope our army
is as invincible in the field
as it is in its offices.
Yes, I know.
Zach's been after
the navy department...
about theShenandoah.
They want him
to take it
to Detroit,
to a state fair.
Is that old river cow
still around?
[ Door Opening ]
Hi, honey.
Hello, darling.
Billy!
Gee, I'm glad to see you.
I called the club.
How are you?
You're looking
great.
Feeling fine.
Except for a couple
of sore feet
and a slightly sore head.
Yeah, I heard.
It's a shame.
How do you happen
to be home so early, Zach?
Orders came through.
What orders?
We're taking theShenandoahup
in the morning.
Oh, no!
It'll be all right, honey.
Don't worry.
But you said you wouldn't
take her up again.
I did everything I could.
I kept arguing
till the order came through.
You can't stop now.
You said you'd never take
her up this time of year.
Honey, I've got my orders.
I'd understand
if it were a war
or even a maneuver,
but they're
just doing it
for publicity.
The publicity's
supposed to make Congress
vote us money.
Please tell him not to go.
You're the only one
he'll listen to.
Margaret, please--
Don't worry about it,
Margaret.
It's a lousy balloon,
but it'll have
a good crew aboard...
and a good skipper.
Besides, if the navy's
not worrying about it,
why should you?
Look, I've got
to run now.
I'll be back for another
crack at Washington
in a few months,
and we'll-- we'll have
a real reunion then, hmm?
Do you have
a car outside?
No.
I'll help you
flag a cab.
Good-bye,
Margaret.
[ Zach ]
Be right back, honey.
[ Door Opens ]
How bad is
theShenandoah?
In this weather,
it's a deathtrap.
Then why do you
take it up?
I've got my orders.
You could disobey them.
Are you
out of your mind?
No.
But you are, if you
follow orders that send you
and your crew to your deaths.
Billy, you know
better than that.
If I refuse to go up,
then I'm relieved of command
and get a general court.
Someone else takes her up.
What have I accomplished?
At least you'll have
brought attention to the fact
that the flight is unsafe.
That isn't the point.
Drawing attention to it
isn't gonna save the men.
And I'm better qualified
to fly my ship than
any replacement would be.
Zach, don't you see?
If you refuse to take
that thing up,
there'll be
such an unholy row
that it might never take off.
Yeah, maybe.
But why should I
stick my neck out...
on the improbable chance
that they might
ground the ship?
No, it doesn't make sense.
What's your neck compared to
the whole future of aviation?
How much are you doing
for the future of aviation
buried in Texas?
Never mind about me.
We're talking
about you.
Mm-hmm.
Well, there's not much
I could do...
if I were court-martialed
and dismissed
from the service.
There'll be
no service left...
unless people know
how bad things are,
unless it's shown to them.
You must think that over.
I don't have to
think it over.
I've got my orders.
This flight
has been studied out.
They're taking
a calculated risk.
"Calculated risk"?
Uh--
You're staking
the lives of your crew...
to protect your career
in the navy.
Oh, hello, Billy.
Sit down.
Terrible thing,
thisShenandoahbusiness.
It's all over
the front pages.
Makes all the services
look bad.
Tough enough
getting recruits
as it is.
What did you want to
see me about, Billy?
I request
the general's
permission...
to attend the funeral
of Cmdr. Zachary Lansdowne
at Arlington Cemetery.
Was he a friend of yours?
A close friend, sir.
Why, sure, sure.
Go ahead.
Emergency leave
granted.
Thank you, sir.
Oh, wait a minute, Billy.
You're one of
those flyboys yourself.
I don't know
how headquarters
is reacting to this.
Public opinion may be
running very high.
Reporters running
all over the place...
covering the funeral
and asking questions.
Better let me
get a confirmation
from Washington...
before you take off.
May I ask
the general's permission
to withdraw my request, sir?
You mean you don't want me
to get a confirmation?
No, sir.
Whatever you say.
Thank you, sir.
???? [ Radio:
"Tea for Two" ]
Heard the news? Those planes
making the nonstop to Mexico
are reported lost.
[ Tuning Frequencies ]
Where'd you get that?
My gunny says he heard it
over the radio.
How does he know they're lost?
He didn't know.
That's all he told me.
Wait a minute.
[ Tuning Continues ]
[ Announcer ]
We interrupt
this broadcast...
to bring you
a news bulletin.
In the greatest disaster
in aviation history,
six planes en route from
San Diego to Fort Huachuca
have crashed.
The flight was composed
of members of the famous
Billy Mitchell squadron...
which, in 1921,
bombed and sank
the battleshipOstfriesland.
Ground parties
have been dispatched...
to the rugged
mountain area near
the Mexican border...
to search for
possible survivors.
We now return you
to our program.
???? [ Orchestra ]
I've asked you gentlemen
of the press to come here...
because I want to
make a statement.
Flying is a very
dangerous business,
and a normal
amount of accidents
are to be expected.
But these
recent disasters...
of theShenandoah...
and the planes of the army
of the Mexican flight...
are outside the range
of normal accidents.
I would not be keeping faith
with my dead comrades...
if I kept quiet
any longer.
These--
These accidents...
are the direct result of--
of incompetence,
criminal negligence...
and the almost
treasonable administration
of our national defense...
by the navy...
and the war department.
That is my statement.
Well, that's
sure somethin'.
Is this off the cuff?
You want us to print it?
It's a statement
for publication.
Baby, is this gonna
blow some brass tops off.
Would you mind
initialing that?
Colonel, my editor's
an ex-army man.
He may call you
to verify this.
Do you mind?
No.
I don't know anything about
army procedure, Colonel,
but couldn't you
be court-martialed for this?
That's exactly
what I want.
Colonel Mitchell?
Major.
By order of
the secretary of war,
you've been placed
in arrest, sir.
I've been ordered to
serve on you the charge sheet
and court-martial papers.
Thank you.
I'm instructed to tell you
that you're restricted
to the Washington area.
You will remember at all times
that you are in arrest
and deport yourself accordingly.
I understand, Major.
Report to the office
of the adjutant general
by noon tomorrow,
where your quarters
will be.
Is that all?
Yes, sir.
Now that that's over,
will you gentlemen join me
in a cup of coffee?
Thank you, sir.
I really don't quite--
That's okay, Major.
Carry on.
Mitchell.
Good morning,
General Guthrie.
I don't suppose
it's occurred to you
to resign.
Resign under fire?
Not a chance, sir.
I must say
I'm sorry, Mitchell.
Sorry for the army.
Good afternoon,
Colonel Mitchell.
Hello.
I'll send it
right up.
Welcome back. It's good
to see you again, sir.
Thank you, Phil.
Can I have
my old room?
It's ready for you, sir.
Excuse me.
You're Col. Mitchell,
aren't you?
Yes.
I'm Lt. Col. White.
I've been appointed
your defense counsel
by the judge advocate general.
I'm glad to see you.
Come up to my room.
We can talk there.
Fine.
I assume, sir,
that you've been served.
Got them right here.
I don't think there'll
be much for you to do.
It's an open-and-shut case.
Is it?
Oh, yes, I'm guilty.
Definitely.
You'll plead guilty?
No, I guess I'll have to
plead not guilty
if I want my day in court.
You mean, you, uh--
you did it
deliberately?
I had to make somebody
listen to me.
You chose the hard way,
Colonel.
I know it,
and I haven't
got a chance,
but I want to
go through with it
anyway.
Sound crazy,
don't I?
No, sir.
No, I, uh,
I think I understand.
Have the members
of the court
been announced?
Just came through.
I saw General Guthrie
downstairs.
So did I.
What does he
have to do with it?
He's been appointed
the president of the court.
Who are
the other members?
[ Chuckles ]
A regular who's who
of the army.
"Maj. Gen. George L. Irwin,
Gen. Slade, Gen. Graves,
Gen. Ford.,
Gen. Douglas MacArthur,
Gen. Bolling."
There's not
a flying officer
among them.
Sir, have you considered
taking on a civilian counsel?
You're entitled to one,
you know.
Could use
the heavy artillery, huh?
Well, honestly, sir,
I don't think we can afford
to overlook any possibility.
Big name?
The biggest possible.
I've never had to go
outside the army before.
Why, Col. Mitchell!
It's so good to see you
again, sir.
You look as well
as ever, Mrs. Sturges.
Is Congressman Reid in?
Yes, he is.
Go right in.
Thank you.
Hello, Frank.
Billy! It's about time
you showed up.
Well, you finally did it.
You kicked 'em
where it really hurts.
I'm proud of you.
I hope you're here
for the reason I think.
Gonna let me handle this?
You're stuck with me.
I've been
counting on it.
Been preparing since you
got in your jam. I'm ready
to go to court tomorrow.
Let's see what section
they've thrown at you.
I thought so.
Article 96,
the catch-all clause.
Covers everything
from kicking a horse
to kissing a sergeant.
"Conduct prejudicial to
the good of the service,"
my eye!
This is the way
I see it.
We won't wait for the
court-martial to start in on us.
We'll open up on them first.
We'll call a press conference,
we'll issue a statement,
blast the navy out of the water.
Then we'll take on
the general staff
of the army--
No, Frank, no.
What's the matter?
I don't like it.
I don't want it.
I won't fight that way.
This is what
you've been fighting for
all these years--
a chance to get recognition
for the air service,
to tell the people about
the importance of air power.
You haven't changed
your mind about that,
have you?
No, I haven't.
I want a new air program
and a new air service.
But I don't want
to wreck the army to get it,
or the navy either.
I don't understand you, Billy.
In a fight like this,
it's all or nothing.
[ Sighs ]
I don't see it that way.
I see.
You want to kick
the army in the pants,
but do it politely.
All I want is a chance to tell
the whole tragic story...
of this country's
air defense.
All I want
is my day in court.
And that's exactly
what you'll get--
one day, with Gen. James Guthrie
as president of the court.
Have you heard
about Guthrie?
What do you think I do
around Washington,
warm a chair?
What can I do?
Challenge him for prejudice
and kick him off the court.
I'll not be a party to anything
that casts aspersions
on the integrity of an officer.
[ Scoffs ]
The old school tie, huh?
The army took me in
when I was a raw kid.
It taught me everything I know.
I'm not at war
with the army.
Billy Mitchell,
you're not talking
like your father's son.
That great old man would be
fighting with everything he had
to get a fair trial.
I'm being court-martialed
by officers of
the United States Army.
I'll get a fair trial.
Unless you believe that, Frank,
don't take the case.
All right.
You've handcuffed me,
but I'll try to get you off.
If I do,
it'll be quite a trick.
This looks like
a warehouse.
Itwasa warehouse.
Last night
they converted it
into a courtroom.
[ Photographer ]
Just one second,
Colonel, please.
Thank you.
Good morning, Colonel Moreland.
I see we're tangling again.
Yes.
Well, good luck.
It's a fine place
to hide a trial.
I would say they want
as little public attention
as possible...
for your day in court.
Colonel Mitchell?
My name is Carlson.
I'm reporter
for this court.
George Carlson.
Yes?
My son served
under you.
He was shot down
over the Argonne.
Do you mean
Glen Carlson?
Yes, sir.
Well, I'm very glad
to meet you.
Glen was a fine boy.
Looked a lot like you,
as a matter of fact.
I've always wanted
to thank you for
the letter you wrote.
It was such
a great comfort
to us.
I wish I could've
done more.
Well, I'm sorry
about all this.
I'd just like to say...
Stand up when
the court enters!
good luck.
The court
will come to order.
Colonel Moreland.
The prosecution is
ready to proceed
with the trial...
ofThe United States
against William Mitchell,
Colonel.
Whom does the accused
wish to introduce
as counsel?
As counsel,
the Honorable Frank R. Reid,
and as associate counsel
the regularly appointed
defense counsel,
Lt. Col. Herbert A. White.
Before this court
is sworn,
I would like to state
that it will be conducted
as a military tribunal.
I expect
the fullest cooperation
from both sides...
to bring it to
the speediest possible
conclusion.
The trial judge advocate
will now swear in the court
and read the charge.
"Further, that the accused
did conduct himself...
"to the prejudice
of good order
and military discipline,
"and in a way
to bring discredit upon
the military service.
"Further, that the accused,
"with intent to discredit
the administration
of the war department,
did make a statement highly
contemptuous and disrespectful
of said administration."
Colonel Mitchell,
you have heard the charge
and the specifications.
How do you plead?
Not guilty.
[ Spectators Murmuring ]
The prosecution
may proceed.
does not desire to make
any opening statement.
If the court please,
I wish to withhold
my opening argument...
until the government
states its case.
However, we intend to
show that Col. Mitchell's
statement was justified...
by the deplorable conditions
in the army and navy.
Justification
is not an issue here.
This is a very simple case.
Did or did not the accused
make the newspaper statements
attributed to him?
- If he did, he's guilty.
- Not if the statement's true.
We want a--
You will have an opportunity
to develop that point later,
Mr. Reid.
The trial judge advocate
will call the first witness.
The prosecution
calls Carl Tuttle.
Carl Tuttle!
Mr. Tuttle, are you
the author of this article...
which contains
an alleged statement
by the accused?
Yes, sir, I am.
At this time I ask
that this newspaper
be received...
as the prosecution's
exhibit number one.
It will be
so received.
Now, Mr. Tuttle,
who gave you this statement
which later appeared in
the columns of your newspaper?
Col. Mitchell, sir.
And it was printed exactly
as he gave it to you?
Yes, sir.
Where did Col. Mitchell
give you this statement?
In his office
in Fort Sam Houston.
How did you happen
to be there?
Col. Mitchell telephoned
my editor and asked him
to send over a reporter.
No further questions.
Does the defense desire
to cross-examine?
Mr. Tuttle,
did your paper
make any effort...
to find out the truth
or the untruth of
Col. Mitchell's statement?
Yes, sir.
I was put on the story.
What did you do?
I called up 50 officers
in the various branches
of the service...
and asked their opinion--
Objection.
This is hearsay.
Sustained.
Did the 50 officers
you interviewed all agree...
that the conditions
in the army and the navy,
as described by Col. Mitchell--
Objection!
This is irrelevant
and calls for a conclusion
on the part of the witness.
Sustained.
You must stop when you hear
the court's ruling, Mr. Reid.
I'll put the question
another way, General.
The question
is irrelevant
in any form.
The court directs you
to confine yourself to evidence
permissible under its rulings.
Col. Moreland,
call the next witness.
The prosecution
calls Howard Millikan.
Mr. Millikan, did your paper
receive any letters from
your readers in this matter?
Yes, many.
What would you say
was the general tone
of these letters?
Objection.
Question is irrelevant.
Sustained.
Were your readers
shocked?
What was their feeling
about Col. Mitchell and his
devotion to his country?
Objection.
Question is immaterial.
Do not answer,
Mr. Millikan.
Mr. Reid, my patience
is nearing its end.
My belief
in military justice
is also nearing its end.
We have a right to prove
the defendant was justified
in saying what he did.
In a military court,
Mr. Reid,
there is no justification
for disobedience,
insubordination or treason.
I don't agree,
General.
It's one thing when a man
accuses another of being
a murderer without cause.
- It's something else
when he can prove it.
- I object!
Mr. Reid
is arguing his case.
The issue here is,
did the accused make the
statements attributed to him?
And did he make them
without authority?
On this point,
uncontradicted proof
has been presented.
And on this point,
the prosecution rests.
[ Spectators Murmuring ]
[ Guthrie ]
You may step down.
Is the understanding
of the court correct?
The prosecution has
no further witnesses?
That is correct, sir.
The defense may summon
its first witness.
[ Whispering ]
We got anybody
on deck?
No.
I had no idea
they'd finish so quickly.
If it please the court,
witnesses for the defense
are still en route.
They're not present
in Washington?
The brevity
of the prosecution's case
has upset our timetable.
These witnesses
should be standing by,
Mr. Reid.
That would've been difficult
for most of our witnesses,
because they're officers
in the armed forces...
and need special permission
to leave their posts.
Who are these officers?
"Major H.H. Arnold,
Major--"
Just a moment, Mr. Reid.
What would be the nature
of these witnesses' testimony?
- To prove the truth
of Col. Mitchell's statement.
- The prosecution objects.
The truth or falsity
of Col. Mitchell's statement
is not an issue here.
Was this Major Arnold
present...
when the accused made
the alleged statements
to the press?
- No, sir,
but he'll prove justification.
- Objection.
- The court has already
ruled on that issue.
- Sustained.
Who are
your other witnesses,
Mr. Reid?
"Major Carl Spaatz,
Capt--"
Objection!
May I see that list,
please, Mr. Reid?
"Captain E.V. Rickenbacker,
"Congressman
Fiorello La Guardia,
Admiral William S. Sims"?
Were any of these people
present in Texas
at the stated time?
No, sir, they were not.
Then, I regret to say,
they're inadmissible.
Without them,
I haven't any case.
Then the court
will stand adjourned...
and give you time
to prepare one.
[ Spectators Murmuring ]
What do you think
about the day's doings,
Col. White?
It's court
procedure.
My dear friend,
that's not a court.
A man's allowed to
defend himself in court,
even a triple murderer.
They're operating
under army rules,
Frank.
You stay out of this.
I got to figure out something,
or we're through, licked.
No way of changing
the procedure, Mr. Reid.
You call that
procedure?
[ Chuckles ]
The accused is permitted to
give his name and address,
then off with his head.
We'll get our innings.
We'll get nothing.
You don't have a chance
if they don't let us try to
prove you were justified...
in making
that big pronouncement
of yours.
It's like refusing
to allow a defendant
to present an alibi.
I'll give them
what you call my alibi.
I'll testify and give them
my story in full, for the court
and for the whole country.
And I'll bring up
all the justification
there is.
You're talking through your hat.
You be asked, "Did you make
that statement? Yes or no?"
Am I right, Colonel?
That's right.
Colonel, what do you think
the chances are...
of our getting
one justification witness
into this trial?
Nonexistent.
If they let one on the stand,
they'd have to let them all.
Then I've got to stall
till I can get an idea.
Do you know
what a filibuster is?
When a politician can't
think of anything to say,
he talks.
I'm going home and gargle.
And now,
if the court please,
I ask permission
to read into the record...
newspaper comments
concerning this trial.
These are editorials...
which have been
printed in newspapers
from coast to coast.
I wish at this time
to have them entered...
as evidence
for the accused.
What is your purpose,
Mr. Reid?
Are you seeking to delay
the proceedings
of this court?
I believe public opinion has
a bearing on the deliberation
of this court.
Objection.
Irrelevant
and immaterial.
Sustained.
You are obviously addressing
the ears of the press,
Mr. Reid.
You are instructed to make
your publicity statements...
outside the precincts
of this courtroom.
[ Clears Throat ]
I have here...
a copy of theManual
of Courts-Martial,1921.
It states that under
the procedure governing
trial by court-martial,
a charge having been made
must first be referred...
to the immediate
commanding officer
of the accused,
and, thereafter, the person
who preferred the charges,
together
with available witnesses,
shall appear before him,
and the accused shall then
be given a chance to defend
himself before that officer.
The court is aware
of all that.
You're referring
to paragraph 76-A
of theManual.
Well, if
the trial judge advocate
is aware of that clause,
I ask why this opportunity
was never afforded
to Col. Mitchell.
I ask the name of the officer
who preferred charges
against Col. Mitchell.
That name is not
presently available.
It shouldn't be
so hard to find.
Wouldn't he be Col. Mitchell's
immediate commanding officer
at Fort Sam Houston?
- Not necessarily.
- Then according to
the chain of command,
wouldn't he be the commanding
general of the core area
in which Col. Mitchell served?
That need not be so.
Well, then he'd certainly
be the chief of staff
of the army, wouldn't he?
He would not have to be.
Well,somebodymust have
preferred these charges
against Col. Mitchell.
And since we can't
seem to locate him,
I'm left no alternative
but to name the one officer
in the army...
who's the commander
of every soldier serving
under the American flag.
I name the president
of the United States.
[ Spectators Murmuring,
Talking ]
Order in the court.
For the court's convenience,
I have prepared here
a subpoena...
calling upon President Coolidge
to appear before
this tribunal...
and to testify as to
his personal knowledge
of the facts of this case.
I call upon the court
to issue this subpoena
and have service made upon him.
This will be considered
in closed session.
Court will adjourn.
[ Spectators Chattering ]
[ Man ]
Congratulations, Frank.
Congratulations.
[ Overlapping Dialogue ]
[ Knocking ]
It's open.
Morning.
I'm disappointed.
I thought it would
be President Coolidge.
[ Chuckling ]
Had your breakfast?
Yes, thanks.
They're all
in a dither.
Who's that, Colonel?
The newspaper boys.
That Cal Coolidge thing
has them all agog.
The newspapers
aren't gonna help us.
They're good for
crying at a funeral
or a... hanging.
They've never yet
stopped one.
Hmm.
[ Knocking ]
Come in. It's open.
Gentlemen,
we can make a deal.
A what?
A compromise.
Now, this isn't official
yet, but my connections
assure me...
that if you'll retract
your Texas statement, they'll
pressure the War Department...
into letting you off
with a reprimand.
I have a draft
of a statement here
I think they'll accept.
Can I see it?
Hey, this isn't bad, Frank.
In fact, it's very good.
Dignified, no crawling.
Oh, "I errored
through overzealousness."
That's fine.
Excellent.
Have you got a moment,
Billy?
I can't do it.
How's that?
I can't retract
what I've said.
For heaven's sake, why not?
You only said it
to get your day in court.
You found out you can't have
a day in court where you're
allowed to prove anything.
So you're
losing nothing.
The trial isn't over yet.
Maybe I'll get a chance
to say what I've got to say.
What are you expecting,
a miracle?
Day after day, you've
sat in that courtroom.
You know you'll
never be allowed
to open your mouth...
on anything other
than the charges
brought against you.
Don't be a fool, Billy.
This is no good. Get out
of it while you can.
I can't think of myself alone.
There's all the rest of them.
There's the whole future
of this country in the air.
I've got to go on with it
while there's any chance
this trial will break open.
And you must go on trying
to win for me, Frank.
I never said I'd win for you.
I hoped I'd get you off.
That's just what I've done.
I've saved your career for you.
I've made it possible for you
to stay in that precious
uniform of yours.
That's the best I can do.
That's the best anybody can do.
Now sign this.
I can't do it,
Frank.
[ Pen Clatters ]
As I don't believe
in miracles,
I should tell you to get
yourself a new lawyer.
But I do believe a man
should be buried
by his friends,
so I'll stay
for the funeral.
Come on, Colonel.
Ah, why don't I give up?
What am I
struggling for?
If we could only get
one witness on the stand...
to punch one air disaster
into the record,
we'd punch a hole
in the dike.
Impossible.
Margaret Lansdowne.
It's against procedure.
It's perfect.
It's the other half
of our case.
Don't you see? It wasn't
only the army Billy accused.
It was the navy too.
The navy wouldn't
listen to Lansdowne...
any more than the army
would listen to Mitchell.
Perfect justification.
Mr. Reid, the court
has ruled repeatedly
on this.
They won't allow her
to take the stand.
The widow of a naval hero?
Huh. When the papers
print her story...
and spread it in headlines
across the country,
no court on earth can refuse
to put her on the stand.
I'll see you in court
tomorrow.
Mrs. Lansdowne?
Yes.
I'm Congressman Reid.
I know.
I've seen your picture
in the papers.
May I come in?
I know what
you're here for, sir,
and my answer is no.
I'm sorry.
May I talk to you
a minute, please?
If you wish.
Do I understand you
correctly, that you...
don't want to testify
for Col. Mitchell?
That's right.
But why?
You must have a reason.
I wish you'd tell me
what it is.
I'm sorry. I can't.
May I sit down,
please?
I don't think
we have very much to say
to each other, Mr. Reid.
I think we have
quite a bit to say.
Please?
All right, if you don't
want to tell me,
I won't ask you why
you don't want to testify.
Maybe you have a reason.
Maybe somebody got to you
and convinced you not to talk.
Maybe you think you ought
to protect somebody.
I don't know,
and I don't care.
But one thing
I must know though.
Please don't think
I'm impertinent,
Mrs. Lansdowne.
- I assume that you loved
your husband. Am I right?
- Of course.
All right. And you know that
he died fighting for a cause.
Yes.
That his sense of duty
was so strong...
that he took up a ship
that he knew was unsafe...
and that he fought
in every way possible
to keep grounded.
- How do you know
all this?
- That's immaterial.
I'm trying to tell you
that Billy Mitchell...
is fighting the same fight
your husband fought.
And if your husband
were alive today,
he'd be right in there
with Billy helping him
in every way he could.
[ Crying ]
Please, I wish
you wouldn't.
The only way to avoid such
needless, futile sacrifices
as your husband made...
is for the people
to know the truth.
[ Crying ]
Billy Mitchell has staked
his entire military career
to get it to them.
And I know that your husband
would want you to help him.
[ Sniffling ]
You know he would too.
Mrs. Lansdowne, may I ask
why you have waited until now...
to spread this tale
in the newspapers?
- Nobody asked me before.
- And who asked you now?
It was my own decision.
As I understand it,
Mrs. Lansdowne,
you and Col. Mitchell
have been close friends
for a long time.
That's right.
Isn't it possible
that you came here
to aid an old friend...
at the expense
of the exact truth?
- I object!
- Sustained.
Very well.
You say, Mrs. Lansdowne,
that Col. Mitchell did not
ask you to testify here.
That's right.
Did someone else ask you?
Yes.
Who?
Congressman Reid.
Congressman Reid?
And did Congressman Reid
suggest...
that you tell the story
as it actually happened,
or did he perhaps suggest
that you emphasize
elements in it...
which would prove favorable
to Col. Mitchell?
I object!
I object most violently...
the suggestion that I
suborned this witness.
I am only trying to find out
why this witness--
You are trying to imply
that I put pressure
on Mrs. Lansdowne...
to come here
and perjure herself.
I think, sir, that
my reputation in the Congress
of the United States--
- I am not impugning
your reputation.
- Order in the court.
Allow me
to rephrase my question.
Prior to your appearance here,
was pressure brought to bear
on you?
Yes.
Very strong pressure.
Well.
[ Spectators Murmuring ]
Suppose you tell us
about it.
- I was told
not to testify.
- Not-- By whom?
I'd rather not say.
Go ahead. Tell them.
Tell them who told you
not to testify.
Some friends of my husband--
naval officers.
- Objection! I withdraw--
- Let her speak.
Let her speak.
Tell the court what they said.
[ Guthrie ]
Just a moment, Mr. Reid.
Mrs. Lansdowne,
you're making
a very serious charge.
Are you telling this court
that you were approached
by naval officers...
who asked you
to withhold information?
Yes, sir.
Tell the court
who they were.
I object! This is irrelevant
and-and immaterial!
Objection overruled.
I would rather not
identify them.
They thought
they were doing it
for the good of the navy.
- What did they say?
- They said it was the duty
of a navy wife...
to protect the service
at all costs.
Didn't you
agree with that?
Yes.
They told me that my husband
was a naval hero...
and that I owed it
to his memory...
not to drag his name
through the mud of a trial.
Then what made you
change your mind?
Because
I realized...
that by
telling the truth,
I would be doing my duty
to the navy and to Zach.
If Zach were alive,
he would be here to
testify for Col. Mitchell.
I am testifying
in his place
and telling the truth.
He tried everything.
He wrote letters,
made phone calls,
protested to everyone.
He knew it wasn't safe
to take that ship up.
On the last day, I drove out
to the mooring mast with him
to say good-bye.
Everything was ready
for the takeoff,
but he kept delaying
the departure.
He was waiting, hoping
for some last-minute word
from Washington.
We walked to the communication
shack together,
and he asked the chief on duty
if a message had come for him.
There was none.
And when the ship was ready,
he kissed me good-bye
and climbed into the cabin.
He waved to me
through the window once,
and then he gave the order
to cast off.
I never saw him again.
Zach and his men were
sent to their deaths
by indifference!
Zach was too young
to be insubordinate,
too young and too brave
to save his own life.
I see no need
of prolonging
your appearance here.
Thank you, madame.
You are excused.
The prosecution moves
that Mrs. Lansdowne's
testimony...
be stricken from the record
as irrelevant...
and as a violation of
the court's previous ruling
on justification witnesses.
The defense considers
Mrs. Lansdowne's testimony
to be of extreme relevance.
Moreover, I request
the court to reconsider...
its prior ruling about
justification witnesses...
and allow the defense
to call the witnesses whom
it has previously requested.
In my opinion,
the entire court should
vote on this objection.
Court will be closed.
[ Bailiff ]
Stand up!
Sit tight.
Keep your fingers crossed.
Thank you.
I'd say
that this changes
the whole picture.
I don't see how.
She's just
an emotional woman.
Emotional or not,
I think we ought
to listen to her...
and to anyone else who may
have pertinent testimony.
I agree with MacArthur.
Well, I don't.
We're here to try Mitchell
for insubordination.
We're not here to listen
to a lot of wailing
about the navy...
or to hear people try to
justify his behavior.
You just said it.
We're here to try Mitchell.
And to give him a fair trial,
we have to listen
to every bit of evidence...
whether or not it's
technically called
a justification.
Did you hear
what that girl said
about theShenandoah?
Suppose other witnesses
had equally positive
testimony.
The trial would go on for weeks,
and the publicity would be bad
for everybody.
Well, that's the chance
we have to take.
The whole foundation
of our legal system
and of our country...
rests
on the right of a man
to defend himself,
on his right
to use every means
to defend himself.
He may be wrong, but
at least he's entitled
to tell his story.
And the minute
we forget that,
we're in grave danger.
I mean that, gentlemen.
Very grave danger.
I agree wholeheartedly
with General MacArthur.
Anybody else
have any thoughts?
I haven't.
No.
I think not.
Then I suggest
we vote on it.
[ Guthrie ]
Court will
come to order.
Under the 31st
Article of War,
it's the court's ruling...
that the motion to strike
Mrs. Lansdowne's testimony
is overruled...
and that the defense
may proceed with
its witnesses.
[ Spectators Chattering ]
Order in the court.
- Are your witnesses
present?
- Yes, sir.
One witness, Mr. Reid,
will not be here.
The president has declined
your kind invitation
to appear at this court.
The defense wishes
to thank Mr. Coolidge...
for his gracious
consideration
of our request.
Our other witnesses,
however, I'm sure,
will compensate
for his absence.
[ Man ]
Major Hap Arnold.
Major Arnold,
how many pilots have we lost
in peacetime flying?
The total is 517,
sir.
That is from
January 1919
to date.
How many of them
met their deaths
in modern planes?
In machines built
since the war,
12 were killed.
To your knowledge, Major,
have there been
any recommendations...
made to the general staff
with respect to safety measures
for the air service?
Yes, sir. Dozens of them,
most of them
by Col. Mitchell.
Do you know
what became of them?
Yes, sir.
They've beenfiled.
[ Spectators Murmuring ]
Captain Rickenbacker,
will you tell the court...
how many enemy planes
you brought down
in the last war?
Yes, sir.
Twenty-six.
Approximately how many hours
did you spend flying
over enemy lines?
About 300.
Now, based on your experiences
in the World War,
I should like to ask you
three questions.
First, is it proper
to send an aviator up
without a parachute?
It's suicidal. It's like
sending a man to sea
without a life preserver.
Second, what is your opinion
of the aircraft presently
being used by our flyers?
The graveyards
around our airfields
prove their worth.
Third, do you happen to know
what the aviation rank
of the United States is...
in comparison
with other nations?
According to the latest
information I have,
we're now in eighth place.
[ Spectators Murmuring ]
Thank you,
Capt. Rickenbacker.
Your witness.
Would it surprise you
to know, Captain,
that the latest
official reports contradict...
most of your so-called
informedstatements?
I wouldn't be surprised
at anything in the official
reports you refer to.
I would be surprised
if anybody believed them.
No further questions.
Major Spaatz,
what is your present
military assignment?
I am chief of the
tactical unit section
of the training command.
Now, Major Spaatz,
can you inform this court...
as to how many planes
our armed forces presently
have for combat purposes?
Yes, sir. Nine.
But the War Department
carries on the army list
1,800 planes.
That is technically
correct, sir.
But of that number,
1,400 are museum pieces...
which are obsolete
and of little
serviceable use.
And the remaining 400?
331 of those
were flown in France
in 1917...
and have not
been modified
or improved since.
And the remaining 69?
Sixty are used
for training purposes.
That leaves nine
for use against
a possible enemy.
And of that number, not one
pursuit ship is equipped
for wartime service.
So you believe the organization
of the tactical unit
of the air service...
is being retarded
by the War Department.
- I do.
-Thank you, Major.
Thank you very much.
Is it your experience,
Mr. La Guardia,
as a member of the Congress,
that younger officers
invariably want to carry out
the wishes of the general staff?
Well, let me put it
this way.
When the army testifies
before Congress,
it operates like
a self-greasing axle.
[ Spectators Laugh ]
Thank you, Congressman.
Your witness.
Mr. La Guardia, is it true
you made a speech in New York...
in which you said Col. Mitchell
is not being tried
by a jury of his peers?
- That is correct.
- By what logic do you
arrive at the conclusion...
that general officers
in the United States Army
are not equals to Col. Mitchell?
That's easy. Their feet
are stuck in the mud.
[ Spectators Laugh ]
Not one of them has ever
flown in an airplane.
Isn't it possible, Congressman--
having flown a plane yourself--
that your judgment is clouded
by the natural sympathy
you feel...
for another man
who also flies a plane?
I have no more
natural sympathy
for an airplane pilot...
than I do for some
of my colleagues
in Congress.
[ Spectators Laugh ]
Yet you say that officers
who have never flown...
are not equals
to Col. Mitchell.
In that respect only.
It's as reasonable
to have them judge him...
as it is for you
to run for Congress.
[ Spectators Laughing ]
No further questions.
Admiral Sims, how does
the United States Navy
handle its aircraft?
What is its policy?
Well, it has no policy.
It bumps along
from day to day.
[ Spectators Laugh ]
Does the navy
consider the airplane
a major weapon?
The Navy Department
is ignoring the airplane...
in the hope that,
if they don't notice it,
maybe it'll disappear.
[ Laughter ]
Thank you, Admiral.
Your witness.
Admiral, how do you account for
this difference of opinion...
between you and your
colleagues of the navy?
Well, they are just not
educated about the air.
Surely,
they're capable officers...
who can inform themselves
on the problems of aviation.
Reading a lot of golf books
doesn't make a man
a good golf player.
[ Laughter ]
As I understand it, Admiral, you
are no longer in active service.
- Is that right?
- Yes, sir.
I am retired.
But I can still think for
myself, and I'd like to tell
this court one thing, sir.
This row on air power
is not a row between
the army and navy.
It is a clash between
men who love to fly
and men who don't,
men who think
in terms of air power...
and men who can't
think at all.
Col. Moreland,
this Mitchell business
is getting out of hand.
It looks as though
he's put the army on trial.
Mr. President, the army
has no intention of being
on the defensive.
You may depend on that.
The prestige
of our armed forces...
is being affected
all over the world.
The sooner this is over with,
the better it'll be
for the whole country.
I can assure you, sir,
the complexion of the trial
is going to change very shortly.
Thank you.
Yes, sir.
Where's the--
[ Men ] ?? Come, Josephine
in my flying machine ??
?? Going up, she goes
Up she goes ??
?? Balance yourself
like a bird on a beam ??
?? In the air, she goes
Hey, here she goes ??
?? Up, up
a little bit higher ??
?? Oh, my
the moon is on fire-- ??
Hey! There's Mr. Reid.
[ All Cheer ]
What's the matter
with Congressman Reid?
[ All ]
He's all right.
Who's all right?
[ All ]
Congressman Reid!
Hello, fellas.
George, bring Congressman Reid
a couple of brass hats on toast.
They're not very good.
They're hard to digest.
Give you gas.
Gentlemen, I move that
we appoint Congressman Reid
President of the United States.
[ All Cheering ]
Thank you, gentlemen.
I promise to move
the White House
into a bomber.
First, I'd like
to talk to my client.
Where's Col. Mitchell?
He's still in his room.
Come on, Mr. Reid.
Let's go get him.
?
?? Come, Josephine
in my flying machine ?
?? Going up, she goes
Up she goes ????
[ Knocking ]
Yes?
Billy?
You all right?
Me? Sure. I'm--
Just a little headache.
Well, forget the party
and get a good night's sleep.
I want you fresh
on the witness stand
in the morning.
Look at me, sir.
Go away, Russ.
I'm all right.
I thought so.
It's his malaria.
He needs more
than this quinine.
I'd better get a doctor.
You'll do nothing
of the kind.
Come back here, Russ.
You can't go on the stand
in this condition.
I'll be all right tomorrow.
I've had these attacks
before.
I've got to go
on the witness stand.
Why do you want to do it?
You don't have to.
I haven't testified yet.
But you don't have to.
We won.
I haven't won,
not till we get
an air force.
Listen.
I'm listening.
Frank... are you
gonna put me on?
If you insist.
Better get that doctor, Russ.
Ask him to stand by
in court tomorrow.
He may be needed.
Court will come to order.
Col. Mitchell, at this time,
I remind you that under
the Articles of War,
you have three choices
as to procedure.
You may remain silent,
and, if you do so,
no inference
will be drawn
one way or the other.
You may, if you wish,
make a statement
not under oath.
Or you may be sworn,
in which case,
you'll be subject
to cross-examination.
The rights of the accused
have been explained to him,
and he elects
to testify under oath.
Do you swear the testimony
you shall give in
the proceedings now before us...
shall be the truth,
the whole truth and nothing
but the truth, so help you God?
I do.
May it please the court,
I should like to note
the addition...
of Major Allan Gullion
to my staff.
He shall conduct
the cross-examination
of Col. Mitchell.
Who's he?
One of the best legal minds
in the army.
I didn't know
he was in Washington.
And now, Colonel,
as an aviation expert,
as a flyer who's been
highly honored
by his government...
for his services
in war and in peace,
is there something you wish
to say in conclusion?
As an officer
in the United States Army,
I had to choose between
my duty to the army...
and what I considered
to be my duty
to my country.
I chose the distasteful
method of inviting
my own court-martial...
because I felt
in no other way
could I focus attention...
upon a desperately
urgent problem.
I hope I've made it clear
that our country needs
an adequate air force.
But above and beyond that,
it needs immediate
consideration...
for the safety
of our flyers.
[ Chattering ]
Order in the court.
Thank you, Colonel.
I know your words
will not go unheeded
by the people of this country.
You may cross-examine.
[ Knocks ]
Col. Mitchell, I've been
studying your war record,
and I must confess
it overwhelms me.
Those ribbons on your breast,
sir-- would you mind stating
what decorations they represent?
The Distinguished Service Medal,
the Distinguished Service Cross,
the Legion of Honor,
the Crown of Italy,
the Order of Saint Michael
and Saint George
and the Croix de Guerre.
That's very interesting, sir.
Now, Colonel,
to your knowledge,
are you the only American
officer in the army today
that wears such decorations?
Of course not.
Many other officers
wear them.
I see.
Now, tell me this.
Have any of these
other officers
ever been court-martialed?
Objection. That's immaterial.
You needn't answer that,
Colonel.
I was merely trying
to establish what
a unique officer you are.
But you are.
You are very,
very different...
and a special
sort of man.
I assume, Col. Mitchell,
you share with me
the respect I have...
for those officers
in the American army...
who wear as distinguished
decorations as your own?
Of course.
They earned them.
By risking their lives
in combat in the defense
of their country?
Yes.
Then why did you
call such men traitors?
Objection.
That question assumes
facts not in evidence.
Objection overruled.
To repeat the question,
in your statement
in San Antonio,
why did you call
such men traitors?
I wasn't referring
specifically to any officer.
But you certainly must
have had some men in mind...
when you accuse
the general staff of conduct
that was virtually treasonable.
I was thinking of the system,
the system of administering
air power...
in the army
and the navy.
I see. You were speaking
in generalities.
Yes.
But isn't it possible, sir,
that many of your statements
have been generalities?
No, sir.
And am I to understand,
when you use a phrase,
"guilty of criminal
negligence,"
that you meant that?
That statement was
and is accurate.
Negligence
of the ordinary--
No. Forgive me--
Forgive me
for interrupting, Colonel,
but I'm sure the court
would like to be clear
on this point.
You do then reiterate
your accusation...
that certain high-ranking
officers in the American
army are criminals.
You're twisting my words.
Col. Mitchell,
did your public attack
on the army...
start after
a series of accidents
involving your friends,
in which some
of your friends were--
were killed?
Yes.
Isn't it possible, sir,
that the sense of grief
that you felt
over their loss...
inspired you
to make your statement?
It did not.
Then why didn't you
attack your superiors...
before the accidents
involving your friends?
I wasn't ready.
You mean
you didn't think the iron
was hot enough to strike?
I recall no such thought.
And don't you mean
that you wanted to wait
until you felt sure...
that the newspapers
would be on your side?
On the side of a bigger
and better air service.
You consider the press qualified
to influence and dictate
to the armed forces?
I object to this whole
line of questioning
as irrelevant and immaterial.
The matter before this court
is the facts behind
the alleged offense.
May it please the court.
The accused is attempting
to establish justification
for the offense,
and I'm trying to prove
that there's no
justification.
[ Guthrie ]
Sustained.
Colonel, I have here
original letters
written by you...
to the War Department
over the period
of the last two years.
You recognize them?
They're mine, all right.
I've read them
with great interest.
I'm glad somebody did.
[ Laughs ]
I should like to question you
about some of the statements...
you make
in these communications.
You say here that
"In future wars,
"soldiers will invade
peaceful lands...
by leaping in parachutes
from airplanes in the sky."
Would you care to reveal
who gave you
this startling information?
Nobody gave it to me.
It's quite obvious
to anyone with
the slightest foresight.
I see. Then do you mean
that the chiefs of staff
of the army and navy...
are not only treasonable
and incompetent...
but are lacking
in foresight as well?
You said that.
I didn't.
[ Spectators Laugh ]
Now, in this letter,
you recommend that
the armed forces...
be separated
into three branches--
the army, navy
and the air force.
Is that your opinion?
It is.
Why did you seek to divide
the fighting forces
of this country?
I didn't mean
to divide them.
I recommended that
they all be combined...
under a single Department
of National Defense...
with specialists
in command of each branch.
And did you see yourself, sir,
in the role of the specialist
in command of the air force?
Objection. The line
of questioning up to now
is a familiar one...
seeking to falsely
characterize
the accused...
by the clever
manipulation
of semantics.
Sustained.
You state here that "The army
should investigate methods
of protection against air raids,
including alarm signals
and bomb shelters."
[ Chuckles ]
Bomb shelters.
Is it your actual belief that
this country is vulnerable
to attack from the air?
It is my belief, if not now,
at least within
the foreseeable future.
Col. Mitchell, do you have
any idea of the width
of the Atlantic Ocean?
Approximately 3,000 miles.
And the Pacific Ocean?
I know what you're
getting at, and I tell you,
it won't be long before
an airplane will fly
nonstop across both oceans.
Carrying bombs.
Col. Mitchell, do you realize
that your declarations,
if taken seriously,
could result in creating
panic among the people
of our country?
I'd rather have the people
scared than dead.
[ Spectators Laugh ]
Now, here's one
in which you propose
that the government...
build an academy
like West Point for airmen.
What do you have
against West Point?
I have nothing
against West Point.
It's a fine school
for infantrymen.
There should be
an equally good school
for flyers.
Now, in this one, you make
the statement that, quote,
"Airships traveling
a thousand miles an hour...
will fight each other
in the stratosphere."
Unquote.
Col. Mitchell, do you have
any comprehension how fast
a thousand miles an hour is?
Of course I do.
Do you know that it's faster
than the speed of sound?
It's approximately
250 miles faster
than the speed of sound.
Are there any airplanes today
that can go 250 miles an hour?
Wedon't have any.
I can tell you that.
[ Laughter ]
But you said, sir, that
they wouldn't only go
250 miles an hour,
but they would go
250 miles...
faster than
the speed of sound.
That's correct.
Well, now, would it be
asking too much...
if I could learn from you
what crystal ball...
you got
these astounding facts from?
Objection. The prosecutor's
attempting to ridicule
the witness.
I'll answer that question.
There is no crystal ball.
Anyone with any knowledge
of the air knows...
that the ultimate speed
of aircraft
is almost unlimited.
It depends only
on technical developments.
Amazing.
Here's a letter
to headquarters you wrote
after a short trip to Hawaii.
You say, quote,
"The army and navy commands
here are concerned...
"principally with the question
of jurisdiction.
"There is so much
petty bickering between them...
that the Islands are virtually
undefended." Unquote.
[ Spectators Murmuring ]
Do you consider that
a proper observation...
to be made by an officer
about his superiors?
That was written
in connection
with my belief...
that air power
will control the Pacific.
It's very important that
the missions of the army,
the navy and the air...
be-- be sharply defined.
Thank you.
You seem to have quite a bit
to say about Hawaii, Colonel.
For example,
you write that...
"Pearl Harbor has no adequate
defense against air attack--
It hasn't.
"and that a foreign power
could attack...
and reduce the Hawaiian Islands
in a matter of minutes."
Do you actually
believe that?
I not only believe it,
if you'll look into
those letters, you'll find
my specific observations...
on how it can be done.
I was coming to that.
Oh, yes. Here it is.
Your letter dated
December 14, 1923.
I'll read this slowly
and distinctly...
because I want the court
to know that you are
second to none,
that you are an expert
in palmistry,
table-tipping
and the reading of tea leaves.
I object!
The prosecutor's
being abusive.
- Objection sustained.
- My apologies, Colonel.
I'll let your words
speak for themselves.
"Preceded by
scouting submarines,
"enemy aircraft carriers
will lay off
the island of Oahu...
"at a distance
of about 150 miles.
"The attack will be
launched in two waves
and without warning.
"The first wave will strike
at Pearl Harbor,
"Schofield Barracks,
and the Ford Island airdrome...
"and the naval
fuel and ammunition dumps.
"This attack will be followed
by a second shortly thereafter,
its objectives being
the city and wharfs
of Honolulu."
[ Spectators Murmuring ]
Colonel--
[ Chuckling ]
Colonel, what was
your condition--
What was your state of mind
when you wrote this?
If you mean was I crazy,
the answer is no.
And you still cling
to this, uh, prediction?
Unless we repair
our defenses, we can
certainly be attacked.
I see. Now, there's
one piece of information...
I couldn't seem to find
in your communications.
Perhaps you could
enlighten us.
Does your crystal ball
reveal by what enemy...
this mythical attack
will be made?
Objection! The prosecutor
is goading the witness.
By whom, Colonel? By whom?
Will the court
instruct the witness
not to answer that question?
I'll answer that question.
The attack will be made
by the Japanese.
[ Spectators
Chattering Loudly ]
The prosecution would like
to submit these documents...
as the exhibit
next in order.
They will be received.
Col. Mitchell,
what explanation
the War Department...
will have to make
to the Japanese
ambassador...
is beyond the province
of this court.
However, now that you
have said your say,
now that you have done
your-- your little piece,
now that you have, uh,
proclaimed your vision,
might you not say
that you have
overstated your case,
and, upon sober reflection,
things aren't as bad
as you said?
Most certainly not.
I meant every word of it,
and I still do.
Then I submit,
Col. Mitchell,
that you are guilty
of the most flagrant
disorder...
to the prejudice
of good
military discipline.
I don't agree.
Col. Mitchell,
is it, uh,
is it your desire today
to remain in the army?
- It is.
- And should the occasion
arise in peace or war,
and you thought
your superiors wrong,
would you rush
to the newspapers...
with attacks
against their behavior?
Objection. That question
is ridiculous and outrageous.
The witness is being asked to
speculate on his future conduct.
Why not? Why not,
if the witness
can speculate...
on the future conduct
of the world
and its armies?
The issue bears
on the only question
before this court--
Col. Mitchell's
qualifications to remain
in the United States Army.
I'll answer that, Major.
I don't know
what I would do tomorrow.
Then you don't know
if you could behave
as an army man.
- I didn't say that.
- Are you ready...
to give
unquestioned obedience
to your superiors,
even though you may
consider their conduct
negligent and incompetent?
I consider myself
a good soldier.
Oh. Well, now,
then you
have changed from
that William Mitchell...
who denounced
his superiors in Texas.
- I have not changed.
- Oh, then you still
insist upon...
your right
to break an army rule.
- I didn't say that either.
- I am merely trying
to establish...
your exact feelings
on the question
of insubordination.
Col. Mitchell,
what is
the first duty...
of a soldier
to his superior?
- We've been over that.
- Are you afraid
of the word, sir?
- What word?
- The word that
answers my question,
in all
the armies of the world,
is the word "obedience."
You're trying to quibble me
out of the army.
You know better than
to call me disobedient.
Col. Mitchell,
why didn't you
resign from the army...
and conduct your campaign
legitimately
from a civilian position?
Because
I'm an army man, sir.
And do you consider
your statement in Texas
justified?
Objection.
The witness is being asked
to pass judgment on himself.
- I'll answer. My--
- Col. Mitchell, you don't
have to answer that question.
Objection sustained.
In view, then, of your
present opinion...
that your superiors
are negligent
and incompetent,
could you give them
unquestioned obedience...
should you be
returned to duty?
I ask the court
to instruct the witness
not to answer that question.
I'll answer
that question too.
You have asked me
to state that I am unfit
to remain in the army...
because I have
incurred the hostility
of my superior officers.
I can't admit that,
and I won't.
I've been wearing the uniform
of the United States Army...
most of my adult life,
and I've worn it
with pride.
But if being a good soldier
is your kind
of good soldier,
of being unable
to think for himself
and say what he thinks,
of being narrow
and blind...
and insensible
to a higher duty,
you can have the uniform
and all that goes with it.
[ Spectators
Chattering Loudly ]
If trying to do something
for your country,
if fighting
to correct injustice...
is being a bad soldier,
then I'm glad
I'm a bad soldier.
This issue goes far beyond
being a good soldier in--
in his sense of the word.
It goes beyond
blind obedience...
and depends on--
on a man's faith...
in his knowledge
of what is right.
If being
a good soldier is...
submitting dumbly
and passively to--
to injustice, indecision
and complacency, then I'm--
[ Voice Breaking ]
I'm glad I'm a bad one.
[ Spectators
Chattering Loudly ]
Billy.
Thank you, Col. Mitchell.
That's all. No further
cross-examination.
The army rests its case.
Does the defense
wish to make
a closing statement?
The defense
has nothing further.
The court will retire
to consider its finding.
[ Spectators Chattering ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
Stand up when
the court enters!
The court
will come to order.
The accused will stand.
Col. William Mitchell,
the court,
in closed session...
and upon secret
written ballot,
two-thirds of the members
present at the time
this vote was taken...
concurring therein,
finds you, of all specifications
and the charge, guilty.
[ Spectators
Chattering Loudly ]
Order in the court.
The court,
again in closed session...
and upon secret
written ballot,
two-thirds of the members
present concurring therein,
sentences you to be
suspended from rank,
command and duty...
with forfeiture of all pay
and allowances for a period
of five years.
The court is thus lenient
because of your military
record during the World War.
The court has adjourned.
Do you have a statement
to make, Colonel?
Will you remain in Washington?
[ Reporters Shouting ]
No comment.
How do you feel about
the army now, Colonel?
The army owes me nothing.
I owe the army everything.
What do you intend
on doing--
[ Shouting Continues ]
Ten-hut!
[ Heels Click ]
Thank you, gentlemen.
Russ.
Carry on.