(crashing and rumbling)
(ship whistle blows, distant)
(band playing)
"Happy maiden voyage. Mr. and Mrs. John Jacob Astor." Stateroom A-56.
-Not so fancy as some. Only bluebells. -Have a look.
"From the woods of Windsor Castle." Blimey.
Devonshire cream for Mr. Benjamin Guggenheim. Drop it in the icebox.
"Happy maiden voyage, Mr. Guggenheim."
"Happy maiden voyage." They're in a blooming rut.
"Captain E.J. Smith." Deliver this to the bridge and hop to it!
"Mr. and Mrs. Straus."
(band continues)
(chattering)
(band playing)
With this lot we're taking on from the continent, we'll have 2,200 aboard.
Rather thick weather inside the harbor, but it'll be clear when you get out.
Cherbourg to New York. You'll go by the Great Circle Route.
Yes, by southern track.
A fine start, Captain. This is excellent tea.
As for your running time, we know you'll exercise normal prudence.
However, the company won't resent a record run on her maiden voyage.
They're good engines, sir. We'll use 'em. Any other instructions from the company?
With a ship like this, there isn't much to be said, except good luck.
-And I wish I could go with you. -(laughing) Perhaps next time, sir.
Yes, but that isn't a first sailing.
For you, sir.
I suppose my wife dug up an extra shirt.
"From Henry Evans, Benbecula, the Hebrides."
Captain Henry Evans. I thought he was dead.
(chuckles)
It flew from the mainmast of the old Star of Madagascar nearly 40 years ago.
I joined as an apprentice. She was a fine sea boat.
Shall we hoist it, sir?
She's not top issue nowadays, but up she goes.
Mr. Sanderson.
(band continues)
CAPTAIN: Looks pretty good at that.
The tender is coming up from Cherbourg, sir.
Ah. Mr. Sanderson will go ashore on the tender.
-Will you show him to the gangway? -Yes, sir.
-Well, Captain, she's all yours. -Good-bye, sir.
(whistle blasts)
(whistle blows)
MAN: Mind your helm. Steady as you go.
Julia? Julia!
JULIA: Sandy! I thought you were in Biarritz.
My beautiful Julia, to these ears Biarritz has become a dirty word.
(chuckles) How much did you lose this time?
These are borrowed trousers. Where's that husband of yours?
-He didn't come. -Good! Maybe we can cause a scandal.
I'm afraid that would be a little clumsy. I brought the children.
What about your summer plans? I thought you were taking a house at Deauville.
I changed my mind. Annette! Norman!
Sandy! (speaking French)
She means "hello."
-Norman. -Good afternoon, sir.
I have to go over to the right side, the starboard side to see the Marconi aerial.
Stay right here. I'll try to get a chair.
Oh, John, stop worrying.
I'm not the first woman in the world who's going to have a baby.
As far as I'm concerned, you are. I'll get a chair.
Forgive me, Mr. Astor,
but if you're looking for a chair for Mrs. Astor, perhaps my suitcase would do.
-Why, thank you. -Mr. Astor, my name's Earl Meeker.
-Yes. Thank you. -MAN: I'm looking for the Widener maid.
The maid of Mrs. Widener. Is Mrs. Widener's maid around?
The Wideners? I think I saw them over there...
I'm looking for the Widener maid.
Widener maid. I'm looking for the Widener maid.
Well, don't look at me.
I've got so many maids, some of the maids are taking care of the maids.
Can't say I blame the poor fellow.
I just haven't got the kind of a face that goes with the bankroll.
I'll flash my badge and blind a few people.
Name's Maude Young. Montana lead mines.
Seasick? That some kind of a cure?
No, it doesn't cure anything.
(ship whistle blasts)
MAN: No running, no pushing.
(speaking French)
Have your boarding tickets ready.
(man speaking French)
(man continues in French)
-(tapping desk) -I'm Richard Ward Sturges.
-Get me the proper man. I want to arrange passage. -On the Titanic?
-I have that in mind. -I'm sorry, sir. This first trip has been sold out since March.
My congratulations. However, I must be on that ship.
I'd like to help you, sir, but I'm sorry.
(speaking foreign language)
-Pardon. You are Spanish? -We are Basque.
From wine country. We go to California. Oregon perhaps.
Start grapes. Make good wine.
-You have land there? -We buy little piece.
Well, it needn't be such a little piece.
Now, you give me that ticket and there's enough money here to buy five times as much land.
(foreign language)
(woman speaking foreign language)
Madam, there's nothing to discuss.
He can take the next boat and join you in a week or so. One boat's as good as another.
(foreign language)
All right. I can always get someone else.
Now, just stop and think.
How many years would it take you to buy 100 acres?
Now, go into one of your tribal huddles and convince your wife.
(foreign language)
-Thank you, Mr., uh... -Uzcadum.
You've done me a great favor.
(whistle blasts)
MAN (shouting): Tender alongside. Prepare for boarding.
Stand by, main elevator.
YOUNG MAN: ♪ Let every good fellow now fill up his glass ♪
YOUNG MEN: ♪ Vive la compagnie
♪ And drink to the health of our glorious class Vive la compagnie ♪
♪ Vive la, vive la, vive l'amour vive la, vive la vive l'amour ♪
♪ Vive l'amour, vive l'amour Vive la compagnie ♪
-♪ Oh... -Look at the one in the fur hat!
She's mine. You get the one way back there.
Don't fight, boys. There's plenty to go around.
I'm the steward assigned to you, lady. Just call me Giff Rogers.
Carry your bag? Draw you a bath?
-Shouldn't you be in school somewhere? -(young men laugh)
Come on. Let's beat it.
(whistle blows, distant)
(bell rings)
Drinks and draw for the first watch. Hurry up, Dan.
Keep it honest. Keep it fair. Come on. Come on.
Well, chaps, here we go.
(laughs) Don't trouble yourselves, gentlemen. Lucky Lightoller.
-Same old story. -Done it again.
Mr. Murdoch, Mr. Wilde, Dan, remove your bottles. It's my treat.
With pleasure.
All passengers aboard. Stations for leaving harbor.
-Very good, Thompson. -Way to go, old man.
And remember: first watch, first man with the ladies.
(men chuckle)
(whistle blows)
Fire all boilers. Have a go, mates. Bend your backs.
-Slow ahead all. -Slow ahead all, sir.
(bell rings)
-Steady as she goes. -Steady as she goes, Quartermaster.
Steady as she goes, sir.
-Full ahead all. -Full ahead all, sir.
(bell rings)
Full speed ahead from the bridge, sir.
(shouting) All right, carry on. Let her have it.
Finish stations, secure fore and aft.
-All right, Mr. Lightoller, you may take her to sea. -Aye, aye, sir.
(whistle blasts)
(chattering)
There you go.
Hey, you can't come up here. This is for first class only.
Really? I'll do my best to behave properly.
Oh, sir, Mr. Sturges, you don't remember me, but I was on the Queen Alexandria.
Of course, you were. Your name is Emma.
You have a daughter who's married to a dentist in Plymouth.
So considerate, sir, of you to remember.
Could you tell me the number of Mrs. Sturges's cabin. please?
Yes, sir, it's Stateroom A-52, 54.
It's right over here. But they've gone up to dinner now, sir.
-Thank you. -Richard!
RICHARD: John. Madeleine, my beautiful peacock!
-This is a surprise! -Yes, it is.
John, I'd like to borrow a shirt and use your razor. I'm wearing my complete wardrobe.
-I left in a hurry. -Well, help yourself. Take whatever you need.
Thank you. One more thing.
If you happen to see Julia in the dining room, I'd rather you didn't tell her I'm aboard.
I'd like to tell her myself.
"Jean Pablo Uzcadum"?
(orchestra playing)
(chattering)
MAUDE: She didn't believe my eagle was real.
I said, "What do you want him to do? Flap his wings?"
(women laugh)
Mama, you should've protested. It's a really bad table.
There's not a person we know at this end of the room.
JULIA: Be brave, Annette. These tragedies happen sometimes in life.
Maitre d'hotel, where is Mrs. Sturges's table?
Mama, look!
Well, well! This ship is filled with nice people.
-Hello, Mr. Sturges! -Richard!
"Pommery, 1892."
Mrs. Straus, be careful of this old fox. He has plans.
-NORMAN: Father. -Norman!
-How did you get aboard? -By the back door. Good to see you, boy.
-Hello, Sandy. -Well, I can see a bridge game at last!
Mrs. Widener, George.
-Annette. -Father.
Julia.
You all look splendid. This is gonna be great fun.
I'll see to it that we have a better table tomorrow.
Oh, Daddy, I'm so glad you're here.
I hope this doesn't upset your plans, Julia.
We might be a little crowded, but Norman and I can bunk together.
-It's wonderful that you could get away after all. -I managed.
My family will be pleased that you're coming too.
It makes it a better celebration already. Can I send a message to Grandfather?
They have a wireless place upstairs. The Marconi room.
Might be a good idea. Run along.
Nothing now. Thank you. I'll have a sandwich in the bar.
Annette, I wonder if you'd get a wrap for your mother.
Yes, angel.
There's something funny about you, Father.
I know! I've never seen you without a flower before.
Finish your coffee, Julia.
We can walk around the deck while I tell you what I think of this performance of yours.
I'm in no hurry to finish my coffee and not too interested in your opinion.
If I hadn't phoned the house from Zurich, you'd have got away with it.
Perhaps you'll explain now why you're kidnapping my children?
-I'm not kidnapping them, Richard. I'm rescuing them. -From what?
-From you. -That was my guess.
This family reunion story is a deliberate trick to get them away.
It is, and what's more, they're never going back.
They're going to stop being rootless, purposeless, superficial hotel children.
-What's wrong with hotels if they're very good ones? -Oh, Richard, I...
Richard, please try to see this sanely. We're Americans. We belong in America,
And yet for years we've been galloping all over Europe
to be at the proper places at the proper time:
winter in Saint Moritz, Deauville in season, summer in...
What's the use? The same silly calendar, year after year. Look at Annette!
I have, with great pride.
She's entertaining. She's discriminating. She has grace and style.
She's an arrogant little prig.
So you've chosen to drag her back to the glories of Mackinac, Michigan.
Any town in any state becomes comic on your lips,
but comic or not that's where she's going,
to a big, ugly, pleasant house with the cheap scent of lilacs around.
Oh, don't worry. She won't turn out dowdy. She'll meet dozens of nice boys.
I have something better in mind for Annette than being tied down to some lumber salesman.
I know what you have in mind, but it won't work.
I've seen a great many international marriages, and I've never seen a happy one.
-Do you think-- -I don't want to seem overeager, but could we?
Not tonight, Sandy. Thank you.
More coffee, Julia?
Do you think Annette is going to be grateful to you for hauling her into the wilderness?
In time. And as for Norman, I can only tell you this:
there's not going to be a carriage with two ponies
waiting for him at nine o'clock every morning.
From now on, he's going to walk to school.
Hm. I should've anticipated this.
Twenty years ago I made the pardonable mistake of thinking I could civilize a girl
who bought her hats out of a Sears Roebuck catalog.
I was wrong.
And don't think I haven't had my share of regrets.
One thing, Richard, you've...
You've always been honest.
-Will this one do? -Yes, thank you.
-Where's Father? But-- -Never mind. It's bedtime. Come on. It's been a long day.
I sent the wireless, sir.
Good.
Well, one game of checkers before we turn in?
Yes, sir.
(bell rings)
No more seagulls. It's a mystery, it is.
Take all the fish in the sea. There must be millions of them,
and you don't feel friendly towards a single one.
But put a bird in the sky, and you feel like old chums.
-(taps on wireless) -Listen, lad,
this'll teach you what kind of a boat you're working on.
"Mr. James J. Hays, on board the Titanic." When he gets to New York,
he's gonna have a whole bloomin' private train waiting for him.
That's handy. No waiting for a seat.
"Mr. Benjamin Guggenheim,
Countess of Rothes, Lady Duff-Gordon,
Colonel Archibald Butts."
The ship I was on before, all we got was weather reports.
Yes, sir?
A form, please.
Hm. Must have broke the pencil.
Perhaps... Perhaps I could take it down for you, sir.
No, no. I'll do it myself.
(George sighs)
Well, maybe if you would.
It's to my brother.
It's Mr. Frank Healey.
689 Boylston Street, Boston.
"I am coming home.
I think you should advise the family now...
that last week the authorities in Rome..."
"Authorities in Rome"?
"Authorities in Rome..."
-I've got that, sir. -Oh.
Uh. Well, then let's say, uh...
Look. I... I'll be back later.
(door closes)
(knocks on door)
The bar doesn't open till 11:30. It's the rule on a British ship, sir.
I forgot.
-A cup of bouillon, sir? -No.
He's not interested.
That poor fella had no dinner last night and no breakfast this morning.
What ails him?
-I've seen that look before. He's a runaway. -From what, some woman?
No. He's running too fast for that.
What's the commotion?
Well, where I come from, this would either be a revival meetin' or a craps game.
Step up and get your tickets for the anchor pool.
Ten dollars gets you a chance to win 600.
Wait a minute. I wanna get in on this.
MAUDE: How do you play this?
Just draw a number. If it corresponds to the minute we drop anchor, you win.
Five.
Don't be shy, Mr. Straus. Draw a good one.
You draw, Mama.
-What's our lucky number, dear? -Seventeen.
Hey, Tom... Here you get it, will ya?
Morning. They're selling tickets on the anchor pool down there.
-Oh? -Yes, I... I thought you didn't notice.
Maybe you want a ticket. I could get one for you.
-No, thank you. I'm not much of a gambler. -Oh.
-How about some soup? Nice and hot. -Thank you. I just had some.
This is for Purdue. It's a college out in Indiana.
Everybody thinks it's Princeton, but it's Purdue.
I see. Well, to answer your questions:
Her name is Annette, she's going on 18, and I think she's very pretty too.
Well, now that you brought it up,
-I think I kinda got off on the wrong foot with her. -Oh?
Yes, last night, when I asked if I could have the deck chair next to her,
she said she'd rather stand all the way to New York.
Oh! What's your name?
Giff Rogers. Gifford is a family name.
My mother said one of us kids had to be called Gifford.
-Oh, I'm sorry. I always get friendly pop off the bat. -Sit down.
I'm on the tennis team.
The athletic association shot us over to play Oxford during Easter.
We didn't win a single match.
-Will she be at the dance tonight? -She likes music well enough.
Well, I better hurry and get my blue suit pressed.
(chuckles) Still the same. Young men hurrying to get their blue suits pressed.
Mrs. Sturges, I bet I can count on you to put in a good word for me.
"When I was one and twenty, I heard a wise man say,
'Give crowns and pounds and guineas, but not your heart away.
Give pearls away and rubies, but keep your fancy free.'
But I was one and twenty. No use to talk to me.
When I was one and twenty, I heard him say again,
'The heart out of the bosom was never given in vain.
'Tis paid with sighs aplenty, and sold for endless rue.'"
That's pretty, but do you believe it?
I can't answer for myself, but if I were a tennis player from Purdue,
I wouldn't believe it, not a single word.
A fine, healthy bumpkin.
-Are you breaking ground for Annette? -You're up early.
I had to scratch around for something to wear. Not a bad shop; they have everything.
-Dinner jackets, I trust? -Naturally.
It'll be ready tonight. So... life can go on.
-JULIA: Good morning, Annette. -RICHARD: Morning, darling.
Oh, Dad, I thought you were a pot of coffee. What time is it?
Eleven o'clock. A brand-new day that's never been touched.
ANNETTE: I'm absolutely famished!
-That brother of yours, he never picks up anything. Where is he? -Where's my breakfast?
I sent him to order it half an hour ago.
-Beautiful! Lanvin? -Mm-hm.
-This one, Lucile, I imagine. -Yes, angel.
Your mother seems to have packed everything.
Of course, some of them will be a little out of place in Mackinac.
Still, plenty of practical things.
What? Only high heels? You'll have to have something to walk in.
Julia, as soon as we arrive, I think you ought to buy her some of those flat shoes.
They're called ground grippers, I believe. She'll need lots of things.
-That would be a waste of money for just a short visit. -Visit?
JULIA: Let's not talk about wardrobe and shoes now. Get up, Annette.
As your mother has said, it's a brand-new day that's never been touched.
-(knocking on door) -Yes?
Ah, thank you, Emma. Those cheeks of yours bloom in the salt air.
Oh! Mr. Sturges!
Annette.
There we are.
-May I bone your kipper, mademoiselle? -ANNETTE: Yes, angel.
-Is today the 12th or the 13th? -The 13th.
With the time difference, they should just be sitting down to luncheon
in that extraordinary room overlooking the fountains.
The dear, arthritic old princess sitting under the finest crystal chandelier in Europe,
and Mr. Paderewski complaining about the draft...
and at the end of the table, one young man next to an empty chair with a tear in his eye.
A crystal tear is my guess.
-What excuse did you give him, Annette? -I dropped them a note.
-Let's go, Richard. -What note? Was I to be somewhere?
It's perfectly all right if your mother explained it to them. See you later, Annette.
Wait a minute. Explain it to me.
What's the difference one party more or less?
Now, Julia, a luncheon at the Metternichs' is not exactly a wiener roast.
Was there some reason I wasn't told I was invited to the Metternichs'?
Annette, your mother's a sensible woman.
She probably felt something might come of it.
Some involvement with the young master.
To be perfectly frank, I was afraid. He's an arrogant little toad.
Mm. He does look a little like a toad, but he's a highly eligible toad.
Not many young men are related to both the Metternichs and the Rothschilds.
I don't think he looks in the least like a toad.
I see no reason we couldn't have left a week later.
I'm sorry I'm not there and I think it was mean of you!
RICHARD: Annette, mind your manners!
It wasn't a question of a week or two weeks. This was as good a time as any to bow out.
-Bow out? -Yes. I'm afraid so.
Adieu, great world.
Your father is saying that I'm taking you home for good. You may as well know it now.
I won't see an arranged marriage, I won't see you jumping from party to party,
from title to title, all the rest of your life.
Father, I want to ask you one question. Do you approve of all this?
Annette, I adore you. You know that.
Are you going to stay in Michigan for good?
I'm a hopeless case, far too old to alter my preferences now.
-When are you going back? -RICHARD: On the next boat.
Whenever you go, I go with you.
As for you, Mother, I love you very much,
but my address is Paris, France.
Thank you, Richard. You were most helpful.
Now you see why I wanted to steal a little more time.
Please, Julia, let's not bicker since there's no love lost between us.
That's the tragic part, Richard.
There's been so much love lost between us.
Hurry up! We have our first match at 11:30.
If it's not asking too much, what match?
The shuffleboard tournament. I entered us, you and me.
Good. We're the team to beat.
-I'm going to dress for dinner. -Yes, sir.
You'll alter course at 10:00. It's posted in the chart house.
What's this note, "binoculars"?
-That's Murdoch's writing. We're shy on binoculars. -How did that happen?
I don't know, sir. We've got just enough for the bridge.
The lookouts in the crow's nests are doing without.
-Make out a requisition. We'll pick up some in New York. -Yes, sir.
-It's very nice material. -Yes, it's a beautiful suit.
I said it was nice material.
You did a fast job. Thank you. I better have a handkerchief.
Norman, it's time for us to pick up our ladies.
-Norman! -Yes, sir?
Father, would it be all right if I ate in the cabin tonight?
Don't be silly, Norman. We're dining at the captain's table.
That's just it, sir. I'd feel out of place.
There's something bothering you. What is it?
It's nothing, sir.
(chuckles) Is this what's worrying you?
Look, Father. There are two other boys on this ship.
They're an inch shorter than I am, and they have long trousers.
Norman, you're a worthless scamp.
You've been growing behind my back.
Mr. Webster, this is no way to let a young man walk out of your shop.
-It seems you'll have to put in some more overtime. -It's a pleasure, sir.
Your fitting, Mr. Sturges.
Thank you, sir.
Mother, could you help me with this snap, please?
If you're busy, I can call for the stewardess.
That won't be necessary.
I love those earrings on you.
Thank you.
Are we going to cross the entire ocean in polite silence?
Annette, I'd be very happy to chatter like a magpie
if I could think of a single word to say.
-(knocking on door) -JULIA: Come in.
-Well, are we ready? -ANNETTE: Yes, angel.
-Julia, you look very beautiful. -I'm glad you're pleased.
Annette, Norman's at the tailor shop. Will you pick him up?
I don't want to walk into the dining room with him.
Then you can trail at a respectful distance.
-We'll all meet at the captain's table. -Yes, angel.
Well, Julia, I imagine after a few hours, we've reached the same conclusion.
We scream, we shout, we hurt each other, but we calm down.
Things aren't so bad.
Things are never bad for you, Richard. You always win.
I don't regard this as a victory. It's an adjustment.
Before you go down and eat and drink, you'd better know how things are going to be.
I've given up on Annette. Her standards will always be the chic club, the best table,
the Royal Enclosure, and that's her decision. She's almost of age.
But Norman is still a child. I'm not taking any chances with him. He stays in America.
Now, wait a minute, Julia. What is this all about?
I should think it'd be perfectly clear.
I'm not gonna see Norman thrown away.
He stays with me and if you try to interfere, I'll be as common as you think I am!
I'll fight you tooth and nail. I'll take you to the courts!
Could you be common in a slightly lower voice?
I'll say it in any tone you want. I'll whisper, I'll write it down.
That's the way it's going to be! He stays with me!
You crazy woman. You're talking about the most important thing in my life.
-I have plans for Norman. -What plans? That he should grow up to be you?
Possibly. I'm satisfied.
Is it so extraordinary that I should want to have some hint, some portion of myself survive?
Some portion of-- Yes, I forgot. "The best-dressed man of his day."
That's what they're going to write on your tombstone.
That may be all right for you, but I won't have it for Norman. He stays with me.
My dear Julia, I've been around enough bridge tables
to recognize someone who is holding a high trump.
Play it now, if you're going to.
We'll discuss it later.
Now!
All right, Richard. One question first?
If it's about Norman, you know the answer.
No court in the world,
no power under heaven can force me to give up my son.
He is not your son.
(folk music playing)
(orchestra plays)
-All I propose, Mr. Straus, is a small game at small stakes. -Oh, yes.
Don't act as though I were working the banana boats. I prefer good bridge and poverty.
-SANDY: It sounds rather like Saint Francis, doesn't it? -(people laughing)
Excuse me. Mr. Sturges, there's someone looking for you.
-Richard, this young man. -Yes?
At the door, there's a woman. Some name like Uzcadum.
-She's French, I guess. -Thank you.
-RICHARD: Will you excuse me a moment, Captain? -I believe we've all finished.
Do you expect to be long in New York, Mrs. Astor?
Hello. Your mother thought you might be in the mood for dancing tonight.
She and I got to be very good friends.
Oh, I'm afraid I forgot to mention you, Mr. Rogers. You'll have to forgive me.
My daughter and I were talking about something else.
-If Mr. Rogers would like a dance, I'd be delighted. -You would?
The dance floor is this way, isn't it?
Say, his is great, and the band's slicker than beets.
Wait till you meet the other fellas.
-We're going to have one dance. -Just one?
I was quite horrid to my mother today.
If I can please her a little by dancing with you...
as I said before, I'd be delighted.
Okay. What's the difference?
If you get a good omelet, who cares whether the chicken likes you or not?
Keep going.
All right. Now, sign this too.
Both of them.
I still say, not right to sign this. I am not head of family. You--
Please, Mrs. Uzcadum, do me a favor and stop worrying. Here, sign it.
-(music stops) -(applause)
(music continues)
Now, you keep these papers. I'll send the steward tomorrow.
Say... We're getting up a bridge game.
Sandy Comstock tells me you're a player from way back.
Yes.
(door closes)
You need a topcoat, Richard. It's grown cold.
Yes, it has.
The Labrador current.
I wonder if you'd tell me, Julia.
Have I been the laughingstock of our friends all these years?
Does everybody know?
No one except you and me.
Aren't you forgetting at least one other person?
Not even he. I never saw him again.
What very good manners.
There's no way for me to make it seem right.
It happened after one of those endless rows and private humiliations...
in the days before you made me over into your image.
One of the summers we had the beach house.
I'd left a party that night because I knew I'd cry
if there was one more reference made to my gaucherie, to the...
To the dress I had chosen to wear.
On the beach by our cottage,
there was a young man skipping stones across the water.
He assured me he was not a burglar, and we began to talk.
He said something admiring to me when I needed it most.
A pure, sweet, unsolicited compliment.
I... I took his face in my hands and kissed him out of gratitude.
You...
You needn't trouble yourself as to who he was...
except that he was a much nicer person than you or I.
(purse hits deck)
I think I understand.
From now on, Norman belongs to you. I shall make no claim.
Both of you will be taken care of decently.
But I don't want to see him or hear from him or... be remembered by him.
-Is that really necessary? -I'm afraid it is.
As you pointed out, Norman and I began as strangers.
So be it.
Oh, my poor Richard. How you hate me.
And for the wrong reasons.
Not because I committed an offense against common decency,
but because Norman isn't an elegant extension of Richard Ward Sturges.
For you, what happened isn't a mortal sin.
It is an inexcusable breach of etiquette.
Thank you, Julia. I stand reproved.
Good evening, Mr....
Harry. Thank you.
I see you have your game.
And you're in it. Mr. Guggenheim's been keeping the seat warm.
Two no trump. A heart bid from there.
You can only play one more rubber, Mr. Straus.
-Whenever you feel like stopping, I can take over, sir. -My trick.
Do you mind?
Aldebaran...
you lonely star.
GEORGE: Look around at the others.
The friendly Pleiades are better off. There's seven of 'em.
Now, wait. Let me count.
Answer up for the roll call.
There's four, six, seven.
They're all there.
Have you ever noticed, my dear lady, that the stars are never late?
They made you cry,
or wasn't it the stars?
Yes. Yes, I... I'm drunk.
I'm always two things: I'm drunk and I'm helpful.
Thank you. I don't need any help.
Then you're very, very unique. Oh! "Very unique."
It's a grammatical error. "Unique" stands by itself.
(hits deck)
Are you hurt?
(groans) I'm all right.
If... you would just be so kind as to point me toward the bar.
You're going to your cabin. What number is it?
My dear, unique lady, I am going to the bar.
No, you're not. Where's the key to your cabin?
-I'll send in the ship's doctor. -No, no, no, let him sleep.
I've got some, uh, spirits of ammonia over here.
I'll get it. Sit down.
Take this.
Good night.
Thank you for being so generous.
-That's all right. Just go to bed. -You know what I mean.
Thank you for not mentioning my strange luggage.
Are you a minister?
A priest, or rather, I was until last week.
At three o'clock on April 8th,
my duties, my privileges as a servant of God were formally terminated.
It was this.
You know why I started, or at least the reason I gave myself?
A priest in a slum parish knows all the sadness of the world. He needs support.
So I used to lean on a little Hennessy's. Just a little at first.
People said, "Well, that's only natural. The young father has a bad cold."
(chuckles)
It got so I used to have those colds in the middle of July, lots of 'em.
I can hear the bishop's voice now.
"You prefer that stuff to your God?"
Well, God and I knew better, but... I couldn't stop,
because I had a private devil all of my own.
In Rome, they were very kind, but they were very final.
I was sacked, and prayed for, and sent off in the morning.
How do you cover that in ten words in a wireless
to a family that loved you and sacrificed for you?
You see, my dear lady, you're not the only one who walks in trouble.
Goodnight.
(door closes)
-Can I have some eggs, please? -Three minutes.
-How's topside? -(bell ringing)
Is that bridge game still going on in the lounge?
I don't think they're ever gonna stop.
Time to relieve the chief.
Be careful of that coffee. It can stand up and walk.
(chuckles)
Morning, Chief.
-Good morning. -Ready to relieve.
Steering south, 71 west. Speed 21 knots.
Twenty-one? Who ordered the increase?
The captain.
Jackson.
Take over a moment. I must speak to the captain.
♪ Holy, holy, holy
♪ Though the darkness hide thee ♪
♪ Though the eye of sinful man ♪
♪ Thy glory may not see
♪ Only thou art holy
♪ There is none beside thee ♪
♪ Perfect in power ♪
♪ In love and purity
♪ Amen
The Lord bless us and keep us.
The Lord make his face to shine upon us and be gracious unto us.
The Lord lift up his countenance upon us, and give us peace now and forevermore.
Amen.
-Good morning. -Good morning, Captain.
Lovely day, isn't it?
LIGHTOLLER: Excuse me, sir.
There's an iceberg warning posted in the chart house.
Yes, I know. I put it there.
I just wondered about our speed, sir.
It's a clear sea,
and our track takes us quite a bit south of the reported ice field.
-Anything else? -No, sir.
Er... Mr. and Mrs. Astor, I should like you to meet our second officer, Mr. Lightoller.
How do you do?
-He's worried about our ship. -Not worried, sir.
I remember a man like that in the old days. Always afraid we were carrying too much sail.
But the wind never did us any harm. I like your spirit, Mr. Lightoller.
Thank you, sir.
-All right if I skip now, Mother? Big match coming up. -Yes, dear.
I believe that's your trick, Widener.
Are you leaving it there to hatch?
(chuckles) Sorry, Sturges. I'm knocked out.
It's almost 10:30, Father. We should have a warm-up.
This may be a tough match.
You'll have to find someone else, Norman. I'm busy.
-Yes, sir. -SANDY: An evenhanded rubber.
That's enough for me.
I guess it's time for us all to quit.
I see no reason for stopping. We'll get a fourth.
I'll be glad to fill in, Mr. Sturges, if it's all right with everybody?
Please do. Cut.
The name's Meeker. Earl Meeker.
All right. Let's have more coffee and double the stakes.
-How much do I owe? -We'll let you know.
Excuse me, Father, but if you're busy, maybe I could have the match postponed--
I told you, Norman, I'm not interested in the match. Find someone else!
Yes, sir.
-RICHARD: A spade. -SANDY: Pass.
MAUDE: Two hearts.
He certainly clouded up.
Well, a word'll do it faster than a hickory stick anytime.
A spade, two hearts. Your call.
MEEKER: I pass.
Morning.
Hello.
I guess it's of no importance, but I wanted to tell you something about last night.
No need to.
You danced with me four times. It's more than I figured on.
No, I mean the way I walked off without saying anything.
It wasn't very adult of me, and I believe in being adult.
Forget it. You did your bit. Only I kind of figured you were having a good time.
-To be frank, I was. -So you left me standing right in the middle of the floor?
That's just it! I didn't know what to do
when the orchestra started playing that funny dance.
-What do they call it? -"The Navajo Rag"?
-That's the one. I'd never heard it-- -Never heard it before?
Where have you been? Locked up in some art gallery?
Why, that's the hottest jig that kids do!
Yes, I noticed those girls with your friends.
They seemed to... well... shake automatically,
especially the pretty one with the dark hair.
Oh, the dark-haired one! She's a glue-foot.
Come here, I'll show you how to do it.
Now, look, all you have to do is this.
(clapping)
♪ There's a dance they do on the reservation ♪
♪ It's a dip and a glide and a hesitation ♪
♪ Then you grab your squaw and drag ♪
♪ They call it the Navajo Rag ♪
-♪ Ho, ho, ho, that Navajo Rag ♪ -(harmonica plays)
♪ What a rag, what a rag what a rag ♪
♪ Ho, ho, ho, that Navajo drag
♪ That drag that drag, that drag ♪
♪ Shake your moccasins and roll your eyes ♪
♪ Tear my blanket make my feathers fly ♪
♪ Whirl me
♪ Twirl me
♪ Whirl me, twirl me to that Navajo Rag ♪
(applause)
If we're going to be stared at, I think we should do this to real music.
Whenever there's another dance, will you ask me?
Goodbye, gentlemen.
Bye, Giff.
Bye.
Yee-hoo!
-Three spades. -Double.
-Content. -Content.
(bugle plays)
Why do the British find it necessary to announce dinner as if it were a cavalry charge?
-Shall we break? -Just when I'm getting some good cards?
Your grief has been noted. We'll break later.
Oh, that's what you said about luncheon.
By the time we dock, I'm gonna be one long loaf of liverwurst.
Sorry, partner. Not much there.
-Oh, Harry. -HARRY: Yes, sir?
-Is the water still hot? -I just brought it, sir.
Thank you.
Is it necessary to lurk in dark corners?
I've come to ask you to have dinner with the children.
What I really mean is, to have dinner with Norman.
Don't worry. You won't have to put up with me. I'll eat in the cabin.
Oh, please, Richard. Don't take it out on him.
He's too young to be slapped in the face without any explanation.
Then give him the explanation.
(Julia sighs)
Richard, you can't mean that.
Richard, it doesn't concern him. It's an issue between you and me.
Norman adores you. You're the man he's loved since the moment he opened his eyes.
Can't you, for the few days we're still together,
at least show him the courtesy you would show a headwaiter?
I'm sorry, Julia.
You're asking me to do something which involves character.
As you have pointed out, I am not a man of character.
Oh, please, Richard. Please!
You're in my light, Julia.
MAUDE: We made it, partner. Three spades, doubled.
Well, aren't we the lucky ones!
(tapping on wireless)
How long will it take to get to Boston?
About seven or eight hours, sir.
There's a lot of traffic going out.
Seems like when we get to New York, everybody's...
planning to have a party.
Yes, sir. About seven or eight hours.
Well, I guess that'll be soon enough.
That'll be 11 shillings, sir. Shall I bill it to your cabin?
-Yes, sir? -What time did this message come in?
I think Phillips handled that one, sir. He's having his dinner now.
Check your log. There's a mix-up.
This morning we got an iceberg warning from the Baltic.
Half an hour ago, this one from the Caronia was delivered.
Yes, that's right, sir. It came in at 7:40.
But it's dated April 12th, two days ago. Why the delay?
I don't know, sir. Something to do with transmission.
We got it half an hour ago and sent it straight to the bridge.
-Well, what did they say? -Held up at the other end, sir.
-Hello, Chief. Thought you'd be having dinner. -Finished, sir.
Where's your plot on that iceberg reported by the Baltic?
Right here, sir. Ahead and slightly north of our track.
We should sight it about 8:00 in the morning.
There's another report from the Caronia. Plot it in, will you?
42 north, 49.50 west.
That would put it up here, sir.
But the Caronia report was filed two days ago.
That'd be about right. There's a strong southerly drift.
A large enough berg could have moved down there...
almost where the Baltic sighted it.
Do you want to alter course, sir?
-What's the weather forecast? -Clear and calm.
Oh, I don't think so. No need to alter course yet.
I'll be on the bridge during the morning watch.
Shouldn't be too hard to spot it in daylight.
Mr. Murdoch, I thought I'd let you know,
the captain will be topside for the morning watch.
Night order book as is.
-We gonna stay at 22 knots? -Why not?
-At 30, we couldn't reach that berg before daylight. -That's true, not this one.
But what if these are two different icebergs?
(piano plays)
♪ Oh, Amherst, brave Amherst
♪ 'Twas the name known to fame in days of yore ♪
♪ May it ever be glorious
♪ Till the sun shall climb the heavens no more ♪
YOUNG MEN: ♪ Bo-bo-bo-bo bo-bo-bo-bo ♪
GIFF: ♪ Oh, oh, Lord Jeffrey Amherst was a soldier of the king ♪
EVERYONE: ♪ And he came from across the sea ♪
GIFF: ♪ To the Frenchmen and the Indians he didn't do a thing ♪
♪ In the wilds of this wild country ♪
♪ And for his royal majesty he fought with all his might ♪
♪ He was a soldier loyal and true ♪
♪ And he conquered all the enemies ♪
-♪ that came within his sight -ANNETTE: ♪ Sight
♪ And he looked around for more when he was through ♪
♪ Oh, Amherst, brave Amherst
♪ 'Twas the name known to fame in days of yore ♪
♪ May it ever be glorious
♪ Till the sun shall climb the heavens no more ♪
Should be seeing gulls by morning.
The birds of the Grand Banks, fair filled with courage.
Overtrumped. Never send a baby to buy the beer.
YOUNG MAN: ♪ Far above Cayuga's waters
♪ With its waves of blue
EVERYONE: ♪ Stands our noble alma mater ♪
♪ Glorious to view
♪ Lift the chorus speed it homeward ♪
♪ Loud her praises tell
♪ Hail to thee o alma mater
♪ Hail, all hail, Cornell ♪
♪ Far above the busy humming
♪ Of the bustling town
-(humming) -♪ Reared against the arch of heaven ♪
♪ Looks she proudly down ♪
♪ Lift the chorus speed it homeward ♪
♪ Loud her praises tell...
What a lot of songs they know.
That's only a few. There must be hundreds more.
Fifty, anyway.
Jesus, Mary!
(bell rings)
Iceberg! Dead ahead!
Iceberg dead ahead, sir!
Hard a-starboard! Full speed astern!
Hard a-starboard, sir!
Helm's hard a-starboard, sir.
Keep the helm hard over. We're going to clear.
(metallic scraping, rumbling)
♪ For once again comes Williams' day ♪
♪ Yard by yard we'll fight our way ♪
♪ Through Amherst's line
♪ Every man in every play
♪ Striving all the time
(rumbling continues)
♪ Cheer on cheer will rend the air ♪
♪ All behind our men...
(rumbling)
Iceberg, sir. We must have picked up a spur.
(rumbling stops)
GEORGE: It's over there.
We must have come close.
Did we hit it?
No, sir. It hit us.
No damage above the waterline, sir, but the forepeak is flooded to the orlop deck.
Three feet of water in the firemen's passage, port side,
additional damage abaft of Bulkhead B.
Damage that far aft? Check again.
All right. I'll tell him. We're taking water
in number one, two and three holds,
and number five and six boiler rooms.
-Can they shore up? -LIGHTOLLER: No, sir. Ripped us like a tin opener.
Tell the chief engineer to start the forward pumps.
Wilde.
MAN: Start the forward pumps!
Order all hands to stations.
Passengers and crew don life jackets. Prepare to lower away all boats.
Captain Smith.
(tapping on wireless)
Break off traffic and get him up.
Stand by to send a C.Q.D. to all vessels. I'll send you the position immediately.
-C.Q.D.? That's for distress. -That's right. We struck an iceberg. We're going down.
Captain, I want to know exactly what's happened.
-There's been some, uh, underwater damage. -You can trust me, Captain.
-Is it critical? -MAN: Give me a hand with this cover!
MAN #2: Over here, mate.
-Call up Boat Crew 6. -Well, to be on the safe side, we're clearing away the boats.
Captain, I will not be put off. Is this ship going to sink?
She is. I'm ordering all women and children into the boats.
As for the rest of us, perhaps some vessel can get to us in time.
Captain Smith, in other words, there aren't enough lifeboats for the men.
(gunshot)
(ship whistle blasts)
(ship alarm blaring)
MAN: All passengers go to their cabins and put on life jackets.
There is no cause for alarm.
You'll find life jackets on the rack in your wardrobe.
Please proceed to your cabins immediately.
You're to put on your life jackets.
After that, you're to proceed to the promenade deck by the after ladder.
(alarm blaring)
(whistle blasts)
Did you hear what's happened?
We ran into an iceberg. None of us even saw it. Isn't that the biggest cheat?
I knew there was something. It woke me. Norman, get dressed immediately.
Please relax. I've talked to the captain. There was a collision of sorts.
The steamship company evidently felt we needed something to break the monotony.
-Is there any danger? -RICHARD: Danger? On a ship like this?
Nonsense. However, we have to follow instructions.
Now, put on warm things, everybody.
Comfortable, but as becoming as possible.
Annette, get the other jackets from in there.
It might be a good idea to bring some blankets along.
It may be chilly in the lifeboats.
Lifeboats? And you say there's no danger?
Julia, I'm afraid you don't understand the corporate mind.
Steamship companies serve the public.
To prove they're on the job, they like to inconvenience people.
Here, Julia, help Norman.
I imagine they'll row us out a few hundred yards while they repair the damage.
All right, Julia. We're assigned to number six lifeboat.
Remember, number six.
Well, I believe we're ready.
Norman, you better take these. Catch.
Father?
Haven't you forgotten something too?
Oh, I have.
Pay a thousand dollars to ride on the greatest ship that was ever built
and three days out somebody pokes a hole in it.
Why don't they patch it up and leave us alone?
Hey, don't you walk out on me. I was gettin' some good cards. We're goin' on with that game.
Don't worry, Mrs. Young. When we get back, the cards will still be warm.
-This way, madam. -All right. Do you mind?
MAN: Put on those jackets, please! Don't push! Please. Don't push! Please.
Here, put that jacket on.
Annette! Annette!
MAN: Tie your jackets up, please! Tie yours up, sir.
Take it quietly, madam. Don't push. Please, don't push.
(ship whistle blasts)
LIGHTOLLER: Number four boat, swing out!
Number two crew, see your boat clear of the ship's side before you lower away.
Officer, there's nobody to man this boat.
There's a crew on its way up. Keep your people together.
WILDE: Find your proper boat!
Them to starboard's odd. Them to port's even.
Is there any way I can help, sir?
Yes, you can move out of the way,
and see that this passage is kept clear. Stand back, everybody, and keep together!
Are all your people with you? Your entire family?
Yes, they're all here. On second thought, I have some stragglers.
-Number eight crew! -Wait over here. I'll be back shortly.
-You can't leave us now! -I'll be back.
Mr. Sturges, can you use your influence? Do you know what's going on?
Stand back. Keep the passage clear.
Mrs. Sturges, they say it's nothing, but they're lying. There's water below.
And now somebody says there aren't enough lifeboats for the men.
(ship whistle blasts)
Richard, I see they got you into one of those. This doesn't fit.
-You're not busy. I may need you. -Can't be that bad.
I'm afraid it is. We may be having sand for supper tonight. Come on.
(alarm blaring continues)
-MAN: Put on your life jackets! -(crowd clamoring)
MAN: Leave everything behind!
Walk by the after deck! Please, put on your life jackets.
Walk by the after deck. Please, you must take a life jacket. Come on.
Steward! Can't you get some order here?
They don't want to go, sir. We can't make them understand about the trouble.
Well, give me a try. Here.
-Mrs. Uzcadum. -(foreign language)
-(foreign language) -Get to your feet!
-No, safer place here. -I am at the moment the head of this family. Now, get up!
(Sandy speaking foreign language)
-(anxious chattering) -(alarm blaring continues)
MAN: Remain on this deck. The boats will be lowered down.
-I don't think it's so serious. We'll get help. -I think so too.
I'll bet there are practically seven or eight ships coming right now.
But anyway, just in case we get on different boats...
if you get to New York first, would you mind calling up home for me?
Of course not. They'll all be worried.
There's just Jackie. That's my kid sister.
Tell her I didn't win any medal, but I bought her a pocketbook instead...
with beads on it.
MAN: Keep your falls clear!
It was supposed to get there for Easter, but I'll bet it didn't.
You'll be there to tell her, Giff. You're just as apt to be there before me.
Oh, sure.
But even if not, there's one thing I want you to know.
I don't think you'll believe it, but I wouldn't have missed this boat trip.
Not for anything.
(ship whistle blasts)
Officer, Officer, have you room here for four more?
I think so, sir. Are they assigned to this boat?
They are now. Go ahead, Mrs. Uzcadum.
RICHARD: Here's a nice lady. She'll take care of you.
Bon voyage, Madeleine, my dear.
Bless you, Richard.
LIGHTOLLER: Stand back, there.
Hop in for you, lad.
Take a turn on that line! Keep your falls clear!
Keep your falls clear!
-Some loose ends to take care of, Julia. -Yes, I saw.
They're loading your lifeboat.
I'd better go to my own. It's on the other side.
It will be a long walk, Richard, but thank you for lying.
I know you're trying to make it easy for us.
This way is easier for me too.
Oh, Richard, where did we miss out on each other?
I... I beg your pardon, sir.
I put you down as a useless man, somebody to lead a cotillion.
After all, it was my major talent.
Oh, I'm sorry. Sorry about everything.
(cries)
We have no time to catalog our regrets.
All we can do is pretend 20 years didn't happen.
It's June again.
You're walking under some elm trees in a white muslin dress.
The loveliest creature I ever laid eyes on.
That summer, when I asked you to marry me...
I pledged my eternal devotion.
I would consider it a great favor, Julia,
if you would accept a restatement of that pledge.
-(ship whistle blasts) -Oh!
-Please, madam. -(Julia sobs)
Go ahead, my dear.
(Julia sobs)
MAN: Hurry up! Number six boat ready to lower away!
Stand by your falls!
Come along, Annette.
Help your sister, Norman.
NORMAN: Shouldn't I wait and go on the boat with you?
-The officer put you here, didn't he? -Yes, sir.
-You know the rules. A good soldier obeys orders. -Yes, sir.
Au revoir, my pets.
You look fat and funny in those life jackets.
Like Tweedledum and Tweedledee.
MAN: Numbers four and six lifeboats, stand by to lower away.
All passengers to the promenade deck.
(alarm blaring continues)
LIGHTOLLER: Stand back, everybody, and keep together!
(ship whistle blasts)
Attention! Attention, all able-bodied men!
We need your help further aft as quickly as you can, please.
MAN: Over here at once! Over here! This side.
All right, men. This way.
Keep moving.
MAN: Remain on this deck. The boats will be lowered down.
All right! Give me one of them paddles!
Over here, mates! Lend a hand! She's stuck!
Some of you, on the end of this rope. The rest of you, over on the other one. Come on!
MAN: All women and children to lifeboat number six.
In your lifeboat, please.
-I'm sorry, ma'am. She's loaded. -Where will I go, Officer?
Well, there may be another boat. Sorry. There's no room in this.
MAN: Stand back.
Here's a space.
MAN: All right. Lower away.
MAN: Keep your arms in.
Where's Norman?
Norman? Norman!
He gave a woman up front his seat.
(yelling) Norman! Norman!
(ship whistle blasts)
(sobbing)
MAN: Jam problem! We're stuck in the block!
She won't clear. Get a marlinespike.
We'll never do it this way.
MAN: Number ten is farther aft, sir.
Seaman on number four line, fall away!
(people screaming)
(tapping on typewriter)
From the Carpathia, sir. "We are coming full speed,
41 degrees, 30 minutes north, 49 degrees, 21 minutes west."
CAPTAIN: Give me their position again.
MAN: 41 degrees, 30 north, 49 degrees, 21 west.
Have Mr. Lightoller pass the word to the lifeboats.
Steer east southeast. They'll be picked up by dawn.
(alarm blaring continues)
-(ship whistle blasts) -MAN: All clear, Officer.
-Can you still keep up steam? -We'll give her a try, sir.
Good. We need power for the Marconi instrument,
and I want to keep the lights burning as long as possible.
-If there's a ship coming, she has to see us. -Right, sir.
I presume you know you may not make it out of here.
Yes, sir. That's the way of it sometimes.
Good luck.
I see you made it, Mr. Meeker.
(ship whistle blasts)
(alarm blaring continues)
Oh, Norman. Oh, my little boy.
-Steward, you know Mr. Sturges. Have you seen him? -No, I haven't.
MAN: Number seven coxswain, to starboard.
LIGHTOLLER: Please sit down when you get in the boat. Please keep still.
Fasten your life jacket, please, ma'am.
(ship whistle blasts)
MAN: Number three boiler room, flooded.
We're flooded to the after-coal bunkers, sir.
The transverse bulkheads are about to go.
We're finished when the water hits the main boilers.
Order all hands up from below.
-Their duty's done. -Yes, sir.
Mr. McDermatt's waiting amidships, sir.
-What? -Mr. McDermatt, sir.
Oh... yes.
-You sent for us, sir? -Yes, Mr. McDermatt, I think it might help if you'd play.
Yes, sir. "Londonderry Air."
(band starts playing)
Please sit down the moment you get in the boat.
Please sit down when you get in the boat.
Take your places, please, and keep still. Keep your hands on the inside.
MAN: Mind your head.
All right, Mrs. Straus.
-No, please. -Mrs. Straus, this is the last lifeboat.
Please, sir, I'm a very old lady.
I've been with Mr. Straus most of my life.
I will not leave him now.
All right, ma'am.
Slack away your first lines.
Keep your hands inside the boat.
Easy, men.
(band continues)
Let go your first lines. Please sit still in the boat.
Fasten your life jacket, ma'am! Lower away!
Look out! She's gonna blow!
(explosion)
(coughing)
Don't go in there, sir!
The starboard boiler's gone, and the port one's about to go!
-Are there men in there? -A few, pinned under the rig.
For God's sake, mister, don't go in there!
For God's sake, I am going in.
(explosion)
(screaming)
RICHARD: Norman. Norman!
What's happened? What are you doing here?
-I was afraid I couldn't find you, sir. -Come with me.
On the lower decks, it won't do any good to jump.
The water's near freezing! Move aft!
-Move-- -Officer,
this boy's still aboard. Where are they loading?
Sorry, sir. All the lifeboats have gone.
Well, Norman...
I didn't count on this.
All of the other men were staying. I thought perhaps I should too.
I'm wearing long trousers, sir.
I guess long trousers are enough to prove you're a man.
Just the same, you're sore at me for coming back, aren't you, sir?
Yes, I'm sore at you...
the way I've always been sore at those fool drummer boys
who stayed on to play "Last Retreat".
I... I thought maybe we could make a swim of it, together.
Well, whatever happens...
I love you very much.
I've been proud of you every day of your life.
Never as much as at this moment.
I feel tall as a mountain.
Mr. Sturges, there's a boy up forward looking for you, sir.
Yes, Harry, I found him.
He's my son.
(tapping on wireless)
She won't spark.
We're finished, mate.
Mr. Jackson, you will make the last entry in the log and secure.
"At this hour, all wireless communication broken off.
All lifeboats manned and lowered away.
This vessel sinking hard by the bow."
(band playing "Nearer My God To Thee")
(passengers singing) ♪ Nearer my God to thee
♪ Nearer to thee ♪
♪ Nearer my God to thee
♪ Nearer to thee
♪ E'en though it be a cross
♪ That raiseth me
♪ Still all my song shall be ♪
♪ Nearer my God to thee ♪
♪ Nearer my God to thee
♪ Nearer to thee ♪
♪ Though like the wanderer
♪ The sun gone down
♪ Darkness be over me
♪ My rest a stone
♪ Still in my dreams I'd be ♪
♪ Nearer my God to thee
♪ Nearer to thee
♪ Still in my dreams I'd be
♪ Nearer my God to thee
♪ Nearer my God to thee ♪
♪ Nearer--
(explosion)
NARRATOR: Thus, on April 15th, 1912,
at 02:20 hours, as the passengers and crew sang a Welsh hymn,
R.M.S. Titanic passed from the British registry.
(women singing) ♪ Nearer my God... ♪
NARRATOR: Seven hundred and twelve people in 19 lifeboats survived.
(men and women singing) ♪ Nearer my God to thee ♪
♪ Nearer to thee