What Next, Corporal Hargrove? (1945)
[Band playing You're
in the Army Now]
[Band playing The Caissons
Go Rolling Along]
A few short weeks after
D-Day, the allied
forces broke out of the
Normandy Peninsula.
Most of the American
army was racing
across the plains and fields
of France toward Paris...
Most, but not all.
Man: All right. Heave!
Heave!
Come on, fellas! All together!
Cut it, Lupot! Cut it!
[Truck idling]
You know, this is almost as
tough as basic training.
Well, it won't be too long till
V-E Day. Let's just sit it out.
If I don't get this gun up
on that road and catch up
with the battery, you know what's
going to happen to me, don't you?
Yeah. You'll get busted.
That's right. I've been a
corporal for 5 days now,
and I want to make
it an even week.
All right, fellas, now, once
more. Start it up, Lupot!
Here we go!
Heave!
Hargrove!
Yes, sir... I mean,
yes, sergeant.
Where is Sergeant Hill?
Uh, well, he left
me with the unit,
and he went on a
reconnaissance,
and then we got shoved
off into the ditch.
It was either them or us,
and they were officers.
All right, keep trying
to get started,
and I'll see if I can't
send back a wrecker.
Send a mess truck, too, sarge.
We may be here for days.
Now, we're headed for Mardenne.
That's about 40 miles.
Here's a map, and I'll
show you where it is.
Just stay with this road.
If you can't catch
up with the battery,
check with the M.P.s
handling the traffic.
All right, let's get started
around here. Come on. Get busy.
Fighters coming in!
Uh, turned out to be
our own, sergeant.
Fathead.
Now, use your head, Hargrove,
and don't get fouled up
behind the German lines.
Don't lose your gun, and
whatever you do, don't open fire
on anything or anybody that
doesn't first open fire on you.
Right.
All right, let's get
busy around here.
You know, he doesn't
seem to have
much confidence
in me, does he?
I wonder why.
Don't worry about a
thing, corporal.
The crew is with youse 100%.
Thanks, Burk. Let's get going.
Lupot, when I give you the
signal, you gun her like mad.
Everybody back to their original
positions on the double.
"On the double."
I knew we'd get to
that before long.
We'll get her out this time,
fellas. I'll help you.
Heave!
[Everyone yelling]
Come on!
Keep it going!
Watch it, corporal!
Heave! Come on, push!
Don't break your
backs on me, now.
Hey! Hey, come on!
[Men cheering]
Corporal Hargrove, sir.
We're "B" Battery,
352nd Field Artillery.
You're blocking
traffic, corporal.
Get that truck off the road.
But, sir, we're trying
to rejoin our unit.
I'm sorry, corporal. I have
a priority column here.
Get that truck off the road.
Yes, sir.
Back in the ditch, Lupot.
Well, come on, Hargrove.
Think of something.
Heave.
We're not getting
anywhere on this road.
The battery might move again, and we'll
never catch up to Sergeant Cramp.
Hey! Hey!
I think I've worked out
a shortcut, though,
if a certain side road
up ahead is open.
What's the matter?
Don't you trust me?
Oh, sure. You're the corporal.
The intersection
is plainly marked.
There's a side road
that goes directly
into the town we want.
Well, here it is on the map.
Look for yourself.
Burk: Corporal, you
got something.
We're on a road now.
That's good enough for me.
Are you going to defy an order
issued by the supreme
commander of this truck?
No, corporal.
All right. By the authority
of the power invested in me,
we're going to
take the shortcut.
Burk: Mais oui!
How is your French
coming, Billy?
Get a load of this:
Ne cirez pas les bouts de ma
moustache, s'il vous plait.
Hargrove: Wonderful! Hey,
fellas, listen to this.
Go on, bill. Give it to them.
Ne cirez pas les bouts de ma
moustache, s'il vous plait.
What does that mean?
It means "please do not wax
the ends of my mustache."
Great, great. Well, from now
on, you're staff interpreter.
I learned another one, too.
Ne decrochez pas les chevaux
parce que le patron a ete
abattu par l'eclair.
What does that mean?
It means...
Do not unhitch the horses,
as the innkeeper has been
struck by lightning.
I hope I come to something that's about
girls or eating pretty soon.
Man: Ah, girls!
Eating!
You know, I wish you
wouldn't get me thinking
about girls and eating
at the same time.
It's very confusing.
I wish we'd stop pretty soon
and let that mail
catch up to us.
Hey, yeah, you got some royalties
coming to you from that book.
Who wants royalties? I
want to hear from Carol.
She had some pictures made.
She's going to
send them to me.
Pictures? He's got
12 of them now.
11.
Ellerton, you will
appreciate these,
being a true artist.
Her name is Carol...
Men: And she lives
in New York,
and she has brown
hair and blue eyes,
and she works for
the Red Cross.
Did I mention her before?
She's a swell girl.
Ah, you guys are just jealous.
Lupot!
Lupot: Yo!
Head down the road until
you hit that intersection,
about 4 miles. We're going
to take a shortcut.
Lupot: Yo!
I'll direct you from there.
Sergeant, we're not
going into position
around Mardenne. We're
moving on ahead of it.
The French have liberated the town, and
other units will move in to clean it up.
Yes, sir.
[Snaps fingers]
Hargrove.
What is it, sergeant?
Sir, I've got one gun
and a crew back on the road...
Corporal Hargrove.
They were stalled an hour, and
Hargrove's headed for Mardenne.
Well, go on back
and tell them.
Yes, sir.
Come on.
Lupot!
Yo.
That's the road I want
up ahead, to the left.
Ok, corporal.
Oh, boy. At the
rate we're going,
we'll catch up with that
battery in no time.
Hargrove: We're headed
for Mardenne, sergeant.
We're going to
rejoin our battery.
Well, go ahead.
All right, go ahead, Lupot!
If we keep on going in
this direction, sarge,
we'll be back where
we came in on D-Day.
That fatheaded Hargrove. I wonder
what could have happened to him.
Maybe he made a
separate peace.
Come on. Let's get
back to the battery.
Man: Nice landing, corporal.
Ha ha ha!
Boy, I ruined my tail
assembly on that one.
Hargrove, what did
you see up there?
Not a sign of the
United States Army.
Didn't expect you would.
Why?
Well, it's just
that I didn't see
any "K" ration boxes
along the road.
Everywhere the army's been,
you find those boxes.
Yeah, and there's no
wire laid along here.
Hmm.
How's that, corporal?
Uh-huh.
You know, I'd know
that uh-huh anyplace.
That means we're in trouble
and we're headed for more.
Oh, I wouldn't say that. That's the
town up ahead. I'm positive of that.
I'm just a little curious about what
happened to the rest of the army.
Well, Mardenne is our position,
and that's where we're going...
If I have to take the
town singlehanded.
Burk: That's the
stuff, corporal.
Hargrove: All right, let's get out our
camouflage. Mulvehill, get out of there!
You and Burk cut down some of
that shrubbery... on the double.
Hold still, will you?
It tickles.
Hargrove's right. We got to
be camouflaged, don't we?
I may get the Chestnut Blight.
Well, we'll get a tree
surgeon to spray you.
Hold it, Lupot. Hold it.
Pull over to the side.
Not in the ditch.
Hargrove: I'm going
on reconnaissance.
Hey, corp, you don't want to go in
there alone. Let me go with you.
Men: Yeah.
Shh! Quiet.
I'm going to sneak up that ditch and
see if I can't locate the battery.
I can do it much better alone.
Men, reluctantly: Ok.
Now, you stay here, and
above all, keep quiet.
[Canteens clatter]
Quiet.
[Whispering] Hey, corporal,
we won't make a sound.
[Children shouting]
The Americans are coming!
Man: The Americans!
Man: Get the mayor!
Get the mayor!
The Americans are coming!
Monsieur le maire,
the Americans.
They're on the side road.
They're coming this way.
Jeannie, do you hear?
The Americans.
Get my hat and coat!
There's one cannon and
a truck of soldiers.
I saw them plainly. The
others will surely follow.
Jeanne: I want to go, too!
Come, come. Summon everyone
and bring flowers and
wine and food! Come!
Man: Let's go! Come on!
The Americans are coming!
Go on. Scat!
Get out of here, you little...
You little saboteur.
Get out of here.
Go on! Go on!
Stop here! We'll
greet them here!
And silence!
Perhaps we should go down
the road to meet them.
No. We'll wait here and receive
them with proper dignity.
Oh, it will be a brave sight...
this big American army,
their colors flying,
music. Maybe they
have their own band.
Jeanne: Yes!
We must give them
a big welcome!
Voila! There they are!
There they are!
Wait! Wait! Don't
touch anything!
Is this Mardenne?
Yes, it is. Are you
the American army?
Well, yes. I'm part of it.
[Cheering]
As the Mayor of Mardenne...
excuse me. A little
improvised speech.
As the Mayor of Mardenne
and as the leader
of our French forces of resistance
in our district here...
I have many other functions,
but I don't want to
mention it here...
I have the great privilege
and great pleasure
to greet our dear friends,
our liberators,
the American armed forces!
[Cheering]
Well, thanks, uh... On
behalf of myself, uh...
Well, on behalf of
myself, thanks.
I thank you... ahem... too.
Uh, now, if you
will come with me,
m-Mr...
Oh, excuse me. Oh.
Lieutenant.
Oh, no. Corporal.
Oh, corporal.
Oh, corporal! Oh, that's a
very honorable rank.
I myself was corporal
in the last war in
our glorious army,
so it's nothing, uh...
Now, if you want to...
oh. It's, uh... Oh, yes.
That's my daughter...
Jeannie...
And corporal...
Uh, Hargrove, mayor.
Hargrove mayor... uh,
Hargrove, mayor.
[Laughter]
Now, if you'll summon
your comrades,
we can go to my house
and have a nice lunch.
Man: Did somebody say lunch?
Just lead on, governor.
Lead on.
Woman: Ooh!
[Crowd cheering]
Mayor: Here they are!
Of course, we knocked out so many tanks
and vehicles in the first advance,
it was very difficult
to keep track of them,
but I was able to keep track
of what we destroyed each day.
I have a little list right here.
Ah, here it is.
Uh...
Uh, 123 tanks, assorted sizes.
63 armored cars,
that's including half-tracks.
236 trucks... Vehicles,
not counting horse-drawn
carts or squad cars.
Of course, we owe
all our success
to our leader Hargrove.
Oh, Corporal Hargrove.
Fine type. Wonderful man.
You can take my word for it,
he won't be a
corporal for long.
Man: He's to be promoted?
Well, I can't say definitely,
but believe me, he
won't stay a corporal.
Ah, what coolness.
Mmm.
What daring, what courage.
What an imagination.
Oh, imagination.
Oh!
Yes, those are the real
qualities of a military man.
I can say it because somehow
I'm in the same position,
but I...
Well, I wonder where the
sightseeing party is.
They've been gone 2 hours now,
and they only paid
for the hour tour.
Man: I think I hear them
now, Monsieur Himmeville.
Mulvehill: Uh, it's Mulvehill.
M...Himmeville, yes.
Oh, yes, here he is...
Corporal Hargrove.
Mayor: Oh, good evening!
Welcome, corporal.
Hargrove: Quite a town
you've got here, mayor.
And we have had a fine
talk with Monsieur M...
Mulvehill:
That's right, indeed.
Hargrove: You didn't sell
them anything, did you?
Uh, well, mayor, Private Mulvehill
is quite a good talker.
Mayor: Oh, yes. Where did you
leave your comrades, corporal?
Oh, I wanted to tell
you about that.
I saw a big barn
down the road,
and Jeanne told me that it was
empty, so if you don't mind,
I'd like to billet the
boys there for the night.
D'historio's barn, father.
In a barn? Impossible.
No, I can't allow that.
Hargrove: But I don't
like to impose on you.
Oh, please, corporal. A man with
your record, your achievements,
to sleep in a stable...
I'm ashamed.
That would be an
insult to our allies.
After all, Marion, if our good friends
want to make us more comfortable...
excuse me, sir, but what has
this con man been telling you?
Con man? What's that...
con man?
Oh, con man is an American
phrase meaning friend.
Hargrove: Oh, it does?
Mayor: No. Not a word.
Come, follow me. My hat.
Hargrove: But, mayor,
the barn is fine.
Ha ha ha!
Yahoo-hoo-hoo!
Mulvehill: Burk! Burk!
Didn't you learn any manners
with those French lessons?
Get your filthy feet
off that spread!
Ahh!
Oh, you were going to get it fixed
for us to stay in a stable.
What a fixer!
How do you like this?
You know, something's wrong.
They're treating me as if I
was a big shot or something.
Well, that's your natural
manner... very impressive.
You know, the mayor said you
reminded him of a tall Napoleon?
He did? Well, there
you are, you see?
They think I'm a
visiting diplomat.
Well, just be diplomatic.
If you ever get stuck with
anything, just call on me.
Yeah?
Especially if you get stuck
with the mayor's daughter.
Yeah. I tried to kiss her on the
way over here, and she said,
[Imitating jeanne] "No! It would
not be fair to the corporal!"
What?
Jeanne: Corporal?
Corporal Hargrove?
Uh-huh.
Look, tell her I'm not in.
Tell her I was
called out of town.
Mulvehill: I will
not permit you to
jeopardize my comfort,
Corporal Hargrove.
Uh, the corporal will
be right down...
Honey.
Oh! Hey, it's nice up here.
So peaceful and quiet.
Let's sit down, shall we?
It's quite a climb to the top.
Sure.
Out that way is
the next village,
where he have the fire and
the cinema in peacetime.
Also, there are
the school and...
There is a stadium for games.
Is that a fact?
Well, isn't that interesting?
Uh, you don't have
a coat, Jeanne?
Aren't you a little cold?
No.
Are you cold?
No. As a matter of fact,
I was thinking it
was rather warm.
Also, in the village
over there...
you know, speaking
of the stadium,
you don't happen to know any recent
American baseball scores, do you?
Baseball? Oh, it is a game?
Oh, wonderful game.
Is that the only
game you play?
Well, no. Uh... But
it just so happens
that it's a very close
race for the pennant
in the National
League this year.
You see, I'll explain it to you.
There are 8 teams...
your friend Mulvehill,
when he walked with me,
he tried to kiss me.
Oh...
Well, about the pennant,
the winning team then plays the
winning team in the American League,
and that's what we
call the World Series.
Of course, I would
not let him kiss me.
Well, I should think not...
that wolf.
Wolf? You mean like
the animal wolf?
Well, it's what we call a
fella who chases after girls.
Anyway, the world series
consists of 7 games,
and the team who
wins 4 out of the 7
becomes the world's champion.
But you are not a wolf?
Me?
No.
You wish for the girls
to chase after you, hmm?
Oh, no, no. Not that.
Oh, but it is clear.
If you are the wolf,
then you chase
after the girls.
If you are not the wolf,
then the girls chase after you.
What else?
Well...
You know, there must be
some answer to that,
but, uh, I just can't
think of it right now.
Isn't it, uh, getting
awfully late, Jeanne?
Only about 9:00.
9:00?
Oh, well, I've got to
get home to my boys.
They're my responsibility.
All right, Mr. Wolf.
Hargrove: Well, the battery
must have been sidetracked,
so I can't say how long
we're going to be here.
[Man speaking
French excitedly]
Jeannie, help me!
My wife, the baby.
We are all alone. I
run all the way...
we must get Madame Godinot.
Come!
What's he so excited about? His
wife and baby are all alone?
No, no. My wife is
going to have a baby!
Oh! Oh, well, let's go.
Hey, wait a minute. What
do you want me for?
Oh, it is too far.
If you could take us in
your truck, it would help.
Oh. Oh, well, come on.
She's in here.
Godinot: We will send
for you in due time.
Man: Yes, madame.
Be sure and tell
her to be calm.
And you, my friend,
my benefactor, am I not calm?
Well, sure.
Oh!
Yeah, you're getting
calmer all the time.
Boil water!
Yes, sergeant!
Uh, yes, madame.
Funny how she reminds
me of Cramp.
All right. Up!
Soldier!
Yes, sir. Command me.
The water! The hot water!
It's boiling, madame.
Well, be quick about it.
Hurry up.
How do you feel?
I'm fine. Fine. Ca va.
Ca va. I'm calm now.
Oh, good. Well, stay that way.
Uh, it might help you if you
put some wood on the fire.
Ah, wood, yes!
Thank you.
[Door opens]
Hargrove: Hello.
How is everything?
Oh, it will be fine.
I must have some clean sheets
and towels for madame.
Oui, mademoiselle. Tout
de suite. Tout de suite.
I can never thank you
enough for coming with us
and for being so helpful.
Oh, that's all right.
Just don't tell the guys
in the crew about it,
or they'll kid my ears off.
Here, mademoiselle. Take
everything. Command me.
Jeanne: Thank you. Now,
be calm, won't you?
Man: I am an icicle. I am a
creature without nerves.
The water. Quick, quick!
Here, here. Let me do it.
Relax, now, won't you? You'll
be a father before you know it.
Just be calm.
I'm calm. Monsieur,
I am a man of iron.
You can inquire
in the village.
Who fought the Germans in
our guerrilla movement?
Who fought them with ferocity?
Who blew up their ammunition?
Who...
[Baby crying]
Listen!
It's a boy, Billiet!
Oh!
Isn't it wonderful?
Aw, great.
Isn't that...
That's it. Just relax.
Mayor: We shall always
remember you, our liberators,
with great affection
and esteem.
Isn't that so?
Oh, yes. Very affectionately.
Well, you've all
been very kind,
and thank you for everything.
Cramp: All right, let's break
it up and get to rolling.
Crowd: Bye!
These artillery men seem
to have softened up
the local situation
for us, major.
Yes. They've done pretty well.
Bye!
Good luck!
Good-bye! Come back soon!
I located Hargrove and the
crew in Mardenne, sir.
I thought you checked the road
into that town, sergeant.
I did, but Hargrove
worked out a shortcut.
He went off of the main road.
Against orders?
He was trying to
beat the traffic
and join up with the battery
a little sooner, sir.
All right, sergeant.
Yes, sir.
Corporal Hargrove
reporting, sir.
You may go, Private Hargrove.
Yes, sir.
[Artillery firing in distance]
Oh, my aching back!
Oh!
Oh! Dig it, shovel it, scoop
it, pile it, move it.
We've got to get this done.
It's a garbage pit, you know.
We've got to get it finished
before they get here
with the garbage.
Looks like I've changed my
garbage cans for this shovel.
I thought we came overseas
to get out of all that.
Cramp: All right, let's stop the
yakking and dig. Come on. Scoop.
What do you expect us to
do, sarge, strike oil?
I expect you to get your
garbage pit dug nice and deep.
And after that,
I got a few other chores
around the place for you.
When you finish up here,
come on over to the
ammunition dump.
You see, Monsieur Mayor, in
these nearby communities,
we know very little about the civil
governments which have taken over.
Now, for maximum security, we must
have reports on those officials...
whether or not they can
be completely trusted.
Your men can furnish us
with that information.
Yes, I know, major,
but you see,
my men have so much to do.
We have the fields and
all necessary repairs
and the restoration of all the
damage. It's very difficult.
Man: Oh, it shouldn't take long,
Monsieur Mayor. Perhaps a week.
We can discuss it. Of course, I
can't tell you the answer now.
[Speaking French]
Oh, no more for me, thank you.
Man: No, thanks.
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't
mean to disturb you.
I was only wondering...
Wondering about
Corporal Hargrove...
If he's located nearby.
Is there any news of him?
Oh, yes.
Corporal Hargrove. Fine
lad, splendid soldier.
You can see it immediately.
You know him, of
course, major.
Corporal harburg?
No, I don't think so.
Corporal Hargrove,
Monsieur Major.
Yes. He's the artillery man who stumbled
in here the day before we took over.
That's him.
Oh, yes. Now I remember.
Created quite an
impression, as I recall.
Yes, he became quite dear to us.
Oh, what a man.
What a soldier.
What a character.
You see, I'm an expert
in those matters,
so I can tell you.
I would like to tell you...
about that other matter,
Monsieur Mayor.
Just think it over. There's no
hurry. We'll discuss it later.
Mayor: It was very nice.
Jeanne: Au revoir.
Good-bye.
Mayor: Come... Again.
Man: Come and get your mail.
Gilly!
Here!
Mulvehill!
Hargrove!
Catch it.
Thanks, sarge.
Hey, they're from Carol!
Don't go away. I'll
be right back.
Here's a package for
you, too, Mulvehill.
Hiya, sarge.
Cramp: Hi, fellas.
Hey, he's happy.
Must be reading about
some new kind of shovel.
Ha ha ha!
Cramp.
Yes, sir.
Just what happened to
Hargrove and Mulvehill
when we lost them back in...
What's the name of that town?
Mardenne.
Oh, back there. Nothing
that I know of, sir.
Ain't much I'd put past them.
Why, captain?
Well, I've got an
order detailing them
for military government
detail back there.
Why, those shiftless slackers.
They didn't wangle it. This
came through from way high up.
You don't know Mulvehill, sir.
I'd suspect him if it came
from supreme headquarters.
Hey, Mulvehill!
Yes, sergeant. Yes.
Hargrove!
Did you want me, sarge?
I called you, didn't I?
Well, I'm, uh...
Not quite finished
with the ditch, sarge.
Cramp: No, leave it.
All right. With pleasure.
Mulvehill, you
parlez-vous any French?
Beg your pardon?
Hargrove, do you know
anything about a transfer
for you two men to civil
affairs in Mardenne?
No, sir.
Mulvehill?
You've been temporarily
assigned to duty there.
Arrange to get them
back, sergeant.
Yes, sir.
Oh, now, don't look
at me, sergeant.
If I could fix transfers,
there's one I would
have arranged long ago.
Don't look at me, sarge.
It's all news to me, honest.
Naturally, if someone at Mardenne
was impressed with our fine...
that's enough.
It's lucky for you two guys
I can't prove anything.
Yes, sir.
Ahem. Uh...
Will I have time to finish
my ditch, sergeant?
Get over to the
Service Battery.
I'll arrange to send
you back on a truck.
I only wish I could
shoot you out of a 105.
I've got Hargrove and
Mulvehill outside, major.
Who? Oh, the charm boys.
I thought we might assign
them to the M.P. squad.
Then we can call on them
for liaison work
whenever we needed them.
Good. Bring them in.
Hargrove. Mulvehill.
At ease.
You men have been in
this town before?
Yes, sir, but we didn't
do anything, captain.
You got to know the
mayor, didn't you?
Yes, sir. We got here by
mistake after they had
wiped out the German
Garrison by themselves.
I guess they were pretty happy
to see any American troops...
even us.
All right, Hargrove. Get on
over to the mayor's house.
Tell him that Major Kingby would
like to have 5 or 6 of the French
assigned to check up on these civil
officials in the area. Got that?
Yes, sir.
Get going.
You can report to the M.P.
headquarters, Mulvehill.
Yes, sir.
Let's see what happens.
[Knocks on door]
Oh, mon cher ami!
Oh...
Come.
Looks like the kid got action.
How do you like that?
I'd have been arguing with
the old boy for 3 hours.
Then he would have told me
he'd like to talk it over
with his colleagues.
Looks like it's all
in the approach.
Now, why didn't I
think of that?
Sergeant! Mulvehill,
look who's here.
Oh, I hate to say this, but
you're a sight for sore eyes.
How's the battery, hmm?
How's Gilly and Burk?
What's the matter with you?
Very pretty!
Very, very pretty.
Now, look, we didn't make up this
color scheme. We were issued these.
The sergeant doesn't approve of
anything unless it's caked in mud.
What kind of a racket have
you two guys got here?
What do you mean racket?
You think men of our character would
stoop to swindle a deal like this?
I'd hate to have
to count up to 3
while you thought it over.
Oh, sarge, now, quit
kidding, will you?
Tell us about the battery.
Are you still up the line?
Just for the time being.
We're cleaning the Krauts
out all through there,
and the infantry's pushing
up pretty fast.
We're going right along.
Oh, good.
We're on our way
to Paris, huh?
We? Ha ha!
I was coming back this way,
so I brought you some mail.
Hargrove: Thanks, sarge.
Well, so long, fellas.
Toodle-oo.
Hello there. Ooh, I
like your uniform.
It is so pretty.
Hargrove: Sarge, you're
blocking traffic.
Well, let them wait.
I came to invite
you to dinner.
Papa would like it very
much if you would come.
Oh, well, I'm awfully sorry,
but you see, I'm on duty now.
But Papa has already arranged
with Captain Parkson.
It is all right
for you to come.
Oh.
So it is all fixed?
Well, yeah, yeah.
I'll come over later.
Oh, come early, and we will pick
some flowers for the table.
Good-bye.
Ha ha ha! What a dumb detail!
Tisk tisk tisk.
You might strain yourself bending
over to pick the flowers,
but Papa could fix it so you
would get the decoration.
[Laughs]
Look, sarge, it wasn't that
way at all. You see, she...
All right, so what?
My, isn't it dusty
around here?
And will I get it from
the battery commander
if I'm not crisp and dandy.
Well! Chin up, chaps.
Ha ha ha!
Go on. Just make a crack.
Make a crack.
[Bell ringing]
Oh, Monsieur Mulvehill!
Good morning.
Monsieur Sutin, uh...
As the most modern,
up-to-date,
and progressive merchant
in this community,
I'm sure you'll be interested
in what I have to discuss
with you this morning.
You don't even
want to hear it?
The very latest in
modern merchandising.
I am busy. I have the
bread in the oven.
Oh, well, now, uh, maybe
you'd be interested
in a sensational postwar plan
to turn this charming little
village into a tourist paradise...
big hotel, gambling casino,
the trimmings, you know.
Excuse me. My bread
is in the oven.
I must watch my dough.
Parkson?
Yes, sir?
Got a job for the French here.
Details are all in there.
See that the mayor
gets it, will you?
Hargrove is due
back any minute.
I'll have him take
it right over.
Good. Certainly getting bang-up
cooperation these days.
See that it stays that way.
Yes, sir. Oh, uh,
this just came in.
It's from Army headquarters.
They think you're
doing a great job
and handling the French
situation brilliantly.
Anything else, major?
Not at the moment.
Yes, sir.
Hello, Hargrove. How are you?
Oh, I'm fine, thank you, sir.
Good!
Well, you look
startled, Hargrove.
Yes, sir. The major hasn't
spoken to me like that before.
Maybe the major is just beginning
to realize your fine qualities.
Yes, sir. Sometimes it
takes quite a while, sir.
Oh, take these reports
over to the mayor.
Ask him to study them and let me
know how he can help us. I need...
Well, what's the matter?
Oh, nothing, sir.
You're on good terms with
the mayor, aren't you?
Oh, yes, sir.
His daughter isn't
mad at you, is she?
On the contrary, captain.
That's fine.
Uh, captain, you
see, on this job,
I, uh... I'm with
her all the time.
Oh, tough luck.
Well, I've got a
girl back home,
and I don't think
she'd exactly approve
of these foreign
entanglements, captain.
Hargrove, your
conscience is clear.
Isn't it?
Oh, yes, sir.
It's in the line of duty, and
I'm sure you've done nothing
to encourage this romance.
Maybe not, but on
the other hand,
I haven't done anything
to discourage it either.
I'm afraid I haven't got
much character, captain.
If you'd like to send
me back to the battery,
it's all right.
Not a chance. We need the
cooperation of the French here.
They're doing a fine
job, and your liaison
work with them has
been outstanding.
You might even get a
promotion out of it.
Is that a fact?
If it's too much trouble,
captain, don't even bother
because they always bust me
in a couple of days anyway.
Uh...
While we're having this
little conversation, captain,
I'd like to ask you your
advice about something.
Do you think that if I told
Jeanne about my girl back home,
that she would understand?
What?! Hargrove, if you
do anything like that,
I'll personally see to it
that you finish out this war
in the dirtiest
job I can dig up.
Before you know it, the
girl will be sore at you,
and then the mayor
gets tough with us.
If that happens,
it's permanent K.P. For you,
garbage detail.
Oh, no. Not that.
Not garbage cans.
Just that. Now, hustle over to
the mayor with these papers.
Get him to start on
them right away.
Yes, sir.
Hello, wallingford. Sold any
interesting gold bricks lately?
No.
Why don't you give it up, Tom,
and live on your army pay?
Never.
Marion has told me how you are
unable to swindle anybody.
It is too bad. I'm very sorry.
I will speak to my father.
Oh, no, now, none of that.
I'll make good on my own.
Proud people, the Mulvehills.
You bet. Why, I've just
begun to fight.
I'll put over some kind
of deal in this town,
even if I have to give
them their money's worth.
Oh, poor Tom.
I like him. He is a nice man.
Yeah, well, I wouldn't
sign anything.
He has always told me very
nice things about you.
Really? Well, I still
wouldn't sign it.
You are worried
about something?
Me? Oh, no. Nothing at all.
But you are grave and concerned.
I see it.
No. I was just thinking.
Then I will be quiet and
permit you to think.
I was thinking how quiet and
peaceful this village is.
I'm happy that you like it.
It's going to be
tough to leave it.
You are going away?
Well, I'm in the army, Jeanne,
and the company may move
or they may send me
back to my battery.
You see, I haven't got
much to say about it.
Then I will go, too.
You can't do that.
Oh, but I want to do that.
Look, Jeannie, you're probably
getting your emotions
a little mixed up.
You feel the way you think you feel
about me because of gratitude.
No. It is not gratitude.
I am certain.
Oh, sure, it is.
It's not me. It's the
United States Army.
No, not so many as that.
Well, it's the
idea of the army.
The German occupation was
pretty terrible for all of you,
and the army kicked them out,
and that's why
you feel the way
you think you feel.
You are trying to tell me
that you do not like me,
that you wish to go away.
Oh, no, I'm not, Jeanne.
Not at all.
Yes. Yes, I feel it... Here.
You hate me.
Oh, honestly, I don't.
Don't cry, Jeanne.
Yes!
Oh, look. Look, Jeanne...
Look, I'm not mad at you,
and I don't hate you.
Now, don't cry. I'm
crazy about you!
Good work, Hargrove. I like
your devotion to duty.
Well, for a small
investment in advertising,
the whole American army
will be at your doorstep,
their watches in one hand,
their money in the other.
Most desirable,
Monsieur Himmeville.
Most desirable.
I see a huge army camp.
The men are unhappy.
Why?
Their watches are out of order.
They don't know what time it is.
An airplane hovers overhead.
It showers leaflets upon them.
They run, they pick
up the leaflets.
They smile, they laugh.
They come running
to Marcel Vivin.
To Marcel Vivin!
I could buy new equipment,
perhaps hire assistants to
handle the flood of business.
Well, of course, you'd have
to enlarge the premises.
It can be done.
Well, suppose we say a down payment
at this time of 500 francs
just to get the
campaign started?
Well, of course, 750
francs would be better,
then, when we see our advertising
taking effect, why, we...
Marcel! Marcel! I have news.
Wonderful news.
N-no. Everything is safe.
We'll be rich.
Later. Later. Just
think of it, Marcel...
all those beautiful
watches safe in Paris.
Not now. We'll
talk of it later.
But I do not understand.
Why...
Oh, pardon, monsieur.
I did not know...
no. It's quite all right.
Monsieur... Himmeville
is our friend.
However, we'll talk of it
later when we are alone.
Yes, I will go now.
Good day, Marcel.
Good day, Monsieur Himmeville.
Yes, we'll talk of this later.
Well, that's, uh...
That's very good news.
Congratulations.
Please forget what
you've heard.
Let's discuss our advertising.
You will require 750
franc as a down payment.
Well, that is quite agreeable.
These watches... were
there many of them?
It was quite a large shipment.
It came in just before
the occupation of Paris.
We could do nothing except
bury them in a house.
But let's turn to
our advertising.
Monsieur Vivin, of
course you realize
it will be some time before
you can get to Paris.
Ah.
That house may be
searched at any moment.
Oh, by the way, where did
you say that house was?
It is centrally located.
Uh-huh.
Hmm.
No doubt you of the
military will be in Paris
long before a civilian
is permitted to return.
That might be.
If you know someone who
would be interested
in the enormous profit to be
made from a small transaction...
Well, I'll keep it in mind.
For a trifling sum, a
few thousand franc,
a fine profit could
be realized.
I have a diagram
indicating everything
in detail.
Of course, you are a dreamer,
a visionary, like myself,
uninterested in
money or profit,
but perhaps you know someone.
I do.
Now, don't tell anybody about
this. I'll be right back.
[Whispering] Don't breathe
a word of this to anybody.
My lips are sealed.
Now, will you listen?
There's a fortune
to be made in this.
The First Army is headed
straight for Paris.
The first chance we get,
we scoop up this treasure,
and from then on,
we're sitting pretty.
Look, it's no use.
We're stuck.
I talked to the captain today,
and he won't let me go
back to the battery.
Marion, if you go
in on this with me,
I will personally guarantee
that we will be sent back.
You will? How?
How? What? When?
I give you my word of honor.
Isn't that enough?
Nope.
This is the scheme
of the century.
Now, will you
please shell out?
Oh...
Look, I'll...
wait a minute, Mulvehill! That's all
the money I've got in the whole world!
Well, I'll try to get
you some change.
Oh, quaint, isn't it?
Let me congratulate you.
Oh, yes. Thank you very
much, Monsieur Vivin.
I have to run along now.
Au revoir, my
dear Halberville.
That's Mulvehill.
Helmeville.
Ha ha. Yes.
Ha ha ha.
Hi.
Oh! I thought for a minute
you were going to
miss out on a meal.
Now, don't be bitter, chum.
Why not? You not only walked
away with all of my dough,
but you know darn well we're
never going to get into Paris.
You know, I've been giving
that a lot of thought.
Yeah, I'm afraid of that, too.
That means more trouble.
Ah, "C" ration hash again.
You know, sergeant, this lacks but
one thing to make it perfect.
What's that?
Chloroform.
Man: Hey! You almost
bought it that time.
You know, I can't wait to get
to Paris and those watches.
Ha ha ha.
What do you mean, ha ha ha?
Because you know we're never
going to get out of here.
You better start paying me back
some of that dough you borrowed
to pay for that map, too.
You know, I've been thinking.
We're stuck in this town because
that girl's attached to you.
Now, uh, why don't we get
the girl out of town?
Why? Because, you addlebrained
idiot, she won't go.
And even if we get sent
back to the battery,
she said she was
going to follow me.
Well, it's all set.
She's waiting over at the
house to say good-bye to you.
What?
Hey! This food is
bad enough, bud,
without your foot in it.
Yeah, well, excuse me.
Here, here. Take mine.
You'll love it.
Every minute of it.
Tom, you miracle man.
How did you do it?
Tell me, what did you say?
It was a cinch.
She told me she was
going to follow you.
That gave me an idea.
I told her that would
be impossible.
Then I gave her a pitch
about what might be done.
She leaves tonight to
join the French WACs.
Ah, that's wonderful!
I knew you would...
Man: Ugh! No!
You got that?
Hello. Operator?
What's happened?
Operator!
The wire's out again.
Yes, sir. Check your radio.
Somebody coming this
way must have tripped
over the wire and knocked
everything haywire.
They'll get right on it, sir.
We haven't had anything
like that happen
since Hargrove
left the battery.
That's right, sir.
[Knock on door]
Come in.
Private Hargrove
reporting, sir.
I should have known.
Well, welcome home.
I haven't done anything.
On your way over here, you didn't
happen to trip over any wires, did you?
Well, as a matter
of fact, I did,
but I didn't hurt
myself, sarge.
Get back to your section.
Hi, sarge.
Ahem. I was just
trying it on for size.
Well, get back to your section before I
think of something else for you to dig.
Right, sarge. Right
away, sarge.
On the double. I'm going.
Hey, are we still batting out
congas on that roll over there?
No. We're shelling some strongholds
the Krauts are trying to reinforce.
Ah! That's my meat. Here,
let me at that lanyard.
That's for me. Here we go!
We finished that
mission, Hargrove.
Oh, you point killer.
See if you can get
fire direction
and find when the ammunition
train will be in, Sergeant Hill.
Operator?
Gone dead on you?
Yes, sir. The wire seems
to be out, lieutenant.
I'll run over to the switchboard
operator and see what I can find out.
No. Let's get this
wire fixed right away.
Yes, sir.
Hang onto that, Hargrove.
I'll get the wire section
for Lieutenant Morley.
Ok, sarge.
You just missed it, Hargrove.
Fire direction said
we dropped one
right on an ammunition train.
Mulvehill: And we got it
without you on the sights.
Hargrove: Oh, well, that
was just a lucky hit.
Oh, get him. They'd count
it as a direct hit for you
if it landed in
the same country.
Oh, is that so? Well, let
me tell you something!
Man: Hey, Hargrove. Don't
shout into the phone.
They may still be plugged
into fire direction.
Oh, my gosh.
Hello?
Hello!
Ha ha! Oh, it's dead.
Not a sound.
It's going to take them hours
to repair that line anyway.
It's as dark out there as
a supply sergeant's soul.
Now's my chance to tell the
old man what I think of him.
Give me that. Ha ha!
Hello?
Hello?!
Oh, so you can hear me, eh?
Well, this is
Mulvehill speaking.
Thomas Mulvehill.
Just plain Private Mulvehill
due to prejudice.
Otherwise, I would have been
commissioned in the
field months ago!
That's telling
them, huh, fellas?
Listen, while you're about it, ask him
why he broke the eminent Hargrove,
the best artillery man
in all of France.
Yeah, and put in for a 30-day
furlough for me, too, will you?
Yeah, uh...
Well, colonel, you just watch your
step from now on, that's all.
You know, I wish this was a pay
telephone. You know what I'd do?
Men: You'd call your girl.
I guess it sort of shows
on me, doesn't it?
Well, I would. I
would call Carol,
and I'm not ashamed
of it either.
Man: Nothing to be
ashamed of, kid.
Of course it isn't.
Nothing whatever.
I didn't say a thing.
Well, don't.
Oh, I'm sick of trying to
dig my way into Berlin.
I'm tired, and I'm cold,
and I'm homesick.
I'm sick of these foxholes.
I'm sick of "K" rations.
And, oh, brother, how sick
I am of the way I smell!
Ha ha!
You know, I wish I could
talk to Carol, though.
You got a phone. Go ahead.
Don't be silly. You can't...
Uh...
By George, I will.
Hello, operator. Get
me Regent 6-6599.
Deposit 364 bucks, please.
Oh, yeah, would you
hurry, operator, please?
Hello? Hello, Carol.
Love... 3,000 miles away
with a dead telephone,
and he gets the
number in a second.
He sure makes a sucker
out of Marconi.
Oh, shut up, will you?
Hello, Carol.
I, uh... I'd like to say
a lot of things to you,
but I can't very well because
I'm with a bunch of the guys,
but I just wanted to talk to you
because I miss you so much.
I, uh... I don't like being
so far away from you, honey.
I wish I could be nearer to you so
I could see you once in a while
and, well, where I could
sort of look forward
to seeing you the
rest of the time.
You know, I, uh...
I wish I could just sort of
reach out and... and touch you.
Here's Baker's trunk line.
You splice it.
Right.
Give me Sergeant Hill's line.
You sure that's it?
Yeah, yeah. That's it.
We'll have to change the direction of
our fire to around 1800 mils, Drake.
Now, that should bring us nearer
the center of our sector.
That fool phone keeps
holding us up.
Maybe I can get right through to
your battery. Is this your computer?
Man: Yeah, but I think
that line's out, too.
Hargrove: Yeah,
well, good night.
Good night. Parting
is such sweet sorrow
that I shall say good
night till it be morrow.
Sleep dwell upon
thy eyes, peace...
man: Hey, better cut it short.
Oh, yeah. Well, Carol,
we better hang up now
because this phone might be
hooked up with headquarters,
so now a lot of brass hats
might be eavesdropping.
So good night, precious.
Man: Good night, lover!
Good... What?
[Band playing The Caissons
Go Rolling Along]
Hargrove: All right, men, on the double.
Let's unload this. On the double!
You know, when they
make you a corporal,
it doesn't go to your head;
It goes to your vocal cords.
Hargrove: Come on!
All the way.
All the way. Drop it.
Put her down.
Hey, Paris is out
there somewhere.
That's for me.
You hear that, Hargrove? Paris
is out there somewhere.
Paris! The city of wealth.
Ah, the Germans are
out there, too.
Let's get this ready to fire.
All right, men, on the double.
Ellerton, get the ammo.
There we go. Spread it.
He's all corporal,
isn't he, sergeant?
Sure is. He ain't the coolest
head in the battery,
but he tries hard.
How did he work out when we tried
him at the observation post?
All right. Promoted him
to sergeant after that.
Yeah, I remember.
2 days later, he was
busted for backing a truck
right into the division C.P.
But he was all right in the
observation crew, sir.
Well, we'll try him again.
We're short an
instrument operator,
and he probably knows enough
procedure to fill the bill.
Yes, sir.
Get your aiming circle set up.
Hello.
You think that we'll get
into Paris tomorrow, sarge?
Well, I don't know. I
haven't gotten my report
from General Eisenhower
yet today.
Hargrove, been talking to
the old man about you.
Uh-oh. You want to cut
them off yourself?
No, not yet.
Do you suppose you could work
in an observation post again
without gumming up
the whole campaign?
Oh, sarge. That's my meat.
"Eagle-eye Hargrove," they call me.
Keep digging.
I want to check with our
liaison officer here.
Hello, captain. What's the best
place around here for the O.P.?
Well, I think about 500 yards
up the road and to the right.
That ought to give you a
pretty good range of vision.
Can darn near see our guns
from that high a ground.
Any cover up there?
There are 2 or 3 shot-up
tanks and a house or 2.
Ok. We'll be up
there somewhere.
You have any missions for
us, contact us by radio.
Right. And, uh, keep your eye
open for some Kraut stragglers.
We bypassed a lot of
them in the woods.
They may drift back your way.
Thanks, captain.
Go on about 300 or 400 yards,
Hargrove. Keep to the right.
They're moving up
some more artillery.
We've got to spot it
and knock it out fast.
Lieutenant, how about that?
Man: No, that's no good.
When you've been at this a
little longer, Hargrove,
you'll realize that if a spot
for an O.P. Looks good to you,
it will look just as
good to the enemy.
They'll shell your
ears off every time.
We'll have to get up along that
ridge and find a hole somewhere.
Let's go.
[Incoming missiles]
[Explosions]
There goes your cozy
nook, Hargrove.
I can pick them, can't I?
It's ok. You'll learn.
Come on. Let's find...
oh, lieutenant, it was a pretty
punk idea about that house before,
but maybe it's better now.
They've hammered it
pretty hard already,
and they probably figure they've
knocked out whatever was in there.
Well, it's only a suggestion.
It's not bad. Let's try it.
Hargrove: There's some of
their artillery, lieutenant.
Can we get fire
direction, sergeant?
Just a minute, sir.
Operator.
Give me fire direction.
Just a minute.
I have fire direction,
lieutenant.
Fire mission.
Fire mission from Baker O.P.
Coordinates...
8-0-4 point niner.
Coordinates 8-0-4 point niner.
Dash 1-6-3 point 7.
Concentration 2-7-6,
Battalion Baker.
3 volleys. Set a range.
Battery right.
Elevation 3-6-0.
Set.
Ready.
On the way.
300 left. Repeat range.
Right 4-8-3-6-0.
Fire!
On the way.
5-0 short. Fire for effect.
Baker's firing.
Battalion is firing.
It's amazing how
good the battery is,
considering I'm not with them.
Request intermittent
harassing fire
on road intersection
just fired upon.
No, there's nothing
moving now.
Oh, this is terrible.
Oh, no, no, sir. I
didn't mean you.
Hargrove.
Stop eating while you talk on that
phone. You'll have them firing on us.
Hargrove: Yes, sir.
I'm all through.
I'll take it.
Better keep an eye
peeled toward the woods
once in a while, Hargrove.
A Kraut patrol might
sneak up on us.
No. Not on me, they won't.
There's some more flashes.
That's a new position.
Hey, Lieutenant! Staple!
Ok, Hargrove.
Where are you, Staple?
Staple: I guess I'm all right.
Hello?
Hello? Operator?
It's dead.
Must have got our
wire that time.
Almost got my wire, too.
Try the radio.
Well, we'll try
what's left of it, sir.
Hargrove, you get
back to the battery.
Yes, sir.
Give them these coordinates
on that last position.
Yes, sir.
Get another radio. Staple,
you stay here with me.
We'll try to get
our wire back in.
Yes, sir.
And, Hargrove, be careful.
Halt!
It's me... Hargrove.
Don't shoot.
Give the password.
Um... I'm trying
to think of it.
That proves
it's Hargrove, all right.
Oh, I got it!
It's Lana Turner.
Ok.
Lieutenant Dillon wants
you to blast away
at coordinates 805.1-163.8.
You got it?
I'm going to get right
over to fire direction
and check on your mission.
Wait a minute, sarge. Our radio
and wire were knocked out,
and the lieutenant wants me to get
another radio and come right back.
Get Hargrove the radio. He's got
to get back to the O.P.
Come on! Don't sit there
with egg on your face!
Get what the man wants!
Hustle!
Right away, sir.
Ah, this is worth
fighting for.
[Distant artillery fire]
I wish Hargrove
would get back.
He made the
battery, all right.
They're opening up on the
coordinates he gave them now.
Good. Good.
But I wish he'd get
back in with that radio
so we can keep in touch
with the battery.
Sir, we'd better
get out of here.
They'll have this place
pulverized soon.
I think you're right.
Let's go.
[Softly] It's me... Hargrove.
Here. Hold this gun, will you?
I thought for a
minute you'd gone.
Do not make a noise.
You are a prisoner.
Put that down.
Now you will tell us
what we want to know.
Where are your
headquarters located?
About 300 yards to the right.
What's wrong with
that lamebrain?
Hargrove: Maybe I was off
a little bit on that one.
It's more like 400
yards to the right.
He's giving us the correction
on our last round,
but something's wrong.
Somebody's up there with him.
Baker, take that as a sensing.
Left 72420.
How far are your front lines?
You're right on top of them.
That did it. That's the range.
That kid's gotten
himself captured,
and he's giving us the range
right under their noses.
We will start now, and
you will go with us.
Oh, you won't be needing me.
But we'll take you,
and in case we should
encounter any difficulties,
we will deal with you first.
Wonder what Hargrove's up to.
He should have been
back a long time ago.
Shh!
What is it?
Only one of them has a gun.
We can handle them.
Look out for Hargrove.
Uh, we'd better go this way.
We got to watch out
for the mines.
Good.
Duck, Hargrove!
[Speaking German]
Sorry I took so
long, lieutenant.
Well, there I was,
coming up to the O.P.,
and on the inside was this flock
of Germans, armed to the teeth,
but did that stop me?
Frankly, no.
I crept up to
one of the broken windows.
I looked in,
and I sized up the situation.
It was only all too...
[Explosion]
It was all too plain that
they outnumbered me completely.
I didn't know
what to do, so...
so you gave the
Germans your own gun
just to even things up.
Oh, sergeant, have you been listening
to that Nazi propaganda again?
I'm surprised at you,
taken in like that.
You believe me, don't you?
Oh, I like that.
So you gave the
Germans your gun.
You'd have probably
sold it to them!
Cramp: All right, let's cut out
the chatter and get back to work.
Come on. Let's go.
Yahoo! We made it! Paris!
[Cheering]
We're rich!
♪ Paris, I hope to know ya ♪
♪ Paris ♪
Hey, fellas, look! Hey, look!
"Paris 12 kilometers!"
[Cheering]
Prosperity is just
around the corner.
Oh, boy! Champagne, eats!
Me for the museum!
I'm going to take a
big fat hot bath!
A stroll down the
boulevard with a girl.
[Laughing]
To my left, the
Arc de Triomphe.
Triumphal arc.
Isn't that wonderful?
What street are we on?
Champs-elysees.
Une femme de Paris.
Girl.
La place de l'opera.
Et across la rue,
le cafe de la pain.
Across?
Yeah, like I was saying.
Voila!
Hey, the Ritz! C'est une...
Hotel.
Where are we now?
Dans le suburbs.
What does that mean?
In the suburbs.
In the suburbs!
Yeah!
Are you kidding?
Why didn't you say something?!
In the suburbs!
♪ The last time I saw Paris ♪
♪ Her heart was warm and gay ♪
Hey, fellas... Look.
"Paris 16 kilometers."
That's the quickest tour
of Paris on record.
Yeah, and I didn't even get
to go past the museum.
Business before
pleasure, guys.
We got to keep
them on the run.
What do you want to do,
stop for sightseeing
and expect the Germans
to wait for us?
Ah, shut up!
Burk is right, absolutely
right, 100% right.
Well, mastermind, what about
our Parisian investment?
I'm thinking.
What more do you want?
My money.
Money.
All you ever think
about is money.
Good evening, sergeant. Why
don't you give us a hand?
I can do better than that.
We're moving out of here.
That's great. We can drag
these guns around some more.
Lieutenant, the captain
told me to tell you
the battery's been ordered
back to a rest area.
We're to be ready to move out of
here as soon as possible, sir.
Rest area! That's what...
did you hear...
a rest area! Hey!
Movies! Hot water! Loafing.
How do you like
this crooked army?
Rest area. "Go to a rest area.
"You look tired, my boy.
Have a nice rest...
In a rest area."
Well, I'm in a rest area!
Why don't we sneak back to the
front lines and get some rest?
The army promised me a rest,
and I'm going to get it.
Hargrove: How?
I don't know how,
but I'm thinking.
You know what burns me?
Here we are, just a little
ways from Paris. Paris!
Do you know that we'd be rich
if we could only get to
Paris for a few hours?
Ha ha ha!
The army's not going to
make a sucker out of me!
I'm going to find
Sergeant Cramp
and tell him exactly
where to get off.
Cramp: Hey, Mulvehill!
Get some arm into that job!
You bet, sarge.
That's telling him.
Sergeant, it
wouldn't do any harm
if you were to give Hargrove
and myself a few hours off.
We have some very important
business in Paris.
Sure, sure.
Then when we get back,
we could tell all the
fellas about it.
It's almost as good as letting
the whole battery go.
Of course, if you want me to
bring you something back...
perfume, silk stockings.
Not for personal use, of course.
Ha ha ha!
You'll find me a very
effective purchasing agent.
No passes.
Aw, now, sergeant! This is a
matter of life and death!
Not a chance, Mulvehill.
It just so happens,
Private Mulvehill,
that when you came in here,
I was just wondering
which 2 men
I could send out on
a little detail...
matter of loading a truck
with some supplies.
It just so happens that
I've come to a decision.
Yep. You and Hargrove.
Why, you...
well, how do you do, chaplain?
Cramp: Evening, chaplain.
Sergeant.
Get a 3/4-ton truck
ready to roll,
and you and Hargrove stand by.
Yes, sergeant. Ha ha.
I have an idea, sergeant,
I kept Private
Mulvehill from using
some very violent
language just now.
I wouldn't be a bit
surprised, chaplain.
Now, with all the
rations and supplies,
you ought to have a
pretty good truckload.
When you get back here,
unload everything
at Service Battery.
You'll find the
quartermaster railhead
right along that road.
You got it?
Sure, I got it.
Ok, let's hustle!
Hey, sarge, do me a
favor, will you?
What is it?
If we have ice
cream for dessert,
carry mine extra-hard and
keep it cold for me.
There's a road up ahead.
We'd better look
at this map again.
You stick to driving.
Last time you looked at a map,
you practically steered
us out of France.
Oh, sorehead.
Hey, Mac! Which way to the Q.M.
railhead?
Follow us. We're
going there, too.
Good deal. You
see, it's a cinch.
We fall in at the
end of this column,
ah, we don't need
this anymore.
Well, drive on!
I sure wish you hadn't torn
up those directions, Tom.
Cramp said that it
wasn't very far.
Will you take it easy? This whole
column's headed for the railhead.
You heard the man
say so yourself.
Yeah, I know, but...
forget it.
[Whistle blowing]
I don't see "pretty baby."
Hey, what happened
to "pretty baby"?
I don't know, precious.
Did you lose her?
He must mean one
of those trucks
that turned off back
at the railhead.
Turned off? Where? When?
Where are we now?
In Paris. Out of the way, boys.
We're rolling.
Hey! I know what we can...
it's no good.
Wait a minute! Why don't we...
nope. That won't work either.
Look, will you quit
thinking out loud?
You got me going up and
down like an elevator.
Well, the best bet is for us
to lie low till daylight.
Then we can go out of the
city like we came in.
We can always tell Cramp
we had engine trouble.
Cramp will fix our engines, too.
You know that.
But I guess that is
the best thing to do.
Have you got a piece of paper?
I'll mark down the road
that we took coming in.
That's a good idea.
Here you are.
What is this, a map?
A map? Let's see.
Ho ho! I'll say it's a map!
That's the location of that stuff
I bought from the jeweler.
This is going to make us
rich when we get to Paris.
Paris.
What am I saying?
We're in Paris!
Look, will you not
get so excited?
We're not going on
any treasure hunts.
What's the odds we're here?
We can't budge till daylight.
Hargrove, destiny
brought us here.
Fate intended for us
to make some money.
An inscrutable higher wisdom
guided us to this spot.
Mulvehill, will
you listen to me?
We're in enough
trouble already!
Hargrove, don't fight destiny.
Drive on.
[Starts engine]
Shh. Shh.
23. This is it.
Go ahead.
Me?
Well, you're not a
silent partner.
I couldn't fit through there.
Besides, you can make it easy.
Go ahead.
I'll pass you the
shovel and flashlight.
You mean I have to dig
it up all by myself?!
Don't quibble about
technicalities.
Are you scared?
No. I shake like
this all the time.
You keep a watch out.
If anybody comes,
give me a signal.
Yeah.
[Thump]
Hey, you hurt?
That first step is a killer.
Well, here. Start digging.
You'll loosen up.
[Clang]
Ouch!
[Yawns]
How's it coming?
It looks like the
Panama Canal down here.
All I found is 2
more blisters.
Listen, maybe you're just
skimming the surface.
Why don't you dig
down a little deeper?
I'd like to skim you.
Hi.
Who's down in that cellar?
Oh, nobody. I'm just looking
for something I dropped.
Hargrove: You'll have to
talk louder, Mulvehill.
I can't hear you.
That's what I dropped.
You see, sir, we can explain.
We were just looking for
something that belonged to us,
something we bought.
23 Avenue Court, eh?
You men ever stationed in
a town called Mardenne?
Yes, sir.
Ever have any dealings
with a man named Vivin?
Yes, sir. He's the one
that sold us the watches.
You see, I have a
bill of sale here
entitling me to any watches
found in the cellar
of 23 Avenue Court.
I know all about it.
You're the third bunch we
found digging up that cellar.
You've been swindled,
Private Mulvehill.
[High voice] Me?
[Normal voice] Me?
That's just what I mean.
In the future, private,
don't be such a hick.
Don't fall for every con
game that comes along.
No, sir.
Let's see your passes.
Hargrove: Our passes?
Yes, your passes.
Oh, Paris.
Paris, city of love.
And here I am.
I dig a cellar, and I
wind up in a cell.
And to whom am I indebted
for this rare experience?
T. Mulvehill, mastermind!
That's right. Kick a
man when he's down.
You don't have to get down.
Just bend over.
Is it my fault they
didn't believe the story
of how we got to Paris?
I told the M.P. sergeant,
I told the lieutenant,
I told the captain,
I told the major.
All they did was laugh at me.
Well, I don't blame them.
It sounds crazy to me.
I don't see why they
should believe it.
Well, I swore on my honor!
You'd think
they'd believe that.
Ha ha ha!
Man: Good evening, chaplain.
How are you?
Hey, there's the chaplain!
Oh, the chaplain. I guess he goes
along with a firing squad, huh?
No, dummy. Our chaplain.
Hey, he's coming this way.
I'll hail him. Maybe
he can help us out.
Hargrove: Oh, forget it.
Oh, uh, chaplain.
Mulvehill, what are
you doing in there?
I'm in trouble, chaplain.
I can see that.
As a matter of fact, Hargrove
and myself are both in trouble,
and if I could just talk
to you for a minute,
I could explain it.
Honest, chaplain.
Oh, please, chaplain.
All right.
Aw, thanks, chaplain.
Oh, what's the use?
We've told that
story so many times
that even I don't believe it.
It's pretty thin.
It's not very
convincing, is it?
You know, Mulvehill,
it's really a pity.
This is probably the first
time in your whole life
that you haven't
told the truth.
Mulvehill.
Yeah, that's me!
Hey, now don't
desert the ship.
I got a good idea.
I realize you didn't leave
a combat zone, Mulvehill,
but you're in this
area without a pass,
and I don't think I
should interfere.
According to the law,
chaplain, you're right.
There's no doubt about it,
but we wouldn't have
done a thing like this
unless it was very important.
If you could have
seen Hargrove,
the way he was suffering.
Suffering? What about?
Tossing and turning,
not able to sleep.
What was wrong with him?
W...
No. No, chaplain.
You're right.
It isn't fair to
burden you with this.
Don't be ridiculous,
Mulvehill.
Perhaps I can help.
Well, it's a girl.
Not just a girl, but the girl.
It's such a beautiful love
that just being a party
to it has purified me.
Well, she was in Paris.
She wanted to see Hargrove.
She needed him, and
he couldn't get here,
and it was driving him crazy,
and this just seemed to
be the only thing to do
to keep Hargrove from
cracking up entirely.
We only needed a few hours
for them to get married.
That's very touching.
Of course, if somebody
cared about the happiness
of just 2 plain kids,
it would be different,
but this is the army...
big, heartless, impersonal.
Ah, I guess it has to be.
Oh, I wouldn't say
that, Mulvehill.
Oh, no, they're right.
We broke regulations. We
have to suffer for it.
I must say, Mulvehill,
it's splendid of you
to become involved in
your friend's difficulty.
It's very gratifying.
That's my nature. I'm
Irish, you know.
Just a big sentimental fool.
Wait here, Mulvehill.
I can't believe it! We're out!
And we got a pass!
The chaplain took a
shine to me, I guess.
He squared it with the M.P.s
by personally guaranteeing
our return to the battery,
and we don't have to be
back till tomorrow night.
Isn't that wonderful?
He said he'd square
it with Cramp, too.
Tom, I, uh... I owe
you an apology.
I was a little rough on you
back there in that jail.
You were excited. Forget it.
You don't owe me a thing...
Except maybe some money.
Ha ha ha! Ha ha ha!
We're going to see Paris and
have a whale of a time.
Look, I've got a guidebook.
"The educational and cultural
possibilities of Paris
"for the soldier on leave
are truly boundless.
"The museums, the art
galleries, the libraries...
all offer their facilities"...
They're not allowed to
make dates. It says here.
Really? Oh.
Well, in that case,
let's get some culture.
Now to continue.
"The great many places
of historic interest
"are opened to the
armed forces,
"such as the Tomb of
Napoleon, Versailles"...
Jeanne: Marion! Oh!
Marion!
[Men whistling loudly]
Oh, that's fine.
You get the girl.
I get the coffee.
Ha ha.
I've always hoped whenever
I come in the Red Cross
that you might be in Paris.
And I finally made it.
I hope the rest
of the soldiers
don't expect that
with breakfast.
This is wonderful.
We've got a whole day,
and you can show us around
Paris, Jeannie. Here, sit down.
Mulvehill, get Jeannie a
cup of coffee, will you?
You bet.
Thank you.
Chaplain: Hello, Mulvehill.
Well, hello, chaplain.
I've been looking for you.
Oh, really?
I put a call through to
the battery this morning,
and everything's all fixed up.
They had you down A.W.O.L,
but I took care of it.
Thank you, chaplain.
Thank you very much.
Where's Hargrove?
Hargrove?
Oh, Hargrove!
Oh, yes. Well... He
didn't come down yet.
Oh, that's too bad.
I wanted to congratulate
him and wish him luck.
Well, I'll tell him.
I'll tell him, chaplain.
Fine. Well, enjoy yourself.
Thank you, chaplain!
Thank you.
There's Hargrove now.
[Cup rattles]
Where?
And with his girl.
Well, so he is. So he is.
Let me do the talking.
For Pete's sake, don't blow
up, no matter what I say.
What is the matter with you?
Hargrove, it's so good to
see you up and around!
You remember the chaplain.
Oh, hello, chaplain.
Hello.
By the way, thank
you very much
for getting us out of jail.
It's a pleasure to see
you two together.
Oh, Jeannie, this is
Chaplain Mallowy.
Jeanne: How do you
do, chaplain?
Chaplain: You may not
know it, my dear,
but I'm the cupid that
arranged all this.
Chaplain, don't
let us keep you.
Oh, no. I've plenty of time.
This fellow has been
eating his heart out for you,
and now that I've met
you, I can understand it.
Oh, Marion!
He's a lucky chap to have
a sweetheart like you
and a friend like Mulvehill.
Oh, well, thank you, chaplain.
Yes, thank you very
much, chaplain.
Tell me, have you had
the wedding yet?
[Fork clatters]
Wedding?
Not yet, chaplain,
but it's all arranged,
isn't it, Hargrove?
[Voice cracks] Yeah.
Yes, I guess it is.
Are you all right, Hargrove?
Oh, everything is so sudden!
I do not know what to say.
But, Marion, you
do not look happy.
Oh, but he is. Look at him.
He's speechless with joy.
Is this the first you've known
about this wedding, Jeannie?
Oh, yes, but it
doesn't matter.
We wanted it to be a
surprise, chaplain.
Yes, apparently.
Jeanne: Oh, it is
a big surprise.
I do not hear from him
for ever so long,
and then I just bump into
him here at the Red Cross,
and still he does not
mention the wedding,
and now suddenly... it
must be the American way.
Fast. Very fast.
Did I say something wrong?
You men get back to
your organization.
That was a shabby way to get
your release last night.
But, chaplain...
get back to your battery
at once. That's all.
Yes, sir.
I'm so sorry about this.
I didn't know anything
about it, believe me.
What a dirty trick.
Well, you finally topped
all your past performances
and finished up a double-dipped
heel, didn't you?
Now, wait a minute.
I had to tell the chaplain
something, didn't I?
You made a sucker out
of the chaplain,
out of me, and out of Jeannie.
You had to bring
her in on it, too.
Her feelings don't count.
My feelings don't count.
Just as long as you can work
that big flapper of yours
up and down in some
complicated swindle.
Well, my fine friend...
please do not fight over it.
It is all right.
It's a matter of principle.
I'm fed up with this swindler.
You thought I was
pretty good last night
when I got you out
of that cooler.
Oh, sure. You know, I
took it for granted
there was some petty
larceny involved in this.
I've gotten used
to that with you,
but I also thought that there would be
some things that you would stop at.
Well, I was wrong,
but, brother, I'm not
going to be wrong again.
I'm going back to the battery
and take what's coming to me,
and I'm going to ask Cramp to
put me in another section,
and take a tip from me...
don't speak to me,
because if you do and
I've got a shovel in my hand,
I'm going to swing it!
Ok, if that's the
way you feel.
That's just how I feel!
Good-bye, Jeannie.
I'm so sorry.
Good-bye, Marion.
I beg your pardon, miss.
Were those 2 soldiers
bothering you?
No.
Is there anything I can do?
No, nothing.
I'd like to be of
service if I can help.
My name is Sergeant Wolf,
Sergeant John Wolf.
Wolf? You mean like
the animal wolf?
Well... Yes.
You like baseball, sergeant?
Can't stand it. Bores me.
Well, sit down, Sergeant Wolf.
Hargrove, on the
strength of this report,
I could throw you up
to a court-martial.
What have you got to
say for yourself?
It's all true, sir. We didn't
intentionally go into Paris,
but it's all true otherwise.
And that's enough, no matter
how you got into Paris.
What do you think, sergeant?
Well, sir, we could
use him and Mulvehill
if we're moving
up again tonight.
Why don't you leave
them to me, captain?
I'll see they work
off this rap.
All right.
Aw, thanks, sarge.
Shut up. You think I'd lift a
finger for you 2 chiselers
if I'd have had time
to replace you?
You haven't cleaned
this up, not by a mile.
You got a long way to go,
so get out of here and
report to your section.
Wait a minute.
Where is Mulvehill?
I don't know, and
I don't care.
Hargrove, how did you come
to go off without Mulvehill?
Don't even mention his name.
I'm through with
that chiseler.
But he ain't back yet.
If we pull out without him,
he'll be grabbed for deserting.
That's a big rap.
I don't care if they
make it murder, arson,
or piracy on the high seas.
Anyway, he's probably
back here now,
hiding somewhere while we're
getting ready to move out.
That way, he gets out
of doing any work.
I just checked. He isn't
anywhere in the area.
Well, it's no skin off my arm.
Where are you going?
Just around.
Cramp: All right, fellas, let's get
ready so we can move out fast.
You understand it...
what do you want?
Could I talk to you
for a minute, sarge?
Whatever it is,
the answer is no.
Honest, sarge, this is very
important. Could I talk to you?
All right, fellas, just stand
around so we can move out fast.
Soldier: Ok.
All right, shoot.
Well, I'm a little worried
about Mulvehill, sarge.
He hasn't turned up...
what do you want
me to do about it?
Put a candle in my window?
Something must have
happened to him.
Whatever it is won't compare
to what happens to him
when he gets picked up.
They'll have him
down for a deserter.
Sarge, we ought
to do something.
What are you getting
so worked up about?
I thought you were
through with him.
Well, I am, only...
only nothing, and
I don't want you
sneaking out of this
camp looking for him.
That'll only get you
a mess of trouble.
You got that? You stay put.
Yes, sergeant.
All right, get back
to your section.
[Vehicle approaching]
[Brakes squeaking]
Hi, sarge.
I told you to stay put.
I warned you not to
leave that camp.
Yeah, I know, but
what if he's sick
or in some terrible
trouble or something?
Look, what if you
were in the same jam
or you were sick or you
were wounded or something?
What do you think
I'd do about it?
You'd give 3 cheers
and go your own way.
That's right.
Oh, no. No, I wouldn't.
I wouldn't rest
until I got to you,
no matter what it involved.
That's the spirit of
the field artillery.
One for all, and all for one.
Why, greater love hath no man.
Oh, you're breaking my heart.
I can't set here jawing
with you all night.
Come on. Get in.
Oh, thanks, sarge. You're a
prince... For the time being.
[Big band music playing]
I got a lead, sarge.
Some guys in the club said
they saw him about an hour ago
in a small restaurant near
here, and he was drinking.
All this and drunk, too.
We ain't got much time.
We got to get back
to that battery.
It's right down here
and to your left.
I'll direct you from there.
[Speaking French]
What the heck is he saying?
I don't know.
Do you know any French?
Yeah, a little bit.
Will you give us a hand?
Sure.
What is he saying?
Qu'est-ce que vous dites?
[Speaking French]
What is he saying?
He says it sounds
like the soldier
who paid for his dinner
with a half interest in
an oil well in Newark.
Sounds like him.
That's Mulvehill.
Ask him where he went.
Ou et il?
[Speaking French]
Where?
He says he thinks he's still
somewhere in the neighborhood.
Let's go, sarge.
[M'aitre d' speaking French]
Hey, he wants to know when he
can start getting some oil.
Tell him that he's got all the oil
he's going to get from Mulvehill.
Hargrove, I've been in this
man's army for 20 years,
and I've never been A.W.O.L.
in the whole stretch,
and I don't intend
to start now.
We got half an hour to get
back to that battery.
Let's not waste time.
If this winds up with
me getting put in jail,
oh, boy, you better
watch your step.
Hargrove: Hey, sarge.
Look.
[Mulvehill laughing drunkenly]
Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
Come on with us.
"Come on with us."
Well, now, it's my chums.
It's my pals, my buddies!
Sarge, what are
we going to do?
We can't go away
and leave him.
I got an idea. Can you run?
Like a rabbit. Try me.
Lose those 2 M.P.s, and I'll pick
you up at the Red Cross club.
Hey, stop that guy!
He stole my watch!
Stop, thief! Stop that man!
Hey, those are my pals!
Buddies! Hey, buddies!
Come on home to papa.
Got a nice little bed for you.
There you go.
Hey, that's my chair!
I got to get my chair!
Get my chair, please!
Did Sergeant Cramp
come back yet?
Or Hargrove or Mulvehill?
No, sir.
We'll roll out on schedule.
They'll be dealt with later.
Yes, sir.
How's he doing?
Sobering up any?
Well, some.
He's got to be able to walk
when we get back
to that battery.
Back to the battery! I'll walk.
I'll fly.
I'll do anything
you want, pal.
Yeah, I know it, Tom.
You're my best friend.
Yeah, I know that, Tom.
You saved my life!
Yeah. Forget it, Tom.
You don't believe me, do you?
Yeah, I do.
You can have my money.
You can have my wallet.
Listen, pal, you can
have anything I got!
He ain't sobering up yet.
Take it easy, Tom.
Take it easy.
I'm going to turn over a new
man and be a whole new leaf!
Strictly on the level!
I'm going to work hard!
Why, Sergeant Cramp,
what are you doing here?
Listen, no more swindles,
no more deals,
no more schemes, no more
angles, and no more schemes!
Man: All right, Sergeant
Hill, let's go!
[Engines starting]
[Bugle playing charge]
You don't look very well.
You all right? Huh?
I'm fine.
Hey, look there, sarge!
Hey, there's a tree here!
Hey, there's a tree!
[Men shouting]
[Whistles]
Pull over! Pull that
truck over there!
Come on! Let's get
this thing rolling!
[Men shouting]
Where you been?!
Ok, Lupot, drive on!
Where'd you find him?
[Engine racing]
Hargrove: Everybody
out, on the double!
Heave!
Heave, buddies!