[Hail to the chief plays]
[My country, 'tis of thee
plays]
* of thee I sing
* land where my fathers died
* land of the pilgrims' pride
* from ev'ry mountainside
* let freedom ring
hooray! Hooray! Hooray!
Fight, fight, fight!
Sis sis sis!
Boom boom boom ba!
Princeton!
Yay!
If coach only
has sense enough
to put in felton
at left half.
Is felton
good, father?
He's the greatest
rogan field runner
since Willy hessen
of Michigan.
Oh.
[Band stops playing]
Run!
Go, felton, felton!
Run! Run! Run! Run!
Ohh!
Stop him!
Stop him! Stop him!
[Band plays
boola boola]
Felton.
* fight, fight for Yale
* the sons of Eli
are out for glory... *
felton!
Yes, sir?
Never mind, felton.
You played
a great game.
Everyone's entitled
to a fumble
now and then.
Thank you, sir.
There you are,
young man.
Thank you, sir.
All right,
my dear.
Mister!
Are you Mr. Wilson?
Yes.
Are you the president
of Princeton?
Yes.
Why the heck don't you
get a football team?
I've been thinking
about that myself,
young man.
If you know anybody
who wants to swap
a good halfback
for a moth-eaten
Professor of economy,
here's your man.
* put on your
old gray bonnet *
* with the blue
ribbon on it *
* while I hitch your dobbin
to the shay *
* through the fields
of clover *
* we'll drive
up to Dover *
* on our golden
wedding day *
* put on your
old gray bonnet *
* with the blue
ribbon on it *
* while I hitch your dobbin
to the shay *
* to the shay
* through the fields
of clover *
* we'll drive up to Dover
* on our golden
* wedding
* day.
Mr. Wilson in?
Yes, sir.
Will you tell him,
please,
that senator
Edward Jones would
like to see him?
Will you come in,
please?
Thank you.
[Pianist playing
the old folks at home]
Will you come
into the study?
Is that him?
Yes.
What kind of
a Professor is he?
Shh.
I'll tell
Mr. Wilson
you're here.
Thank you.
Hmm. Not a bad layout
for a schoolteacher.
The college owns it.
They just let him
live here.
You know, I think
it'd be kind of nice
if the state did
something like this
for us boys.
"History of
the American people,
"constitutional
government...
Mere literature."
Say, did you know
he wrote these himself?
Good evening,
gentlemen.
Good evening, Professor.
I am senator Jones.
Big ed?
[Laughing]
That's right.
This is my nephew
Jim beeker.
How do you do, sir?
My old friend ed Sullivan.
Professor Wilson.
Mr. Sullivan.
Won't you
sit down?
Thank you.
Excuse me, senator.
I'll take your coat.
Yes. Thanks.
Well, senator,
what can I do
for you?
Mr. Wilson,
how would you like
to be governor
of new Jersey?
Governor?
There's a strong
progressive movement
running
in this country.
People are looking
for a change.
Yes, but why me?
I'm not a politician.
No, but your fight
to abolish these
social clubs
and run Princeton
on an equal footing
for everybody
has a lot
of people talking.
I was under the impression
I'd been defeated
in that fight.
[Senator]
Oh, people don't take
those schoolboy matters
as seriously as you do,
Professor.
All they can see
is that
you're against
special privilege.
That's enough
for them.
Besides, your books
on how to run a government
are known
all over the world.
Oh, you read my books,
Mr. Sullivan?
Well, I, uh...
Let's say we've heard them
spoken of very highly.
Of course, gentlemen,
this is all
very flattering,
but to be perfectly Frank
with you, senator,
you're barking up
the wrong tree.
I'm a schoolteacher,
which must make me
something of an idiot
in the eyes
of a lot of good people.
Ha ha.
It's even worse.
I'm a Southern
democrat
in a yankee
stronghold.
Ha ha ha!
We just won't tell
anybody about that,
Professor.
Besides,
you must realize
this isn't
the sort of decision
I can make overnight.
Take your time,
Professor.
There's no hurry.
Convention's still
a long way off.
We won't take
any more of your time.
We know how busy
you are.
Here you are,
sir.
Thank you, Sullivan.
I'm going to say it.
I'd be afraid...
Mr. Wilson,
I have a feeling
that this casual meeting
will be the beginning
of a delightful association
for all of us.
Indeed, it is
the beginning
of a new era
in the state of new Jersey,
one upon which
we will all look back
with everlasting pride.
Good night, sir.
Good night,
senator.
And you will
think it over,
Professor?
I'll do better
than that, senator.
I'll have my wife
think it over.
Good night.
Good night, Mr. Wilson.
Was that really
big ed himself?
In person.
What did he want?
Oh, nothing
of any importance.
He... he merely wants me
to run for governor.
Governor?
Jerusalem!
You governor?
And why not?
What did you tell him?
Oh, that
I'd think it over
and, of course,
ask your permission.
Woodrow, you didn't.
Have I ever done
anything foolish
without asking
your permission?
Woodrow,
I know
you haven't any
personal ambition
just to hold office,
but you must admit
the opportunity
is rather unusual.
So it is.
You must get awfully
tired sometimes
of a mere
talking profession.
You're quite right,
my dear.
I will admit
there are moments
when the academic life
has its drawbacks,
but the idea
of a man my age
suddenly giving up
a nice, comfortable
way of life
and launching out
on a sea of ifs and buts
sounds like
the account of a fool.
But you've always
been interested
in politics.
Only as an observer
on the sidelines, my dear.
How about the time
you were a student
at the university
of Virginia
and wrote your father
that you'd decided
to be a senator?
And had cards printed...
"senator Thomas
woodrow Wilson."
A youthful
indiscretion.
I was young then,
young lady.
Very young.
About your mental age.
Besides, you know
perfectly well
I have certain
responsibilities
to Princeton.
You know your work
at Princeton is done.
You believe
in the principles
of Democratic equality,
the abolition
of any special
privileged class.
If these things
are worthwhile,
don't they apply
to all the people,
not just to Princeton?
You mean
you really think
I should seriously
consider it?
Oh, I do, woodrow.
I most assuredly do.
We all do,
father.
We all do.
You'd make
a beautiful governor.
Of course.
I declare,
I never met
such a collection
of ambitious women
in my life.
If I do
go into this...
And mind you,
I'm not saying I will...
I warn you and you
and you and you,
you'll have to kiss
all the babies.
That's one thing
I draw the line on.
[Laughter]
How about a locomotive?
You ready?
Hip! Hip!
Hooray! Hooray! Hooray!
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Sis sis sis!
Boom boom boom ba!
Princeton!
Yay!
Do you really think
they'll like him?
Mother, stop worrying.
They'll love him.
But he's never had
any experience
with people
like these before.
Neither have they
had any experience
with a man
like father before.
[Band stops playing]
And now,
ladies and gentlemen,
I'm going to let you in
on a little secret.
Many of my friends
are very much worried
about this campaign.
They tell me
I'm conducting it
in the worst
possible way
because, it appears,
I'm asking you people
to think.
[Crowd laughs]
On the other hand,
my opponents
are even more worried
because they expected
my speeches
to be mere academic
lectures on government
filled with
glittering generalities
that have nothing to do
with the situation
in new Jersey.
Apparently, they've
deluded themselves
into thinking
that I have
no political experience.
Good heavens.
No political experience?
I wonder
if these gentlemen
have ever attended
a faculty meeting
or seen the wives of
the trustees in action.
[Laughing]
That's all very amusing,
Mr. Wilson.
But why don't
you tell us
what kind of deal
you've made with the bosses?
Sit down!
I've made no deal
with anyone.
I suppose
you're going to deny
that there's even
such a thing
as a boss system
in new Jersey!
No. The existence
of the boss system
is notorious.
Then what are you
going to do about it?
Bend all my energies
to breaking it up!
[Cheering and applause]
When you say bosses,
do you mean
big ed Jones,
Jim beeker,
and ed Sullivan?
Who's that?
Joe tumulty,
one of them Irish lawyers
in the legislature.
Claims to be a democrat,
but he ain't
voted right once.
Come on!
Shut up!
Keep quiet, you hear?
[Woman]
Aah!
Quiet!
Everybody, quiet!
All right.
Go ahead.
Thank you, judge.
Of course
I mean big ed.
I feel about him
exactly as I feel
about every other boss,
whether he's a democrat
or a republican.
Yay!
Senator Jones understands
exactly how I feel.
In fact,
just so there would be no
misunderstanding about it,
he has given me his word
that in no circumstances
would he permit his name
to be presented
to the legislature
as a candidate
for re-election
to the United States senate,
an office for which
I consider him
utterly unfitted.
Yay!
What do you say,
big ed?
Heh heh heh heh.
I say the candidate
speaks for the party.
Yay!
[Band plays]
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Sis sis sis!
Boom boom boom ba!
Princeton!
Yay!
Mother!
Suppose somebody
sees you.
Let them!
Great, great. He'll win.
Yeah? Suppose
he means it?
Nonsense. They had him
in a corner.
What else could he say?
Just the same,
I don't like
the cut of that
fellow's jaw.
I tell you,
he's something new
in politics...
A scholar
and a gentleman
with ideals
and principles.
You can't beat that
when it comes
to electioneering.
Wasn't he wonderful?
The most idiotic
campaign speech
in the whole history
of politics.
I don't understand.
He means what he says.
Gentlemen!
Your attention,
please!
9:18 P.M.
Returns from
22 counties.
Wilson leading
by 40,000.
Majority!
Yay!
Good work, boys.
I'm proud of you.
* for he's
a jolly good fellow *
* which nobody can deny
nice smile now.
Get closer.
Mr. Wilson,
will you step
on the other side?
All of you,
look this way, please.
Where do you expect
to live, Mrs. Wilson?
We haven't made
our plans yet.
What will
you girls wear to
the inauguration?
We haven't decided.
What jewelry
will you wear?
None.
That's right.
The Wilson girls
don't believe
in jewelry.
We do. We just
haven't any.
If you'll step
over here...
What's your
first move, governor?
Have you made
any appointments?
Gentlemen, if you'll
wait a minute,
I'll be glad
to write out
a statement.
Just give us
some personal stuff.
Quite an upset,
Professor.
Any election's an upset,
young man,
if you're unfortunate
enough to be elected.
Lean closer to Mrs. Wilson,
governor.
I have to
put up with this
in my home?
Every day until
the end of your life.
You might as well
get used to it.
Smile.
Hold still!
The legislature
has had sufficient time
to digest the contents
of this bill, gentlemen.
Therefore, I must insist
that it be brought
to a vote immediately
regardless
of the opposition.
You're right.
We have the votes.
Let's go ahead
and let them howl.
Excuse me.
Yes, tumulty?
Senator Jones has arrived...
With Mr. beeker.
Thank you, tumulty.
Send them in,
please.
Will you gentlemen
excuse me?
Surely, governor.
Good morning,
governor.
senator.
Mr. beeker.
Sit down,
gentlemen.
Thank you.
Thank you, sir.
Well, you sent
for me, governor?
Yes.
Did you authorize
this statement
to the effect
that you have decided
to be a candidate
for the
United States senate?
At the insistence of many
of my friends, governor.
But you publicly stated
that in no circumstances
would you be
a candidate.
A man says
a lot of things
in the heat
of a campaign.
To go back on your word
so soon
after the election
would be outrageous
and indecent.
Oh, come, come, come,
governor.
People don't take
these matters
as seriously as you do.
They've probably
forgotten all about it.
I beg to differ
with you, senator.
I haven't forgotten,
nor have the people.
Surely if the party feels
Uncle Ed's their man...
Those who elected me
have already
decided he's not.
Hold on, governor.
Let's get one thing clear.
I nominated you.
I elected you.
Then you should've
exercised better judgment
in your choice.
Would you be satisfied
to announce
your opposition publicly
and let it go at that?
If you insist
on going through
with such
bald-faced deceit,
I shall have
no recourse
but to fight you
with every means
in my power.
Well, looks to me
as if the Professor
will give us
the bum's rush
and run this
whole show himself.
I consider your
language coarse
and your manners
offensive.
However, you seem
to have grasped
the idea perfectly.
I don't want to quarrel
with you, governor.
I know how seriously you
take all these reform issues
and how hard
you've worked.
What you need
is a nice, long rest.
Good day, senator.
Be sensible, governor.
We know you're aiming
for the white house.
What chance would you have
for the nomination
if your state
organization's
against you?
Get out.
You're no gentleman.
You're no judge.
I still don't
understand it.
He seemed like such
a nice fellow, too.
I told you
I didn't like
the cut of that
fellow's jaw.
What gets me
is the way
the newspapers
around the country
are picking this up,
making him a hero.
Be just like
that darn convention
to nominate him
for president now,
whether we
like it or not.
The Republicans
split wide-open
between
Teddy Roosevelt
and taft,
they can
elect him, too.
Well, if you ask me,
that would
be a whole lot better
than having him
hanging around new Jersey.
Yes, I'll tell
governor Wilson you called
the moment he returns.
[Knock on door]
Come in.
Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
Yes, thank you, sir.
Hello, boys.
Hello, tumulty.
What's that?
More applications
for the Wilson
for president clubs.
There's Rochester
and Atlanta
and oyster bay.
What?
That's Teddy Roosevelt's
hometown.
Well, uh, I come from
there too, Mr. tumulty.
[Ring]
Governor Wilson's office.
This is his secretary.
Oh, yes, congressman.
How do you do? Sorry.
The governor's out of town
at the moment
on an important mission.
I wish I could
tell you where he is,
but it's something
very close to his heart,
something I'm sure
you'd approve of.
[Orchestra plays
moonlight bay]
* we were sailing along
* on moonlight bay
* we could hear
the voices singing *
* they seemed to say
* you have
stolen her heart *
* now, don't go away
* as we sang those
old sweet songs *
* on moonlight bay
Henry.
Mr. Holmes.
A very important
mission, hmm?
Official business, no doubt.
Yes, it's odd,
but it seems something
important like this
comes up at least
once a week.
Yes. Every time the palace
changes its program.
You've taken to politics
like a Billy goat
to tin cans,
raising Cain
all over the place.
No wonder they want
to kick you upstairs
into the white house.
Don't take these
Wilson for president
clubs too seriously.
Remember, a lot of
people still regard me
as a pretty
dangerous fellow.
So you are,
but it's too late.
I've already paid $5.00 to
help bamboozle the public.
Just throwing it
away.
Maybe, but Teddy Roosevelt's
a Harvard man.
Bill taft's from Yale.
I'd give $5.00
of my money any day
to let a Princeton boy
have a crack at them
in the same game.
Bully! Bully!
I'm de-lighted.
[Band plays dixie]
[Gavel pounds]
Quiet!
Order!
The delegates...
Will resume...
Their seats.
And the sergeant at arms
will clear the aisle.
The chair has the honor...
To present to you...
That great democrat...
That fearless leader...
Who has never...
Sold the truth
to serve the hour.
The great
commoner himself...
Nebraska's favorite son...
William Jennings Bryan.
[Band plays
onward Christian soldiers]
Mcadoo!
Mcadoo.
What is it,
Daniels?
Wilson's at the governor's
mansion in sea girt.
Get him on the telephone.
I don't like the way this
Bryan thing is going.
Neither do I, but mccombs,
his campaign manager,
isn't worried.
It's too early.
Besides, every
newspaper in New York
has a direct wire
to the governor's
place.
He probably
already knows
what's going on.
[Typewriter]
That William
Jennings Bryan.
He's trying to steal
the nomination
for himself.
What's he done now,
tumulty?
He's got his band
playing hymns.
It is my great honor...
And distinguished privilege
to place in nomination
for the exalted office
of president
of the United States...
That great statesman
from Alabama...
Oscar w. Underwood.
Yay! Yay!
* I came from Alabama
* with a banjo on my knee
* I'm going to Louisiana
* my true love
for to see... *
* I thought I saw susannah
comin' down the hill *
* oh, susannah
* oh, don't you
cry for me *
* I came from Alabama
* with a banjo
on my knee *
* I came from Alabama.
I give you that great
statesman from Missouri...
A great servant...
Of the common man...
The honorable champ Clark.
Yay! Yay!
New Jersey
appreciates the honor
of placing...
Before this convention...
As a candidate...
For the presidency...
Of the United States...
The seer and philosopher...
Of Princeton...
The Princeton
schoolmaster...
Woodrow Wilson.
[Band plays school days]
Governor!
Here's the result
of the first ballot...
Clark... 440,
Wilson... 324,
Underwood... 117.
Huh! Sounds like
our golf score.
Thank you, tumulty.
Those reporters have been
after me all morning.
Won't you say something?
Yes.
You may tell them
that governor Wilson
received the news
of the first ballot
in a riot of silence.
Fore!
Good-o.
The chair recognizes
the leader
of the New York
delegation...
The honorable
Charles Murphy
of tammany hall.
New York...
Wishes at this time...
To change its ballot
and cast its 90 votes
for the next president
of the United States...
Champ Clark of Missouri.
Yay! Yay!
Hello, Daniels.
Hello. Hello.
If they don't stop
that fool song soon,
I'll get a real hound
out there and
kick him around.
You can't do that,
josephus.
They'd lynch you,
and we need every
Wilson vote we can get.
Yes?
What?
Oh.
Just a minute.
William mccombs,
governor.
He wants to speak
to you personally.
Hello, mccombs. I...
The jig's up, governor.
It looks like
a stampede for Clark.
This last parade's
gone on over an hour.
You've got to send me a wire
withdrawing your name.
I can't hold your
delegates any longer.
What's the score now?
Clark... 556,
Wilson... 350 1/2.
It's hopeless.
No candidate yet has
ever received a majority
without being nominated.
We should have made
some kind of deal
with that New York
delegation.
What's Bryan going to do?
He's been hoping
he could play you and Clark
off against each other,
then get the nomination
himself,
but it's too late.
We're licked.
It'll be Clark
on the next ballot.
Just a minute.
Mccombs sounds
pretty excited.
Thinks I should
send a telegram
releasing my delegates.
I knew it all along...
That tammany hall.
Now I know why
the Democratic party
picked a jackass
for a mascot.
It's all right,
woodrow.
At least we'll be able to
get away for a holiday.
Thank you, my dear.
Hello, mccombs...
Hello?
Let me have that phone!
Governor.
Hello, governor.
William g. Mcadoo
speaking.
I just heard
what mccombs told you,
but he's dead wrong.
You can't withdraw now.
Clark will never
get a 2/3 vote.
Wait. If you
don't believe me,
here's josephus Daniels.
He'll tell you
the same thing.
Hello. He's right, governor.
Mcadoo is right.
You're stronger than ever.
Your delegates will stick
if it takes all summer.
Just a minute.
That's odd.
My convention manager
tells me we're defeated.
Mcadoo and Daniels
say I can't lose.
What do you think?
Stay in,
by all means.
Certainly, governor.
What do you think,
Eleanor?
That you've nothing
to lose by staying in.
That's what I think.
We'll stay in.
Hello, mcadoo.
Thank my friends.
Tell them
we'll see it through.
The delegates will
resume their seats...
And the sergeant at arms,
clear the aisles!
Mr. chairman...
For what purpose
does the gentleman
from Nebraska arise?
To explain my vote!
Speaking for myself
and for any
of the delegation
who may decide
to join me,
I shall withhold my vote
from champ Clark.
No! Boo!
Boo! No!
So long as New York's vote
is recorded for him.
I...
Cast it for...
Nebraska's second choice...
Woodrow Wilson!
Yay!
[Band plays school days]
The next president
of the United States!
The next president!
* you wrote on my slate
"I love you, Joe" *
* when we were
a couple of kids *
* school days, school days
* dear old
golden rule days *
* you were my queen
in calico *
* I was your barefoot
bashful beau *
* you wrote on my slate
"I love you, Joe" *
* when we were
a couple of kids *
* school days, school days
* dear old
golden rule days... *
* you were my queen
in calico *
* I was your barefoot
bashful beau *
* you wrote on my slate
* "I love you, Joe"
* when we were
a couple of kids *
* school days, school days
* dear old
golden rule days *
we're in.
We're in!
Governor!
We're in! We're in!
We're in, governor!
You've been nominated
on the 46th ballot!
Oh, papa! Oh, daddy!
Congratulations,
governor.
Ha ha ha!
[Playing hail to the chief]
They're playing
hail to the chief.
Congratulations,
governor.
Is this your work?
I've had them
waiting two days.
What if I hadn't
been nominated?
I made arrangements
with them
to fold up their tents
like the arabs
and silently
steal away.
When I speak to you
of business and government,
of capital and labor,
of privilege
and equal opportunities,
my only purpose...
Is to rehabilitate
democracy
and to prove to the world
that the Democratic system
can successfully meet
the economic, industrial,
and social problems
that confront us.
Because I believe,
as Lincoln did,
that democracy...
With all its faults
and failures,
if properly guided
and interpreted,
holds the future
of the world.
My great dream is...
That as the years go on,
the world will turn
to America more and more
for those moral inspirations
which lie at the basis
of all freedom.
And that America...
Will come into the full
light of the day
when all the world
shall know
she puts human rights
above all other rights
and that her flag...
Is not only the flag
of America,
but the flag of humanity.
Yay! Yay!
I thought you'd
like to hear these.
"I cordially congratulate
you on your election
"and extend to you
my best wishes
"for a successful
administration.
William Howard taft."
"The American people,
by a great plurality,
"have conferred upon you
the highest honor
"in their gift.
"I congratulate you
thereon.
Theodore Roosevelt."
President of
the United States.
* through every heart
* and every voice
it's the students,
woodrow.
They've come
to serenade you.
* in every care withdraw
* let all with
one accord rejoice *
* in praise of old Nassau
* in praise of
old Nassau, my boys *
* hurrah, hurrah, hurrah
* her sons will give
* while they shall live
* three cheers
* for old
* Nassau
how about a locomotive
for Wilson?
You ready?
Hip, hip...
Hooray! Ray! Ray!
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Sis sis sis!
Boom boom boom ba!
Wilson!
[Cheering]
Congratulations!
I have no feeling
of triumph tonight.
Only a sense
of solemn responsibility.
I know...
Only too well...
The very great task
ahead of me.
And I look
pleadingly to you,
the young men
of America...
To stand behind me...
To support me.
That's all I can say...
Except...
Good night...
And God bless you.
* through every heart
* and every voice
* in every care withdraw
* let all with
one accord rejoice *
* in praise of old Nassau
* in praise of
old Nassau, my boys *
* hurrah, hurrah, hurrah
* her sons will give
* while they shall live
* three cheers
* for old
* Nassau.
Mr. president,
I'm hoover,
the chief Usher.
How do you do?
This is Mrs. Wilson.
How do you do,
Mr. hoover?
My daughters...
Miss jessie,
miss Margaret,
miss Ellen.
Perhaps you
and Mrs. Wilson
might like
to inspect your
living quarters
before lunch.
Thank you. I would.
This way,
please.
We'll take
the elevator up.
It's this way, sir.
Big, isn't it?
[Laughter]
Who's this?
That's
Mrs. John Tyler.
Oh, yes.
Look, father, here's
a picture of president taft.
Yes. Very good, too.
Oh, mother,
it's lovely!
I thought it was
going to be
overpowering,
and it's not at all.
It's just a home.
Does it amaze you
that our predecessors
had good taste?
Come see my room.
I'm sure it's where
Abigail Adams
hung out
her laundry.
That was the east room.
I looked it up.
Look!
Mistress Dolly Madison.
Don't anyone dare tell me
she didn't sleep here.
Can't you almost
feel them?
Heavens, you don't think
the house is haunted?
A lot of them
were extremely reluctant
to leave here
during their lifetime.
"Of January 1st, 1863,
"whereby four million slaves
were given their freedom
"and slavery
forever prohibited
in the United States."
Imagine,
and in my room.
Miss Nell,
guess what.
They've got three
automobiles here
and an electric,
and
the chauffeur said
we could use them
whenever we wanted.
Not bad for a family
that never even owned
a horse and buggy.
Oh, I wish we would have
an inaugural ball tonight.
It'd be such fun.
Father hates
a lot of fuss.
I know, but tonight,
I wish he was
a republican.
Shh!
President Lincoln's
bed.
He must've been
an awfully big man.
He was.
My dears, your father and I have
a gift for each of you
in commemoration
of this day.
Oh, mother!
How sweet!
Oh, mother.
Oh, it's exquisite.
It's the most
beautiful ring
I've ever seen.
Oh, a bracelet watch.
Mother, it's just
what I've always wanted.
Ohh...
Oh, look.
Mother.
Diamond pendant.
Oh, it's too beautiful.
But why did you...
I mean, how did you...
I borrowed money
from the bank
to pay my campaign
expenses,
and this
was left over.
Oh, woodrow,
it's too nice.
Perhaps, but I've
got a better job now...
Shorter hours,
more pay.
[Knock on door]
Come in.
Excuse me,
Mr. president,
but luncheon
is served.
Oh, thank you...
Simms, sir.
Thank you, Simms.
Howdy, miss Ellen.
You don't remember
me, do you?
Why, no, I...
My family lived
right behind yours
in Rome, Georgia.
My mother did
your mother's washing
for close on
to 30 years, I reckon.
How nice to have
someone from down home.
Yes, indeed,
miss Ellen,
it's going to be
mighty nice for me, too,
having ladies
and gentlemen around
that speak my language.
[Giggling]
I don't know
what I came for.
He didn't want
my advice.
Once he's made up
his mind,
nothing in heaven
will change it.
Bye, Joe.
Goodbye, senator.
At least he listened
to our side of it.
He was polite, but
somehow he makes me feel
like an unruly
schoolboy.
I catch myself
being afraid
he's going to rap me
over the knuckles.
Good morning,
gentlemen.
Senator lodge.
Morning, senator.
Didn't expect
to find you here.
Oh, yes. We Republicans
still do business
with the government...
Occasionally.
[Laughter]
Good morning,
senator lodge.
Tumulty.
Will you announce me
to the president?
Yes, of course,
senator.
Won't you
sit down, sir?
Thank you.
Awfully glad to see
you back, colonel.
Glad to be back,
thank you.
Colonel house.
Hello, tumulty.
Welcome home.
Come in.
The governor's
waiting to see you.
Senator.
Colonel house.
Go right in, sir.
Oh, thank you.
I'm sorry, senator.
Colonel house
just got back
from Europe.
The president's
anxious to see him.
You don't mind
waiting, do you?
Not at all.
House.
Governor.
Welcome home.
Thank you.
My, I'm glad
you're back.
Have you seen
the morning paper,
senator?
Yes.
* by the light
* by the light,
by the light *
* of the silvery moon
* the silver moon
* I want to spoon
* to my honey
I'll croon love's tune *
* honeymoon
* honeymoon,
honeymoon *
* while we're
singing in June *
just a minute.
Ellen, come
and help us out.
Oh, I can't.
I promised Helen
we'd finish
this list tonight.
Helen, I told you
what you were
getting into
when you took
this job as
Ellen's secretary.
Yes, cousin woodrow,
but you didn't say
what a white house
wedding's like.
It's all
jessie's fault.
If she hadn't decided
to get married...
Well, I like that.
What about your own wedding?
That's different.
Mac lives here
in Washington,
but you have to
marry someone
that lives
at the other end
of nowhere.
Well, Helen,
if these people
are going
to be blue,
I'd better
join them.
Goodness only knows
why they need my voice.
They know I never
could sing a note.
* by the light
* by the light,
by the light *
* of the silvery moon
* the silver moon
* I want to spoon
* to my honey
I'll croon love's tune *
* honeymoon
* honeymoon, honeymoon
* keep a-shining in June
* your silv'ry beams
will bring love's dreams *
* we'll be
cuddling soon *
* someday soon
mother!
* by the silvery moon
what's the matter?
* the silvery...
Are you ill?
I don't know.
I'm all right.
Come and sit down.
I'm just
a little faint.
Get some water.
Mother,
what is it?
I'm just a little dizzy,
that's all.
You've been
doing too much.
It's all
this entertaining.
You can't
keep it up.
Well, that's my job.
The president
has to entertain.
Not if it's going
to affect your health.
You'd better lie down.
Nonsense.
I feel perfectly
all right.
I'll just sit here
while you go on
with your song.
Not tonight.
Please.
I insist.
It'll sound
much better
without me.
Please. Go on.
[Piano plays]
* by the light
* of the silvery moon
* I long to spoon
* to my honey
I'll croon love's tune *
* honeymoon
* keep a-shining in June
* your silv'ry beams
will bring love's dreams *
* we'll be
cuddlin' soon *
* by the silvery moon
oh, Washington's
so hot in the summer.
I wish you girls
didn't feel
you had
to sit here with me.
Oh, mother,
we like it here.
Your poor father.
He's hardly been out
of that chair
for a week.
Where's father
now?
I made him lie down.
He looked so tired.
Besides, I wanted to speak
to you girls alone.
Of course, I'm sure
I'm going to be all right,
but if anything
should happen to me,
I want you girls
to promise me one thing.
Mother, don't even
say such things.
Your father
is a great man.
Promise me
you won't let him be
a lonely great man.
Mother.
Please.
More than anyone
I've ever known,
he needs sympathy
and loyalty,
companionship.
He needs
a woman's love
and attention
and understanding...
Someone he can
turn to and trust.
A wife is as much
a part of him
as his very mind
or heart.
I know... Because
I've been his wife.
Promise?
Of course
we promise.
But, mother,
it's ridiculous of you
to talk like this.
You'll be up and about
in no time.
You know it.
I'm sorry, Mr. president.
Excuse me,
governor.
Senator Carter glass
telephoned.
He wants to know,
can he see you
this afternoon
about that
federal reserve
bank matter?
He'll have to
excuse me.
I can think
of nothing while
Ellen's like this.
All right, governor.
He'll understand.
Father, you
promised mother
you'd play golf
this afternoon.
I know.
But I can't.
I can't bear the thought
of her suffering.
Father, she
wouldn't want you
to feel like this.
She's always been
the most radiant
person I've known.
For 30 years,
I've never
had a thought
in which
she didn't enter.
I can't...
I couldn't go on
without her.
I'll never forget
the first time
I ever saw her.
I was practicing
law in Atlanta.
I had to go to Rome,
Georgia, on business.
Her father was
the presbyterian minister.
I went to his church.
I'm afraid I couldn't
have told you
what the sermon
was about.
She saw you, too.
She always
said she was glad
she had on
her prettiest hat.
I don't think
any two people
were ever so happy.
When I was teaching
at bryn mawr
and at Princeton
when you girls
were babies...
It's this place
that's killing her.
She's been happy
here, father,
and so proud of you.
No. She's done too much.
I didn't realize it.
She wouldn't
have been happy
doing any less.
Well, Grayson?
She's sleeping now.
So far as I can tell,
there's been no great change
since yesterday,
just a gradual
weakening.
There's no hope?
Medical science
is not the last word,
Mr. president.
We can only wait
and see.
[Singing hymn]
[Explosions and gunfire]
[Piano plays]
If there were
only something
we could do,
some way
we could help.
It's difficult.
Extra! Extra!
Lusitania torpedoed
off coast of Ireland.
Over 100 American
lives lost.
Extra! Extra!
Dirty huns!
Ought to be wiped out,
the lot of them.
German sub sinks
lusitania.
Over 1,500 die.
Lusitania torpedoed
by German sub.
It's cold-blooded
murder.
Wholesale slaughter.
[Ding ding]
We'll be at war
with Germany in a week.
It's not our war.
Why should we
get involved?
If Americans
don't want to get hurt,
let them stay home.
I bet Teddy Roosevelt
would know what to do.
Over 100 American citizens
murdered on the high seas,
and that man
in the white house
too proud to fight.
But we have
no choice.
These huns must be
taught a lesson.
We can't watch the world
slipping into anarchy.
We've got
to declare war.
No, no, no!
Our people were warned
to stay off that ship.
How do we know
that it wasn't
carrying munitions?
Nonsense. That's nothing
but German propaganda.
Congress is all set
to act.
It'll back us up.
What about
the people?
Don't worry.
They're good and mad.
Read your newspapers.
Mr. president,
do you know people
are saying openly
that this administration
lacks courage?
They may call me
a coward or anything else,
but I won't be rushed
into this war.
You'll overlook
the most
dastardly crime
of which any
civilized nation has
ever been guilty?
No. I shall warn
the German government
in the strongest terms
that in future
it will be held
to strict accountability.
Another note?
Yes. Another note.
These Germans
pay no attention
to notes.
The only thing
they understand
is force.
I'm not
so much concerned
with what
the Germans do
as I am with our own
responsibility,
which is to keep out
of this war if possible,
so that
at the right time,
we can offer ourselves
as the only nation in the world
with sufficient strength
and influence
to bring about
a decent and lasting peace.
The vast majority
of Americans
expect me
to keep my head
and save them
from this awful mess.
I don't want them
to say
when the casualty lists
come in,
"why did Wilson
have to move so fast?
Why didn't he make
one more effort?"
Have you considered
what this policy
of uncertainty
is doing
to our economy?
Cotton down
to 6 cents,
our goods rotting
on the docks,
afraid to put to sea,
our farmers
and railroads
facing ruin.
I haven't thought
to consider this war
in terms
of dollars and cents.
Nor have the fathers
and mothers
of this country.
No, gentlemen.
It would be the easiest
thing in the world
for me as president
to ask for
a declaration of war.
The man on horseback
is always a hero.
But I wouldn't have
to do the fighting.
Some poor farmer's boy
or the son of some
great family
would have to do
the fighting
and the dying.
When I ask them
to do that,
I want to be very sure
that what they're
dying for is worthwhile.
Good morning.
[Typing]
Oh, thank you,
my dear.
You really should
be in bed, father.
It's very late.
Yes.
I'll go along
directly.
It would be nice
if we could
run away from it all.
You know,
once upon a time,
your mother and I
did just that.
I'd been working
very hard
on the first draft
of mere literature.
Without telling anyone
at the university,
we slipped out
for a holiday
in the country...
And it was just about
the most perfect
two weeks
I've ever known.
We tramped
in the hills,
slept in the sun,
and walked alone at night
under the stars.
Your mother was
a very wonderful woman,
Margaret.
She had
that rare quality
of always being close
to you when you wanted her,
when you needed her.
[Typing]
Extra! Extra!
Read all about it!
Germany agrees
to quit submarine warfare!
Read all about it!
Germany agrees
to quit submarine warfare!
Extra! Extra! Germany agrees
How long will Germany
live up to it?
As long as it suits
her convenience.
I suppose
we'll have to go along
with Wilson's
preparedness program.
Not his preparedness
program... ours.
We started it.
We pushed it when
he would have nothing
to do with it.
Now he's claiming
it for himself
because he thinks
it's good politics.
Never mind that.
It has to be done.
Not only will we
have to go along,
but we'll have
to lead the way,
put aside
any thought of party
and do what we can
to save this country.
Well, Mr. president,
Teddy Roosevelt
can't say
that you haven't
adopted at least
one of his policies.
Thank you, Joe.
What's that?
The strenuous life.
Oh, it's the president.
And looking the worse
for wear, I'm afraid.
Hello, cousin woodrow.
Come in. Come in.
Cousin woodrow,
I want you to know
my friend Mrs. galt.
I'm delighted,
Mrs. galt.
Mr. president.
You know Dr. Grayson.
Very well,
for a long time.
Have you forgotten?
I introduced you
to Edith.
Oh, yes.
Yes, of course.
We've been for a walk
in the rain.
Edith came here for tea
with Margaret and me.
Tea? Sounds delicious.
May we come, too?
Shall we let them?
As patriotic citizens,
I don't see how we can
very well say no.
You're from the South,
Mrs. galt?
Yes. I have the honor
to be born in the same
state as you... Virginia.
She's a descendant
of pocahontas.
Well, that is Virginia.
We shan't keep you
waiting long.
Oh, don't hurry. Give us
time to freshen up a bit.
Excuse me.
Charming woman.
Very.
Do you play golf,
Mrs. galt?
Oh, yes, Mr. president.
And this will give you
an idea how well.
The last time, I was
200 yards from the green.
I asked my caddie
if he thought
I could make it
with my mashie,
and he replied,
"yes, ma'am,
you can make it,
allowing you hits it
often enough."
We're going down
the potomac next weekend
on the yacht.
Would you care
to join us?
Oh, I'd love to,
but I promised to visit
the Hastings in Virginia.
That's a shame. I'd
hoped you could come.
Cousin woodrow will be
terribly disappointed.
The president
asked for me?
"You're the only
woman I know
"who can wear
an orchid.
Generally, it's the orchid
that wears the woman."
I think this is
my favorite spot
at the white house.
It is lovely.
I asked Margaret
and the others
to leave us alone
for a while
that I might have
an opportunity to say
something to you.
Yes?
I need you, Edith.
Will you be my wife?
Mr. president.
I know this comes
as a shock to you.
Perhaps I've been
too impulsive,
but if I'm to continue
to make opportunities
to see you,
I must speak.
But how can you be sure?
You've only known me
a few months.
Time isn't always measured
in weeks or months.
In the past year,
I've lived a lifetime
of loneliness and heartache.
You've changed all that,
given me hope that happiness
is still possible.
Have you spoken
to your daughters?
Yes.
They tell me they already
love and admire you
and that nothing would
make them happier.
But I've never
thought of you
except
as the president.
And, besides,
I've had no training
that would befit me
for the responsibilities
of such a life.
Would you rather
I had not spoken?
Oh, no.
There isn't any woman
who wouldn't be touched
to be told that
she could be of help
to a man in your position
in times like these...
But I'd have to have time
to know you and to see you
and to be with you.
Do you want to see me?
Yes, I do.
Then I'll wait...
And in all fairness
to you,
there's something
you should understand.
There's a spotlight
on this house.
Everyone who comes here
is observed and discussed.
Everything I say
is quoted...
Sometimes even correctly.
No matter how I try,
I can't protect you
from gossip.
I'm not afraid
of gossip.
It would be even worse
if I came to your house.
But surely you have
the right to choose
your own friends.
In this job, I'm not sure
I have any rights at all.
This gossip
you speak of,
would it hurt you,
what you're doing?
It's you I'm thinking of.
Well, then, I suggest
we go on exactly as
we have in the past...
But as to being
your wife,
if I have to say
yes or no now,
then I'm afraid
the answer must be no.
Won't you at least
give me the hope
that you might
change your mind...
That maybe when you
know me better...
I'd be less
than a woman,
Mr. president,
if I didn't reserve
that right.
[Take me out
to the ballgame plays]
Mr. president.
Yay!
That's her.
Yes. An election
coming up, too.
There's no use beating
about the bush, Edith.
You know about
the whispers,
the gossip
that's going on.
He heard about it today.
Naturally, he would be
the last to hear.
I've never seen him
so angry in my life.
His lips went white.
His hands shook.
I think if he could
get his hands on those
scandalmongers,
he'd forget he's president.
Oh, no,
he mustn't do that.
What's worse,
some of his own friends
are mixed up in it.
They're afraid
that a second marriage
will prevent
his re-election.
What do you think?
That his own
political fortunes
don't make
any difference to him.
It's you.
Nothing must
stand in the way
of his re-election.
I'd never
forgive myself
if I were the cause
of his defeat.
Edith, he's the president
of the United States,
but first of all,
he's a man,
and he loves you.
To do what he has to do,
he... he needs you.
Thank you, Dr. Grayson.
It was very kind
of you to tell me
all this.
I'll write him
my decision.
Thanks, Edith.
[Typing]
Hello, Joe,
what's the news?
Not a thing.
How's with you?
Oh, all right.
Mm-hmm.
No notes
to Germany?
Nope.
No sinkings?
No.
No messages
to congress
about us being
too proud to fight?
Sorry. Just
the usual routine.
Jumping Jupiter!
What? What is it?
What's the matter?
The story. The list.
The announcement has just
been made of the engagement
of Mrs. Norman galt
of Washington, D.C.
And woodrow Wilson, president
of the United States.
[Hail to the chief plays]
[Applause]
His imperious majesty
appears to be
in good spirits tonight.
Time will remedy that.
Do you really think
we have a chance to
defeat him in November?
Not defeat, senator,
obliterate.
You can't enjoy the convention
without a hot dog!
Buy it hot! Buy it now!
* we take out hats off to you,
Mr. Wilson *
* our hats are off to you
* you're the man
of the hour *
* you stood like a tower
* and no one could do
for the red, white, and blue *
* you're the right kind
of man *
* in the right kind
of place *
* like Washington
and Lincoln *
* you set the pace
* we know at home
and abroad *
* your pen is greater
than the sword *
* we take our
hats off to you *
* I didn't raise my boy
to be a soldier *
* I brought him up
to be my pride and joy *
* who dares
to place a musket *
* on his shoulder
* to shoot some other
mother's darling boy? *
* he's got those big
blue eyes like you, daddy *
* reminds me of you
all the time *
* when he grows
to be a man *
* I'll give him up
to Uncle Sam *
* just like I did with you
* daddy mine
we must rid ourselves
of this college sissy
and once again
substitute action
for elocution!
He kept us
out of war!
Woodrow Wilson
is the most incompetent...
Vacillating...
Insincere...
And cowardly leader
this nation has ever endured!
He kept us
out of war!
Wilson and his dynasty,
his heirs and assigns,
anybody who with bended knee
has served his purposes,
must be driven
from all control,
from all influence
upon the government
of the United States!
While we watch
a world in flames,
we must not forget
what is happening
here at home
under our very noses.
Private initiative
is being stifled,
business is being
put into a straitjacket,
all under this false claim
that this is democracy.
When, as a matter of fact,
it is nothing
but the blundering
of a starry-eyed idealist.
Re-elect woodrow Wilson!
He kept us out of war!
[Playing dixie]
"A weak and imbecile man,"
"the weakest I ever knew
in a high place."
"If I wanted
to paint a despot,
"a man perfectly regardless
"of every constitutional
right of the people,
I would paint
his hideous form."
That's outrageous!
"When he goes out
of office next march,
"the whole country
except thieves, cowards,
"public plunderers,
officeholders,
and traitors
will rejoice."
Woodrow,
that's the last straw.
You've got to do
something about it.
They've no right
to say such things
about you
even to win an election.
They weren't talking
about me.
That's what they said
about Abraham Lincoln
when he was running
for re-election in 1864.
[Laughter]
I understand
Teddy Roosevelt says
you're the most
incompetent man
to ever occupy the office,
worse even than
Thomas Jefferson.
[Laughter]
Frankly, I've been
much more concerned
with what our own side's
been saying.
All this prating
about "he kept us
out of war,"
as if I can see
what is or is not to be.
Any little German
lieutenant can put us
into the war tomorrow
by some new outrage
on the sea tonight.
Would you mind very much
if you should be defeated?
I don't suppose
any man wants to see
his policies repudiated.
I heard that betting
in wall street
closed at 10-8
against you, father.
I hope you didn't
take any of it.
Governor.
Yes, tumulty?
Governor,
the New York times
has just conceded
the election to Mr. Hughes.
Why, it's only 9:00.
How can they be sure?
They're still at
the polls in the west.
Yes...
It does seem a bit early.
Coffee, tumulty?
Thank you, governor.
However, the times
is generally right.
In the meanwhile,
I see no reason to despair.
The government's
not going to collapse
just because I've
been left at home.
Hughes is an honest man
and a very capable one.
As a matter of fact,
his own party referred to him
as Wilson-with-whiskers.
With whiskers.
Of course, my wife may feel
the country's judgment's
a bit warped.
I can only think
that you'll be free
from all this worry.
Waiting for election returns
is like a hen
sitting on a nest,
except that the hen
uses better judgment
than a politician...
She never cackles
until after she's
laid the egg.
[Laughter]
May we talk
to Mr. Hughes?
The president
has gone to bed.
He has left word that he
was not to be disturbed.
Well, when the president
wakes up, give him this
and tell him you're not
so sure he's president
after all.
Thank you.
Well, Mr. president,
we can do this
all over again.
Another four years.
Yes, another four years.
Congratulations,
Mr. president,
and the public's to be
congratulated, too...
For their good judgment.
Thank you.
I never gave up
for one minute.
I did. I'd have
sold out pretty cheaply
election night.
You just got by
in the electoral college,
but you polled three million
more popular votes
than in 1912,
and that's not to be
laughed at.
Why on earth
any man should want
a job like this
for another four years
is beyond me.
[Laughter]
But I confess,
I did want it.
Mr. president.
Baker.
Mr. secretary.
Has the president retired?
Yes, sir.
Wake him.
Tell him Mr. Lansing,
secretary of state,
his excellency
count Von bernstorff,
the German ambassador,
are here,
and that we must
see him at once.
Will you wait
in the east room, sir?
Thank you.
Mr. president.
Mr. Lansing.
Your excellency.
What is it, gentlemen?
I'm sorry to disturb you
at such an hour,
but count Von bernstorff
has just handed me
another note
from his government.
Beginning tomorrow,
Germany will resume
its policy of unrestricted
submarine warfare.
We have
no other choice.
And will sink on sight
and without warning
any neutral vessel
entering European waters.
With certain exceptions,
of course.
One American ship
will be permitted to leave
a designated port
each week,
provided it is properly
lighted and marked.
We deeply regret
the necessity
of this decision.
We sincerely hope
it will not interfere
with your noble efforts
to bring about peace
with our enemies.
Sit down, sir.
We also have received
indisputable proof
within the last hour
that the German government
has been using
our own state department
cables to foment trouble
between this country
and Mexico.
What?
With California,
new Mexico,
and parts of Texas
as bait.
I deny
any such thing.
The proof is overwhelming,
Mr. president.
There can be no doubt.
Count Von bernstorff...
For more
than two years,
this government
has exercised
every restraint
in its efforts
to remain neutral
in this conflict,
but you and your
military masters
apparently
are determined to
deny us that right.
But I assure you...
Every way we turn,
we run into a blank wall
of German cruelty
and stupidity.
Every time we think
we've escaped,
you blindly
and deliberately
block us
with some
new outrage.
Mr. president...
Sit down.
Won't you Germans
ever be civilized?
Won't you ever learn
to keep your word...
Or to regard other peoples
as men, women, and children,
not as inferiors
to be treated
as you please,
in the name of
your discredited
German culture
and race superiority?
I wish to withdraw...
We are not
exactly fools!
We know about the spies
you've sent among us
in an effort to
corrupt our opinions
through lies and rumors
and of your
ceaseless attempts
to sabotage
our industry and commerce.
Unfortunately,
some of our own people
have fallen in
with your plans.
Day after day,
I see them
going up and down
this country,
crying out
in their innocence
that this is just
another European war
that can't touch America,
building up
a false illusion
of safety and security,
appealing to our ancient
traditions of isolation...
While you smile
behind their backs
and go right ahead
with your evil plans
of world conquest
and exploitation.
I bid you
good night.
You will wait!
Is your kaiser
so contemptuous
of American
military prowess?
Does he think
we're so weak
and disunited
just because we prefer
peace to war
that we will not fight
in any circumstances?
Or is he
so drunk with power
that he can't understand
that such action
will unite this nation
as never before
in its history
and that he has
made it clear at last
that this is, in truth,
a fight for freedom
and decency
against the most evil
and autocratic power
this world
has ever seen?
Mr. Lansing.
Mr. president.
You will hand his excellency
count Von bernstorff
his passports immediately.
Good night, sir.
[Chorus]
* yankee doodle
went to town *
* riding on a pony
* he stuck a feather
in his cap *
* and called it
macaroni *
* yankee doodle
went to town *
* yankee doodle dandy...
* glory, glory
hallelujah *
* his truth
is marching on *
* glory, glory
hallelujah *
* his truth
is marching on *
with a profound sense
of the solemn...
And even tragic character
of the step
I am taking...
And of the grave
responsibilities
which it involves,
I advise that the congress
declare the recent course
of the imperial
German government
to be in fact
nothing less than war
against the government
and people
of the United States
and that it formally accept
the status of belligerency
which has thus
been thrust upon it.
Whoo!
In so doing,
let us make clear
to all the world
what our motives
and objectives are.
We have no selfish ends
to serve.
We desire no conquest,
no dominion,
no material compensation
for the sacrifices
we shall freely make.
We are but one
of the champions
of the rights
of mankind.
We shall be satisfied
when those rights
have been made as secure
as the faith and freedom
of nations can make them.
It is a fearful thing
to lead this great,
peaceful people into war.
But the right is more
precious than peace,
and we shall fight
for the things
which we have always carried
nearest our hearts...
For democracy,
for the right of those
who submit to authority
to have a voice
in their own government,
for the rights and liberties
of small nations,
for a universal
dominion of right
by such a concert
of free peoples
as shall bring peace
and safety to all nations
and make the world itself,
at last, free.
Through such a task,
we can dedicate our lives
and our fortunes...
Everything we are...
And everything
that we have...
With the pride of those
who know that
the day has come
when America is privileged
to spend her blood
and her might
for the principles
that gave her birth
and happiness...
And the peace
which she has treasured.
God helping her,
she can do no other.
[Fanfare]
* keep the home
fires burning *
* while your hearts
are yearning *
* though your lads
are far away *
* they dream of home
* there's a silver lining
* through the dark cloud
shining *
* turn the dark cloud
inside-out *
* till the boys...
[Instrumental
medley continues]
* pack up your troubles
in your old kit bag *
* and smile,
smile, smile *
* while you've a Lucifer
to light your fag *
* smile, boys,
that's the style *
* what's the use
of worrying? *
* it never was worthwhile
* so
* pack up your troubles
in your old kit bag *
* and smile, smile, smile
[instrumental continues]
* goodbye, Broadway
* hello, France
* over there
* send the word,
send the word *
* over there
* that the yanks
are coming *
* the yanks are coming
* the drums rum-tumming
everywhere *
* so prepare
* say a prayer
* send the word,
send the word to beware *
* we'll be over,
we're coming over *
* and we won't come back
* till it's over
over there *
commissions, commissions,
commissions.
Good heavens. How many
second lieutenants are there?
[Knock on door]
Excuse me, father.
There's someone here
who wants to say
goodbye to you.
Come in. Come in.
Felton.
Hello, Mr. president.
Mrs. Wilson.
Congratulations,
lieutenant.
Thank you.
I don't want
to take your time,
Mr. president.
I just wanted
to say so long
before I shoved off.
You're
leaving soon?
I'm afraid that's
a military secret,
sir.
Yes.
Yes. Quite right, too.
Well, take care
of yourself, felton.
Yes, sir, I will.
And... Don't be
too impatient with us.
No, sir.
I'll try
not to be.
Well, son...
Goodbye.
Goodbye, sir.
Goodbye, lieutenant,
and... Good luck to you.
Thank you.
Thank you
for coming to see me.
Thank you very much.
Very much.
Goodbye, sir.
[Door closes]
It's her,
I tell you.
Oh.
It couldn't be.
I'm sure of it.
Ah, don't kid me.
Why don't you
go and ask her?
Find out
for yourself.
O.K., I will.
Thank you, ma'am.
Lady...
Coffee.
They've been trying
to tell me
that you're
the president's wife.
Really?
They can't
string me.
You don't think
I look the part?
I say you don't.
I agree, but when you
come back from France,
if you come
to the white house,
I'll do my best
to look as I should,
or better still,
speak to the president
himself about it.
There he is.
Slippery,
aren't they?
I'll get you
another.
You are the... the...
Even the president
has to do kp
occasionally.
Hiya,
Mr. president.
How are you,
young man?
I never thought
I'd be shaking hands
with you.
I can't wait
to write home about this.
Only they'll never
believe it.
Hello, Mr. president.
Where are you from?
Milwaukee, sir.
German?
My father was German.
I'm just an American.
And you?
My name's vespucci,
but I'm just
an American, too.
I guess there's
something funny
about all of us.
Mike here's
a bohunk.
Me? I'm just Irish.
Tex here claims he's
just from plain Texas.
Nobody told me
any different yet.
Well, this is all
very interesting, boys.
I want you
to remember it.
Here we are,
men of all races, with
different backgrounds
and ancestries,
working together
for a common purpose.
That's what's made
America what it is,
and that's what
the whole world
must learn to do
someday.
I know there are people
who say
this is just another war
to protect
the great fortunes
or for some other
economic reason,
but don't believe them.
If anybody
tries to tell you
that universal peace
is just an idle dream...
Tell him he's a liar.
Say your president said
that you're
fighting this war
so there won't have
to be any more wars,
and that when we
get through with it,
we're going to sit down
with other people
who feel as we do
and work out some plan
which will make it
unnecessary
for boys like you
and your sons
to have to go out
and shoot one another.
Maybe we'll call it
a... a league,
maybe something else,
but whatever it is,
that's what you're going
to France for,
and with the help
of God,
that's what
you're going to get.
Yes, sir.
Company, fall in!
All right.
Get back on the train!
What are you trying to do,
hold up the war?
Take it easy. We've
just been talking
to the president.
Says you!
All right, you...
See?
What did I
tell you?
Carry on, sergeant.
Yes, sir.
All right, men.
Get back on the train.
So long, soldiers.
Goodbye.
Goodbye,
Mr. president.
Don't you worry
about this war.
We'll take care of it
for you.
Thank you,
soldier.
Bye, sir.
For our part,
we see very clearly
that unless justice
is done to others,
it will not
be done to us.
The program of the
world's peace, therefore,
is our program,
and that program...
The only possible program...
Is based, as we see it,
on these 14 points.
Open covenants
openly arrived at.
Freedom of the seas.
Self-determination.
Free trade.
An impartial adjustment
of all colonial claims.
League of nations.
Did you bring this month's
casualty figures, Baker?
Yes, sir.
This is not one of my
most pleasant tasks,
Mr. president.
I know.
112,000 of our boys
dead so far.
That's only
an approximation,
Mr. president.
All the figures
are not in.
183,612 wounded.
The fighting's
been heavy,
almost ceaseless,
in the past week.
Woodrow...
It's bad...
But try to think
what these boys
are dying for.
112,000 dead.
[Knock on door]
Come in.
Governor...
Yes, tumulty?
Governor,
here's a message
that just came
from the Swiss military.
"The German government
"requests the president
of the United States
to take steps for
the restoration of peace."
Woodrow.
Mr. president.
"The basis to be
the program laid down
by the president
in his 14 points."
Thank God.
[When Johnny comes
marching home again plays]
[Train whistle blows]
[Playing classical music]
So you're going
to Paris to write
the peace?
And to buy my wife
a new bonnet.
Is that
a smart thing to do?
To buy me
a new bonnet?
I don't know
how smart it is,
but I consider it
most essential.
Mr. president,
I was wondering...
It's only a thought...
No, thank you...
If your influence
wouldn't be greater
if you stayed here
and served as
a sounding board...
Thank you very much...
And if mistakes
were made,
you could
repudiate them.
I hope no mistakes
will be made.
Lettuce
sandwich.
I'll get you another.
Don't bother.
Who'll
go with you?
Lansing and house.
I meant someone
from the senate.
Remember, they'll
have to approve
any treaty.
Whom have you
in mind?
Senator lodge is chairman
of the foreign relations
committee...
And a very practical man.
Have one of these,
Professor.
Thank you, Edith.
Ah, one with meat in it.
That's the trouble.
Too many treaties
have been written
by practical men.
If I take anyone
from the other party,
it'll be someone
like Henry white.
He's served in
our Paris embassy,
he knows Europe...
May I point out,
Mr. president,
that this is the heyday of
nationalism among nations.
In Paris you'll meet
the ablest politicians
in the world...
Practical men...
Many of whom
will be concerned
not so much with peace
as with national boundaries,
indemnities,
new balances of power.
Many of our own people are
going to share their views.
It might be wise to have
a practical man along
to cope with such people.
Mac, I agree with you
as to the situation.
I disagree with you
as to the solution.
In a world full
of practical men,
more practical men
would hinder
rather than help.
Our great hope
lies not in me
or in any other
individual,
but in
the power of right.
People
all over the world...
The common people...
Have set their hearts
and minds against
selfish nationalism.
They've paid
with their blood
and treasure.
I must go...
Not alone, as president
of the United States,
but as the spokesman
for these peoples of
whatever nationality.
Our own people
expect me to go.
To do anything less
would be unthinkable.
Well, I suppose
if your mind
is made up,
there's
nothing we can
do about it.
Still, if it
were up to me,
I'd take lodge,
put him right
out in front,
make him help
carry the load.
I'd keep my eye
on the little...
Oh, excuse me,
Edith...
On that little
goatee of his.
Thank you,
senator.
[Chuckling]
They tell me
in Italy
they're even
burning candles
in front of
his picture.
Kaiser woodrow.
Or is it
Saint woodrow now?
He's having
a field day,
but wait till
that old tiger
clemenceau
gets through
with him.
He'll be lucky
to keep his shirt.
It's America's
shirt I'm
worried about.
This'll put
a firecracker under him.
Maybe now he'll realize
there's such a thing
as the senate
and the constitution.
All this business about
remaking the map of Europe,
giving away this,
giving away that,
talking about America
not having any material
interest in this war...
What about the money
we lent them?
I don't think
we need to worry,
gentlemen.
We now have the names
of 37 members of the
United States senate
affixed
to this document.
Senator lodge, you haven't
expressed yourself.
Are you still with us?
My views
on this subject
are well known,
gentlemen.
Nothing that has
happened in Europe
or elsewhere
has caused me
to change them.
You'll introduce
the resolution
yourself?
I should consider it
an honor, sir.
Thank you,
senator.
Mr. president, France
can accept no treaty
that does not include
the saone basin
and all territory
west of the rhine!
But France has
no right to that land.
It belongs
to the people
who live on it.
They can
go where they please.
My government
demands the land
and its resources!
So do our people!
That's impossible.
When the Germans
surrendered,
it was on condition
that we protect
their rights.
That's written
in the armistice.
You yourself
signed it.
The Germans forfeited
their rights in this war.
They are murderers!
Monsieur clemenceau...
I will never be a party
to such an agreement.
It violates
everything we said
we were fighting for.
To take part of Germany
and cede it to France
is nothing
short of theft.
You live in America,
Mr. Wilson,
with an ocean
on either side.
You can afford to be lenient
with your enemies.
If you won't abide
by the armistice,
I might as well
go home.
If such a position
to our just claims
is continued,
I might as well
resign!
You're breaking
your word!
You are pro-German!
Gentlemen, gentlemen...
Let us consider
these matters calmly.
We all believe in the
self-determination clause
of the 14 points.
It is not right
to do wrong,
even to make peace.
Besides, the covenant of
the league of nations
is sufficient guarantee
of France's safety.
Under its provisions,
there is not the slightest
shadow of a doubt
but that
the United States
and Great Britain
will instantly rise
to the defense of France
should Germany ever
again become hostile.
That's all very well,
Mr. president,
when you speak of
what America will not do,
but are you
prepared to guarantee
what America will do?
I am.
Are you aware that
a block of 37 senators
have signed a resolution
stating that the league
as you propose it
is not acceptable
to the American people?
I am perfectly aware
of that document,
monsieur.
However, I should
like to remind you
that these men
do not compose
the entire senate,
nor do they reflect
the opinion of
the American people,
regardless of party.
As a matter of fact,
some of the leading
members of
the republican party,
including
former president
William Howard taft
and
Charles Evans Hughes,
have expressed approval
of the league...
And I will also
give you my word for
this, too, monsieur...
If these 37 men,
who represent no opinion
but their own,
dare try to block,
to thwart, to betray
the first honest attempt
of the world to achieve
a permanent peace,
the American people
will rise in their anger
and smash them
as they would
an alien enemy
landing on their shores.
Mr. president,
I bow to you.
Shall we resume
our discussion?
Now.
I've asked you here
in the hope
that we might come
to some understanding
about the league of nations.
I don't mean
to be facetious,
Mr. president,
but whose understanding...
Yours or ours?
One we can
mutually uphold.
In view of our
stated positions,
I wonder if that isn't
expecting a great deal.
Senator, I'm sure
we all have one
purpose in common...
To serve the best
interests of
the American people.
Apparently, we have
very different ideas
as to what constitutes
their best interests.
In that case,
shouldn't we
at least try
to reconcile
our differences?
The treaty would have
been approved weeks ago
if it weren't attached
to your league.
Not my league,
senator.
As a matter of fact,
I'd be more inclined
to call it your league,
for I seem to recall
that in 1916,
you yourself
advanced the thought
that the nations
would have to
unite for peace
and that
an international
police force
would enforce it.
The fact that a man
has changed his mind
does not bear
on the real merits
of any question,
and even if he happens
to be a convert,
some good work has
been done by converts
from the days of Saint Paul
to the present.
Besides, even in
my wildest dreams,
I never contemplated
placing American arms
and economic sanctions
every time some
ambitious ruler
coveted the lands and
resources of another.
We should constantly
be involved in broils
and quarrels
that are none
of our business.
Yet let me remind you
that in every discussion
of peace during the war,
we promised...
I beg your pardon.
You promised.
This government
promised...
That...
Some way
would be found
to avoid
such catastrophes
as we have just
been through.
Other nations
have accepted
the principles
of the league.
It is inconceivable
that we who advanced it
should go back
on our word.
If that is your
unalterable view,
I'm afraid we shall
not get very far.
Just a moment,
senator.
Perhaps we've
made mistakes...
All of us...
But regardless
of the treaty
or what you individually
may think of it...
Or of those
who wrote it,
let me remind you
that the league
is irrevocably
attached to it...
And the league...
Is the only hope...
The world has
to avoid wars
in the future.
Unless you can advance
a better idea...
I beg of you
to consider that
and to help
save that hope.
I, too, have my ideals,
Mr. president,
and one of them is peace.
But a realistic peace
that we can surely maintain,
one which will not
siphon off the power
and prestige and resources
of the United States.
If you had wanted
my views on this matter,
you could very easily
have obtained them
before you went to Paris,
before you made concessions
to the statesmen of Europe,
before you burned all
your Bridges behind you.
This is not
the age of miracles,
Mr. president...
Nor of miracle workers.
America has
but two choices,
gentlemen...
It must accept
a league of nations
or live with a gun
in its hand.
It's for the people
to decide.
Thank you
for coming.
Good day.
Good day, sir.
Mr. president.
Tumulty, you may start
making arrangements
at once for our trip.
Governor, your health...
I'll have
no more haggling
with that man.
I'll stump
the country
and let
the people know
exactly
what's at stake.
But, governor, you know
what Dr. Grayson said.
You can't afford
to take the risk.
I promised
the young men
of this country
that we were
fighting this war
to end wars.
It's up to me
to see that we meant
what we said.
Woodrow...
For my sake,
why don't you do
as they ask?
Accept the senate
reservations
and get this awful
quarrel settled.
Don't you desert me,
too, Edith.
I... I couldn't stand that.
My dear, I'm only
thinking of you,
of your health.
I have no right
to accept any changes,
and even if I did,
they'd come back tomorrow
with 46 more.
It's just a scheme to kill
the league entirely.
Forgive me.
I should have known.
Whatever mistakes we've
made about disarmament,
boundaries, reparations,
war colonies,
the league will be in a position
to arbitrate and rectify.
[Train whistle blows]
The league is the vital
and compelling part
of the treaty.
But there can be
no united action,
no league of nations
in the true sense,
without America's
participation.
The isolation
of the United States
is at an end!
Mr. president,
you'll have to
give up this trip
and return to
Washington at once.
That's impossible.
It's not only
possible,
it's imperative.
But I can't stop now.
People are beginning
to understand.
If I desert them now,
they'll be confused
and misled.
40 speeches
in 17 states
in 22 days.
No one could
stand it.
I'm scheduled
to speak here in pueblo.
People are waiting for me.
There are several
points that still have
to be explained.
But you could
speak here
another time.
I wouldn't
ask you to stop
if I thought there was
the slightest chance
you'd be able
to go on,
but you'll
kill yourself.
I must go on.
I'm all right.
[Crowd cheering]
People of pueblo...
My fellow citizens.
I feel like asking
the secretary of war
to get the boys who went
across the water to fight
together on some field
where I could
go and see them...
And I would stand up
before them and say,
"boys, I told you before
you went across the seas
"that this was a war
against wars,
and I did my best
to fulfill that promise..."
[Train whistle blows]
"But I am obliged
to come to you
"with mortification
and shame
and say I have been unable
to fulfill that promise."
"You are betrayed."
"You fought for something
that you did not get...
"And the glory
of the armies
"and the navies
of the United States
"is gone like a dream
in the night,
"and there ensues upon it,
"in the suitable darkness
of the night...
"The nightmare of dread,
which lay upon the nations
before this war came."
"And there will come
some time,
"in the vengeful
Providence of God,
"another struggle...
"In which not
a few hundred thousand
"fine young men from America
will have to die...
"But as many millions
as are necessary
"to accomplish
the final freedom
of the peoples
of the world."
I will...
Thank you for coming.
[Wilson]
I am so tired.
Mr. tumulty,
will you please
tell
the newspapermen
we're returning
to Washington
immediately?
Yes.
No.
[Train whistle blows]
His whole left side
is paralyzed,
but his mind
is perfectly clear
and untouched.
Will he recover?
He'll improve with time,
but for the present,
he needs rest and quiet,
release from every
disturbing problem.
But how is
that possible?
Everything that comes
to the president
is a problem.
Wouldn't it be better
if he'd resign
and let Mr. Marshall
succeed him?
No, no, no, Edith.
He's staked his life
on getting
the league ratified.
If he resigns now,
this incentive
to recovery
will be gone.
Besides, his resignation
would have a very bad
effect on the country.
For that matter,
on the whole world.
Our thought is that
you have everything
of an official
nature come to you.
You can weigh the importance
of each matter,
and, in consultation
with the heads of
the various departments,
decide what he must see and
what can be left to others.
In this way, Edith, you can
be of great service to him.
No.
I can't do it.
It's too great
a responsibility.
Even though his life
may depend upon it?
In that case,
there's only one answer.
I'll try.
Here.
Yes, ma'am.
Well, Mrs. president...
Woodrow!
What's on tap for today?
Don't you dare
to call me that.
You know very well
I never even
made one decision
without
your knowledge
and consent.
I know it, and you know it,
but do our enemies
know it?
I'm not concerned
with what
our enemies know.
You should listen
to them, my dear.
You'd learn
a great deal.
Such as what,
cousin woodrow?
Well, during the war,
for instance,
I never would have
dreamed that Edith
was a German spy
if I hadn't
kept my ears open.
Nor, I suppose,
did you bargain
with wall street
to bring on the war
in the first place.
For that matter,
I never would
have suspected
that I was insane
if the senate
hadn't sent
the honorable
Albert fall to
look me over.
Oh, that man.
I don't see how you
take it so calmly.
I'd scratch
their eyes out.
Woodrow handled
senator fall
beautifully.
As he was leaving,
that gentleman said,
"Mr. president,
the senate is
praying for you."
And woodrow, without
batting an eye,
asked, "which way,
senator?"
I'm afraid
I'm much more concerned
with what my grandchildren
and their generation
think of me
than I am with what
the present lords of
the earth have to say.
No memoranda today?
They've passed
the volstead act
over your veto.
Well, now we'll
have prohibition,
I trust.
Well, tumulty.
Governor,
the democrats
have nominated
James Cox of Ohio.
Cox on one side,
Harding on the other.
Cox for the league,
Harding against it.
Well,
the lines are drawn.
It's clearly up to
the people to decide.
[Piano playing]
Governor?
Yes, tumulty?
[Piano stops]
Governor, it appears
that senator Harding
has won an overwhelming
victory.
Mm-hmm.
Senator Harding
has issued a statement
to the American people
declaring that
the league of nations
is now a closed incident.
Thank you, tumulty.
Yes, sir.
Well, Edith?
Yes, woodrow?
If these good people
will excuse us.
Good night.
Is that everything?
That's all, dear.
Thank you, Mrs. Wilson,
Mr. president.
Thank you.
I'm sorry I can't stay for
the inauguration ceremonies,
but Mr. Harding
and Mr. coolidge
have been kind enough
to excuse me.
I told them it was bad enough
for the senate to throw me down
without my stumbling
up the steps
on my own account.
Mr. president, I...
Eight years.
Goodbye,
Marshall.
Mr. president.
Goodbye,
Mr. Marshall.
Mrs. Wilson.
Good luck, sir.
It was a pleasure
serving under you.
Thank you.
Mr. president, I...
Daniels, we've taken
a house in "s" street.
I hope to see you
there often.
Yes, indeed.
Thank you.
God bless you.
Goodbye,
Mr. president.
Goodbye, Alexander.
Goodbye.
It's a great
honor to have been
in your cabinet.
Houston, thank you for
your very able support.
Goodbye,
Mr. president.
Goodbye, Wilson.
Mr. president,
now that the United States
has rejected the league,
can we ever
hope for peace
or real understanding
between nations?
Yes.
I'm not one of those
who has
the slightest anxiety
about the eventual
triumph of the things
I've stood for.
The fight's just begun.
You and I may never
live to see it finished,
but that doesn't matter.
The ideals of the league
are not dead
just because
a few obstructive men
now in the saddle
say they are.
The dream
of a world united
against the awful wastes
of war
is too deeply embedded
in the hearts
of men everywhere.
Goodbye,
Mr. president.
Goodbye, Mr. Payne.
And I'll even make this
concession to Providence
it may come about
in a better way
than we proposed.
Goodbye,
Mr. president.
Just woodrow Wilson now.
You still have
one minute to go,
Mr. president.
Goodbye, sir.
Goodbye, Baker.
Goodbye, Edith.
We hope to see you often.
Mr. president?
Senator lodge.
Mr. president,
a joint committee of
the house and senate
is here to notify you
that congress
has completed
the business before it
and now stands ready
to adjourn,
unless you have some
further message.
The president has nothing
further to communicate.
[Clock chimes]
Good day, sir.
* long may our land
be bright *
* with freedom's
holy light *
* protect us
* by thy might
* great God
* our
* king