MAN [ON RADIO]: Miss Harding and
Mr. Kieran both have their hands up.
- Full title.
TESS AND KIERAN: "Nights in..."
ELLIS: Hello, Sam.
PHIL: Hi, kid.
Hi, Sammy. You missed most
of the Information Please!
TESS: I guess I have lived around a lot.
With my father, that is.
Tess Harding. Treat for the intellect.
Rest your intellect and give me
a Scotch and water.
The Chronicle ought to form
a cheering section for her.
Because we write on the same paper?
- Did you ever meet her?
SAM: Uh-uh.
She don't talk if you haven't
signed a nonaggression pact.
[PHIL CHUCKLING]
MAN:
Prescott lists four seaports...
... which have had great
strategic importance in this war:
Dakar, Narvik, Derna and Singapore.
Were any of these ever under
the American flag?
TESS:
Derna, in 1803.
- The war with Barbary pirates.
MAN: Right. Most of us...
Can you figure a dame that knew
what was going on in Libya in 1803?
Fadiman says she's number-two dame,
next to Mrs. Roosevelt.
So they're giving them numbers now,
like public enemies.
MAN: Mrs. Prescott does not receive
$ 25 and a set of the Britannica.
The next question comes from
Mr. C.A. Copeland of Glenport, Florida.
What is the most frequently run
distance in American sports?
- Hundred yards.
- No, no. It's a mile, counting horses.
MAN: I'll try our guest expert first.
Miss Harding.
Ninety feet, sister.
TESS: I really don 't know anything
about American sports.
MAN:
Mr. Kieran?
KIERAN: Ninety feet.
MAN: Care to explain?
KIERAN: The distance between
home plate and first base.
MAN: Yes, or between any of the bases
in the game of baseball.
Thousands of men and boys
run it every day.
TESS: Seems like a waste of energy.
- What?
KIERAN: There's a lot of energy
wasted in the world these days.
That's telling her, John.
TESS: ... isn 't anything more wasteful
than war.
However, all the more reason
people ought to give it their full attention.
MAN: What would you suggest,
Miss Harding?
Abolish baseball for the duration
of the emergency?
TESS:
I think that's a very good idea.
- Have I said something wrong?
KIERAN: Just a minute...
- Things they let them get away with.
- Maybe she was kidding.
She knew what she was saying.
Know what that does?
ABBOTT: Take it easy, Sam.
Don't blow your top.
We're concerned with a threat to
what we call our American way of life.
Baseball and what it represents
is part of that way of life.
What's the sense of abolishing
what you're trying to protect?
That's a beautiful thought, Sammy.
- You ought to write a poem about it.
- I'll do better than that.
"...and she might remember what the
Duke of Wellington said about sports.
GERALD: The duke was the baby
who whipped Napoleon at Waterloo...
...and made an ex-champ out of him.
After it was all over, the duke let out
that the battle was really won...
...on the playing fields of Eton."
What?
Well, that's about all, Miss Harding,
except at the end he calls you:
"The Calamity Jane
of the fast international set."
Huh?
Yes, Miss Harding.
I've got my pad right here.
Ready. Yes.
PHIL: "Mr. Craig cites Wellington's
observation concerning Waterloo.
I assume his purpose is to demonstrate
that at one time or another...
...he was subjected to
a grammar-school course in history.
[LAUGHING]
Naturally, Mr. Craig doesn't realize
times have changed since Waterloo."
- What are you gonna do?
- What do you think?
Swing with both hands.
We men have only ourselves to blame.
Women should be kept illiterate
and clean, like canaries.
[PHONE RINGING]
Hello? Yes.
Oh, yes, Mr. Clayton.
Yes, sir. Yes, I'll be right up.
- She's waiting for you.
- Thanks.
CLAYTON:
Come in, Sam. Come in.
- Haven't you met Miss Harding?
- Yes, in a belligerent sort of way.
- He hit me first. Hello.
- Hello.
Now, fellows, I realize as much
as anybody that controversy...
...is a very stimulating thing. Very.
I encourage it when someone
on the paper gets into a good fight...
...over an important issue. Always.
But not intramural fights. Never.
It's my job to think in terms
of the paper as a whole.
I'm dead sure that it just doesn't
do any one of us any good...
...for one department to rap another.
To come directly to the point, I'd like
to see you drop this business right away.
How about it, Sam?
You ready to kiss and make up?
I'll kiss. I don't know about making up.
- How about you, Tess? Wiling to quit?
- Sure.
- Okay?
- Fine, thank you.
I'm always delighted to quit
when I'm losing.
Glad to be able to reconcile
you two. Very glad.
Cooperation is the essence
of efficient organization.
The essence.
Sorry.
Isn't the sports department
downstairs?
Uh...
Why, yes, yes. I guess it is, but l...
Then aren't you going
in the wrong direction?
Well, maybe I am. L...
Are you always much too busy?
What for?
- I was wondering about this afternoon.
- Sorry.
SAM:
Tomorrow afternoon, maybe?
What's on your mind?
I'd like to take you to a baseball game.
Okay.
[CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
Are all these people unemployed?
No, they're all attending
their grandmother's funeral.
- He's got Tess Harding with him.
ABBOTT: Where's your manners?
No women in the press box.
A rule as old as baseball.
- No women.
- So what?
She's a newspaperman,
and she's pretty. Hi, Sam.
PHIL: I haven't seen it happen in 20 years.
Worst scandal since the Black Sox.
SAM: I want you to meet Miss...
PHIL: Harding, I know. How do you do?
TESS: Hello.
SAM: Chronicle.
You mean our paper sends
two men to cover one game?
No. I cover the game,
he kicks it around in his column.
- We've only got one man at Vichy.
- Vichy? Are they still in the league?
Who's pitching?
[CROWD CLAPPING AND CHEERING]
The hat.
Thank you.
Hey, buddy, tell her it ain't raining.
Fella wanted me to tell you
that it ain't raining.
- Who's playing today?
- The Athletics and the Yanks.
The Athletics will bat first, you see,
and after they've made three outs...
...then the Yanks come to bat.
I see. Then they have to make
the same number of outs.
That's right. That's right.
And each team has nine innings.
But wouldn't it always come out even
if they made the same number of outs?
No, no, no. You see...
You see, an out... An out is...
Well, it's just an out.
- Come on! Play ball!
MAN: Play ball!
Okay.
Now, there's the first batter.
Now, he's gonna try to hit the ball
as far as he can...
...and get around as many bases
as he can.
If he could get around all the bases
and back to home plate...
...that would mean a run for his team.
The pitcher's gonna try
to make him miss it.
- Which one is the pitcher?
- The one pitch...
The fellow in the middle.
One out.
No. No, one strike. That's a strike.
Two more of those before he's out.
- Why?
- Well, because it's... Are you kidding?
[CROWD CHEERING]
How could that be a strike?
He didn't even swing at it.
Well, he doesn't have to swing at it.
You see, it's a strike as long
as he puts it over the plate...
...between the batter's
shoulders and his knees.
I see. If the batter were really smart,
he'd stoop down and fool the pitcher.
I'll bet you this next one's
a double upcurve in the side pocket.
PHIL: Yeah. Maybe he'll hit
into a quadruple play.
Do you think he will?
Wouldn't surprise me a bit.
Safe? He's out a mile!
How much are they paying you,
you one-eyed chiseler?
What do you do in the winter,
burn down hospitals? Grave robber!
- Ain't there no laws in this country?
TESS: Shut up, will you?
What do you mean, shut up?
You got a lot of nerve.
That guy was out a mile. By six miles!
I'll beef all I like!
You'd think I didn't buy a ticket.
Well, I did. You wanna see it? Here!
$ 1.65 of good American dough.
CROWD:
Sit down. Sit down.
- Took his foot off the base,
and he's claiming he didn't.
Got as much right here as anybody. More
than most, because I'm here all the time.
Ask the usher, the ticket office.
First in line at the opening game.
- If the shortstop had kept his...
I mean, if the short...
Maybe I could draw you
a diagram of it here a little.
- Come on, Joe!
- Two on, two out.
- Have a peanut.
Thanks. A homer would win
the game, wouldn't it?
- Nothing less.
- What's the matter?
- You're wonderful.
- Of course. Didn't you know?
I had you mixed up.
What is your name again?
- Just call me Tessie.
- Hi, Tessie. Call me Sammy.
[CROWD CHEERING]
FAT FAN: Come on, Joe!
- Come on!
Run!
- Well, we win.
- No.
- What's the matter?
- He's out. That's the end of the inning.
- The score is tied?
- Like a wet shoelace.
What a shame. We almost won.
Let's get out of here.
- Wait, the game isn't over.
- You said nine innings.
After nine innings, if the score
is tied, they play until somebody wins.
- Oh. What time is it?
- 4:30.
4:30! Boy, I better beat it.
I'm late already.
I've got a rehearsal at NBC.
You stay and finish. I'll be fine.
- So long.
- So long, pal.
- Wait, I'll go with you.
TESS: Oh, please...
Looks like the ball game isn't
the only thing that's tied up around here.
[CROWD CHEERING]
Sounds like a hit. Two-bagger.
NBC, and hurry, please. 9:00.
[PIANO PLAYING]
SAM: I'm sorry, I must... I thought...
Looking for Miss Harding.
- Well, come right in.
- Is this Miss Harding's?
Yes. May I have your hat?
- Oh, I don't... I don't...
TESS: Sam.
Sam, I'm so glad you came.
- Thanks.
- Who won?
- Who won what?
- The game.
- The Yanks in the 10th.
- How nice.
Everyone in Philadelphia
must be so happy.
You dropped your flowers.
Thanks.
- Flowers.
- Sam, you're sweet.
Shall we pass them around again now?
Come on. A few people always
come in after my broadcast.
Why do you broadcast?
Just wait and tell them here.
[SPEAKING IN FRENCH]
[SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
Are they kidding
with that "da-da-da"?
You don't speak Russian,
they speak nothing else.
Now, let's see.
I wonder who you'd get along with.
There's Madame Laruga
sitting over there.
- Probably don't speak Slovenian either.
- No, just a little broken English.
Hello. Sam, will you excuse me?
He doesn't know anyone here.
[MAN 1 SPEAKING IN SWEDISH]
[SPEAKING IN ARABIC]
MAN 2: How did Harry come out with that
Customs deal he was working on?
MAN 3: He didn't. I went to the consul,
and he couldn't do anything.
- He stopped you?
- Absolutely.
- Why didn't you go the limit for Harry?
- I went to the Mexican authorities...
Dr. Livingstone, I presume.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Yes?
Yes. Sit down.
I get kind of lost at these big parties,
don't you?
Yes.
The situation is pretty warm
in your part of the world, isn't it?
Yes.
TESS: Having fun?
- Yes.
We haven't met. My name is Craig.
- What's yours?
- Oh, yes.
You don't speak English,
do you, Charlie?
Yes.
You're a silly-Iooking little jerk
with that towel around your head.
- You know that, don't you?
- Yes.
- That's all, brother.
Yes.
Hey, ask her if it's true about
Rudolph Hess' toenails, will you?
I don't think we'll make a definite
reservation for the return flight.
Just a moment, please. Sorry.
Either tomorrow night
or Monday morning. Thank you.
- My name is Sam Craig. It's all right.
- Will you kindly be seated?
It'll just be a moment.
This is Gerald Howe,
Miss Harding's secretary, speaking.
I'd like to make a call
to Havana, Cuba.
Miss Harding calling the office
of Señor Batista.
Colonel Fulgencio Batista.
Just ask for the president
of the country. Right.
You read Chinese?
Fluently.
[BUZZING]
- You may go in now.
SAM: Thanks.
[PHONE RINGS]
Yes? Hold on a moment, please.
Cuba on the wire.
[TESS SPEAKING SPANISH]
[MACHINE RATTLING]
Nice party you had last night.
It was a nice baseball game.
- Thanks for the thing.
- Not at all.
I'd like to talk to you, Tess.
Shoot.
No, no. It's nothing in particular,
you know.
I thought the two of us
could sit down somewhere...
...and kick the thing around.
I thought I'd have
a chance last night...
...but when I walked into
the League of Nations...
...with two sparrows under my arm...
They're lovebirds, Sam,
and they're wonderful.
SAM:
How did they get here?
How the dickens do you think
they got here?
Get your hat, and we'll go
get lost in New Jersey.
I'd love to, Sam. But gosh darn it all!
I have to speak at a meeting
up at Riverside Hall this afternoon.
- Hey, pick me up after the meeting.
- All right. What time?
- About 5: 15. Meet me backstage?
- All right, 5...
Wait. I wonder if that'll
give me time. I have a 6:00 plane.
- Plane? What...?
- I'm going to Washington.
- Washington?
- Yeah. Sure it won't be inconvenient?
- To go to Washington?
- No, to take me to the airport, silly.
- No. Where do I pick you up?
- Riverside Hall.
Yes, hold on please. It's Vichy calling.
TESS: Get on the extension and
take down every word. See you later.
Hello.
[SPEAKS IN ITALIAN]
Look, do you mind
if I take this with me?
I didn't finish the crossword puzzle.
[IMITATING CHINESE]
Where's Miss Harding, please?
I'm late.
Too many feel about women's rights the
way a girl I know does about her fur coat.
All her life, she dreamt about having one.
She got it after a tough struggle.
I suppose there's
a sort of contentment...
[WOMEN CHUCKLING]
...and I wouldn't quarrel with her
about it.
Sit down, Sam. There's a chair.
I do, however, take issue violently...
...when women try to apply
that same reasoning...
...to the rights we fi...
Finally won 22 years ago.
At this very moment, we're facing
the first major test of our fitness...
...to shoulder this responsibility.
Ellen Whitcomb has pointed out
to you this afternoon...
...the deep obligation we have
to take a vital part...
...in the crisis confronting
our country.
It is our simple duty not only
to accept what she has said...
...but to translate her words
into terms of positive action.
Ellen Whitcomb represents,
as no other individual...
...the development of the rights
women fought for...
...and the responsibilities
we must assume.
In her words, "What we fought for was
not only the privilege of equal rights...
...and a share in the determination
of state policy...
...but also the grave responsibility
which accompanies that privilege.
Today, women of the world
are faced with the first major test...
...of their fitness
to meet that responsibility.
Our place is no longer only in the home.
It is also in the first line of battle."
There is so little
that I can add to her words.
There is so little anyone can add.
Possibly, I'm prejudiced
because she's my aunt.
I don't think so.
Her life and her work
speak eloquently enough.
Twenty years ago,
she was the youngest leader...
...in the feminist movement.
Today she's a tremendous force
in the battle...
...to preserve and extend democracy.
Let us draw from her the inspiration
to use the freedom we have won...
...to defend the freedom of all.
- Well...
- Miss Harding.
You'd better park the car
and meet us at gate 2.
It made me feel very strange,
having Tess call me "aunt."
I've come to regard myself
so completely as her mother.
See, my sister died
when Tess was a little baby.
- Tess was once a baby?
- To begin with.
She and her father were in China.
I went out to take care of her.
And him.
- Interesting place, China.
- Yes.
Especially if you're a maiden aunt
teaching a Chinese nurse...
...things you don't know about.
Which reminds me...
...the Chiang Kai-sheks are having
an anniversary soon. I must tell Gerald.
- Hope we haven't ruined your day.
- No, not at all.
Kept me off the streets
and out of poolrooms.
- What's the matter, Sam?
- Nothing.
- Sure?
- Well, I can't quite figure you out.
What are you trying to prove?
Why am I here?
- Well, Sam...
- Nurmo could've driven you here.
Why did you ask me?
Thought you might want
to kiss me goodbye.
They're holding the plane for us.
Goodbye, Gerald. See you Monday?
- What time?
- Send you a wire?
Yeah, but you do it.
Don't have the little corporal do it.
ELLEN:
Goodbye.
Could I drop you somewhere,
Miss Whitcomb?
Drop the "Miss Whitcomb."
Sounds like a reproach.
Bet it has been,
to fellas who didn't know better.
Just for the record, Sam,
it wasn't that exciting.
There was only one
who should've and didn't.
The others did and shouldn't have.
- Going by my hotel?
- Right by. Which one is it?
- I warn you. I'll talk your ears off.
- It won't hurt.
What point are you trying
to make, Sam?
Maybe there isn't any point.
- You like your work, don't you?
- Uh-huh. More all the time.
I don't know why, either,
unless it's because I like people.
I like meeting them
and writing about them.
Unimportant people, though. Guess
that makes me an unimportant guy.
That makes you
a very important guy, Sam.
Not because you rate a byline,
but because you have a heart...
...a job you like to do and a future.
You're just a normal
human being, Sam.
Go on leading your normal human life.
That sounds fine.
How do you go about arranging it?
You mean, how do you go about
arranging it?
Yeah.
[PLANE HUMMING]
Well, I'd say marry the girl.
All right, I will.
He comes out and starts
peppering me with light lefts.
I'm taking it, see? I'm waiting
for an opening with me right cocked...
...but it don't come.
First round, pepper.
Second round...
- Hello, Sammy.
- Hi, Pinkie. Back booth empty?
Well, if it ain't, I'll empty it.
Two Scotches, on the house.
SAM:
You'll like this place.
Tess Harding, Pinkie Peters.
He's telling me who you are.
You write for Sammy's paper.
I read your column all the time.
I don't understand it, but I read it.
- Is that from the right bottle?
WAITER: The best we have, sir.
Don't give them
the cockamamie bar stock.
WAITER:
No. No, sir.
Well...
...what can I do for you?
Skip your story of your fight
with Braddock.
Sure.
The Carnera fight, maybe?
No. Another Scotch, maybe.
Good idea.
- Make mine a double.
- Me too.
Sure.
Well, we're alone. Talk.
You do have something to talk about?
Yeah, yeah. You.
I'd like to know what you like
and don't like...
...and how you feel about being you.
I feel very good about it. Always have.
I like knowing more about
what goes on than most people.
- And telling them.
- Yeah, and telling them.
Thanks, Joe.
Lot of drink in these.
TESS:
I don't know.
Well, I just mean
if you're not used to them.
Oh, don't worry about me.
As a diplomat's daughter, I've had
to match drinks with a lot of people.
From remittance men
to international spies.
And I may say I've never
wound up under the table.
Reminds me of my year at college.
We used to bet on drinking.
Make a contest out of it. Kid stuff.
Imagine.
Silly.
Lots of people make the error...
...of grouping Pareto
and Spengler together...
...because they both feel that democracy
is through, whereas actually...
...Spengler is the philosophical basis
for Fascism.
Or... No, he's not.
Pareto is.
While Spengler...
Well, actually, they both are.
That is, at least, basically.
Well, it's about the same thing.
Were you there at the end?
In Madrid, I mean.
Um... After I came back,
I wrote a series of articles...
...which finally blossomed
into a regular column.
And I've lived happily ever after.
Did you live happily ever before?
How do you mean?
Well, I wanna know the story,
you know, behind the story.
The girl without a country
and how she grew up.
She grew up by remote control.
I've read Uncle Tom
in the Argentine and...
The Argentine.
Argentine.
And I read Huckleberry Finn
going down the Yangtze.
- Did it seem like the Mississippi?
- I've never seen the Mississippi.
So then I grew older, and I went
to school in Switzerland...
...and in Leipzig and the Sorbonne,
and then I became quite busy...
...and my father decided to come home.
So I decided to come home with him.
That isn't when you came home.
I was there the day you came home.
It was in the ballpark.
- That was fun.
- Yeah.
Fun being with the people
instead of telling them, wasn't it?
I had kind of an idea that it had
something to do with being with you.
With me? Really? Why?
- Look, Sam...
- I'm looking.
What do you see?
- Right now?
- Right now.
A little gal I ran into at the ballpark,
name of Tessie.
I know you by the freckles
on your nose.
You're the first to mention
those since I was 12.
You mind? Trouble is, you can't
see them most of the time.
Maybe you bring them out.
Look, Tess...
I'm looking...
...Sam.
Um...
Maybe you better take me home.
- Do you feel you'd like some air?
- Hmm.
PINKIE: We're coming up
for the 14th round, see.
I come out bobbing and weaving.
I'm as fresh as a daisy.
I'm giving it to him with lefts
and a hard right and...
This is good.
This is better.
- Tess.
- Hmm.
- Something I've gotta get off my chest.
- I'm too heavy.
No.
Then what?
I love you.
- You do?
- Positive.
That is nice.
Even when I'm sober?
Even when you're brilliant.
[BRAKES SQUEAK]
This is it.
You're telling me.
DRIVER:
Say, would you like me to wait?
Why don't you let him go.
You can get another cab.
Just drop your hat anywhere.
SAM: Joint doesn't look half bad
when it's empty.
TESS:
Know what?
No, what?
How about a nice cold glass of milk?
- I think that might be a good idea.
- Back in a flash.
- Like it?
- Beautiful.
It's a little too high to reach.
TESS:
I'm not.
Sit down, Sam.
I won't be staying very long.
TESS:
I feel so nice and relaxed. Don't you?
SAM:
No.
[TESS GIGGLING]
TESS:
Sam, you're just a bundle of nerves.
SAM:
I think it's getting kind of late now.
TESS:
No, it isn't.
SAM:
All right, it isn't.
TESS:
I think I better get the milk.
[WHISTLING]
PHIL:
"Lilly Dache"?
Why, Sam.
[CHUCKLES]
Just an old snood I had reblocked.
- She's in the wire room.
- Wire room?
Dr. Lubbeck's escaped,
and nobody knows where he is.
Who's he?
Mladen Lubbeck,
the Yugoslavian statesman.
Miss Harding knew him well. She's
worried about whether he got away.
Oh. Oh, yes. Yes, of course.
- Found him yet?
- UP located him in Moscow...
...and AP in Lisbon, both at the same...
Hello.
Did anyone ever tell you that
your manners left much to be desired?
Look, Tess...
There's one thing I want you
to understand.
You're practically the only woman
I would've walked out on last night.
That's about the prettiest compliment
I've ever had.
Tess, don't you understand
what I mean?
I wanna marry you.
Anything happening?
- Plenty.
- Great.
- Sure you want me?
- Yeah.
How about you?
Always swore I wouldn't.
The frightening idea
of getting tied down.
Guess there's one thing
I didn't figure on.
What?
You, Sam.
Yes, Mom.
Oh, but, Mom,
she is good enough for me.
Now, look, Mom, I'll write you
all about it tomorrow.
This long distance will cost me
a week's salary.
What?
Oh, well, Mom, you don't ask girls
a thing like that.
I didn't say it wasn't important,
I just said...
Yes, all right. I'll find out
if she's a good cook, yes.
I'll wire you as soon as the date's set.
All right, dear. Goodbye.
When do you think we...?
- Macinock.
- South Carolina's the most...
...convenient place. No waiting period.
Very handy for your father.
We have to arrange this to suit
plans of three people.
- Three?
- Pop, Aunt Ellen and myself.
She's in Minneapolis Thursday.
Make it tomorrow.
- Will that be all right for you?
- I can't make it. I'll be busy.
- Oh...
- 5:00 seems to be the best time.
Allow half an hour for the business.
You can fly back to meet Dr. Lubbeck
in case he is on the clipper.
We'll set it for then. Send the wires,
Gerald. Will that suit you, darling?
- Well, do we have to do it so quick?
- Don't you want to?
Yes, but the whole thing seems
so important for such rush.
I don't know, I always looked forward
to the day I was gonna get married.
I thought I'd do it up right,
like most people do.
I thought I might go for the striped
pants. Just for the wedding, I mean.
I just don't think you can do the thing
right in such a hurry.
We'll do it right.
[GIRLS GIGGLING]
[SIREN WAILING]
TESS:
Here he is.
Pop!
You're beautiful.
- How dare you be late to my wedding.
- I couldn't walk out on the president.
- Since when is he more important than I?
- Since 1789.
Pardon me, Mr. Harding,
but we only have 10 minutes.
Twelve. Hello, Ellen.
- Where's the sacrificial lamb?
- There he is. Sam, Pop.
- Will you need me on the way back?
HARDING: Yes, you'd better wait.
POLICE MAN:
Yes, sir.
- Sam.
- Pop.
I've been worried about you
since yesterday.
- Well, I've worried about you for years.
- He'll do.
I think we can both stop worrying.
JUDGE: By authority of the powers
invested in me...
...by the state of South Carolina...
...I pronounce you man and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
Yes, I know.
May I, Mrs. Craig?
Hey.
- Well, Pop, you're stuck with me.
- It's a pleasure, Sam.
- I've poured some wine for a toast.
SAM: Ah...
Miss Harding... I mean, Mrs. Craig.
That call you put to New York's waiting.
- I didn't want to interrupt.
- That's Gerald. Excuse me.
- I thought a toast to the bride...
- Mr. Harding, we have to hurry.
- Ten minutes rushed by.
- I need a lift. I told Eleanor I'd drop in.
If you're able to go right away.
I'm sorry to rush...
...old boy, but you know...
- Newlyweds should be left alone anyway.
Now, look here... Just a minute, Gerald.
Goodbye. You were sweet to come.
Goodbye, good...
I'm not going. I'm staying.
TESS:
Now, look, Gerald.
We ought to be able to get out
of here in about half an hour.
I don't know, I suppose
around 10 or 11:00.
No. Well... You better have a car meet
us. We'll go straight to the apartment.
No, I want them tonight.
If any word did come through, I'd...
Well, I'm afraid it's hopeless.
Good heavens, Miss Harding,
you've been in an accident?
Shame on you.
What a way to talk about marriage.
- Any calls?
- Yes, Miss Harding...
- No, we're married now, Alma.
- Oh, Mrs. Harding.
- No, Mrs. Craig.
- Yeah?
- I put all the messages on your desk.
- Thank you. Bring in the things.
I'll get them.
[MACHINE RATTLING]
Oh, Mr. Craig, if there's any
little thing that I can do...
SAM: I won't be much bother.
- I know. Miss Harding said you won't.
He didn't make it. I thought he might
have caught the clipper in Lisbon.
- His name's not on the passenger list.
- Good.
- Sam.
- Just tonight, I can't seem to work up...
...any enthusiasm for somebody
who missed a clipper.
I'm sorry, darling.
It's just force of habit.
You suppose I could interest you
in some new habits?
[CHUCKLING]
Alma, you must learn
to be more considerate.
Yes, Miss... Ma'am.
- These bags...
- You can just leave them.
Well, I gather this is going to be
my boudoir tonight.
Where are we going to live?
Why don't we find a place by the river.
By the river? You mean, move?
- Sam, I thought, for a while...
- You thought what? Now, Tess...
...you can't expect me to move...
- I have a lease, and it's all established.
Everyone knows my address
and phone number.
- Can't you see what a mess I'd be in?
- Yeah, but I'll feel like a weekend guest.
No, you won't.
[MACHINE RATTLING]
Please don't mess around with
anything on the desk, Mr. Craig.
I'm not gonna mess around
with anything on the desk.
- She don't like things being misplaced.
- I'm not gonna misplace anything, Alma.
[BUZZING]
Alma.
Dr. Lubbeck. Come in.
They stand between me and the
Gestapo. I must see Miss Harding.
Where is she?
No, you don't, Alma. No, you don't.
Oh... She's going to bed.
- Couldn't you wait until tomorrow?
- Not even a minute.
Yeah. Then...
Come on, then.
Okay.
Holy jumping Jehoshaphat!
- Dr. Lubbeck.
- Yes.
He couldn't wait.
[TESS SPEAKING GERMAN]
Tess.
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
Hey!
Sam. Dr. Lubbeck.
- Dr. Lubbeck, this is my husband. Sam...
SAM: Craig.
He made it.
He has a great sense of timing.
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
- Please, come. Join with us.
- I don't like to intrude.
No, not at all. No.
Dr. Lubbeck came to see me before
anyone else. Most wonderful break.
First real inside dope
on the Balkan smashup.
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
He's telling about the Nazi infiltration.
Isn't this thrilling?
I'm all goose pimples.
[YELLING]
The Yugoslavian consul.
Dr. Lubbeck called them.
Hello. Hello, Pinkie? Sam. Hi, Pinkie.
Well, having a little party.
What are you doing?
Why don't you come up here
and join us.
Sure. Sure. 851 Fifth Avenue,
apartment A.
Yeah, write that down so you
won't forget it. Sure, bring Flo along.
Bring some of the gang, Pinkie.
MAN: Looks pretty ritzy to me.
WOMAN: Boy, some joint!
BOD YGUARD: No, you don't.
PINKIE: Yes, I do!
Ah. Ah! Pinkie!
Pinkie. I'm so glad to see you, Pinkie.
Hello, Flo.
I want you to meet a
distinguished gentleman...
...from Europe.
Dr. Lubbeck, Pinkie Peters.
Well, hi, doc.
Everybody, meet Dr. Lubbeck
and his friends.
Dr. Lubbeck's a great fight fan.
I wanted to tell him about Braddock...
...but I don't do it so well.
- I'll be glad to give it to him.
Hey, punchy. You.
Come on over here. You be Braddock.
- Take care of this, will you?
- Don't let him. He'll drive you nuts.
Shut up, will you, honey?
All right, take your stance.
Now, this guy Braddock,
a very smart, cagey boxer...
...starts peppering me with light lefts.
All right, go ahead, pepper.
I'm taking it, see?
I wait for an opening with me right
cocked. First round, pepper.
Second round, pepper.
Third round, pepper.
I catch him in the corner, feint with my
left, his guard comes down...
What are you trying to do,
crab up my story?
Come on, get up, you dope.
Braddock didn't go down till the seventh.
I hit him again.
All right, get up, get up.
He's groggy, he's hanging on the ropes.
I wind up a terrific right and:
He hits me three in a row.
- You get rid of yours, I'll get rid of mine.
- All right, how?
- Well, what about...?
- See, Sammy?
I told you not to start him off.
He's like a hophead with that yarn.
Hello.
Say, Sammy. Whose dump is this?
I don't want to get personal, but...
...I don't get it.
SAM: Our dump. See, Tess is my wife.
What do you know! That's wonderful!
Oh, don't take it wrong, Mrs. Craig.
I'm just so excited. When did you do it?
- Today.
- Who'd have thought that you two...?
What's the matter with you two?
Don't you wanna be alone?
Just leave it to little Flo.
Come on, Pinkie. We gotta beat it.
- I ain't knocked him out yet.
- Knock him out later.
- We're going to Pinkie's.
- What is this?
- Quiet, or I'll let you have it.
- Well, all right.
- All right, then. Come on, grandpa.
PINKIE: Come, doc, we'll go to my place.
What's the matter?
Bye.
FLO:
Come on, come on, let's get going.
[IMITATES GERMAN]
[CROWD CHEERING]
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
MAN: Looks like Krakowitz again.
SAM: No, number 17's Donato.
MAN [OVER SPEAKER]: Donato carried
the ball, tackled by Loomis and Fry.
They're crazy.
I could tell it was Donato
by the way he raised his knee.
Here's the shift to the right.
Sweep out around the end.
Murphy carrying the ball.
He turns on a cutback,
tries to find a hole, loses his...
- Fifteen seconds.
- They got time for a pass.
- They haven't caught two passes.
- Not calling time out.
Too late to do them any good.
The shift box formation to the right.
A reverse and spinner...
... behind scrimmage.
This may be the play that does it.
He's going to the sidelines.
He's knocked out of bounds.
And there's the gun for the end
of the ball game.
There you are.
Words that'll live forever.
- They're cold enough.
- Let's grab a cab to the Blackstone.
Let's walk. We miss speeches
and get liquor.
- Those steaks. Remember last year?
- Yeah, but I'm catching the train home.
Are you nuts? This is Saturday night,
even in Chicago.
A day on a train
is a day on a train. Even Sunday.
You got it bad. Now, I'm a family man,
I love my wife...
...but free steaks and beer!
- The first months a guy's married...
...he acts as though it was
gonna be the last.
TESS: Yesterday's parley
must be acclaimed a...
Hello, Daddy.
Even in a period replete with
developments of climactic significance...
...the parley is a major landmark.
Be with you in two minutes.
I have one paragraph left.
- "Is a major landmark."
- Yeah. Tariffs have been the historic...
- Fly in the ointment.
- Fly in the ointment of foreign policy.
- Is what's-her-name around? I'm hungry.
- I gave her the weekend off.
In ordinary times, the internal conflicts
between domestic financial interests...
...are unfortunate. In a national crisis,
they may be fatal.
Now that the problem of beef... Now
that the problem of beef is settled...
...we hope for a quick solution for the
other beefs which thwart national unity.
TIME used the same gag last week.
- You're cute.
- Ow!
So we can look forward with greater
confidence to the grim... Ow!
Greater confidence
to the grim months ahead.
I think that's all, Gerald.
SAM:
Look.
Notice anything different?
Sure, you've got your hat on.
- It's a new hat.
- Oh, I like it.
I was hoping you'd notice.
I've needed one for some time.
I said I like it. It's a fine hat.
I'm glad you bought it.
Be with you in two minutes.
Sorry you don't like it.
I said I liked it.
Pardon me. Miss Harding says,
if you're making eggs, she'd like some.
All right.
She said I should tell you
if I was hungry too.
I am.
[TESS SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[PHONE RINGING]
SAM:
Hello. Yes.
Señor Armato? Just a minute.
- Tess, Señor Armato.
- I don't want to speak. He's a pest.
She doesn't want to speak to you.
You're a pest.
- That's all, Gerald.
- All right, Miss Harding. Thank you.
- Goodbye. Goodbye, Mr. Craig.
SAM: Yeah.
Well?
Tell me about the game.
- Did you read my story?
- I'm going to, but I was in a rush.
I can tell you had fun. It's wonderful
your work keeps you outdoors so much.
Why don't you tell me all about it.
Who won?
- It was a tie, 13-13.
- Did they play an extra inning...
...or whatever?
- In football, a game ends...
...when it ends, no matter the score.
The big thing was a new shift
Notre Dame used.
- Was it really?
- The line spreads out all over the place.
- Any one of the backs might take it.
- Uh-huh.
You figure it's gonna be a pass,
you see, but the twist...
Gosh, must've been exciting.
What else?
What else would you like to know?
- What did you do after the game?
- I drove to the railroad station.
That's where I bought my new hat.
There's a hat store there.
- It's the best one in Chicago.
- Chicago?
I had a feeling at the time.
That's really funny.
- What's funny?
- I was in Chicago yesterday.
- I don't get it.
- A conference. The government...
...called a meeting. I flew out.
- What time?
- 1:00.
- How long were you there?
- I left about 5:45.
- I got through about 5:30.
- We could've come home together.
- It didn't occur to me.
- There was so much...
- Why didn't it? It would to me.
I don't know why it's such an issue.
How could I have told you?
- Call the press box at Soldier's Field.
- I couldn't know that.
- Your whole point's about nothing.
- It's not whether we could have...
...it's you never thought of it.
- How do you know?
- You just said you didn't.
Well, all right.
Yesterday, I wasn't anxious enough
to be with you.
So we're even.
How do you figure that out?
Because...
...today you aren't anxious enough
to be with me.
If you were, you wouldn't waste
all this time arguing.
[SHOUTING]
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
- Gonna put Red in?
- This is marvelous.
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
This is great being on the inside,
right on the player's bench.
You must have influence, Sam.
Hey, suppose I could work this sometime
when you're not around?
Where did I pick you up this morning?
Secretary of state's office?
- Sure. Why?
- I'm a man with influence.
Oh...
- Where'd you play?
- Tackle.
- No, what college did you go to?
- I went to lots of colleges.
Oh.
Have a chew?
Thanks.
Best I could find.
- The picture and the son-in-law.
- Thanks.
I'm gonna give you a treat.
Oh. Is that the stuff they carry around
in those political portfolios?
It'll dissolve an aspirin tablet
as quick as anything.
Thanks.
Mm.
Know when I realized you're
the right man for my daughter?
- No, when?
- When I heard you'd asked her.
I felt whoever had the courage
to propose deserved to be her husband.
A privilege, I hasten to add, which I
don't underestimate in the slightest.
- It's a privilege.
- You're also the man...
...who's responsible for making me
feel my age lately.
- Why?
- Nothing makes you feel your years...
...so keenly as the sense
of being alone.
- There's no reason you can't see Tess.
- Oh, it's not that.
There were times she was miles away,
but I still felt, wherever she was...
...she was my girl.
Now she's your girl. That makes me
admire your courage more than ever.
I once knew a woman who was
an even more difficult case than Tess.
If such a thing is possible.
- Ellen?
- Hm?
Oh, that was an easy guess.
What happened?
Nothing happened. That's the point.
I don't know.
Just never seemed to be quite
the right moment.
Fifteen years of wrong moments.
Fifteen years of having what I've got
instead of what you've got.
What one courageous
moment can make.
I can't see that
what you've got is so little.
Well, let's look at the evidence.
I come back to this.
Unless I can think of an excuse not to.
But you go home to someone.
Someone to talk to, to live with.
- Share each other's work and ideas.
- Yeah.
Unless you've missed out on it, you're
apt to underestimate how important it is.
That other person existing who cares
as much about your interests as you do.
Yeah, it doesn't always
work out so perfectly.
Sam, it's a lucky thing you're not
a salesman. You'd starve to death.
Here's to the continued happiness
of both of you, Sam.
To the continued happiness
of both of us.
- What's the matter, somebody sick?
- Just because a wife waits up...
Darling, you must be tired. Hop into bed,
I'll fix you something to drink.
- I'm not thirsty.
- Help you sleep better.
[GRUNTING]
Good morning.
I think I overslept.
Alma forgot to wake me.
You don't have to be there till afternoon.
I checked with your office.
Don't get up. It's silly to get up
if you don't have to.
SAM:
Tess, what's all this about?
Breakfast.
All right, let's have it.
Well...
As a matter of fact, there is something
I'd like to talk to you about.
I figured that. What is it?
- Darling?
- What?
Um...
Are you...
...perfectly...
...satisfied about us?
What do you call being satisfied?
I mean, do you think that...
...maybe there's a reason for the friction
we've been having lately?
Could be.
Do you think...
...perhaps it's because...
...there are only two of us?
What?
What would you think
about having a child?
Tess.
Tess, is that what this buildup is...?
Did you think I'd have to be
sold on the idea?
I thought I'd better get you
into the right frame of mind.
Get me into the right frame of... Me?
The sooner, the better.
It's already been done.
It's already been done. Well...
- Well, you gotta lie down. Go to...
- I'm all right, Sam.
Tess, but you've gotta be careful.
I'll have Mom come east for this.
She'll walk from Wisconsin for this.
What did the doctor say?
- I haven't seen the doctor.
- You've got to see the doctor.
You gotta stay off your feet,
you know...
Tess, I hope it's a boy.
- Oh, you sweet...
- It is a boy.
It is a boy? What...?
Well, how...? Who...?
[TESS SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
He's... He's a refugee.
A little Greek refugee.
He's ours.
Two weeks ago, they made me chairman
of the Greek Refugee Committee.
I accepted without thinking much
about it.
While you were away,
they had a meeting.
And some idiot suggested
I should take the first one, so I did.
[SPEAKING GREEK]
[TESS SPEAKING GREEK]
He thinks you don't like him.
- What's his name?
- Chris.
Sam, he's been to two baseball games
while he's been in New York...
...and he simply loves it.
So you'll have lots to talk about.
When he learns to speak
a little English.
Hi, Chris.
Do you suppose we could
take him out with Alma?
- I'd like to talk to you.
- He won't understand.
He seems good at sensing attitudes.
I wouldn't want him to think
that mine was anything personal...
...as far as he's concerned.
- All right.
[SPEAKING GREEK]
- We can't keep that kid.
- You said you wanted a child.
I thought you meant
a child of our own.
You know that's impractical.
How could I have a baby?
- How could you have a baby?
- I'm not saying we never will.
I don't see what that has to do
with Chris. This is a humanitarian idea.
If we had a kid of our own, he might be
a swell addition to the family.
But as a substitution, he won't do.
Besides, we haven't got a home
he'd be happy in.
Sam, you cannot send that child back.
I'd look perfectly idiotic.
Besides, it isn't a question of pride.
I wanna help.
I know, your heart is in it.
Your heart is in everything you do.
If you could spare about
10 percent of that heart...
...from the world at large
and apply it here at home...
[PHONE RINGING]
Hello.
It's Gerald. He says there's something
important on the Teletype...
...six or seven items back.
- All right.
Yes, I told her.
Yes, I told her it was important.
Sam, look.
Operator, I want to speak to Miss Ellen
Whitcomb at New Milford, Connecticut.
This is Miss Harding,
at Atwater 9-0599.
Yes. Will you call me, please? Thanks.
[PHONE RINGING]
Hello. Pop! I was just gonna call you.
Well, I don't know,
it's so unexpected. L...
Yes. They're going to present
a plaque at a banquet...
...a week from tomorrow night.
You will? Oh, that's wonderful.
Yes, I'm sure she will.
Well, I haven't spoken to her yet.
I have a call in now.
I can't wait to tell her.
Thanks, darling.
All right, I'll see you then. Goodbye.
Would you have voted for me, Sam?
[PHONE RINGING]
Hello.
Ellen, Tess.
The most wonderful thing that's ever
happened to me has just happened.
Darling.
Do I look like the husband
of the Woman of the Year?
You look fine.
I guess I got time
to go say hello to Chris, huh?
Mm-hm.
I never been to a woman's banquet.
Is the food better than at a man's?
TESS: Chicken instead of steak,
but we get a prize for going.
SAM: They won't ask me
to make a speech, will they?
I don't see why.
Hello, Chris.
[SPEAKING GREEK]
- Hello.
- Attaboy, Chris.
Why, you'll be spouting English
in no time.
Nice set of toys you got here.
All you need
is a baseball diamond and...
...a football field, a playground and...
...eight other guys, and you're all set.
Chris, maybe tomorrow
we'll go to the zoo.
Get some peanuts for the elephants.
Yeah, get some for us too, huh, Chris?
Good night.
- How do I look?
- Beautiful.
That's a great collection of toys
he has in there.
Sam, Ellen's downstairs.
It's 8. They'll think I'm
trying to make an entrance.
What were you planning to do,
come up out of the floor?
- You get him those toys?
- Gerald did. Was he playing?
He was playing
a set of tennis with himself.
TESS: I'll get him some
myself in the morning.
SAM: Alma's no playmate
for that kid, anyway.
Where is Alma?
She's going to the banquet. She feels
responsible for winning this thing.
- The banquet?
- He'll be all right, he's old enough.
We'll be home by midnight.
- He can cry a lot in 4 hours.
- The elevator boy'll look in on him.
- Yeah, they all speak Greek.
- Sam, we've got to go. Ellen's waiting.
- You go. I'll stay till he falls asleep.
- Sam, don't be idiotic.
You simply don't want to come,
that's why the paternal act.
I'm not putting on any act.
We accepted responsibility.
- What shall I say you're doing?
- Say I'm at home minding the baby.
I don't care what you tell them.
Tell them I had something to do.
Who would believe you had anything
that was important enough to do...?
It's too bad I'm not covering
this dinner tonight...
...because I've got an angle
that would really be sensational.
The Outstanding Woman of the Year
isn't a woman at all.
I'm sorry.
You coming?
Chris, we're getting out of here.
[KIDS SHOUTING IN GREEK]
We try not to be too strict with them.
They're so high-spirited.
I suppose you're interested
in an application.
- We have a waiting list...
- I'm afraid you don't understand.
- I just brought one back.
- One of our children?
Yes, yes. His name is Chris.
He just ran upstairs.
Seemed to meet a friend.
Oh.
My wife brought him home
before she talked to me about it.
Didn't you like the child?
Oh, yes. The boy has nothing to do
with it, I just didn't like the idea.
It's a great responsibility, and it seems
to turn the house upside down.
I see. Will you come in?
WOMAN [OVER RADIO]:
Never forget that Adolf Hitler...
- What did you say your name was?
- Craig. Sam Craig.
- Whose pathetic distinction is the number
of male children she contributes...
... to the very state
which holds her in bondage.
That contrast increases the pride
with which we now...
... bestow this plaque on America 's
Outstanding Woman of the Year.
Why, aren't you...?
- Yeah.
- Who so magnificently symbolizes...
... the full and rounded life...
... of glorious emancipation
of womanhood...
...in this country.
Our distinguished guest:
Tess Harding.
[WILD APPLAUSE]
Sam should be here any minute.
While we're waiting,
let's grab shots of you working.
Yes, we need some informal stuff.
I seldom work in these clothes.
I'll change. I won't be a minute.
PHOTOGRAPHER 1: There she is.
Where do you do your work?
What Clayton wants most
is you and Sam.
I work in there. If you don't get me
with my husband, I mean...
...if he doesn't get home, you could get
a shot of me with my... Just a minute.
You name it, Miss Harding.
PHOTOGRAPHER 2:
A shot of you with who?
With my typewriter.
That would be interesting.
PHOTOGRAPHER 3:
Yeah, that would be something new.
Don't you see? We made an exception
in your case.
We only put people on our list who have
children or who want two of them.
- There's a nice Greek-American family...
- What you're saying is sound.
But I accepted Chris.
I intend to keep him.
There's no doubt that Chris
must be very fond of you.
But I gathered Mr. Craig doesn't
share your sympathy for children.
- It's my experience...
- Would you have him brought down?
- Tomorrow. He's sleeping.
- I'm sure he'll like to come home.
Very well.
- Hello, Chris.
- Hello.
We're gonna go home now.
[SPEAKING IN GREEK]
MATRON:
Chris.
[SPEAKING IN GREEK]
MATRON:
Oh, I'm sure he doesn't mean it.
GERALD:
Telegram.
Extension 558, please.
Hello, Sam.
This is Tess Harding. Remember me?
That's nice.
Sam...
...something's come up
which seems to concern both of us.
Wonder if you'd mind
dropping up here for a minute.
No, honestly, it's a telegram.
Quite important.
I'll be right down, Sam.
- Hello, Mr. Craig.
- Hello, Miss Harding.
We got an invitation.
Connecticut, tomorrow night.
I'm afraid I can't make it.
- Won't be any fun alone.
- Sorry, I have to cover the fight.
- What fight?
- Championship.
Couldn't you duck it,
give some excuse?
No.
It's quite important.
In an unimportant sort of way.
I'll phone Ellen, tell her we'll drive up
tomorrow afternoon.
Don't bother.
I've got a pretty heavy week.
But, Sam...
...EIlen won't understand
our not being together.
She'll think there's something
funny about it.
At first, maybe, but...
...later on, she'll see the serious side.
Last night was quite a night.
Mm.
Among other things, it seems that
both my men walked out on me.
Oh, Chris'll be all right.
He just needed a home.
I know.
We agree about that.
We're making progress.
Sam.
Why can't we sit down like adults
and patch this thing up?
I'm afraid that might become a habit.
Then we'd wind up with
a patchwork quilt instead of a marriage.
What do you want me to do,
just throw out everything we've had...
...when it was so perfect?
Is that what you think it was,
a perfect marriage?
Didn't you?
I don't think it was either.
Perfect or a marriage.
I don't understand.
That's just the point.
I guess it wasn't much use,
my conniving my way down here.
Depends on what you were after.
I was sort of hoping
that you'd kiss me goodbye.
that you'd ask me.
Bye.
TESS:
Harriet.
Hello.
Asa. I'm so glad to see you both.
Land's sake, you're just in time,
Mrs. Craig.
In time for what?
Where's Mr. Craig?
He's not coming.
What goes on here?
- You're both in a dither.
- Miss Ellen's upstairs.
What's the mystery?
- All right, you're ravishing.
- Tess.
What goes on?
- How are you, dear?
- Quit stalling. What goes on?
Well, it...
...seems there's going to be a wedding.
If there's one thing I'm not
in the mood for, it's a wedding.
- Who is it? Anyone I know?
- Yes, I should think so.
Me.
- It's Pop, of course.
- Of course.
I think it's wonderful.
I was hoping you'd say that.
Isn't it strange how you can
know someone for quite a long time...
...and never quite... I mean...
- Yes, it is.
I hope you don't think we needed
you to give us the idea.
- Matter of fact, we did.
- Should've asked my permission.
You modern fathers have no respect
for tradition.
I was sure you'd approve my choice,
and I intended to ask for your blessing.
- Dr. Potter here?
- You bet. I went and got him myself.
I'm taking no chances. Where's Sam?
Isn't he downstairs?
[SIGHS]
He had to work.
World's championship. Fight.
But I wanted him for my bridesmaid.
I was his best man.
Oh, getting married without Sam.
He'd feel worse
if you put it off on his account.
Dr. Potter's ready,
wants to know if you are.
Go on. I'll take care of the bride.
Can't marry my father
looking like somebody's aunt.
Were you really surprised?
Frankly...
...yes.
Somehow, I never thought of you
as being anyone's wife.
Well, I know I'm not
a magazine-cover bride, but...
No, I don't mean that.
You're my woman of the century.
I always felt that you were
above marriage.
Well, that's a nice consoling way
of looking at it.
Can't live alone in this world, Tess.
It's no good.
Success is no fun
unless you share it with someone.
I'm tired of winning prizes.
They're cold comfort.
This time, I want to be the prize myself.
Come on, Ellen. There's no reason
for you to pretend...
...you've been miserable
all these years.
I'm sorry I said it.
There's no way you could understand
what I've felt.
No reason why you should.
No chance of your making
a wrong choice.
You have Sam now,
while you're still young.
They're waiting, Miss Ellen.
Come on.
[PLAYING "THE WEDDING MARCH"]
POTTER:
Dearly beloved...
...we are gathered here together
in the sight of God...
...and in the face of this company...
...to join together this man
and this woman in holy matrimony.
Which is an honorable estate...
...instituted of God...
...and therefore is not by any to be
entered into unadvisedly or lightly...
...but reverently, discreetly, soberly...
...and in the fear of God.
You are performing an act
of utter faith.
Believing in one another to the end.
As the bride gives herself
to the bridegroom...
...let him be to her
father and mother...
...sister and brother...
...and, most sacred, husband.
As he gives himself to her...
...let the bride inspire and sustain him...
...let her unite with him
in all the experiences of life...
...to which their paths shall lead.
The great moments and the small.
That the joys of each
shall be the joys of both.
And the sorrows of each,
the sorrows of both.
If you wish your new estate
to be touched with lasting beauty...
...cherish those gracious visions
of your first love.
Let them not be blurred
by the common events of life.
Be not moved in your devotion.
Believe in the ideal.
You saw it once.
It still exists.
It is the final truth.
William...
...wilt thou have this woman
to thy wedded wife...
...to live together after God's ordinance
in the holy estate of matrimony?
Hey. I wonder if you could
let me into my apartment.
JANITOR:
Your apartment?
- I'm Mrs. Craig.
- Mr. Craig married?
Obviously. I've been out of town.
He took this place in my absence.
I'll take a chance.
Uh...
Goodbye.
[ALARM RINGING]
[BLENDER WHIRRING]
Flour.
[RATTLING]
"Separate three eggs."
Oh.
Good morning.
What now?
I've come home, Sam.
Afraid I can't agree with you, Tess.
But, Sam.
This is our apartment by the river
you've always wanted, isn't it?
- I'm going to be part of it.
- What's the gag?
Sam, Pop and Ellen were married
last night.
I listened to the words.
You can't listen to them without...
You listened to them once before.
But I didn't hear them. Honestly,
I didn't. I heard them last night, though.
I love you, Sam.
Will you marry me?
You mean love, honor, cherish
and obey until death do us part?
- Yes, Sam.
- You're gonna live here with me?
Kiss me goodbye and wait for me
to come home...
...with stories about
what you and the girls did?
Yes, Sam.
Gonna run up diminity curtains
and sew my underwear?
- Yes.
- Cook and sew...
...and put on your rubber gloves
and wash the dishes?
- Yes, darling.
- This is the top phony of them all.
You've pulled some dandies, but
you've really reached the heights now.
Barging in here at dawn,
flushed and starry-eyed...
...and expect me to see rice
and old shoes floating through the air...
- Sam, why won't you believe me?
- I'll tell you why I won't believe you.
Every time you've tried to duck an issue,
you've made love to me. And I fell for it.
Until, in the office yesterday,
you realized that I was wise to you.
Now, why don't you drop the curtain
on this act.
But, Sam, you don't understand.
I'm gonna give up my job.
Really? What are you gonna do,
run for president?
I'm going to be your wife.
You don't think I can do
the ordinary things any idiot can do.
- No.
- Why not?
Because you're incapable of it.
You can't expect Seabiscuit to stop,
drink a glass of water and count to 7.
- That takes training.
- Well, I'm not Seabiscuit.
Fourth down, you better kick.
Sam, I can't do it.
I've tried, but I can't.
Tess. I'm disappointed in you.
I've been mad, but this is
the first I've been disappointed.
Make them stop.
Why do you have to go
to extremes, Tess?
I don't wanna be married
to Tess Harding...
...any more than I want you to be just
Mrs. Craig. Why can't you be...
...Tess Harding-Craig?
- I think it's a wonderful name.
Miss Harding... Miss Harding!
They told me at the office
that you'd telephoned for this address.
You've got to launch a battleship
at 8:30.
Gerald.
[GLASS SHATTERING]
I've just launched Gerald.
Subtitles by
SDI Media Group
[ENGLISH SDH]