(MAN SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY OVER RADIO)
...and it's
right down the road,
straight down...
And the great...
And there's great sandwiches
and great sourdough bread.
And they have
great soups as well,
and if you have
enough room...
Why do they always
put braces on teenage girls
at the exact moment
they're most self-conscious
about their appearance?
I don't know.
Tom.
I see him.
Tom!
Jesus!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(HORN HONKING)
(SCREAMS)
Tom!
(CRASH)
(TV PLAYING INDISTINCTLY)
(DOORBELL RINGS)
Hello, Amy.
Hi, Darryl.
Amy, can you tell the kids
you'll be right back,
and, uh... Shut the door
and step outside
and talk to us
for a minute?
Okay.
I'll be right back,
you guys.
SAMMY: You're not supposed
to go out, Amy.
TERRY: She's going
to smoke a cigarette.
(INAUDIBLE)
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
Rudy, come on.
I'm really late.
Come on.
(MUSIC PLAYING
INDISTINCTLY ON RADIO)
How was school?
Stupid.
Why do you say that?
We're supposed
to write a story
for English homework,
but they didn't tell us
what it's supposed
to be about.
Well, what do you mean?
I mean, they didn't tell
us what it's supposed
to be about.
They said do
whatever you want.
Oh, well,
what's wrong with that?
I don't know.
I just think
it's unstructured.
Well, I'm sure
you'll think
of something.
If you can't,
I'll help you.
(ENGINE STOPS)
(MUSIC STOPS)
Okay. Here.
Don't forget
your backpack.
It's not a backpack.
It's a knapsack.
Well, then, don't forget
the knapsack.
Hey. Give me a hug.
Okay.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
♪ Somebody somewhere
♪ Don't know what
he's missing tonight
♪ It must have all started
♪ With that darned
old Late Show
♪ It made me so lonely
and sad ♪
Guess who's been
asking for you?
Oh, no. Really?
Is that his car?
Oh, yeah.
BRIAN: Yeah, come in.
SAMMY: Mr. Everett.
Oh, yeah. Brian.
Brian, hi.
Hi. I'm Samantha Ann Prescott.
I'm the lending officer.
Yeah, hi. Hi.
How are you?
Uh, have a seat.
I am so sorry I was late.
Yeah, we missed
you before.
I got held up.
But believe me,
it's nothing
I make a habit of.
Oh, I'm sure it's not.
Actually, would you mind...
Would you get that
door for me, please?
Thanks.
Sure.
So, I always run out
at 3:15 to meet him
and run him real quick
over to the sitter's house.
Anyway, Larry never
seemed to mind about it,
so I was hoping
you'd feel the same way
about it, too.
Well, Samantha,
I realize that Scottsville
is not exactly
a major banking center.
No, it's not.
(CHUCKLING)
No, I know it's not.
But it's kind of
a personal challenge
for me
to see what we can do
to bring local service
up to the kind
of standards that
we would be trying to meet
if we were
the biggest branch
in the state.
Now, that means
I don't really
want anybody
running out
at 3:15 or 3:30
or whenever the bus
happens to
come in that day.
So is there anybody else
who can pick your son
up after school?
Does your husband
work in the area?
Uh, no.
Rudy Sr. isn't on the scene,
so to speak. (LAUGHS SOFTLY)
Well, I can give you
a few days
to make some other
arrangement, but...
Well, Brian...
I understand what
you're saying and
I think it's great. I do.
Because there are
a lot of things here
that could use
some attention,
believe me.
But I've been meeting
this bus every day
for three years now.
And it really does...
It just takes 15 minutes.
And if I take the time
out of my lunch hour...
Well, I'd prefer if
you made some other
arrangement, okay?
I'll do my best.
So, how old's your son?
(SIGHS)
Uh, he's eight.
Ah, that's a terrific age.
RUDY: Got a letter
from Uncle Terry.
What?
(LAUGHS SOFTLY)
What room is
he gonna stay in?
Well, he can stay
in the living room.
And you know what?
He's not gonna live here.
He's only coming
to stay here
for a little while.
And it's okay if you
don't remember him,
because you were only six
the last time he was here.
But, um, I think it's, uh...
It'll be nice
if you guys have a chance
to get to know each other.
Don't you think?
Hey, Rudy,
would it distract you
if I put on some music?
No.
(SOFT MUSIC
PLAYING ON STEREO)
Did you think
of a story?
Uh-huh.
What's it about?
My father.
What about...
What about your father?
Well, it's just
a made-up story
about him.
Can I read it
when you're done?
It's not very good.
Don't say that.
(SIGHS)
Anyway, Bob,
it's kind of this
adventure story.
Rudy's father
is a secret agent
or something, you know,
working for
the government.
And it made me
feel kind of weird,
you know,
because I never
say much to him
about Rudy Sr.,
because I don't
know what to say.
And I don't know if
I should just let him
imagine what
he wants to imagine,
or if I should sit
him down sometime
and, you know, tell him
that his father's not
such a nice person.
Well, I don't know, Sammy.
What have you
told him already?
Not much.
He knows...
He knows I don't have
the highest opinion of him,
and he knows that
I don't want to see him
and I don't want to know
anything about him
and I don't want
to have anything
to do with him ever.
But I've tried to keep it
kind of neutral.
(CHUCKLING)
Anyway, I could go into
a lot more detail...
No, it's an
interesting problem.
I don't really know
what to tell you.
It's, um, you know,
a little outside
my personal field
of expertise.
All right.
I'd be glad to
give it some thought.
Okay.
What?
No, nothing.
I'm just glad
to see you.
I'm glad you called me.
I bet you were surprised.
Yeah, a little.
I should get going.
Really?
Yeah, I have
the babysitter.
Oh.
But thanks for
a lovely evening.
Oh, thank you.
(UPBEAT MUSIC
PLAYING INDISTINCTLY)
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Hey.
SHEILA: Hey, Terry.
Where'd you get that hat?
I got it on the street
for a dollar.
It's nice.
Well, you know,
it's pretty much
your standard woolen hat.
I had a very similar
reaction to it.
Uh...
Can I get that
money from you?
(CHUCKLES EMBARRASSEDLY)
Oh, yeah. Sorry.
(UNZIPS BAG)
Is that all you have?
Yeah.
Can you borrow
some more
from your brother?
Well, that would involve
speaking to him.
Well, I'm definitely
gonna be gone
for a couple
of days, Sheila.
I mean...
Why do you have
to stay for so long?
Because my sister
is not a bank, okay?
I can't just show up...
You seem to think
my brother's a bank.
Can we just cut
the puerile crap?
I'm gonna be back
as soon as I can, okay?
I am not the kind of guy
that everyone says I am.
I know you're not.
(SIGHS)
Okay. Uh...
I'll call you tonight.
Don't you wanna tell me
that you love me?
I love you.
That was really convincing.
(SIGHS)
Well, I think
after this is over,
you should seriously
consider moving back home.
Yeah.
(SIGHS)
All right.
So you'll call me tonight?
Definitely, yeah.
♪ I'm gonna wipe
this teardrop from my eyes
♪ There ain't no use
for me to cry
♪ And there's something's
I think I need to say
(PHONE RINGING)
♪ I'll think
about you everyday ♪
Hello? Terry!
Whoa.
Terry.
That's me.
Terry Prescott.
That's right.
Well, give me a cuddle.
How are you doing?
Good to see you, man.
You, too. How you
doing, Darryl?
Where the hell have you been?
Oh, man,
I've been all over
the place.
Which way you headed?
I'm going up to see
Sammy at the square.
Can I walk
with you a bit?
Yeah, yeah.
So she said
you'd been to Alaska?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Oh, how you doing,
Mr. Parker?
Good to see you.
Yeah, take care.
So what were you doing?
Were you working up there?
Mmm... Yeah, yeah.
Sammy says she was
getting postcards from
all across the country.
Oh, yeah.
I've been all over, man.
Pretty cool.
It's good to
have you back here,
I'll tell you that.
Oh, thanks, Darryl.
Good to see you, too.
Keep enforcing the peace.
It'll be a little harder now
you're here,
but I'll do what I can.
No, man, I'm reformed.
Oh, yeah.
All right.
Hey, I'll see you around.
Don't be a stranger,
all right?
You, too. Take care.
Sorry about yesterday.
I don't care.
I was studying
the bus description,
and I got on
the wrong bus.
I mean,
I missed my stop.
I don't care, Terry.
I'm so glad to see you.
I'm glad to see you,
too, Sammy.
Um, so you're coming
from work?
Uh...
No, it's Saturday.
Yeah.
No, it's just you're
dressed so formally.
Oh. No. You know,
I thought I'd...
(STAMMERING)
You know, I thought it
was a special occasion,
which it is.
Oh, it's good.
No, it's good.
I thought I'd get
dressed up, too.
It's okay. You look fine.
Yeah, yeah.
This is the haute cuisine
of garments.
What?
Nothing, nothing.
So, how are you?
I'm fine, Terry.
So... Um, how's Rudy?
We're fine, Terry.
How are you?
Uh, yeah.
Where have you
been lately, Terry?
Uh, no,
I haven't been...
I got a postcard
from you from Alaska.
Yeah, yeah.
I was out there
for a little while.
That was in
the fall, Terry.
Yeah. I know.
I've been out of touch.
I was a little worried.
I mean...
I've been to a lot
of different places.
Uh, I was down in Florida
for a little while.
Uh, I was doing some
work in Orlando.
Man, I've been
all over the place.
Well, I wish you
had just let me know
you were okay.
Yeah, I didn't realize
it had been so long.
(CHUCKLES)
You staying in town
for a while?
Well, I don't know.
Uh, I got all these things
I got to do back in Worcester.
Oh.
So I'm probably
not gonna be able
to stay for more
than a day or so.
Oh.
I mean, I'm trying
to keep to
a schedule of sorts.
Mmm-hmm.
Oh. That's...
I just...
That's all right.
(LAUGHS SOFTLY)
It's a very worthy story,
but I won't trouble
you with it right now.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Are you
expecting someone?
Who would I
be expecting here?
You just keep
looking around,
that's all.
I was just, you know,
actually wondering
if we could get some more
refreshments, actually.
I actually gotta confess
to you, Sammy,
that the reason that
you may not have heard
from me for a while
is that...
I've been unable
to write on the account
of the fact that
I was in jail
for a little while.
You were what?
I served a little time,
I guess, down in Florida.
It was just for...
It was for bullshit.
What?
What did you do?
I didn't do anything.
Does it occur to you
that maybe I was wronged?
No! Oh, my God!
Well...
Would you please...
Please let me tell
you what happened.
What happened?
I got into a fight in
a bar down in Florida.
Which I was not the one
who instigated it at all.
Then they worked up
all this bullshit
against me
and threw me in the pen
for three months.
I didn't write you 'cause
I didn't want you
to get all upset about it.
I just figured that
you would figure
I was on the road
for a little while.
It was stupid.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean
to make you worry.
But you wanna
know what?
I can't run around
doing stuff
or not doing stuff
because it's gonna
make you worry.
Because then I come back here,
I tell you about
my fucking traumas,
and I get this wounded
little, "I've let you down"
bullshit
over and over again.
It just cramps me.
I just wanna get
out from under it.
And now I'm back
in this fucking hole
explaining myself
to you again.
Will you please stop
cursing at me?
I realize that
I'm in no position
to basically say
anything ever,
but it's not like
I'm down there
in some redneck bar
in Florida,
I'm having an argument
with some
stripper's boyfriend
and I suddenly say to myself,
"Hey, this would be
a great time
"to really stick it to Sammy
"and get myself locked up
for a few months."
Hey! You don't write me
for six months.
I don't know
where you are!
I'm sorry.
I don't know if
you're alive or dead!
I'm sorry.
And then you show up
out of nowhere.
You tell me
you were in jail!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Sammy.
I'm really sorry.
(SIGHS)
Sammy.
What?
I'm in the midst of
a slight predicament.
What do you need, money?
Um, yeah.
Hmm.
I'm broke.
I got to get back to
Worcester tomorrow.
I got this girl there,
and she's kind of
in a bad situation.
So I just need to
borrow some money,
whatever you can spare.
I'll pay you back, man.
I'll pay you back.
I just...
I really wish
Mom was here.
So do I, man.
No one knows
what to do with you.
Well, I know
how they feel, man.
Terry, can I ask you
a question?
Sure.
I mean...
Do you ever go
to church anymore?
Come on, Sammy.
Can we not talk
about that shit?
Do you?
Um, no, Sammy, I don't.
Can you tell me
why not?
Um, yeah, because I think
it's ridiculous.
Well, can you tell me
without, like, degrading
what I believe in?
I think it's primitive, okay?
I think it's a fairy tale.
Well, have you
ever considered
that maybe that's part
of what's making things
so difficult for you?
No.
That you've lost hold
of, I mean,
not just your
religious feeling,
but lost hold of
any kind of anchor.
I mean, any kind of
trust in anything.
No wonder you
drift around so much.
I mean,
what's to stop you?
How would you ever know
if you found
the right thing?
I'm not really looking
for anything, man.
I'm just, like,
trying to get on with it.
Here we go.
Thank you.
(KEYPAD BEEPING)
(SIGHS)
Thanks, Sammy.
I'm really gonna
pay you back.
Where we going?
To pick up Rudy.
Well, do you not even
want me to visit now?
Because I can
catch the bus at 5:00,
if that's what you want.
Of course I want you
to visit, you idiot!
I've been looking forward
to seeing you
more than anything.
I told everybody I know
that you were coming home.
I cleaned
the whole fucking house
so it would
look nice for you.
I mean,
I thought you'd stay
at least a few days.
I had no idea
that you were
just broke again.
I wish you'd just
sent me an invoice!
(WATER DRIPPING)
(VIDEO GAME PINGING)
Hi, is that...
Is that Malcolm?
Uh... Hi. This is...
This is Terry Prescott.
I'm trying to get
a hold of Sheila,
and the phone
isn't picking up.
And I was wondering
if maybe you guys...
She what?
(SIGHS)
Well, is she all right?
Uh...
Can I...
Can I talk to her, please?
Okay.
Um, then can you please
give her a message
and tell her that I...
That girl I'm with
tried to kill herself.
What?
She tried
to kill herself.
Do you have
everything you need?
I think so.
What are you gonna do?
I don't know.
Just send her
the money, I guess.
Maybe you should stay home
for a while.
Yeah, maybe that'd
be a good idea.
(SOBBING)
(BELLS TOLLING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
MAN ON TV:
This 15-year-old says
she's sick of her brother
trying to control her.
She's dropped out of school,
she's doing drugs
and says there's nothing
he can do about it.
(VIDEO GAME PINGING)
(CLICKS TONGUE)
SAMMY: I'm going to bed.
Do you have
everything you need?
Uh, yeah, thanks.
Good night.
Terry,
I'm really glad
you're home.
Yeah, me, too, Sammy.
Okay. So we'll drop
Rudy off at the bus,
and then all you have to do
is drop me off at the bank
and then pick Rudy up
at 3:30
and drive him over
to Carol's house.
And that's it.
She lives on Harvey Lane
right past where
the Dewitts used to live.
Okay.
Rudy knows
where she lives.
Okay.
(TYPING)
God, Mabel,
don't those colors
hurt your eyes?
Oh, no.
It keeps me fresh.
(KNOCKING)
BRIAN: Yeah?
Oh. Hi, Sammy.
What can I do for you?
Um, Brian, did you
want us to hand
these timesheets in
at the end of the day
or at the end of the week?
Uh, yeah, end of the day
will be fine.
It just seems
like an awful lot
of extra paperwork.
I like paperwork.
You showed up.
Looks that way.
Put on your seat belt.
It pushes on my neck.
What?
It's uncomfortable.
Well, when someone
slams into us
and you go sailing
through the windshield,
that's liable to be
uncomfortable, too.
Now put on your seat belt.
Mom's parents died
in a car accident.
Yeah, I know.
They're my parents, too.
They are?
Yeah.
Your mom's my sister.
Yeah, I know.
So that means
we have the same parents.
Oh, yeah.
Um, Carol just called.
She said that
Terry and Rudy never
showed up at her house.
You've got to
be kidding.
These have to be
filed by number
by the account number,
not alphabetically.
Sammy?
Sammy!
(HAMMERING)
Hey.
What are you doing?
Look.
If you hold it
further down,
you're gonna get
a lot more power
on that. You know?
You should be
able to hit that nail
in two or three hits. Look.
See?
Go ahead, try it.
That's not the way
I hold it.
Well, the way
you hold it is wrong.
Why can't I just
hold it my own way?
You can.
TERRY: One there,
one there,
and one over there.
All right?
You got that?
Right. Good.
That's it.
Um...
Brian, did you
wanna see me?
Yeah. Yeah, I was kind of
wondering what happened
to you today.
Oh, didn't Mabel tell you?
I had a false alarm
about my son.
Yeah, well,
I kind of thought you were
gonna work that out.
Well, I did work it out,
more or less.
Well, then, what are you
doing leaving here
in the middle of the day
without so much as
a word of explanation
to me, Sammy?
Brian, don't yell at me.
I'm not yelling at you.
I'm just...
I'm getting
a little frustrated here.
Well...
Sorry. Would you
close the door, please?
(SIGHS)
And Eddie Dwyer
lives in Buffalo with
his wife and two kids,
if you can believe it.
TERRY:
Oh, that's depressing.
Why?
He just never struck me
as the marrying type.
Who are you
talking about?
Some wild kids
we used to know.
Were you a wild kid?
Not as wild
as your mom.
Yeah, right.
What, you don't
believe me?
No.
Ask her.
Mom, were you?
No comment.
♪ Mendocino
♪ Where life's
such a groove
♪ You blow your mind
in the morning
♪ Hey! We used to walk
through the park
♪ Make love along the way
in Mendocino ♪
(DRAWER OPENING)
(PAPERS RUSTLING)
What are you doing?
Oh... Just reading
some of your compositions.
Why are you smoking?
Um, because it's bad.
Don't ever do it.
I won't.
You know this used to
be my room?
Yeah.
Do you want it back?
No.
Did you fight
in Vietnam?
No, I wasn't
even born yet.
Were you ever
in the army?
No.
My father was
in the army.
I know. Unfortunately,
he didn't fight
in Vietnam, either.
Were you friends
with him?
Mmm... Not really. I mean,
we had some friends
in common, I guess.
I didn't like him
very much.
Why not?
Well, he wasn't
very likable.
Why do you say that?
I don't know.
He was always, like...
He always had to be better
than you at everything,
you know?
Like, if we were
all playing basketball
or something,
everybody's having,
like, a friendly game,
and he's ready to, like,
kill somebody if
his team didn't win.
Or, like, if you told,
like, a joke or a story,
he always had
to tell a better one.
Kind of gets annoying
after a while.
Plus, I thought
it was pretty scummy
how he split on
you and your mom.
He was a prick.
Probably still a prick.
Fortunately for you,
though, your mom is,
like, the greatest.
So you had some bad luck
and you had some good luck.
You mind if I ask you
a personal question?
I don't know.
Do you like it here?
I mean, in Scottsville?
Yeah.
Why? (SCOFFS)
I don't know.
My friends are here.
I like the scenery.
I don't know.
I know, I know.
It's just so...
There's nothing to do here.
Yes, there is.
No, there isn't, man.
It's narrow, it's dull.
It's a dull, narrow town
full of dull, narrow people
who don't know anything
except what things are like
right around here.
They have no
perspective whatsoever.
No scope.
They might as well be living
in the 19th century,
because they have no idea
what's going on.
And if you try
and tell them that,
they wanna fucking kill you.
What are you talking about?
I have no idea.
(SIGHS)
You're a good kid.
Yeah, this doesn't
apply to you, Sammy, but
I've noticed that some
of the employees are
setting their PC monitors
to all kinds
of crazy colors.
Purple, polka dot,
what have you.
And it's no
big deal, but...
I mean, really, this is
a bank, you know? It's
really not appropriate.
So I'm asking that
people use a more,
"normal range of
colors in future".
But like I said,
this doesn't
really apply to you.
No, my computer palette's
pretty conservative.
(TYPING)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(PHONE RINGING)
Bob Steegerson.
SAMMY: What are you wearing?
Mom?
What's up?
Do you know
that you have
an enormous leak
coming from the
upstairs hallway here?
Yeah, I did.
(LAUGHS)
(LOUD HAMMERING)
Are you guys sure
you're gonna be okay?
(CLATTERING)
Yes, yes.
What is happening here?
It's just
the problem is
the pipes are
corroded the whole
length of the hall.
So every time I
put a new piece in,
it starts
leaking further down.
Why don't I just
call the plumber?
Why? He's not gonna
do anything different
than what I'm doing.
Yeah,
we're only
making it worse.
No, we're not. Shut up.
Thanks. Thank you.
So call if there
are any problems.
If I'm not there,
I'm either on my way
back home or on my way.
Okay. Nice to
meet you, Bob.
Yeah, you, too.
So, lights out at 10:00.
Don't spend the
whole night watching TV.
What's your idea
of the whole night?
Two hours, tops.
After you.
(LAUGHS)
(MAN SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY ON TV)
This kid is a sure
bet to lead the way
for the next generation
of California surfers.
What's your
feeling about Bob?
I don't really
know him that well.
Well, I got bad
news for you.
No...
Great.
Now what are we
supposed to do?
You know how
to play pool?
I've played it.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
I don't think they
let kids in here.
What?
I don't think they
let kids in here.
Well, we're not allowed
to watch any more TV,
so it's this or nothing.
But if we get
into any trouble,
you let me do
the talking, okay?
Okay.
Uh, I got
100 bucks here
says me and my nephew
can beat anybody in here.
Only we got to
get the next game,
because he's got to
be in bed by 10:00.
Just hit it nice and soft.
Nice and soft.
One, two, three.
Sorry.
Goddamn, Rudy.
I thought you
said you could play.
Boys, it's all over
but the crying.
(CUE STICK STRIKES)
Bob, are you...
Are you serious?
Yeah.
(STAMMERING)
I don't know what...
I don't know what to say.
Sammy, I mean, I...
Look, I... I know that
I haven't been the most, uh...
...decisive guy in the past.
But I don't know.
I am tired of
fooling around.
And I love you.
Uh, I'm totally...
(STUTTERING) I don't
know what to say.
You could
always say "Yes".
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Or you could think
about it some more.
Would you like
to think about it?
Yeah, that's it.
I wanna think about it.
Okay.
All right. Well, uh...
Fair enough.
(BOTH LAUGH NERVOUSLY)
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(GROANS)
(BALL STRIKES)
♪ She's strange
(CUE STICK STRIKES)
♪ While she looks so sweet
♪ But she can make you weak,
she's strange
♪ And she's long
♪ She's long
♪ Well you think
you are tough
♪ But then it turns out
you're not
♪ She's long
♪ She's kind
It's all yours, baby.
♪ You don't waste your voice
She don't leave you a choice
♪ She's kind
♪ She's mine ♪
Just make sure to hit it
really gentle, but firm.
And hit it a little low
so you can get some backspin.
Okay?
Don't even hit it.
Just kiss it.
What do you mean,
kiss it?
I mean, tap it.
Firm but
very, very softly.
And don't take
the shot until you know
you're gonna make it, okay?
Okay.
(ALL CHEERING)
We creamed those guys.
We creamed them.
(SHUSHING)
Don't move,
don't move.
Let's go.
Go, go, go,
go, go, go!
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
What is going on here?
(BOTH PANTING)
(SNORTS)
(LAUGHING)
We were out
doing some
stargazing and...
Rudy lost track of time,
(LAUGHING) which I totally
warned him about.
You are a bad kid.
Hey, I think it's okay.
Just don't tell
her where we went,
'cause she'll be
really mad at me, okay?
I won't.
Hey.
I mean it, Rudy.
I'm not kidding.
I won't.
Did you know
my mommy used
to take me and
Uncle Terry out at night
to look at
the constellations?
Yeah.
Did you see that one...
Oh, what's the one?
It looks like
a big "W".
Cassiopeia?
Yeah.
(DOOR CREAKING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(THUD)
Ow! Shit!
I've got a great idea.
Why don't I call the plumber?
Do whatever you want.
Oh, what?
That makes you mad?
No.
Ow!
I'm sorry.
Geez.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(SWITCH CLICKS)
Brian, get off my ass.
Excuse me?
I did not change the
colors on your stupid
computer screen.
Well, then,
that's all
you gotta say.
There's nothing wrong
with the work I do here.
I didn't say there was.
I was doing just fine
the whole time
before you got here.
And if you think
that riding people
in this petty, ridiculous way
is gonna improve service
at this bank or
anywhere else...
Can I please...
... you're out of your mind.
May I respond?
No, that's really
all I have to say.
May I respond?
First of all,
I would appreciate it
if you would not
use that language
when you're speaking to me.
I don't talk to you that way,
and I would appreciate it
if you didn't
talk to me that way.
Second of all, if you
tell me that you didn't
change the colors
on my computer screen,
then of course I
accept your answer.
But you and I are
gonna have to find
a way to work together.
Brian...
And that's not gonna happen
with the attitude,
with the lateness.
I do not have an attitude
and I am not late!
And it's not gonna happen
with you fighting me
every step of the way.
Okay, not you.
You're not late personally.
Well, then, don't say
I'm late if I'm not late.
I would like to finish.
(ARGUMENT CONTINUES
DISTANTLY)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(DISTANT TAPPING)
(TV PLAYING INDISTINCTLY)
MAN: (ON TV) Robert says
he won't listen to his
stepfather because...
Hey.
Uh...
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
They were where?
MAN: (ON TV) Her brother
tries to discipline her,
but he works nights.
Okay, you're all set.
Dave, my wife, Nancy.
Hello.
Hi.
And, uh...
(CLEARS THROAT) Mabel...
This is my wife
Nancy. Mabel.
Hi.
Nice to meet you.
And, uh, Chuck.
Hi. Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
This is Sammy,
our lending officer.
Sammy, this
is my wife Nancy.
Hi, nice to meet you.
Brian,
I gotta sit down.
Yeah, sure.
Let's go into my office.
If you want,
I can give you a ride home,
you know?
I'm fine!
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(KNOCKING)
Brian?
Yeah?
Mom.
Rudy!
Look. I am really
glad that you guys
are getting along so well,
like you have no idea.
But if I can't rely on
you to remember
to get him once a day...
You can!
What are you
doing taking him
to play pool in
the middle of the night
and then telling him
to lie to me about it?
I don't know.
God!
(ENGINE STOPS)
Get out of the car.
What are we doing?
You're going to Carol's,
and I'm going home.
Why can't I
come with you?
Because if you're
such a baby
that you gotta tell
your mommy about
us playing pool
when I totally
asked you not to
and I gotta listen
to her shit all day,
then you are going
to the babysitter's
so you can stay
at the baby house.
But I didn't...
You know what?
Don't even
fucking talk to me.
I didn't.
Get out.
(KNOCKING SOFTLY)
You're working late.
How'd your wife
like the bank?
Oh, fine.
She wasn't
feeling so great.
Oh, that's too bad.
Oh, no, I don't mean...
She's not ill.
She just... I don't know.
Pregnant?
Yeah, that's right.
She's pregnant.
Well, it can make
you kind of cranky.
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah.
Look, I'm sorry
that we've been stepping
on each other's toes.
Yeah, so am I.
I'm really not
that bad a guy.
I know you're not,
Brian, but you're
driving everybody crazy.
Well, (SIGHS) I'm trying
to do my best here.
And I'm getting
it from all sides.
I know you are.
Anyway, we'll work it out.
Well, I could
use a beer.
I could use a tranquilizer.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Last I heard, Rudy's dad
was living in Auburn.
But that was
a year ago.
It must be so tough,
trying to raise
a kid on your own.
I'm starting to think
my wife wouldn't
mind a crack at it.
Oh, it's just hormones.
Well, no,
it isn't, but never mind.
Thanks.
Sure.
Well,
here's to improved
employee-management relations.
Amen.
You know, you can't judge
all of Scottsville
by the people in that bank,
believe me.
Well, (SIGHS) let's, um...
Let's not talk
about the bank.
Okay.
Let's just forget
about the bank for tonight.
Good idea.
Sammy?
Yeah?
I want you to
tell me who changed
the colors on my
computer screen.
SAMMY: I'll never tell.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
TERRY: Where were you?
Nowhere.
I had dinner with my boss.
Kind of a late dinner,
ain't it?
Yeah.
How is Rudy?
Fine. He's asleep.
Did the plumber come?
Yeah, the fucking
plumber came.
Terry, just give
me a break!
What's the
matter with you?
Nothing!
I'm... I'm just tired.
(BOTTLE OPENS)
(BOTTLE CAP CLATTERS)
Wanna smoke some pot?
No, I don't.
Why, you got some?
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
So, Bob asked me
to marry him.
Wow. What are
you gonna do?
I don't know.
If he'd asked me
the same time last year,
I probably would've said yes.
But I don't know.
The minute he asked me,
it was like someone
was trying to strangle me.
Whoa. Bad sign.
Yeah, I know.
Plus...
(WHISPERING) Terry,
I fucked my boss.
(WHISPERING) What?
I know.
I know. His wife is
six months pregnant.
Jesus Christ, Sammy!
I know, I know.
Oh...
I'm sorry I got so
mad at you before.
I just...
Oh, man, it's cool.
I don't want him to
be afraid of telling.
You know,
I just don't want
him to be scared.
I really don't think
that's his problem, Sammy.
No? What...
What do you think
his problem is?
Well, I think his
problem is that he's
totally sheltered.
I mean, you treat
the kid like he's
three instead of eight,
so that's how
he behaves.
Uh-huh.
Well, how do you think
he should behave?
Well, I don't think he
should have to run and
tell Mommy every time
he does something
that she might not
approve of, for one thing.
Uh-huh.
I mean, I took him
to play pool, okay?
It was a little
clandestine thing
we did for fun.
It wasn't a big secret.
I mean, who cares?
I mean,
I was actually
trying to be nice to him.
But he's so
freaked out that he
disobeyed your orders
that he's got to
fucking squeal on me,
and then I got
to fucking listen
to your shit all day.
And I didn't
fucking do anything.
Okay.
First of all,
he didn't say anything.
Darryl did. Okay?
And second of all,
I don't give a shit
if you take him
out to play pool.
I was mad at you
because you left him
at the bus stop in the rain.
But no, I don't want
you telling him
not to squeal
because I don't want him
put in that position.
(SIGHS)
Well, that is
a perfect example of
what I'm talking about.
You are an idiot.
So what are you saying?
Darryl told you?
Yes!
(SIGHS)
(TELEPHONE RINGING DISTANTLY)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Good morning.
BRIAN: Yeah,
good morning.
Could you shut
the door, please?
Brian, I just want to...
(BOTH BREATHING HEAVILY)
Brian.
(LAUGHING)
That's enough.
You're awfully quiet.
Sorry.
So have you thought at all
about what I said?
(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)
Well, sure,
I've been thinking about it.
So any decisions, or...
Do you want to
think about it
some more?
Well, I mean...
I don't know, Bob.
I mean, it's not like
we've been going steady
for the last few months,
if you know what I mean.
Yeah. No, I know.
And then we see
each other twice,
and then you suddenly
say you want to get married?
No, you're right.
(STAMMERING) You're right.
I mean, what are
you talking about?
I... I don't know. I...
Last year, I...
I thought that
maybe you were possibly
interested in that idea.
But I was the one
who wasn't ready,
you know, at that point,
so that's why
I sort of thought things
slowed down with us.
Don't make me
feel bad for you.
I don't want you
to feel bad for me.
WOMAN ON TV: Yeah? Well,
where were you last night?
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello.
It's Brian.
Brian, where are you?
I'm buying milk.
Just thought
I'd say hello.
Look, I know it's
probably too late, but...
Is there any way
you can come out
for a little while?
Brian, I think
you're going crazy.
(LAUGHS)
I know I am.
Can you meet me?
Um...
Okay.
(TV CONTINUES PLAYING)
(KEYS JANGLING)
Um, I have to go out
for a little while.
Do you want anything?
Like what?
I don't know.
Where are you going?
Yeah,
where are you going?
Um, I... I just have to go out
for a little while.
Where?
Yeah, where?
I'm going
to Mabel's house.
Why?
You know what, Rudy?
It's personal.
It's... It's a personal matter
that has to do with Mabel,
and I just have to go
see her for a little while.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Listen.
Listen, I'm sorry
I said you squealed on me.
I was totally out of line
and I really owe you
an apology.
Did you hear me?
I don't care.
WOMAN: (OVER RADIO)
I'd like to introduce myself.
♪ I'm the other woman
♪ The other woman
in your husband's life
♪ Now everybody's
blaming me
♪ I'm the other woman
♪ But who are they to judge
who's wrong or right
♪ Their whispers
might be different... ♪
(SHUDDERING) Ugh!
Ugh!
(LAUGHING)
(LAUGHS)
What's on your mind,
Sammy?
Well, a lot.
But, principally,
I was just wondering
if you had an opinion.
If you know
someone in your family
or even just someone
who you really care about
and they just can't quite
get a hold of themselves...
Ah... Guess who
these are for?
Me!
That's right,
my little friend.
Hello.
We're going fishing.
I got a new rod
and reel, five lures,
a hat, a knife
and a fish scaler.
That's great, sweetie.
(DOORBELL RINGING)
I'll get it.
Well, I'm not really sure
why you're here, Ron.
I know I haven't exactly
been the model citizen
since I got here,
but considering how
things have been going
for me lately,
I thought I was
doing pretty well.
And I also find it
kind of discouraging
that you seem to think
that I'm in need of
some sort of spiritual
guidance or what have you,
so much so,
that you're willing
to disregard the fact
that I don't believe in
any of this stuff at all.
Well, I didn't mean
to discourage you.
Yeah, I find it
kind of insulting.
Can I...
Can I say something here?
Sammy asked me to
come talk to you
because it's her opinion
that you're not gonna find
what you're looking for
the way you've
been looking for it.
And how would she know?
But I'm really not here
to try to get you to
do anything
or to try to get you to
believe in anything.
And I'll tell you
the same thing I told her,
which is that as
far as I'm concerned,
the only way she can help you
is by her example,
by trying to be
a model for you
in the way
she lives her life.
And that doesn't mean
that she's supposed
to be a saint either,
if that's what
you're smiling about.
I didn't realize
I was smiling.
(SIGHS)
You know, Terry,
a lot of people
come to see me
with all kinds of problems.
Drugs, alcohol,
marital problems,
sexual problems...
Good job you have, man.
Well, I like it.
Because even in
this little town,
I really feel like
what I do is
very connected with the real
center of people's lives.
I'm not saying
I'm always Mr. Effective,
but I don't feel like
my life is off to the side
of what's important.
I don't feel
that my happiness
and comfort
are based on
closing my eyes
to trouble within myself
or trouble
in other people.
I don't feel like
a negligible little scrap
floating around
in some kind of empty void
with no sense
of connectedness
to anything around me
except by virtue of whatever
little philosophies
I can scrape together
on my own.
Well...
Can I ask you, Terry,
do you think
your life is important?
Um... You mean, like,
me personally, like,
my individual life?
Yeah.
Mmm, I'm not really sure.
What do you mean?
I mean, it's important
to me, I guess,
and, like, to my,
you know, the people
who care about me.
But do you think
it's important?
Do you think it's important
in the scheme of things
not just because
it's yours
or because
you're somebody's
brother.
Because I really
don't get the impression
that you do.
(SIGHS)
I don't particularly
think that anybody's life
has any
particular importance
besides whatever,
you know, like, whatever
we arbitrarily give it.
Which is fine.
I mean, you know,
we might as well.
I mean, I think
my life is as important
as anybody else's.
I don't know, Ron.
A lot of what you're saying
has real appeal to me.
You know,
the stuff they told us
when we were kids.
But I don't want to
believe in something
or not believe in it
because I might feel bad.
I want to believe in
it or not believe in it
because I think
it's true or not.
Yeah, I mean,
I want to think that
my life is important.
That it's connected
to something important.
Well, isn't there
any way for you
to believe that
without calling it God
or religion or whatever term
it is that you object to?
Yeah, I believe that.
So, Sammy, what example
will you be setting
for us tonight?
(TV PLAYING INDISTINCTLY)
What time are
we getting up
to go fishing?
We're not going fishing.
What do you mean?
Why not?
I think you should
go fishing
with Father Ron.
I don't want
to go fishing
with Father Ron.
Well, I'm not gonna
take you.
(EXHALES)
I'll take you, sweetie.
(WATER RUNNING)
(LOW) I realize
you're mad at me.
I'm not mad at you.
But he didn't do
anything to you.
And you cannot promise
a little boy...
It's just after all
that religious conversation,
I just realized
it's probably
not so good for him
to be spending
so much time with someone
who doesn't believe
that his life is important
in the scheme of things.
Would you please?
I'm serious.
Listen.
I am sure if you
put your mind to it,
you can think
of some other way
of getting back
at me besides this.
So would you please
just give it some thought
and take him
fishing tomorrow?
I would, Sammy,
but I really don't think
it's good for him.
You suck!
(FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
(DOOR SLAMS)
(PHONE RINGING)
(GRUNTS)
Hello?
(PHONE RINGING)
(PHONE BEEPING)
(BELLS TOLLING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Hi.
You remember
my wife Nancy.
Oh, yes.
Hello.
Nice to see you.
Father, nice job.
Thank you.
(INAUDIBLE)
(WHISTLING)
(ENGINE STARTS)
Anyway, I don't know
what the church's
official position is
on fornication and
adultery these days.
I felt really hypocritical
not saying anything
to you about it before.
So what is
the official position
these days?
Well, it's a sin.
Good. I think
it should be.
But we try not to focus
on that aspect
of it too much
right off the bat.
Why not?
I think you should.
Well... Well...
I mean, maybe it was better
when you came in here
and they screamed
at you for having sex
with your married boss.
They told you what
a terrible thing it was.
They were really
mean to you.
Maybe it would be better
if you told me
that I was endangering
my immortal soul,
and that if...
If I don't quit,
I'm gonna burn in hell.
Don't you ever
think that?
Um...
No.
Well, it would be
a lot better
than all this,
"Why do you think
you're in this situation"
psychological bullshit
you hear all the time.
(LAUGHS)
Well, why do you think
you're in this situation?
With which one?
All of them.
I feel sorry for them.
Isn't that ridiculous?
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
I've never been so bored
in my whole life.
We should've been here
around 7:00, 8:00 a. m.
What time is it now?
2:30.
Was my father
a good fisherman?
Yeah, he was good
at all that stuff,
you know?
He knew everything
about the woods,
everything about hunting,
everything about fishing
and everything about cars.
If he wasn't such
a pain in the ass,
he would've been a lot
of fun to be around.
Maybe he's nicer now.
I doubt it.
Well, I think he is.
Well, how would you know?
Did you ever meet him?
No.
You ever been curious
about meeting him?
I guess so.
He lives near here.
I thought he lived
in Alaska.
No, I lived in Alaska.
He lives in Auburn,
as far as I know.
We could look him up
in the phone book.
Wanna try it?
All right.
But, Rudy, I'm sure
I don't have
to tell you this,
but I'm not kidding, man.
Don't tell your mother.
Can I get you something?
Or, hey, do you want
to go for a walk or a drive?
It's really nice out.
No, I'm not
gonna stay long.
Bob, I don't want
to get married.
Okay.
I've been thinking about it
for a long time,
and if you had
asked me last year,
I'm sure I would
have said yes.
Oh, (CHUCKLES)
thank you.
But I don't think
it would've been
a good idea then either.
I've been going through
a really hard time lately,
and I just...
I think that getting
engaged to you
or anybody else
would be probably
the stupidest,
most self-destructive thing
I could possibly do.
Okay.
And I really think
you need to grow up.
Well, how's about
we fix my personality
some other time?
Okay.
I really hope
we can still be friends.
Oh. Yes. Me, too.
Bob...
I mean, Bob.
What?
I don't know.
I just... I...
Sammy,
I love you. I...
I really...
(STUTTERS)
I love you.
Well, I love you, too.
Oh, shit!
What? What?
I... I gotta go.
I'm sorry.
Where?
Where do you have to go?
I have to get Mabel her car.
Now? I don't understand.
How are we
leaving things?
I don't know.
Call me later.
This is incredible.
Hmm.
That is not
what I mean.
(COUNTRY MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO)
♪ I was born on this land
♪ This land is my home
♪ And she holds me
and keeps me
from worrying
♪ Well, it took
everything she gave
♪ Now they're gone... ♪
Maybe we should
call first.
Well, we're right here.
(ENGINE STOPS)
(MUSIC STOPS)
TERRY: Come on.
(DOGS BARKING)
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
There he is.
His last name
is Kolinsky?
Yeah. Come on.
Go ahead, knock.
MAN: (ON TV) Out of the yard,
and the Mets add another run
to their lead.
It's now 7-2, Mets.
Yes?
Hi. Uh,
we're looking for Rudy.
Who should
I say is calling?
An old friend.
RUDY SR.: Who is it?
He says an old friend.
RUDY SR.: How old is he?
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Hey!
Hey, Rudy.
Hey.
Hi, I'm Terry.
Hello.
Um, this is Rudy.
You don't say.
Rudy, meet Rudy.
I'll just be
in the kitchen.
TERRY: Nice meeting you.
Okay if we come
in for a minute?
What the hell
are you doing?
What do you mean
what am I doing?
Could you back away
from the door, please?
Just want to
come in for...
Would you back away
from the door, please?
TERRY: All right, all right.
What are you doing here?
Just wanted the kid
to see you, man.
Well, now he saw me.
Now you saw me,
all right? (SCOFFS)
Now, do you mind?
Man, you really...
(CHUCKLES)
I'm trying to be
polite, all right?
So would you just take off?
It's okay. Just take off.
I just wanna...
Do you know what
you're doing here?
Get out of here,
all right?
You know what, man?
You're still a
fucking asshole.
I'm an asshole?
Get out of here.
(GRUNTS)
TERRY: Fucking asshole!
Get your fucking
hands off him!
(CRIES OUT)
Get off!
RUDY SR.:
Fucking woman!
Get the fuck...
MAN: Hey, break it up!
Listen, Officer,
I came down here...
I just came down
here to talk to the guy,
and he starts
shoving me.
You're not the boy's
legal guardian?
I don't even know
if that's my kid.
Fucking lying piece of shit.
WOMAN: He showed up
out of nowhere,
next thing I know
they're outside fighting.
RUDY SR.:
I used to know his sister.
WOMAN: He's on our property.
I don't know
who this guy is.
TERRY: Why don't you shut up?
WOMAN: Man, you know
you came here for it.
You have nothing to
do with this, lady.
We have a right to
protect ourselves.
TERRY: I just came here
to talk to the guy,
and he starts
shoving me.
(ALL CLAMORING)
TERRY: Listen to them.
You can hear,
they're out of their minds.
RUDY SR.: Out of our minds?
You showed up at our...
(INAUDIBLE)
TERRY: Look at how
aggressive he is.
He started the whole thing,
and now I'm being arrested.
OFFICER:
Listen up, stop talking.
TERRY: And what's he...
What's gonna happen
with him? Guy's a total...
Terry, stop talking.
All right, man.
Any idea where
we might be able to
contact his mother?
No, because he's
not my goddamn kid.
Oh, my gosh.
BRIAN: What's the matter?
What time is it?
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God, it's 9:30.
Hey. Uh, you know,
Nancy's gonna be gone
for the rest of the week.
Well, Brian.
Yeah?
I mean, I don't
mean to be...
Couldn't we just...
I mean, could we
give it a rest?
Yeah, sure,
if you want to.
I mean,
I just think...
I don't know.
We've had a great
little fling, you know.
(LAUGHS SOFTLY)
So why push it?
Is that okay? I just...
Yeah, sure.
Okay. No, you're right.
So we're still friends?
Mmm-hmm. Sure.
All right.
(PHONE RINGING)
(CLICKING)
Around 2:00 this afternoon.
Yes. A '97 red Subaru Outback.
New York plates. AUZ 416.
Please.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
Thanks for coming over.
I just...
I want to have
a car handy,
just in case.
No problem.
Yes! What...
What about other towns?
Yes.
Look. I've called
the Highway Patrol
four times.
Well, what am I
supposed to do
all night?
(PHONES RINGING)
Hello?
Anyone hear from
Sammy this morning?
I didn't.
Uh-huh. Well,
if anybody ever hears
from her ever again,
would you let me know?
Yes.
Thanks so much.
I'll give you a call.
All right.
We'll see you.
It's gonna
be all right.
We got on the phone
with Rudy Sr.
a little bit,
he's calmed down.
He wants to forget
the whole thing.
Darryl, I really
appreciate this.
(PHONE RINGING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Hello?
Yeah, it's Brian.
Brian.
What the hell happened
to you today, lady?
(REDIALING)
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello.
You're fired!
Good!
(BANGING)
Rudy?
Yeah?
Is there anything
you want to ask me
about your father?
Oh, that wasn't
my father.
What?
That wasn't him.
I heard him
tell the cops.
No, Rudy, that was him.
I wish it wasn't,
but it was.
No, it wasn't.
Yes, Rudy. It was.
Your father's name
is Rudy Kolinsky.
He lives in Auburn.
(TV PLAYING INDISTINCTLY)
MAN: (ON TV)
Yeah, I'm on my way.
(SIRENS WAILING)
Would you turn
that off, please?
(TV SWITCHES OFF)
You don't have to
say anything, Sammy.
I want you to leave.
What do you mean?
I mean, I don't think
you should live here.
I don't think you know
how to behave around
an eight-year-old,
and I don't know
how to make you stop,
so I don't think
you should live here.
I don't know
what else to say.
I don't know how to behave
around an eight-year-old?
That's right.
I think you don't
know how to behave
around an
eight-year-old.
Are you out of your mind?
Now, just listen to me.
No, I may not be
the greatest mother
in the world,
but I'm doing the best
I know how,
and he doesn't need you
to rub his face in shit
because you think
it's good for him.
He's gonna find out
the world
is a horrible place
and that people
suck soon enough,
and without any
help from you.
Believe me.
(SIGHS)
I think you should
get your own place.
I thought maybe you could...
(STAMMERING)
I'd be happy to
help you out financially.
What do you mean,
get my own place?
I mean, I...
You mean,
here in Scottsville?
Yes.
Why would I do that?
I mean, why don't I
just leave, period?
Well...
If that's what
you want to do,
that's fine.
But that's not
what I'm saying.
You're a very
important person
to Rudy.
And you are the most
important person to me.
But I'm saying
I can't take
any more of this.
Well...
And I thought you
could sell your half
of the house to me,
and then I could
pay you back
a certain amount,
whatever it is,
over a certain
period of time.
No, you know what?
I'll just go.
(TV PLAYING)
Well... That's not
what I'm saying.
(VOLUME INCREASES)
RUDY: Where are you gonna go?
I don't know.
I just want to get
out of this town.
And if you have any sense,
when you get old enough,
you'll get out
of here, too.
You know,
your mom is gonna
stay in this town
for the rest of her life.
And you wanna know why?
Because she thinks
she has to.
She thinks there's
all these things that
she has to do.
But I'll tell you
one thing about
your mom.
She's a bigger fuck-up
than I ever was.
I mean, I know
I messed up, okay?
You think I enjoy
getting thrown in jail
because I wanted you
to face that prick,
your dad,
like a little man
and show you what
kind of guy he is?
All right, I got
a little carried away.
I know it.
And I lost my temper
just a little bit,
which is not
the end of the world
by the way, either.
Just for future reference.
Where's the rest of my shit?
And now she's gonna
throw me out of my
own house because...
(SCOFFS)
You know,
because I fucked up
a little bit.
Which I...
Which I totally admit.
I was, like,
totally ready
to admit that.
RUDY: I could go with you.
(SIGHS)
Thanks, man,
but I, uh...
I can't really
take care of you.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
Is that for you?
Yeah, I'm just gonna stay
at Ray's till I leave.
Well, you don't
have to do that.
Yeah, I know,
but that's what
I wanna do, so...
Well, are you
gonna come back
and say goodbye?
No, I'm just gonna
take off. See you.
(DOOR OPENS)
Well...
Look, I know
you're upset
about Uncle Terry
leaving, and so am I.
But he is not in
control of himself,
and I don't want him
hurting your feelings
anymore, or mine.
Now, you might
not like it,
but that's the way
it's gonna be, okay?
I don't care.
You don't care?
I don't care either.
(SIGHS) Well, I'm sorry
you're having
all this trouble.
Thank you.
But you made
a pretty good speech
to me the other day
about people sticking
to their commitments.
Yeah?
Well, you made
a commitment, Sammy,
to this bank,
to this job.
I know I did.
And to working
things out with this
tough, new
son-of-a-bitch
boss of yours.
Now, whatever may
have passed between
us after hours
doesn't mean you can
just walk away from
that commitment.
Yeah, yeah, even if
you have a legitimate
family emergency.
I'm really sorry
I didn't call in.
That's why I think,
in the calm,
cold light of day,
that you and I both
have to think real hard
about whether you
really want to
continue on
here at
Outpost Bankers Trust.
You've got to
be kidding.
You're not happy.
I'm not happy.
It's no good for you.
And it's sure as heck
no good for the bank.
You know, you're
the worst manager
we've ever had.
Oh, come on, Sammy.
I mean, by far,
the worst.
I don't want to
trade insults with you.
Well, I don't want
to be fired, Brian.
I've been working
here for seven years.
(SIGHS) Well...
You know,
and if I were you,
I'd be a little
nervous about
firing an employee
I just had
an affair with, okay?
What? Hey, don't...
Don't threaten me, Sammy.
I'm not threatening you.
I just... I think
it's an area that
we ought to explore.
You explore it.
I'm going back to work.
Oh, and I have to
pick up Rudy today
because there's
no one else
who can do it.
I'll find someone else
when I have time.
Oh, yeah. Fine.
Why don't you just take
over the whole bank?
(DOOR SLAMS)
Well,
I called Uncle Terry
where he said
he'd be staying,
but there was no answer.
So,
I don't know if he's
still in town or not.
Rudy, are you not
speaking to me?
I'm really sorry that
you're so mad at me,
but I only did what I
thought I had to do.
And I just hope you
don't stay mad at me
for the rest of your life.
Rudy, that's enough. Rudy!
Now, you gotta
cut this out!
What did I do?
You don't know what
you're talking about.
There was nothing else
I could do.
I don't know how
to explain it to you
any better than that.
But you cannot
go on this way
because you don't
know anything about it.
You don't know
what you're doing.
Okay, I'm sorry.
I don't want you
to be sorry!
I want you to stop it!
I'm stopping.
See, I'm stopping.
(LIGHTER CLICKS)
(PHONE RINGING)
Ray's house.
Hi.
(STAMMERING) I didn't know
if you'd left yet.
No, I'm not
leaving till tomorrow.
Well, what time?
Um... Bus leaves at 9:00.
Well...
I'd... I'd really like
to see you before you go.
Can... Can I give you a lift?
Do you want to have
breakfast or anything?
I think Rudy
would really like
to say goodbye.
Yeah. (SIGHS)
I don't know. I mean...
Terry, you can't
just leave like this.
All right, all right.
Um, I'll come by
tomorrow morning.
All right. Uh, just...
We have to be out
of the house by 8:00,
so I don't want to
tell Rudy you're coming
unless you think
you can make it.
No, I mean, I'll be there.
All right.
(LINE CLICKS)
(SIGHS)
You better get
your sneakers on.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(CLOCK TICKING)
Sweetie, I'm sorry,
but we have to go.
Why can't I miss
school one day?
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
Hi.
Hey, how's it
going, man?
Sorry I'm late.
So, Rudy,
if I write you a letter,
will you write me back?
Yeah.
Oh, that's gonna be
pretty nice for you
'cause I write a pretty
goddamn interesting letter.
Yeah, we'll see.
Well, all right.
Say goodbye.
Bye.
Do you need some
cash for the bus?
No, I got
a few bucks.
Aren't you gonna
be late for work?
Oh, yeah.
It's okay.
Terry, I don't
even know where
you're going.
Well...
Yeah, I don't
really have a
concrete plan yet.
Um, I gotta go
back to Worcester
and get my stuff.
Oh, you gonna try
and see that girl?
Yeah, you know.
I thought maybe
I'd try and show
my face,
let her brother
have a crack at me.
What?
(LAUGHS) No.
I don't want anybody to
have a crack at you.
I'm just kidding.
I just...
I just thought
I'd check up on her.
And then after that,
I don't know.
I've been thinking
about Alaska a lot,
you know?
I still got a lot
of friends out there.
I don't really know.
Anyway, I'll...
I'll write you.
You will?
Sure, Sammy.
Of course I will.
You know that.
(CHUCKLES)
What's gonna
happen to you?
Nothing too bad.
But I gotta
tell you, Sammy,
and I know things
really didn't work out
too well this time...
Well, Terry...
But it's really
good to know
wherever I am
and whatever stupid
shit I'm doing,
that you're
back at my home
rooting for me.
It's all gonna be
all right, Sammy.
Comparatively.
(CHUCKLES)
And I'll be back
around this way again.
(VOICE CRACKING) I just...
I feel like I'm never gonna
see you again.
No. Of course you will.
You never have to
worry about that. Ever.
Just don't go anywhere
until you know
where you're going.
I do. I do know
where I'm going.
Please!
I do. I'm going
back to Worcester.
And I'm gonna try
and see that girl.
And then depending on
what happens there,
I'm gonna try and see
if there's some work
for me out west.
And if there is,
I'm gonna go out
there this summer
and I'm gonna
make some money.
And if there isn't,
I'll figure something
else out.
Maybe I'll stay
in the east.
I don't know.
I really liked Alaska.
It was really
beautiful,
and it just...
It made me feel good.
And before things
got so messed up,
I was doing
pretty well out there.
Seriously.
But I couldn't
stay here, Sammy.
I don't want
to live here.
But I'll keep in touch
and I will be back,
because I want to see you
and I want to see Rudy.
We'll have
Christmas together.
How's that, huh?
We'll have Christmas...
Come on, Sammy.
(SNIFFLES)
You can trust me.
Come on, Sammy.
Look at me.
Hey, Sammy.
Remember when
we were kids?
Do you remember
what we always used
to say to each other?
Of course I do.
Remember when
we were kids?
(SNIFFLING)
♪ I am just a pilgrim
on this road, boys
♪ This ain't never
been my home
♪ Sometimes the road was
rocky along the way, boys
♪ But I was never
travelin' alone
♪ We'll meet again
on some bright highway
♪ Songs to sing
and tales to tell
♪ But I am just a pilgrim
on this road, boys
♪ Until I see you,
fare thee well
♪ I am just a pilgrim
on this road, boys
♪ Until I see you,
fare thee well
♪ I am just a pilgrim
on this road, boys
on this road ♪