"United 1523, did you hear your company...
Did you hear..."
"We were just answering your call."
"We did hear that yelling, too."
"We couldn't tell what it was either."
"United 93..."
"- Has he turned to the east now?
- Please state your emergency."
"The flight attendant is advising
our reps that the pilot and
everyone's been stabbed."
"And we can't breathe."
"I don't know.
I think we're getting hijacked."
"Hijacked aircraft headed towards New York."
"- Is this real world or exercise?
- No, this is not an exercise."
"Can anybody get up to the cockpit?"
"What's going on, Betty?"
"Betty, talk to me."
"A plane just crashed
into the World Trade Center."
"I think we might have lost her."
"Hey, Mom, I'm sure that you've heard..."
"...that a plane crashed into
World Trade Center One."
"We're fine.
We're in World Trade Center Two."
"I'm on a plane that's been hijacked."
"I hope to be able to see
your face again, baby."
"I love you. Bye."
"We got reports of another incoming plane."
"We may have to take
cover in the stairwell."
"Lieutenant Brown, Ladder 18.
One of the towers just collapsed."
"- Hello, ma'am?
- Help!"
"That tower just came down
on top of everybody!"
"Are they gonna be able
to get somebody up here?"
"Of course, ma'am. We're coming up to you."
"Well, there's no one here yet,
and the floor's completely engulfed."
"We're on the floor and we can't breathe."
"Hold on one second, please."
"I'm gonna die, aren't I?"
"No, no, no, no, no, no!"
"- I'm gonna die.
- Ma'am..."
"I'm gonna die, I know it."
"Stay calm, stay calm, stay calm."
"Please, God."
"You're doing a good job, ma'am."
"You're doing a good job.
You're doing fine."
"It's so hot. I'm burning up."
"Ma'am, you are fine.
They're gonna come get you."
"Can anyone hear me?"
"Oh, my God."
FarangSiam thanks you.
Have Fun!
I own you, Ammar.
You belong to me.
Look at me.
If you don't look at me when
I talk to you, I hurt you!
You step off this mat, I hurt you!
If you lie to me, I'm gonna hurt you!
Now, now look at me!
Look at me, Ammar!
Come on.
Nobody talks to him.
Roger that.
Are we gonna board these windows
up or what?
Just off the plane from Washington.
Rocking your best suit for
your first interrogation.
And you get this guy.
They're not always this intense.
I'm fine.
Well, just so you know,
it's gonna take a while.
He has to learn how helpless he is.
Come on, let's get a coffee.
No, we should go back in.
There's no shame if you want
to watch from the monitor.
All right.
Might want to put this on.
You're not wearing one.
Is he ever getting out?
Never.
Let's go.
Right now,
all this is about, simply,
is you coming to terms
with your situation.
It's you and me, bro.
I want you to understand that I know you,
that I've been studying and following you
for a very long time.
I could've had you killed in Karachi,
but I didn't, I let you live,
so that you and I could talk.
Then you beat me when my hands are tied.
So I won't talk to you.
Well, life isn't always fair, my friend.
Did you really think that when we got you,
I would be a nice fucking guy?
You're a mid-level guy.
You're a garbage man in the corporation!
Why should I respect you, huh?
Why?
And you're a money man.
Paperboy.
A disgrace to humanity.
You and your uncle murdered
3,000 innocent people.
Yeah.
I have your name on a $5,000 transfer
via Western Union to a 9/11 hijacker.
And you got popped with
150 kilograms of high explosives
in your house!
And then you dare question me?
Come on, man, I'm fucking with you.
I don't want to talk about 9/11 yet.
What I want to focus on
is the Saudi group.
That there is Hazem Al-Kashmiri.
And I know this dude is up to some
serious shit.
What I want from you is his Saudi e-mail.
Ammar, bro, I know that
you know this dude.
Just give me his e-mail and
I will give you a blanket.
I will give you a blanket and
some solid food.
I know that you know him.
I told you before, I won't talk to you.
Have it your way. Let's go.
Come on.
When you lie to me,
I hurt you.
Grab me the bucket.
Come on, grab the bucket!
Put some water in it.
Come on, let's go!
Come on, give it to me.
Hazem was a friend of Ramzi Yousef.
You guys met in Iran, back in the '90s.
I don't know!
Fuck you!
Give me the e-mails of the rest
of the Saudi group.
Give me one e-mail and I will stop this!
Who's in the Saudi group?
And what's the target?
Where was the last time you saw bin Laden?
Where was the last time you saw bin Laden,
huh?
You know, when you lie to me, I hurt you.
This is what defeat looks like, bro.
Your jihad is over.
Get him up.
Try to understand the concept here.
Okay, I have time, you don't.
I have other things to do, but you don't.
It's cool that you're strong.
I respect it, I do.
But in the end, everybody breaks, bro.
It's biology.
Can you open the trunk, ma'am?
It's clear.
How'd it go the other night?
It was good. I mean,
the local cops needed
...a little tactical help,
but he's Tier fucking One, baby.
That's your moneymaker right there.
And this is the guy that's
K.S.M.'s nephew?
- Yeah.
- What's his issue?
He's being a dick.
If he's trying to outsmart you,
why don't you tell him about your Ph.D.
"(Ph. D.: Philosophiæ doctor)"
Yeah. No, but I am gonna have to turn up
the heat on this asshole.
He needs to give up the Saudi group now.
He's got to have that,
given the family ties.
He's tight with his uncle, he's got
his prints all over the 9/11 money.
He's got them in his head,
he needs to disclose them.
All right.
Good.
Bill, she's good to go.
I'll get her the right one tomorrow.
Was I lying or what?
Maya, this is Joseph Bradley,
our illustrious station chief.
Joe and I did Iraq together.
It's nice to meet you.
You, too, sir.
- How was your flight?
- Fine.
And she's been having a great time
since she got in.
Isn't that right?
Good. How do you like Pakistan so far?
It's kind of fucked up.
You volunteered for this, didn't you?
No.
Third floor, northeast corner.
You don't think she's a little young
for the hard stuff?
Washington says she's a killer.
Children's Crusade, huh?
They want to put the next generation
on the field.
Listen, I've got a meeting with ISI
in 20 minutes.
They're slow-rolling us in Lahore,
you might want to bitch about that.
My fellow Americans...
Did I tell you this?
That this dude in Malaysia,
he tells the Malaysian station
that his nephew works with a guy
who knows a guy...
- Here we go.
- Hold on.
He goes to a big feast in Bangkok
about a year ago.
Guest of honor?
Usama bin Laden.
I said, "Was Tupac there, too?"
This is worth five million bucks.
You know we're gonna have to
chase it down.
Hey, that's me, man, no job too small.
That's why I have a gift for you,
my friend.
- Everyone, this is Maya.
- Hey.
Maya, everyone.
Please don't ask her how it's going
...with Ammar, 'cause she's not gonna
fucking tell you.
Ammar is withholding?
Washington assesses Abu Faraj
is officially our new number three.
He's the best man for it.
Yeah, the London station's already asking
if he's contacting anybody in the U.K.
- Like we're just keeping it from them?
- Yeah.
Jordanians are being really helpful
with Ammar's transit papers.
Any imminent threats in here?
They want a consulate, a Marriott,
it's low security.
And they've got Majid Kahn
talking about gas stations in the U.S.
And that's a conversation?
Honestly, there are 600 questions
in there.
I'd do Heathrow, the Saudis...
Does it matter what Faraj thinks about
Heathrow?
How much latitude does he get
to pick targets?
I think he'll give up the Saudis,
but Heathrow's gonna be tough.
Anyway, anything from last night?
Quetta base thinks they have
a bead on the Arabs that escaped.
They're meeting with ISI this afternoon,
hopefully set up...
- a raid down there.
- Great.
And Lahore reporting ISI was painfully
slow last night, again.
They're beginning to think it's not
incompetence.
I agree. I spoke to the chief about that.
- Yeah.
- Anything on bin Laden?
A farmer on the Afghan border
near Tora Bora reports
..."a diamond-shaped pattern in the hills,
tall male in the center of the diamond
..."flanked by four guards."
Consistent with UBL's movements.
That's supposed to be his royal guard?
No, that's pre-9/11 behavior.
We have no reason to believe
he's changed security tactics.
We invaded Afghanistan, that's a reason.
Hey, boss, I got a guy, for $5,000 bucks,
he can set up a taxi stand and
snoop around a bit.
No. Don't need him.
Sorry, the diamond sighting's bullshit.
See if the Paks will send someone
to talk to the farmer.
Anything else? No?
All right, let's put some runs on
the board against Faraj, okay?
Talk to the case officers who didn't see
fit to make it today and thank them.
Tora Bora?
Yeah. Good.
Come on. Here we go. Here we go.
Let's just...
Let's take it easy today, huh?
Hungry?
The food in here sucks,
so I got you some of this.
Good, huh?
Richard Reid.
Oh, man, I was thinking about him.
Guy gets a bomb in a shoe on a plane.
Un-fucking-believable.
You know him, don't you?
Yes.
I'm glad you said that.
I got an e-mail from you to him.
I got all your coms for years, bro.
Who...
Who else is in your Saudi group?
I just handed out some cash for them.
I didn't know who the guys were.
When you lie to me, I hurt you.
Please.
I believe you.
I do, I believe you.
Good, huh?
Do you want the water again?
Or do you want something else?
Water?
Please.
Just give me a name.
I don't know.
I don't know! I don't know!
Come on, let's go.
Bring him up.
Here we go.
You see how this works?
You don't mind if my female colleague
there checks out your junk, do you?
No?
Good.
Dude, you shit your pants?
You stay here. I'll be back.
Your friend is an animal.
Please, help me.
Please.
You can help yourself by being truthful.
This is a dog collar.
- No!
- Come on.
No!
Come on. Come on.
There you go. There you go.
You determine how I treat you.
Come on. Come on.
I got you.
Come on.
You're my dog, I gotta walk you.
What the fuck do you think is going on,
Ammar?
Wahleed has already told me that you know.
Here we go. Come on, you're almost there.
There we go. There we go.
All right. This box here, this box sucks.
Now, I'm gonna put you in it.
When is the attack?
What? What?
Sunday.
Sunday where? No, whoa, whoa.
Sunday where?
Sunday? This Sunday or next Sunday?
Where? Where?
Monday.
What?
Tuesday.
Come on, Ammar, is it Sunday or Monday?
Partial information will be treated
as a lie.
- Come on, let's go.
- Thursday.
Come on, which day is it?
Partial information, you're gonna go
in the box!
Partial information is treated as a lie!
Let's go!
- Saturday!
- In the box you go.
In the box you go.
Saturday!
Come on.
Monday!
Tuesday!
- There we go.
- Friday!
Come on, let's go, come on!
Hang on, hang on, hang on,
hang on, hang on.
Sunday.
Monday.
Thursday.
Ammar, which day is it?
Tuesday.
Which day?
Friday.
Ammar, which day?
Thursday.
Friday.
"A targeted attack against Westerners
and foreigners."
"When you look at the breakup
of casualties, you can see"
"...that non-Muslims were killed and
so were Americans."
Don't worry about the Saudis.
They'll take care of business.
Yeah, now.
You warned them,
they didn't take you seriously.
This is what happens. It's not on you.
Who said that, huh, Zeid?
Fuck him. This is on me.
- Ammar is on me. And it's on her.
- No, no, no, no.
You had what, days, brief custody,
unresponsive ally?
We cannot let this be a win-win for A.Q.
The way you do this is look ahead.
London, Heathrow, mass casualties.
That plan is still active.
Ammar doesn't have a clue about
what happened.
- He knows.
- How?
You have to be really careful with people
in K.S.M.'s circle, they're devious.
He's not gonna talk about attacks
on the homeland.
He's gonna withhold operational details on
the K.S.M. network and probably bin Laden.
But he's been in complete isolation.
He doesn't know we failed.
We could tell him anything.
What, bluff him?
He hasn't slept, Dan. He's clueless.
You don't remember, do you?
Well, short-term memory loss
is a side effect of sleep deprivation,
so it should come back to you.
I don't know.
How can I remember?
After we kept you awake for 96 hours,
you gave us the name of some
of your brothers,
and you helped save the lives
of a lot of innocent people.
Which is the smart thing to do.
You're starting to think for yourself.
Come on, eat up, man.
Some hummus. Tabouleh.
Don't know what that is.
Some figs. You earned it.
So, you flew via Amman to Kabul, yeah?
Hang out with your uncle. Mukhtar.
How did you know that?
Told you, man, I know you.
All right, you got me.
You did, you got me.
Flight manifests.
It must be pretty fucked up for you
guys after 9/11.
What'd you do after the invasion?
Before you went back to Pesh.
After 9/11, we had to choose,
fight to protect our turf, or run.
And you chose to fight, yeah?
We wanted to kill Americans.
Yeah.
We tried to get into Tora Bora,
but the bombing was too high.
We couldn't cross.
I'm sorry, who's the "we"
in that sentence?
Me and some other guys
who were hanging around at that time.
You know, I can always go and
eat with some other dude,
hang you back up to the ceiling.
Hamza Rabia.
Khabab Al-Masri.
And Abu Ahmed.
Who's Abu Ahmed?
I've heard of the other guys.
He was a computer guy with us at the time.
After Tora Bora, I went back to Pesh,
as you know.
And he went north, I think.
To Kunar.
What's his family name?
Abu Ahmed Al-Kuwaiti.
Abu Ahmed means "father of Ahmed." It's a kunya.
"(kunya: teknonym in Arabic names, the name of
an adult derived from his or her eldest child.)"
Ammar, I know the difference between
a war name and an Arabic name.
She got you there, dude.
I swear to you both, I don't know
his family name.
I would have never asked him
something like that.
It's not how my uncle worked.
I know.
My uncle told me he worked for bin Laden.
I did see him once. About a year ago,
in Karachi.
He read us all a letter from the Sheik.
A letter?
What'd it say?
Cigarette?
He said, "Continue the jihad.
The work will go on for a hundred years."
"You and I are gonna talk about some of
the guys in the training camps. Yeah?"
"Okay."
"Some of these brothers have done
some bad things."
"What I want to do is I want to separate
themfrom the people like you."
"Definitely, yeah."
"All right, a guy called Abu Ahmed
from Kuwait."
"Yes, I remember him."
"A nice guy."
"How close was he? What was his
relationship to the leadership?"
"- I don't know.
- Did he eat with you guys?"
"Did he eat with the good guys
or did he eat with the leadership?"
"I don't know, sir.
I have no idea about..."
"Yes, you do. You don't need
an idea about..."
"When you met Khalid Shaikh Mohammed,"
"was this one of the facilitators?"
"Is this Abu Ahmed?"
"Yes."
"K.S.M., your boss."
"I call him Mukhtar."
"Mukhtar. "Po-tay-to," you say "Po-tah-to."
"I say "fucking K.S.M.," you say "Mukhtar,"
okay?"
"After Mukhtar was captured,"
"what did Abu Ahmed do?"
"Abu Ahmed, I believe..."
"I believe he went to work for the Sheik."
"In Karachi in 2003, or 2004."
"He was carrying a letter from bin Laden?"
"Is that him?"
"- Is that him?
- Abu Ahmed."
"- Say it again?
"Abu Ahmed. Abu Ahmed."
"Abu Ahmed."
"Who knows who works directly
for bin Laden."
"Let's say he's part of the mix."
"Were there other people
who carried messages from bin Laden?"
"Sure."
"How many other people?"
"Let's talk about them."
How's the needle in the haystack?
Fine.
Facilitators come and go.
One thing you can count on in life
is that everyone wants money.
You're assuming that Al-Qaeda members
are motivated by financial rewards.
They're radicals.
Correct.
You're assuming that greed won't
override ideology
...in some of the weaker members.
Money for walk-ins worked great
in the Cold War,
I'll give you that.
Thank you.
He says he looks like Abu Ahmed.
Who did he work for?
It was mostly with Abu Faraj.
They were always together.
What did he do for Faraj?
He carried messages from Faraj
to bin Laden
and from bin Laden back to Faraj.
We need to ask him something
to see if he's telling the truth.
We don't know if he really knew Faraj.
He just told me the names of
all of Abu Faraj's children.
I think he's telling the truth.
20 detainees recognize that photo
of Abu Ahmed.
They say he's part of an inner circle
of guys
...that was hanging out
in Afghanistan pre-9/11.
A lot of them say that after 9/11,
he went to work for K.S.M.
When K.S.M. was captured,
he went to work for Abu Faraj,
primarily as a courier from Faraj
to bin Laden.
Well, that's good, but you still...
Yeah, but we don't know if Abu’s
on the outside of the network,
a series of cutouts and dead drops,
or if he has a direct connection
to bin Laden.
I mean, does bin Laden invite him
into the living room
...and hand him a letter directly or is Abu
just the last guy in a long line of couriers,
and that's why everybody knows him?
That's not all you don't know.
You don't have his real name,
you don't have a clue of where he is.
Yes, but we know that he's important.
The fact that everybody's heard
of Abu Ahmed,
but nobody will tell me where
he is suggests that.
Maybe.
Detainees could withhold his location
for any number of reasons.
Perhaps they don't know.
Perhaps this Abu is actually a cover story
and he's really a fucking unicorn.
But the withholding doesn't reveal
what you want it to, does it?
No.
And if you did find him, you don't know
that he'd be with bin Laden.
We don't know what we don't know.
What the fuck is that supposed to mean?
It's a tautology.
"(Tautology: formula that is true
in every possible interpretation.)"
Listen, not one single detainee has said
that he's been located with the big guy,
just that he delivers messages,
am I wrong?
- No.
It's still good work.
Let me know when you get some
actionable intelligence.
Preferably something that leads
to a strike.
"This is what remains of the number 10 bus,"
"which was traveling through
Tavistock Square near Euston Station."
"There'd been explosions"
"...near Liverpool Street and
Edgware Road stations, too."
"Dozens of the survivors were
critically injured,"
"but many of the wounded were also keen
to share their stories."
"We'd just pulled out of Edgware Road."
"And next thing I know, there's a loud...
A large flash of light."
"Felt a burning sensation on my hands,
put my hands up to my face."
"I was on the floor by that point."
"Yeah, I can't recall anything prior to that,
any noise, any bang."
"Normal life in one of the busiest parts
of the capital has now been suspended,"
"as just a few yards down the road here
they continue to care for the injured."
"And all around, groups of Londoners are
standing on corners, asking themselves"
"...what has happened here
and who could possibly have done this."
Come on.
You, too. Come on.
You Agency guys are twisted.
Detainee's ready for you.
Come on.
I want you to understand that I know you.
I've been following you
and studying you for a long time.
I chased you in Lahore.
I had you picked up instead of killing you
because you're not a violent man
...and you don't deserve to die.
Thank you.
But you do have deep ties to Al-Qaeda
...I want to ask you about
...before you get sent to your
next location, which might be Israel.
However, depending on how candid
you are here today,
I may be able to keep you in Pakistan.
What do you want to know?
I'm gonna ask you a series of questions
based on your knowledge of Al-Qaeda
...and your position as key financier
for the organization.
I have dealt with the Mukhabarat.
I have no wish to be tortured again.
Ask me a question, I will answer it.
What can you tell me about
Atiyah Abd Al-Rahman?
He works for Zawahiri.
He's in charge of military tactics.
In what context have you ever
heard the name Abu Ahmed?
He works for Faraj and bin Laden.
He is his most trusted courier.
What makes you say that?
He brought me many messages
from the Sheik.
Where did you last see him and
where is he now?
You will never find him.
Why is that?
Even I couldn't find him.
He always contacted me out of the blue.
He is one of the disappeared ones.
You know how this works?
God willing, we won't have to use it.
Just act naturally.
You're in luck.
I got you a one-on-one with Faraj.
Seriously? Thank you!
Don't you thank me until you hear
what I want for it.
I want you to take care of all this
before your favorite subject.
Deal.
Don't you want to see what's
in the folder?
You want family ties, financial networks,
media sources, disgruntled employees,
imminent threats, homeland plots,
foreign sales, health status,
financial resources...
Thank you!
Tradecraft, recruiting tactics.
Anything else?
No, I think that covers it.
Yeah.
"If what they say is true,"
"the Shaolin and the Wu Tang
could be dangerous."
"What do you like to be called?
Faraj? Farij?"
"Fuzzy? Come on."
"Hey, what do you like?
You like a bit of"
"...you guys like a bit of Bob Marley?
Bit of reggae?"
"Kick back, take it easy
after you've blown some shit up?"
"No?"
"You got some Libyan music you like?"
"You did the U.K. bombings, right?"
"You know, you're the second number three
I've captured."
"I got K.S.M."
Can I be honest with you?
I'm bad fucking news.
I'm not your friend.
I'm not gonna help you.
I'm gonna break you.
Any questions?
No?
All right, you haven't eaten in 18 hours.
We need to keep your energy up.
You hungry?
A lot of brothers told us Abu Ahmed
was bin Laden's courier
...and that he worked very closely
with you.
You are thinking of Abu Khalid.
Who?
Al-Baluchi.
My courier for the Sheik.
Okay.
So you're telling me all the other
brothers are wrong
...and there's some famous Baluchi guy
...working for you and bin Laden
that I've never even heard of.
Why should you have heard of him?
What does this Baluchi guy look like?
Tall. Long white beard.
Thin.
He uses a cane.
Kind of like Gandalf.
Who?
When was the last time you saw him?
A month ago. In Karachi.
But I don't know where he is now.
Sometimes, I wouldn't even see him.
He would just tell me where to leave
the messages.
You're not being fulsome in your replies.
You cannot force me to tell you something
I don't know.
You do realize this is not
a normal prison.
You determine how you're treated.
And your life is gonna be very uncomfortable
until you give me the information I need.
Where exactly is Abu Ahmed living
at the moment?
"Faraj is completely denying knowing
Abu Ahmed."
That's using every measure we have.
Well, he's either gonna
keep withholding
...or he's gonna die from the pressure
you're putting on him.
Hey, you want to take a run at him?
No.
- No?
- No.
Since when no?
You know, I was meaning to tell you,
I'm getting out of here.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine, I'm just...
You know, I think I've seen too many
guys naked.
It's got to be over a fucking hundred
at this point.
I need to go and do something
normal for a while.
Like what?
Go to Washington.
Do the dance, see how that
environment works.
You should come with me.
Yeah, be my number two. You're looking
a little strung out yourself.
I'm not gonna find Abu Ahmed from D.C.
They killed my monkeys.
Some bullshit about escaping.
You fucking believe that?
- Sorry, Dan.
- Yeah, I know.
Look, Maya, you got to be real
careful with the detainees now.
Okay? Politics are changing,
and you don't want to be the last one
...holding a dog collar
when the oversight committee comes.
- I know.
- Yeah?
And watch your back when
you get back to Pakistan.
Everyone knows you there now.
Sorry.
Fucking checkpoints.
- Maya?
- Yeah?
We're socializing. Be social.
Okay.
Look, I know Abu Ahmed is your baby,
but it is time to cut the umbilical cord.
No, it's not.
So Faraj went south on you, it happens.
There are still cells in London and Spain
who are planning the next round of attacks.
I can work on it at the same time.
- Plus, I think it's a good thing he lied.
- No.
Not at the expense of protecting
the homeland, you can't...
Wait a minute, why is it a good thing?
You sound just like Bradley,
he doesn't believe in my lead, either.
It's a good thing because the fact that
...Faraj withheld on Abu Ahmed
is very revealing.
The only other thing Faraj lied about
was the location of bin Laden himself.
That means Faraj thinks Abu Ahmed is just
as important to protect as bin Laden.
That confirms my lead.
Or it's confirmation bias.
We're just worried about you, okay?
Is that okay to say?
I mean, look how run-down you are.
Where's Jack?
Probably stuck in some
checkpoint somewhere.
You two hooked up yet?
Hello, I work with him.
I'm not that girl that fucks.
It's unbecoming.
So? Little fooling around
wouldn't hurt you.
So no boyfriend.
You got any friends at all?
It's Jack.
Hey.
That's okay.
He's stuck in traffic.
Come on!
There's an exit!
Oh, no! Shit.
Come on, over here!
"The blast left a crater 10 meters,
or 30 feet wide, in front of the hotel."
"Police tell CNN the driver
of the truck bomb"
"...tried to talk his way past
the hotel's steel security gate."
"When armed guards said no,
police said the driver"
"...detonated more than 2,000 pounds
of explosives."
"The Marriott, one of the most
popular destinations for locals"
"...and Westerners in Islamabad,
now destroyed."
The Jords have a mole!
What?
He made this video to prove
his bona fides.
Shut up!
Humam Khalil Al-Balawi.
He's a Jordanian doctor.
He's right there in the inner circle.
I don't buy it.
Didn't you tell me yourself nobody turns
on Al-Qaeda?
The Jords have worked him for a year,
dinners, money.
They convinced him it's his patriotic duty
to turn on Al-Qaeda and get rich doing it.
Yeah, well, so the Jords say.
Yeah, you're right.
We can't rely on this or the Jords.
We've got to evaluate him face-to-face.
He may not be that smart.
He may be full of shit.
But we have to talk to him and find out.
The key is to meet him, so we can figure
out for ourselves what he can actually do.
He really asked for a dialysis machine?
Maybe we can fill the damn thing
with poison.
The meeting with Balawi's off.
He can't come to Islamabad.
Can't or won't?
He's not gonna travel.
Security risk.
"I've said repeatedly that America
doesn't torture."
"And I'm gonna make sure that
we don't torture."
"Those are part and parcel of an effort"
"...to regain America's moral stature
in the world."
"Can you give us some sense of
when you might start..."
He wants us to go to him.
He'll meet us in Miranshah
with the Tribals.
He knows we're white.
We'd get kidnapped there.
Maybe do it somewhere else.
Germany or the U.K.?
He's got a clean passport.
He's not gonna travel out
of Al-Qaeda territory.
And you're not going to him.
I'm not, believe me.
We're stuck.
What about Camp Chapman?
Afghanistan.
That could be safe territory.
"This may be going overboard,
but I baked him a cake."
"Muslims don't celebrate with cake."
Don't be so literal, everyone likes cake.
"It's not too late for you to come,
you know. It'll be fun."
No, I don't want to be a straphanger.
It's your show, you were the first
to see the potential in this.
"Come on!"
"We've got lots of wine."
Cool. Bring me back a bottle.
"I will do."
Not to get technical, but this guy is actually
the first big break we've had since 9/11.
To big breaks and the little people
that make them happen.
So far, everything he's said we've
cross-checked, and it's proved legit.
And I think the money is persuasive.
$25 million?
That buys a new life.
Do you think he might be
exaggerating his access?
Possibly.
But Al-Qaeda needs doctors,
and they are short-staffed,
and that could explain his rise.
In six months to a year,
if he doesn't fuck up,
he could be called in to treat bin Laden.
At that moment, with 25 million
on the table,
I think he gives up the big man.
And if he doesn't, we kill him.
- John?
- Yeah.
When he arrives, let me set the tone,
and then I'll flip it to you
and you can talk about asset protection.
Roger that.
Lauren.
I know you want to get some
questions in there,
but give Balawi a little time
after John speaks.
We'll cover the basics,
have his birthday cake,
then we'll get into the nitty-gritty.
Is that order okay?
Or do you want to introduce everyone?
I'll introduce you, you introduce your team.
He knows this is a high-level meeting.
Quick question.
All this taking place inside
our main building?
Right. And, Lauren,
Washington will want real-time updates,
so please stay on top of that.
Be concise.
The director's in the loop.
And I wouldn't be surprised
if he doesn't update the President.
Yeah, I'm on it.
Now, I just got to get his ass down here.
Why are there gate guards there?
We talked about this.
No one is supposed to be there
when my source arrives.
You might have spooked him already.
Well, procedures only work
- ...if we follow them every time.
- This is different!
I'm sorry I can't explain,
but it's for a good cause.
Look, I'm responsible for
everybody's safety, okay?
It's not just about you.
I just need them to go away for a minute.
You can search him as soon
as he gets here.
All stations, this is Whiplash.
"Go ahead and stand down."
Copy that.
Thank you.
"Okay, he's coming."
We're gonna search him when he gets here.
"Sure."
Okay, let's go!
Is he supposed to limp like that?
Get your hand out of your pocket.
Hey.
- Hey!
- Get your hand out of your pocket!
- Do it now!
- Come on.
"The CIA says seven of its employees"
"...were killed and six others wounded
in a suicide bombing"
"...at a base in Afghanistan."
"It was one of the deadliest
attacks in CIA history."
"The Associated Press has learned
that the chief"
"...of the CIA's post in the province
is among the victims."
"Former officials say
she was the mother of three children."
"The Taliban claim responsibility
for the bombing..."
You okay?
I didn't think this day
could get any worse,
but... bad news from Saudi intelligence.
The courier guy, Abu Ahmed, is dead.
It's a detainee video.
"He's dead."
"In Afghanistan. 2001."
"I buried him with my own hands."
"He's dead."
"In Afghanistan. 2001."
No.
"Where was this?"
"Kabul."
No, I don't believe this.
I don't believe this.
Sorry, Maya.
I always liked this lead.
Fuck.
Sorry, I just got here.
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna smoke everybody
involved in this op
...and then I'm gonna kill bin Laden.
Right.
I want to make something absolutely clear.
If you thought there was some secret cell
somewhere, working Al-Qaeda,
then I want you to know that you're wrong.
This is it.
There's no working group
coming to the rescue.
There's nobody else hidden away
on some other floor.
There is just us.
And we are failing.
We're spending billions of dollars.
People are dying!
We are still no closer to defeating
our enemy.
They attacked us!
On land, in '98.
By sea, in 2000.
And from the air, in 2001.
They murdered 3,000 of our citizens
in cold blood.
And they have slaughtered
our forward deployed!
And what the fuck have we done
about it, huh?
What have we done?
We have 20 leadership names,
we've only eliminated four of them!
I want targets.
Do your fucking jobs.
Bring me people to kill.
Hi. I painstakingly combed through
everything in the system and found this.
It's him.
He was one of 10 names on a watch list
sent to us by the Moroccans after 9/11.
Ibrahim Sayeed.
They told us to watch out for him.
Apparently, they think his whole family
and extended family is bad
...and has ties to K.S.M.
He was picked up for fake papers
and a doctored exit visa
...leaving Afghanistan, traveling
through Morocco
...en route to Kuwait.
Abu Ahmed Al-Kuwaiti.
This must be Abu Ahmed.
Doesn't matter, but I wish I had
that five years ago.
How come I never saw it before?
Nobody saw it, most likely.
There was a lot of white noise after 9/11,
countries wanting to help out.
We got a million tips, and you know,
things got lost in the shuffle.
Human error.
Anyway, I thought you should know
about it.
I just want to say, I've heard a lot
about you.
You inspired me to come to Pakistan.
Maybe you'd let me buy you
a kebab sometime.
Don't eat out.
It's too dangerous.
Yeah?
Dan, Debbie found Abu Ahmed.
Really?
Yeah. He's been in the files this
whole time. The family's named Sayeed.
Okay, but he's dead,
so doesn't that make him
a little less interesting to you?
"He may not be."
"We now know Abu Ahmed is one
of seven brothers."
All the brothers in the family look alike.
Three of them went to Afghanistan.
"Isn't it possible that when
the three eldest brothers"
"...grew beards in Afghanistan,
they started to look alike?"
I think the one calling himself
Abu Ahmed is still alive.
The picture we've been using is wrong.
It's of his older brother, Habeeb.
He's the one that's dead.
Okay, and what are you basing this on?
"We have no intercepts about
Abu Ahmed dying,"
we just have a detainee who
said he buried a guy
...who looked like Abu Ahmed.
But if someone as important
as Abu Ahmed had died,
they'd be talking about it online
"...in chat rooms all over the place."
"Plus, the detainee said that
Habeeb died in 2001."
We know Abu Ahmed was alive then,
trying to get into Tora Bora with Ammar.
That means it's probably
one of the other brothers
"...that's dead."
In other words, you want it to be true.
Yes, I fucking want it to be true!
Calm down.
I am calm.
State your request.
Move heaven and earth,
and bring me this fucking
Sayeed family's phone number.
"Okay, I'll go and talk to the Wolf."
I need a couple hundred thousand bucks.
Four max.
Where you gonna get that?
From you.
- You think so?
- Yeah.
This could crack open the facilitator
...Maya's been looking for by giving us
a phone number.
She's your killer, Wolf.
You put her in the field.
Come on.
"Allah rewards those that strive and
fight over those that sit behind a desk."
As you know, Abu Ghraib and
Gitmo fucked us.
"(Gitmo: Naval Station Guantanamo Bay)"
The detainee program is now flypaper.
We got senators jumping out of our asses.
And the director is very concerned.
They will not stop until they have a body.
I ran it.
I'll defend it.
Done.
I tell you what, man, it's good to be
back in Kuwait.
And it's good to see you again.
It's been a while.
I need a favor.
Why I should help you?
Because we're friends.
You saying we are friend.
How come you only call me when
you need help?
But when I need something,
you are too busy to pick up the phone.
I don't think we are friend.
All right, fair enough.
How about a V10 Lamborghini?
How's that for friendship?
Poor fucker had to get out of bed.
Hey.
- Thank you very much for this. Appreciate it.
- You're welcome.
All right.
- Is this a Balboni?
- Yeah.
Fuck me dead.
That's nice.
Really nice. What are you thinking?
Maybe a convertible?
Get a bit of wind in the hair?
Put the top down?
I think I will choose this one.
Give us a minute? Thank you.
That's a nice choice, my friend.
Speed yellow. Go big or go home, huh?
Nice choice.
Sayeed?
Who is it?
Who do you think? Guy's a terrorist.
His mother lives here.
I just need her phone number.
There will be no repercussions in Kuwait?
Somebody might die, at some point,
in Pakistan.
We got a deal?
Hey, Jack.
Sayeed family call in progress,
but you're not gonna like this.
"The Ground Branch guys are dragging
their heels."
- "There's no team deployed right now."
- Fuck.
"He hasn't said anything incriminating,"
"but he's at the Rawal Call Center
in Rawalpindi."
Hey!
Why haven't you deployed a team
to stay in Rawalpindi?
For one thing, it's dangerous.
For another, the area is too
congested for us
...to be effective without some
predictive intelligence.
Yeah, but that's why you should
forward deploy,
so you can shorten your response time.
Still, it wouldn't work.
Why?
The guy never stays on the phone
long enough.
You haven't tried.
Look, I don't have the personnel.
That's bullshit, man.
Yeah? As it is, my guys don't get any sleep
tracking the threats within Pakistan.
Right, I understand.
But, you know, I don't really care
if your guys get sleep or not!
This guy you're obsessed with,
what's his name again?
Abu Ahmed Al-Kuwaiti's the war-name.
His true name, we think,
is Ibrahim Sayeed.
Family lives in Kuwait.
We've been listening in on their calls.
Wasn't it, like, eight brothers
...and a million cousins,
that we know about?
Anyone could be calling home.
- I know.
- I mean, it's not like
...he's saying, "Hey, Mom,
it's me, the terrorist."
Yeah, I know.
But, look, over the course of two months,
he's called from six different pay phones,
from two different cities,
never using the same phone twice.
And when his mother asked him
where he was, he lied.
He said that he was in a place
in the country
...with bad cell reception,
implying he was in the Tribals,
when in fact, he was in a market
in Peshawar.
I'm sorry, but that's not normal
guy behavior, that's tradecraft.
Well, maybe he just doesn't like his mom.
Look, if he talks about an operation
or refers to anything remotely fishy,
I'll get on him, okay?
No, no. Not okay.
Look, Abu Ahmed is too smart
...to tip his hand by talking about ops
on the phone.
He works for bin Laden.
The guys that talk about ops
on the phone don't get that job.
A lot of my friends have died trying
to do this.
I believe I was spared so
I could finish the job.
It is in surveillance video and
pictures like this"
"...of the explosive-laden vehicle
just moments before it was parked"
"...that police hope to find the man
who wanted so badly last night"
"...to leave a body count
in Times Square."
"There are some people around the world
that find our freedom so threatening"
"...that they're willing to kill
themselves and others"
"...to prevent us from enjoying it,
but we're not gonna let that..."
I really need to talk to you about beefing up
our surveillance operation on the caller.
We don't have a surveillance operation
on the caller.
Someone just tried to blow up
Times Square,
and you're talking to me about
some facilitator
...who some detainee seven years ago said
might have been working with Al-Qaeda?
He's the key to bin Laden.
I don't fucking care about bin Laden.
I care about the next attack.
You're gonna start working
on the American Al-Qaeda cells.
Protect the homeland.
Bin Laden is the one who keeps telling
them to attack the homeland!
If it wasn't for him,
Al-Qaeda would still be focused
on overseas targets.
If you really want to protect the homeland,
you need to get bin Laden.
This guy never met bin Laden!
This guy's a freelancer working off
the fucking Internet.
No one's even talked to bin Laden
in four years.
He's out of the game.
He may well even be dead.
He might as well be fucking dead.
But you know what you're doing?
You're chasing a ghost
...while the whole fucking network grows
all around you!
You just want me to nail
some low-level Mullah-crack-a-dulla,
so you can check that box
on your resume that says
...while you were in Pakistan,
you got a real terrorist!
But the truth is, you don't understand
Pakistan!
And you don't know Al-Qaeda!
Either give me the team I need
to follow this lead,
or the other thing you're gonna have
on your resume
...is being the first station chief to be
called before a Congressional committee
...for subverting the efforts
to capture or kill bin Laden!
You're fucking out of your mind.
I need four techs in a safe house
in Rawalpindi,
four techs in a safe house in Peshawar.
Either send them out,
or send me back to D.C.
...and explain to the director
why you did it.
I've been looking for you.
More importantly, he's been
looking for you.
Yesterday, your caller bought himself
a cell phone.
And every time his phone rings,
this phone will ring.
Did I hook you up?
- Did I?
- Oh, my God!
I love you!
"My guess is that he lives close to
where he's making the calls."
"And it makes sense he'd be living
in Rawalpindi,"
"because there's an Al Jazeera
office there."
It'd be convenient for him
to drop the tapes off
...if he's messengering either from
bin Laden or through an intermediary.
So when he wants to make a call,
he leaves the house, walks a few blocks,
"then switches on the phone."
"We need to keep canvassing
the neighborhood until we find him."
We got a shooter.
We're blocked.
Let me talk to them.
They said white faces don't belong here.
If they don't move, shoot them.
He still on?
He's east of us. Try the market.
Okay, heading east.
Fuck.
"We got a signal on Tipu Road
for 10 minutes."
"Then he went to Umar Road
for five minutes."
"Nogaza Road."
"Darya Abad, that's in the Umar Road area."
"In Rawalpindi, Haider Road."
"Roomi Road."
"He went to the Convoy Road,
which is near the hospital."
"All right? So that's Haider,"
"Roomi Road, Said, Nogaza, Taimur."
"He made a call from Haifa Street."
That's the spice district.
Lahore Street, which is also in Pesh,
30 minutes.
"Wazir Bagh Road, five."
"Nishter Abad, five."
"Phandu Road, five minutes."
"The Grand Trunk Road, 45 seconds."
"There's no pattern. Sometimes he calls
every two weeks, sometimes every three."
"There's no consistency."
"I can't predict when he's gonna make
another call 'cause the guy's erratic."
"Right there! Back up!"
"Meanwhile, our chief foreign
correspondent Richard Engel confirms"
"...the CIA's top spy in Pakistan
has been pulled out of there."
"He's been receiving death threats
after being named"
"...publicly in a lawsuit by the family
of a victim of a U.S. drone attack."
"Richard Engel quotes a senior
intelligence official"
"...as saying the officer is returning
to the U.S."
"...after the decision was made the terrorist
threats against him, in Pakistan,"
"were of such a serious nature,
it would not be smart not to act."
ISI fucked you.
I'm so sorry, Joseph.
Still on tower three.
Five.
Signal getting stronger.
Ten. Fifteen.
"Keep going."
"Twenty. Fifteen. Ten."
"Signal's getting weaker."
We lost him. No signal.
Heading south.
He's up at five again.
Fifteen. Twenty.
He's moving fast.
He's in a vehicle.
Weaker now. He's shifted.
We're back to five.
He's close by here somewhere.
I don't get it.
He's driving in circles.
- No change?
- No.
Now let's hope he comes back around.
Okay.
Fifteen.
Twenty.
Thirty.
Forty.
Fifty.
We're within 10 meters of him.
Back to 40.
He's here somewhere.
Look at the cars. Look at the cars.
He's in a vehicle.
The guy with the phone in the white car.
You see him?
Is that him?
- Could be.
- You got him?
- Got him.
- Okay, I'm breaking off.
The guy you've been looking for,
geolocated, on his cell phone
...in his white car.
Thank you so much.
If you're right,
the whole world's gonna want in on this.
So you got to stick to your guns now.
Okay. No, it's great to speak to you, too.
I'm amazed that you're still here.
No, I can do...
Let me have a look.
Why don't we say 1:30.
Yeah.
Can you just hold the line, please?
I need a picket line along
the GT highway
...and men spaced at intervals
along the road and at every exit.
Maya, I know.
So you agree with me now,
this is important.
No, I've just learned from
my predecessor
...that life is better when
I don't disagree with you.
"Our current hypothesis is that he lives"
"...somewhere along the highway,
in one of the towns,"
"or a medium-sized city called Abbottabad,
or up near Kashmir."
"Kashmir's interesting because
it's a way station for the Tribals."
"Abbottabad is interesting
because we know"
"...from detainee reporting that
Abu Faraj stayed there briefly in 2003."
"The good news is he's driving
a white SUV."
"SUVs are actually pretty rare
in Pakistan."
"If he was driving a sedan or a compact,
we'd be fucked."
"Obviously, this assumes he doesn't
change vehicles."
Good morning.
Good morning, Amad.
"Any American in Pakistan is a target."
They don't necessarily know I'm CIA.
Doesn't matter.
You're on a list.
Yeah.
And you of all people should know that
once you're on their list, you never get off.
Next time, there may not be
bulletproof glass to save you.
We'll keep up on the surveillance
as best we can.
"The high-res version.
Can you get closer than that?"
"Yeah, we can up-res this image."
"- Even more?
- Yeah, do that."
"- Make a PDF, e-mail it to me, cc George.
- Okay, that's good."
"- Thank you very much.
- Thank you."
"I'll take that. Thank you very much."
- Take that to her.
- You got it.
"You could clean that audio as well.
Just take the low end out."
Hey.
All right. So tell me how
I'm doing so far.
Basically, we got a guy who
rolled with Al-Qaeda
...and did services for him.
We lost him for seven years.
Now we find him again, and, boy,
does he have a really nice house.
Is that it?
Pretty much.
All right, let's go talk to the boss.
You should sit back there.
- Sorry.
- No.
So, they're gonna ask if bin Laden
is at the end of this rainbow,
is the Pak military with him?
The question isn't,
"Are the Paks protecting bin Laden?"
The question is, "Would he allow himself
to be protected by the Paks?"
I mean, why would he trust them?
He tried to kill Musharraf.
- Hello.
- Sir.
All right, go ahead.
So, a little context here.
If you take a right out of Islamabad,
drive about 45 minutes north,
you'll find yourself here in Abbottabad.
Now, it's a mostly middle-class community,
some ex-military.
Not particularly interesting to us.
Except we did find this compound,
which is unique.
We've got a 16-foot wall around
the entire perimeter.
The windows are blacked out.
There's even a seven-foot privacy wall here,
so even if we got up high,
we couldn't get a vantage point.
I mean, it's a fortress.
Well, can't you put a camera somewhere?
In these trees here, maybe?
Get a look into the main house?
It'd probably be discovered.
Well, we have to get a look
into the house, don't we?
All right.
What's this, this cluster of buildings
down here?
The PMA. It's the
Pakistani Military Academy.
It's their West Point.
And how close is that to the house?
About a mile.
4,221 feet.
It's closer to eight-tenths of a mile.
Who are you?
I'm the motherfucker that found
this place, sir.
Really?
All right, I want to know more about who's
inside this house by the end of the week.
Sir.
"Motherfucker."
Good.
Morning, George!
21 days.
It's been 21 days since
we found the house.
Nothing's happened.
- Yeah?
- "Maya, it's Steve."
Swing by. I want to show you something.
Okay.
Okay, you can leave it paused for now,
but we're gonna...
- play through that, go straight...
- Hey.
- Maya. Come see.
- Yeah.
- Okay, this is from a few minutes ago, okay?
So remember, we've got two males,
- two females and seven kids.
- What's that?
Okay, I'm saying that's Bushra,
the brother's wife.
Well, how do you know the gender?
Well, look, this is a clothesline
right here, for laundry.
Men don't mess with the wash.
Okay, now, watch. It takes her
about four seconds
...to move from there to the front door,
- so she's on the older side.
- What's that up there?
Those are kids, they're shuffling around,
sword-fighting or something with sticks.
You can see their height relative to this,
these are cows.
So they're probably between
seven and nine.
- Boys, definitely.
- Your female's moving fast.
Okay, that's what I wanted to show you.
Can we pause this, please?
That's not the same lady.
That's female number three.
So you found two males, three females.
That's correct.
So if there are three females,
there ought to be three males.
"Observing Muslim women live
with their parents"
...or with their husbands.
We think there's a third family
living in the house.
So this third male that you've identified
as possibly being bin Laden,
do I give up all hope
of ever seeing a photograph of him?
Hope? Yeah.
You give up your hope right now.
We scan for heat signatures,
but we can't validate if it's a man
or a woman up there.
"We talked about burrowing a pinhole camera,
but there's a high risk of discovery."
"We found a safe house,"
"but we can't get a vantage point
to fire a telescope over the balcony wall."
"We have explored the possibility of
digging tunnels,"
"of sending hot air balloons,
of rerouting"
"...supply C-130s to take a peek,
but that might be too alerting."
"We've looked for ways of collecting
available DNA from his trash,"
"you know, looking for his toothbrush,
but they burn the trash."
"We started a vaccination program."
"We sent a doctor to the house,
see if he could pull blood."
"But that didn't work out."
"We thought about sending a guy
with a bucket"
...to pull a sample from the sewer
to analyze his fecal matter.
What was wrong with that, exactly?
What was wrong with that?
The sample would be too diluted.
And it's asking too much to get a voice
confirmation with him on the phone?
They don't make telephone calls
from the compound.
We pulled the cell tower nearby.
And I'm also gonna give up hope that
he might ever get in that white SUV
...and drive around a bit and
we could see him.
Don't they get groceries?
The unidentified third male does not
get groceries.
He does not leave the compound.
He does not present himself
for photographs.
When he needs fresh air,
he paces around beneath a grape arbor.
But the leaves are so thick,
they obscure our satellite views.
This is a professional attempt
to avoid detection.
Okay? Real tradecraft.
The only people we've seen
behave in this way
...are other top-level
Al-Qaeda operatives.
We did a Red Team on your analysis.
According to them, this behavior could
belong to someone other than Al-Qaeda.
They did give a 40% chance
...that the unidentified third man
is a senior Al-Qaeda operative.
But they also said there's a 35% chance
he's a Saudi drug dealer,
15% chance he's a Kuwaiti arms smuggler,
10% chance he's one of the relatives
of the brothers.
Basically, we agree with you.
The house screams security,
it screams someone who wants privacy,
it even screams bad guy,
but it does not scream bin Laden.
You get the point, if you can't prove
it's bin Laden,
at least prove it's not someone else.
Like a drug dealer.
You know we lost the ability to prove that
when we lost the detainee program.
Who the hell am I supposed to ask?
Some guy in Gitmo who's all lawyered up?
He'll just tell his lawyer to warn bin Laden.
You'll think of something.
He'd be the first successful drug dealer
never to have dealt drugs.
He has no Internet access to the house.
He makes no phone calls, either in or out.
Who's he selling to? Who's he buying from?
How's he making his money?
And if you were to say he's retired,
I'd say, where's the swimming pool?
Where's the gold cage with the falcons?
And why does he send his courier
to the two cities in Pakistan
...we most associate with Al-Qaeda
...that have nothing particularly
to do with heroin production?
The President is a thoughtful,
analytical guy.
He needs proof.
Go ahead, you guys.
I got to say, your job...
I just don't get the rhythms of politics.
You think this is political?
If this was political,
we'd be having this conversation
...in October when there's
an election bump.
This is pure risk, based on deductive
reasoning, inference, supposition,
and the only human reporting you have
is six years old
...from detainees who were questioned
under duress.
The political move here is to tell you
to go fuck yourself
...and remind you that I was in the room
when your old boss pitched WMD Iraq.
"(WMD: Weapon of Mass Destruction)"
At least there you guys brought
photographs.
You know, you're right.
I agree with everything you just said.
What I meant was, a man in your position,
how do you evaluate the risk of
not doing something?
The risk of potentially letting bin Laden
slip through your fingers.
That is a fascinating question.
Hey...
I'm not saying we're gonna do it,
but the President wants to know,
if we were gonna act,
how would we do it?
Give us options.
Technically, these don't exist.
I actually tried to kill this program
a couple of times.
They've gone through
an initial round of testing,
and they have excellent radar defeat.
We just haven't tested them
with people in them yet.
You'll notice the stealth panels,
similar to what we use on the B-2.
The rotors have been muffled
with decibel killers.
It's slower than a Black Hawk
and lacks the offense and the stability,
but it can hide.
So, excuse me, but what do we need
this for in Libya?
I mean, Qaddafi's anti-air
is virtually nonexistent.
Maya, do you want to brief him?
There are two narratives about
the location of Usama bin Laden.
The one that you're most familiar with
...is that UBL is hiding in a cave
in the Tribal Areas,
that he's surrounded
by a large contingent of loyal fighters.
But that narrative is pre-9/11
understanding of UBL.
The second narrative is that he's living
in a city.
Living in a city with multiple points
of egress and entry,
access to communications,
so that he can keep in touch
with the organization.
You can't run a global network
of interconnected cells from a cave.
We've located an individual we believe,
based on detainee reporting,
is bin Laden's courier.
He's living in a house
in Abbottabad, Pakistan.
And we assess
... that one of the other occupants
of the house
...is UBL.
General.
Excuse me.
So, UBL, you got an intel source
on the ground?
- No.
- No?
Okay, so how do you know it's bin Laden?
'Cause the truth is we've been
on this op before, it was '07,
and it wasn't bin Laden, and we lost
a couple of guys.
Totally understand. bin Laden uses a courier
to interact with the outside world.
By locating the courier,
we've located bin Laden.
That's really the intel?
That's it?
Quite frankly, I didn't even want
to use you guys,
with your dip and your Velcro
and all your gear bullshit.
I wanted to drop a bomb.
But people didn't believe in this lead
enough to drop a bomb.
So they're using you guys as canaries,
in the theory that if bin Laden
isn't there,
you can sneak away, and no one
will be the wiser.
But bin Laden is there.
And you're gonna kill him for me.
They're nervous downtown.
I don't think we'll get an approval
this decision cycle.
It's her against the world.
Yeah.
I'm about to go look the President
in the eye,
and what I'd like to know,
no fucking bullshit,
is where everyone stands on this thing.
Now, very simply, is he there
or is he not fucking there?
We all come at this through the filter
of our own past experiences.
Now, I remember Iraq WMD very clearly.
I fronted that.
And I can tell you the case for
that was much stronger than this case.
A fucking yes or a no.
We don't deal in certainty,
we deal in probability,
and I'd say there's a 60%
probability he's there.
I concur, 60%.
I'm at 80%. Their OPSEC is what
convinces me.
"OPSEC: OPerations SECurity is a term originating
in U.S. military jargon, as a process that
identifies critical information."
You guys ever agree on anything?
Well, I agree with Mike.
We're basing this mostly
on detainee reporting,
and I spent a bunch of time
in those rooms.
I'd say it's a soft 60, sir.
I'm virtually certain
there's some high-value target there.
I'm just not sure it's bin Laden.
Well, this is a little bit of
a clusterfuck, isn't it?
I'd like to know what Maya thinks.
We're all incorporating
her assessment into ours.
100% he's there.
Okay, fine, 95%, 'cause I know
certainty freaks you guys out.
But it's 100.
They're all cowed.
What do you think of the girl?
I think she's fucking smart.
We're all smart, Jeremy.
May I join you?
How is the food down here anyway?
It's okay.
How long have you worked for the CIA?
Twelve years. I was recruited out
of high school.
And do you know why we did that?
I don't think I can answer
that question, sir.
I don't think I'm allowed to answer.
All right.
What else have you done for us?
Besides bin Laden.
Nothing.
I've done nothing else.
Well, you certainly have a flair for it.
"No. Yeah."
"All right, let's be serious, now."
"Don't fuck around on this one, dude."
"You're just fucking around 'cause
I'm up by two games."
"How many you got?"
So, Patrick, be honest with me.
You really believe this story?
I mean, no offense. No offense, I know.
But Usama bin Laden?
Yeah.
What part convinced you?
Her confidence.
That's the kind of concrete data point
I'm looking for.
I tell you, buddy, her confidence
is the one thing that's keeping me
...from getting ass-raped in a Pakistani
prison. I'm gonna be honest with you, bro.
I'm cool with it.
Yeah?
"Maya, I wanted you to hear it first."
You know that thing we talked about?
- "It's gonna happen."
- When?
Tonight.
"Good luck."
"- 50 bucks?
- 50 bucks."
"- 50 bucks!
50 bucks.
"Lucky shot."
"Go."
"Apache One, you are clear."
Copy.
Copy that.
"Thirty seconds to first turn."
Hey, Justin, what are you listening to?
Tony Robbins.
Tony Robbins, really?
You should listen to it.
I got plans for after this, big-time.
I want to talk to all of you about it.
Who here has been in a helo crash before?
Okay, so we're all good.
"We just crossed the border.
Now entering Pakistan."
Pakistani comms, no chatter.
"Three minutes. Stand by for doors open."
"Two minutes."
"Should be coming up just off our nose,
11 o'clock."
"Eyes on target."
Stay tight.
"Thirty seconds."
Hey! Slide right, slide right!
"- Too much updraft off these walls!
- Hey!"
"We've lost power. Go to lockout."
"Hey!"
"Hard landing."
"Fuck!"
"Prince five-one is down.
Prince five-one is down."
"Black Hawk down in the animal pen."
"This way!"
"This mission is still a go.
I repeat, we are a go."
"Alpha team is in the animal pen,
making entry for AC-1."
"No ropes. Wheels down."
"Prayer room's clear."
"Breacher!"
"Echo team is away.
Prince five-two exiting Alpha Oscar."
"Three, two, one. Execute!"
"Ibrahim!"
"Come on out!"
"- Get down!
- Down, down, down, down!"
"Down! Throw your hands in the air!"
"Down, down, down, down! Down!"
You've killed him.
"All right, go, I got her."
"Down, sit down."
"Echo 11 on perimeter."
"Ready to breach at P-2."
"Fire in the hole."
Failed breach, failed breach.
Back it up! Back it up! Main gate!
We got an unlocked door.
Abrar.
It's okay. It's okay.
"This is Echo 11."
"We're going to breach the main gate."
"Negative. This is Echo 01."
"I'm internal, in the corridor."
"I'll let you guys in."
"Roger that."
Shut that fucking kid up, please.
Talk to me.
No fucking way we can blow this thing.
God fucking damn it,
can you pop it manually?
No.
"Alpha 3, this is Echo 11."
We're at our primary set point,
prepping to breach.
"Wait one. We're internal
on the south side."
This is a negative breach.
Roger. Ready to make our entry out here.
Yeah, roger that.
We're coming to meet you.
Stay with these kids
and don't let them in that back room.
- Good?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Yeah.
I forgot, were we supposed
to crash that helo?
Ibrahim tried to shoot through the door.
- Yeah?
- I popped him from outside.
I fucking smoked Abrar and his wife.
She still alive?
She's gonna bleed out.
- What a fucking mess.
- Yeah.
Go, go, go.
This is Echo 09.
We have unknowns gathering
on the southwest rooftops.
Locked gate blocking the stairs.
Breacher up.
Back it up, back up.
Hey, back it up.
Watch out.
Execute.
- Go, go.
- This is Echo 05 moving to level two.
Hakim, get those guys back.
Khalid.
Echo 02 moving to deck three.
Clear.
Hakim, get them back or
I'll start smoking them.
Wait, wait, wait.
Go back, they will kill you!
They will kill you!
Go back!
Come here!
No vest.
All clear.
Oh, fucking shit.
Usama?
Down.
All right, get him.
Got a possible jackpot.
"Roger that. Possible jackpot."
"Shoot."
It's okay, it's okay.
- Come on.
- Get down.
- Dude.
- It's okay.
Do you even realize what you just did?
Who is he?
Hey, hey, hey!
He is Al Noori Hasan.
Yo, she says it's not him.
Talk to the kid.
It's okay.
Daughter, what is his name?
Name, name.
- We need them down.
- All right.
Okay, come on, come on. Come on.
"This is Red 02."
"Geronimo."
"For God and country."
All stations, target secure,
target secure.
Roger. Copy that. Target secure.
"Target secure. Commence SSE."
"Proper SSE right now."
"Books, DVDs, CDs."
"Every fucking hard drive.
Do not leave a hard drive."
"Hey, open that for me."
"Let's go, guys."
Yo, what's up?
I shot the third-floor guy.
Why don't you get to work? Grab a bag.
"QRF is inbound, eight miles out."
Pak Air Force is responding.
Fourteen minutes to intercept.
"Any station, this is Red 02.
We need a body bag."
This is Echo 09. Stand by.
Hakim, I got this. Get it to them.
Let's go, buddy.
Echo 05, this is Red 02.
How long do you need for SSE?
We're gonna need at least 10 minutes, sir.
Echo 05, you have four mikes.
This is a gold mine.
I need more time than that.
Echo 05, if you're not at the L.Z. at four
mikes, I'm gonna leave your ass behind.
"(L.Z.: Landing Zone)"
The Paks have scrambled the F-16s.
Four minutes!
"Prince five-two, inbound for L.Z."
Where do you need the bag?
"Third deck."
- Here!
- Here.
And up.
"All right, let's move it out."
Let's go! Now!
"You've got one mike to blow
that downed helo."
- You all right?
- Yeah.
"QRF-46 inbound for L.Z., 30 seconds out."
"Chopper 4-6, we are demoing 5-1."
"Chopper 4-6, wave off."
"4-6, wave off! Wave off!"
Up!
Well done, Patrick.
Thank you.
- Move him through!
- "All right, listen up, gentlemen,"
"read the signs."
First floor, hard drives, files, anything!
"Second floor, opposite, down on the right!"
Third floor, ladies' underwear.
"That's right, there can't be
hat many of them, right?"
"- And mark all media!
- CDs, DVDs."
"- Who's got a Sharpie?
- CDs."
"CDs."
- Right here.
- Good job, man.
- This all right?
- "Move it along, bring it in."
- Nice job.
- "All right, all media, CDs, DVDs."
"- I want them! That's all second floor
right there."
"Who's logging on this table?"
"Where do the hard drives go?"
"- Mark on tables.
- Yes, sir."
"You got Ziploc bags and Sharpies,
use them."
"No, mark all media."
"Good job."
"Gentlemen, watch your backs."
"Slow down!"
"Thank you, sir."
"- Good job.
- Slow down."
"- Video cameras?
- Video cameras, where was it found?"
"Second floor!"
"All right."
"Yes, sir. One moment, please."
"One moment, please."
"Sir, the Agency expert gave
visual confirmation."
"Yes, sir, the girl, 100%."
"Thank you, sir."
Are you Maya?
Yeah.
"That's the only name they gave me."
You can sit wherever you want.
You're the only one on the manifest.
"You must be pretty important."
"You got the whole plane to yourself."
"Where do you want to go?"